
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		uh actually it turns out to be an interesting topic because i'm now in the middle of a job search graduating here
 		and realizing that one of the things that's not really well represented in benefits often is flexibility because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will
 		have some set of benefits where ever she's working and the ability to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix</ENAMEX> and match in a useful way particularly with things like medical and dental it's something that i've been uh looking for
 	
 	
 		that's true one of the really disturbing things for me is uh is the way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> mandates that all insurance policies include particular benefits
 		uh even though you could you might never have any need for them uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> they just passed a law for example that every health insurance policy
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		must include coverage for mammograms and pap smears doesn't matter that you're single and male you still have coverage for mammograms and pap smears
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh  it's that kind of thing that uh uh that bothers me
 	
 	
 		that's amusing  yeah
 		yeah i think we have a similar thing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and i think that at the moment you can't issue health insurance that doesn't have coverage for substance abuse and certain other mental health issues and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> treatment yeah drug treatment and alcohol and yeah that's the same thing here even if you're
 	
 	
 		and the result is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't provide it at all or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over</NUMEX> charge
 	
 	
 		even if you're a Mormon you still have to have uh coverage for smoking recovery you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but but in general your idea about flexibility i think is a very good one because uh
 		uh if you if you have a a full gamut of
 		of coverages um uh uh there might there might be a lot of things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>  is willing willing to pay for but that you're simply not interested in and what you rather prefer to do is say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		don't get some of those programs but shuffle the money over to another place to lower your deductibles or something
 	
 	
 		the other things they do seem to be willing to spend money in strange ways for instance i know where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> works she can get for something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or ten</TIMEX> dollars a month sole health insurance but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it would cost her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an additional sixty or seventy a month</TIMEX> to include me on that policy well assuming that we both work at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that feel this way
 		we may very well miss out on the convenience of going to the same place
 		because those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> will never get together and agree okay one of them will pay for all of the uh the dental and optical and the other one'll pay for the medical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		instead it's it's very much designed towards self only insurance
 		i don't know if all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are that way but a lot of them i have seen are
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that uh a a lot of them are that way they uh they
 		they deal they deal with coordination of benefits and and no no particular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> who's the primary carrer and who's the secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> but um
 		uh everyone tries to be the secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> and it's very difficult to to get it worked out uh i know at at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayes</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the coverage for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> is is completely paid by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and to get your entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> covered is thirty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight dollars</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		well that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		it is i'm very pleased uh i think uh very pleased with the benefit package that we have that has uh uh a dental check ups are completely covered um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there's a lot of particular things in the medical package that are covered from the first dollar particularly if you chose low cost alternatives like out patient treatment rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inpatient</ENAMEX> and uh things like that
 		um they have good educational benefits if you want to uh try to improve your uh you know go work further on a degree or or get a master's degree of something uh uh course
 	
 	
 		that's something this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> at at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate student</ENAMEX> negotiated plan was very bad about this idea of low cost alternatives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> around who were affiliated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> who you can go see and all your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> work is covered under their research
 		so in fact you're saving them you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of dollars</NUMEX> in in billings by going to a research uh
 		physician yet at the same time they will only pay based on eighty percent of the customary reasonable charges for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> visits
 		and won't take into account the fact that by seeing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> you're saving them you know a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> over going to somebody else and a lot of things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um one thing i was wondering is something i've noticed that that they don't publicize much but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations school</ENAMEX> and government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have is legal uh services of some sort
 	
 	
 		yeah we don't have that either
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		uh in in some ways i think it's it would be very good thing uh you know to be able to get your wills done and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh advice just by picking up the phone or without having to actually uh you know pay somebody extra
 		
 		
 	