
 
     		
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so do you think our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are honest at this point in time
 	
 	
 		generally i don't think they are uh my my personal opinion is that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are out for their own good because they they're entrenched they don't ever have to go out and get a real job they just stay in their current job you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i agree uh with with both of those things but uh do you see any way of like altering it so that they would become more honest
 	
 	
 		i think by putting term limitations on you could you could slow down some of the problems uh but it has to be not just at the national level but at the you know the state and the local level too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and i don't know which ones but they've been in office since the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nineteen</TIMEX> forties and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i they they've never had a job i mean they've never gone out in the real world and and paid normal taxes i know they pay taxes but they don't you know they they get paid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and twenty five</NUMEX> grand a year
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is more than twice my salary by quite a bit and you know i'm going like i i don't understand how they're supposed to be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> and yet they're paid more than i am and they work less
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know less than i do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh the the only problem the only problem i see with term limitations um
 		is that i think that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as is in with most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> is just so complex that there's a very large you know there there is a learning curve
 		and that you know you can't just send someone off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and expect you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his first day</TIMEX> to be an effective
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Congress</ENAMEX> person
 		uh i think i think there really is a there's a lot they need to learn you know when you get there
 	
 	
 		i think i think that's true however i think that's always been true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean that's true of the presidency too and we seem to be able to get along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> turnover every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years or four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 	
 	
 		and uh they i mean there is a lot to learn but maybe it will keep them on their toes and a little bit more active in trying to catch up i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> is too short
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it has to be extended uh you know a term limitation for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would be like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> terms or even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> terms or you would increase the length of the of each term of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX>
 		uh but maybe standardizing on on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a four year</TIMEX> term for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Senate</ENAMEX> and the the presidency and then uh staggering them so that you don't you we aren't having a massive ballot every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		uh the other the other thing that that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> bothers me about our system is just that um
 		in for for
 		in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> the amount of power any any particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> critter has
 		is based on their seniority and how long they've been there so it's you know for you know uh so unless you have actual you know across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> uh limitations the uh you know the idea of well
 		we're going to just we're  i'm i'm just going to you know vote vote against the incumbent every time doesn't work you know it's going to wind up hurting your state if all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> aren't doing it at the same time
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think i think that that's true but then you have you have the same abuse of power on the flip side of that coin uh the C i A is moving out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> which is a really stupid location for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> like that and for almost any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> i mean the action isn't in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> i hate to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> this information but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it really doesn't  uh the world does not revolve around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> uh as far as this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is concerned the world does revolve around D C you know as far as the politics in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are concerned the national politics and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C I A</ENAMEX> is a a very large very high profile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and to have it located out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> yeah you know it might only be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two hour</NUMEX> drive from here but that's a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two hour</NUMEX> drive
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it it's a i think it's a mistake to move large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> like that or is it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F B I</ENAMEX> i don't remember but i think there's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i mean  i don't see why it makes a big difference the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> because you know officially they don't do they don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> other than administrative
 	
 	
 		yeah that's officially
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean we all know that that's not necessarily true but i i think that there are there are advantages to having seniority and uh
 		turnover or not having a complete turnover every some small number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i think there are i mean there's an institutional memory that you need to maintain
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think that uh all with all the perks that we've given them i mean i heard on the radio back a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>
 		uh during the incidents where they were you know like they aren't paying their their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> bills and they're bouncing checks all over the place uh one of the radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> over here listed off every single one of the perks
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	