
 
     		
 	
 		what do you feel about the um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		present situation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it looks like it's just about as volatile as it usually is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i'd agree i think i think there's definitely been some changes um and i think you know the
 		the um end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> will definitely have it's effect on on the situation
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		you know in that
 		there's there's not you know there you know if
 		you know it's basically since the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> there was always you know that little proxy war going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know with um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> funding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and you had the um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> funding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then we'll see what happens when uh they're not funded quite as much or supplied with arms the same way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum yeah but on the same token you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has lost a lot of their you know value to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> in being you know the foothold of capitalism
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know in
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i we tend to be pretty strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> ourselves you know we support kind of cringe when they make mistakes but yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		overall tend to support them but i think one of the most interesting things to me recently was you know during the war uh in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> was uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the fact that they did not retaliate for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Scud</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> that were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> launched there that just seemed to me to be a uh a phenomenal uh demonstration of restraint and it must have reflected uh uh some awful good uh diplomacy on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah but on the other hand you know if
 		they would've had a hard time retaliating because
 		they you know they they wouldn't have been given access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> codes
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		they basically would've you know had a had a fly they'd had they would've had had to fly through you know two enemies
 	
 	
 		uh you don't think they've got the codes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> already
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> had claimed that they would have not given them to them
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		i mean of course you know
 		public statements can be taken for
 	
 	
 		that's true  they can can't they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well what do you what about this situation with uh you know the uh
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		continual uh harassment by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> right now and uh apparently failing to let the in uh arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> have free access
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you know it
 		
 
 		well to begin with you know i pretty much question our what what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>'s motives were in uh in in actually the original involvement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  i
 		the cynical side of me says that you know who it was more for
 		uh um
 		the the domestic political situation than for anything else
 	
 	
 		hm yeah okay
 	
 	
 		you know and that you know and for portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as a strong president
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		um i mean i really i really think that that
 		my gut feeling is that that that you know he pretty much picked picked a fight with um
 		with um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> i mean i'm not not saying at all that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> wasn't quite willing to get enter that fight
 	
 	
 		um
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i i think i think that
 		that um
 		we chose to have our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> feelings hurt
 	
 	
 		um-hum well do you think that uh we should ignore it and just allowed him to go ahead and uh
 	
 	
 		we're a lot
 	
 	
 		you know move on into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> and see what happened
 	
 	
 		i think i mean i thought
 		i think that
 		um
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> we've allowed lots of things like that to happen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i really don't i really don't think that
 		i think i think it was it was there were there were a lot more demographic related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> involved than
 		true foreign policy interests
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well may have been you know i'm not saying that that's not the case uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and i mean in in in along those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> since
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		since you know it really it really didn't accomplish very much except we're getting getting uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i just don't i just don't
 		i i i don't i i i don't foresee
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> making the decision to invest a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manpower</ENAMEX> and money and
 		you know in in fighting a second battle
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		um
 		you know over over the um
 		over over what what what probably won't accomplish him accomplish much for him politically
 	
 	
 		no it doesn't look like we're getting ready to do to do much more in there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even at this point
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		yeah well what about uh
 		do you have any any views on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s relation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> do you think we ought to you know back off on our support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or what do you
 	
 	
 		well i have i have very mixed feelings about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> um
 		i think that
 		that for a long while we've we've had almost a
 		you know had had this
 		
 		
 	