
 
     		
 	
 		it sounds like you feel like taxes are probably too high
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i think there's a big waste of our tax dollar
 	
 	
 		it does seem that way i was trying to think of whether we pay more tax now than we did <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> but it doesn't seem like we get as much out value for the tax dollar
 	
 	
 		we don't uh we it there's there's too much um
 		uh
 		pocket stuffing uh going on as far as different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> contracting to do things for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> and
 		do uh projects for the state and you know course they they prove that all the time on over the TV
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it does seem like the special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are what what keeps taxes high
 	
 	
 		but i
 		right that uh i just i just pay you know more taxes than than i can imagine if i could get i've got a little piece of property
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just i mean when i tell you little piece of property i mean i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half acres</NUMEX> it's out in the country
 		and if i could get what they're charging me for taxes on that i would sell it in a minute
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		you know so that that's why i just don't uh
 		there's a lot of you know a lot of expense
 		as far as our taxes and all the all the hidden costs that they spend our money on that that they shouldn't be spending our money on
 		but uh
 		i i'm i'm very uh i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> so i'm very touchy about taking every damn dime i make
 	
 	
 		yeah that does make it difficult
 	
 	
 		it does
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		really does are you you are you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh well i used to work in finance but i i don't any longer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was also trying to think of whether our tax rates are high compared to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i seem to recall that uh many many other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have higher tax rates than ours
 		but they may also get better value for the dollar that's the real question
 	
 	
 		right well you know i've i can handle the i can handle the tax money the amount of taxes that i pay i can handle that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it
 		you know when you hit all the uh bad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and uh
 		and you hear of all the misuse of the money and that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's a that's a bigger
 	
 	
 		right that's what's irritating
 	
 	
 		problem to me than than having to pay them
 	
 	
 		It's also irritating that
 		you we keep hearing a lot of lip service about how  how to make it better and how to spend it more wisely but they never to seem hear that that it changes or improves
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i think i think one of our uh and this is really not the total uh thing uh not totally on taxes but one of our things is our on our uh the our
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> is our uh why in the world they don't get rid of
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> either get rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> or get rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> you know get rid of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those housing systems and uh because that's costing that's costing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> multimillions multimillions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh but they govern each other and they they vote their selves in to staying in where they are you know and um
 		i don't i've never understood uh you know why i there is one state what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that only has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> housing i meant one governing body
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't remember hearing that
 	
 	
 		okay there is there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> state i've i in fact i don't know whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> it's a northern state
 		um
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> housing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and uh one governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they their taxes are are
 		more well spent
 		but uh no i've you know i disagree with a lot of things but um a lot of things i can't change
 		but uh
 		what state what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are you from
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but now i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm course i'm
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too but i i'm think my the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> that i pay taxes in are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the highest tax rate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> there are anywhere around here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> are that where where do you live
 	
 	
 		so
 		i live in uh my i have some my little piece of land is in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Benedict County</ENAMEX> and i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is that in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		still in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		still in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you hear this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> accent
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i can't get rid of it
 	
 	
 		course in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> at least you still don't  have income tax
 	
 	
 		well i think we pay it in other ways
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think we i really think we pay it in a lot of other ways it's funny to me too that uh why the government taxes has a tighter higher tax rate for a single person
 		than they do for a married couple
 		
 		
 	