
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay well Mark our situation is that we do have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that is uh in the situation of choosing college she's actually at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bible College</ENAMEX> for this current year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i guess uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost it really it's a question of
 		what
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> wants to have in the way of a career and then uh
 		uh which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> can best offer that program
 		and then it comes down to the dollar you have to uh it's whether or not you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> for that jurisdiction or you know it does it comes down to uh trying to come with a trade off of the costs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh what do you feel about come of the things that need to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		damn it i agree with pretty much with everything you've said um
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the one thing that i you know i'd advise any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> um you know or any or any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> looking for a college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">um</ENAMEX> is that
 		
 
 		i think i think you know it's really important for them to actually visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and actually try and get away from you know the guided tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and try and talk to the you know actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> there
 		because you know they're just um in my experience i've talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges um</ENAMEX> that you know
 		the the the way the you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the</ENAMEX> lifestyle pictured in the catalogs catalogs isn't always  the whole story
 	
 	
 		no you the the college the the catalogs are sales material it doesn't matter whether  you know they're they're selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh and true it uh really is helpful if a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		parent and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> can get there and see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and the real life experiences of the school
 		uh i guess there's a difference in here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX>
 		at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saskatoon</ENAMEX> is primarily uh off campus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident students</ENAMEX> like they just live in the community
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you know i know that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> particularly as they get to be a little bit on the
 		smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">side</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dormitory</ENAMEX> life is uh is right on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> as well and that you know that changes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of it quite a bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> which is you know primarily an engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh you know i think i really do miss the fact you know that it's not a university that there's there's not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the you know it tends to be a very conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and there and there doesn't tend to be the diversity of views that a lot of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> will will have
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i guess we're here this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> that has for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> had the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that uh will travel the farthest on uh
 		on a small quantity of gas our engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in competitions and that's the kind of thing that also you see uh if you can see the kinds of
 		achievements that have been made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> can give you idea of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the school uh whether you you know in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense whether you've got a spirit of innovation and excellence or whether you've got a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know it's sort of
 		somewhat unkind but producing graduates um you know as sort of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some development and some training uh like it's easy enough to crank out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> but to really challenge them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and that can vary between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and faculties even
 		as to how you know what the attitude
 		towards achievement is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		do you uh
 		have anyone that you're seriously needing to uh
 		feed information to i suppose if you're actually at at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> as a student you're a ways away from that
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i don't really know of anyone that's like looking that's looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> now you know because with the exception of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>  then the only advise passed down is don't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX>  uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		no actually actually i'm i'm i'm more interested in in in choosing the right job job when you graduate  type information
 	
 	
 		right
 		well that's that's one of the really a valid point that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to consider as well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know to going to college <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> is going to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four to eight years</TIMEX> depending on
 		the programs programs programs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s involved in and after that you have to be out in the real world and have to be able to support yourself
 	
 	
 		program
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if you go in an area that there is just not much of a job market  jeez the best
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		like a fine arts education i
 	
 	
 		right best training in the world is not going to feed put food on your table
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		
 		
 	