
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> yeah how do you keep up on current affairs
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well Frank um generally i keep on up oh listening to radio news uh listening to some television news uh the rest of it i guess what everybody's talking about um
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i guess if part of me says if it's that important i'll find out if i don't find out it's not that important into the way that it affects my life right now um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's a good way of looking at it
 	
 	
 		that's i guess that's primarily why um we do go through periods where we uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do get the local newspaper um you know and for for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and eighty thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> is still very slanted and uh you know
 		you end up and you say well yeah okay and you
 	
 	
 		slightly liberal to the left or to the right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what'd you say
 	
 	
 		oh i would say maybe it's
 		a little morbid to the right now you know here we kind of talk more liberal and conservative rather than left right but uh it's a fairly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> minded um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i see huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know it's uh you tend to only get the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side you don't get kind of uh
 		a broad coverage of of the reality of what happened
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i get my uh news from really from all the sources uh i will say probably radio is uh
 		is a prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> because i like to listen to radio news uh on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX> for world news and then it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> i listen to usually have local news after that and i also watch the TV for
 		for news and i take two newspaper uh the local city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portsmouth</ENAMEX> and also the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> so uh
 		you know that's that's how i stay informed plus from talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as you say if it's real important you're going to hear about it from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> besides
 	
 	
 		right yeah i i guess i would think that you have a bit of an advantage in that you do have a an option for something that is more local and then something that is more statewide
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um here i guess really we're dealing with uh
 		the regions being
 		i i hesitate to say sparsely populated but really you know we'll get to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> that's uh
 		several <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds miles square</NUMEX> and we've only got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh you know so regional coverage uh is pretty sparse and so we our next step from local tends to be virtually national or international
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and i suppose you might compare it to you don't hear very much <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> news
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		um you know so
 	
 	
 		but you do but you do i i take it
 	
 	
 		uh we we can at times you know being you know being right on the north edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we actually uh some of the current events are more an aspect of uh some uh sports interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saskatchewan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's not hardly an current event as such but um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minot</ENAMEX> does a lot of advertising to uh bring tourist industry down
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		um so you know we kind of get stuck with uh you get your local news or you get your news that's based nationally and uh so then it has
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anything that intends to be local interest uh is quite localized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto Montreal Ottawa Vancouver</ENAMEX> that kind of thing you know so you're getting uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we have a sports interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> mainly uh Montreal uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> there uh both baseball and with uh with hockey of course and with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and also uh one of the uh TV TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> is on the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in this area uh from Sherbrook
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh we we do have some news from from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> from time to time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's uh yeah and you know i suppose of our television we with our cable system we get uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saskatchewan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> with
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yes we do we also have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> which
 	
 	
 		that can be an important source of news international
 	
 	
 		yes uh yeah i i actually i really enjoy their format and so it is it can be quite informative on an international basis uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um i guess that would probably be my primary source for international news but uh not on a
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		regular prescribed basis tend to uh or i happen to be there and i'm and uh
 		
 		
 	