
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um so what is your what why do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't vote in the elections
 	
 	
 		well <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all i think they understated the turnout It's i don't i don't think that in a national election it's ever been under fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> well it's it's it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> but it's been you know it's somewhere in the fifties for sure so it it it understates it a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not vote um well it's  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> usually say they don't think it will effect anything they're certainly wrong about that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i think that that it's easy if you if if you think things are going bad enough to just turn off to the news and just not pay any attention It's the less you pay attention the less you know about what's going to effect you
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i i think i think apathy is is real big thing i mean just in the fact that you don't think you're going to have anything done i to me it's really hard to find um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		any information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> i mean i i voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know you really have to hunt to get information on them and you know as far as the local things go and if you know if you don't know them then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		that's right yeah and i i i agree uh i have made calls to various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before elections well one thing i do  i usually do is go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and study for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election</TIMEX>  before it
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah and and try to get voter guides from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and things and that helps a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		they don't ask their they don't ask enough questions they ask on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> issues and and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can respond with platitudes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what you really need to do  excuse me is find interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that that you know who's interest whose issues you are interested in and then find how the if they have done a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> survey and lots of times they have and then you have something to base it on
 		there was a back when i was living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> for public justice i don't know if you've ever heard of them perhaps
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		perhaps not i it's it's it they they really didn't you know it it sounds like they're some kind of liberal group well they were a little bit liberal on some things but they were a little bit conservative on some things too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they put out this this  uh survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> where they asked them like uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> questions uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
 		now it wasn't that great in that they didn't tailor the the question for you know for the particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> so they asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the local level things that only come up at the national level and vice versa
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh other than that it was a very good way to to see who you sympathized with and you could vote on the basis of that
 	
 	
 		yeah i that's um i don't know what it was that we had that i had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> got it from someone in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that uh it it asked uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it went all the way down well it went to some of our constables but mainly it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Plano</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um it asked it had all sorts of questions about uh economics uh education and and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		family and
 	
 	
 		things things things like abortion presumably
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but it had other things like um do you would you support um
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i know one that kind of stuck out in my mind was was would you support uh a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a two thousand</NUMEX> dollar uh
 		tax credit for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that stay you know at home and and so it had kind of a variety of of um
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		right
 	
 	
 		of questions and it it probably had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty or thirty</TIMEX> questions on it
 		it was really you know that was really good and helpful and it you know it had them you know support if they could support oppose oppose or or you know be undecided about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i
 		do do do you know what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> did it
 	
 	
 		yeah it was it was it was uh i thought it was really good but you know it course it doesn't go through all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and some of them you know you think well this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> won't have any won't have any um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yup
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		say so about any of this anyway but it's kind of good to know their opinions anyway they you know run for a different kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> once you're in politics you probably stay in politics i would think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right because yeah yeah i mean once they
 		yeah that's right that's that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point that was made that that you know uh i read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> article saying even if you don't that abortion makes any difference at uh you know at a at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> local level like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> they might get elected to something bigger and the way that they get known is by getting elected these little to these to little offices
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you got to look at their views and and that was a point that i hadn't considered the reason i ask about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is i just got uh started working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> which does just what you were suggesting and i was wondering if it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and that may have been who had done it i'm i don't remember um
 	
 	
 		if it was theirs yeah
 	
 	
 		i had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> different things i was looking at uh and that was that that was probably the most helpful i wish it had been more detailed i know that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> don't like to respond to all these questions
 	
 	
 		i you
 		
 		
 	