
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Siberian husky</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> springer spaniel
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		sprat
 		Siberian husky and a springer spaniel
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh those are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> very different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> aren't they
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah they are the springer is a little on the small side
 	
 	
 		
  
 		is he kind of hyper too or
 	
 	
 		he's sort of very
 		very hyper
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well this is uh a mutt a mutt of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> it's a part Siamese it's very vocal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tabby</ENAMEX> so um he's orange
 		
  
 	
 	
 		that must be weird to have a howling tabby
 		you know the of course you have the standard Siamese moaning and groaning and
 	
 	
 		you you don't hear it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i do now
 	
 	
 		it sounds like a baby doesn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah i don't know it's kind of strange it the body shape looks a lot like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Siamese</ENAMEX> but it's orange
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's uh male he's smaller than most tomcats you see
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah i grew up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Persians</ENAMEX> one was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighteen pounds</NUMEX> and the other was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> pounds
 	
 	
 		
  
 		wow
 	
 	
 		serious cats
 	
 	
 		huge
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah you ask permission
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah they have uh extra digits
 	
 	
 		
  
 		no
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		they just were just flat big
 	
 	
 		
  
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i've seen some <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> with uh you know extra
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		digit on their paw and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but uh so why do you have pets
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well we got this uh
 		you know the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> one's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siberian</ENAMEX> which is a real mellow thing she looks like a wolf but she's just a big baby
 	
 	
 		yeah well why why did you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the dogs</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i had dogs all my life
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i've had uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siberian</ENAMEX> was basically there for the taking if i wanted it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX>
 		so i brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Siberian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and she's just been just great with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> wanted a had a cocker when she was younger and
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		when she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and she wanted to have a another spaniel type dog
 		and
 		so we wanted a bigger spaniel because we didn't want a cocker as small as a cocker for the husky to beat up
 	
 	
 		they fight do they fight
 	
 	
 		but the what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tooth</ENAMEX> and nail
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 		
  
 	
 	
 		they're not serious except but they're just always at each other
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how do you know they are not serious
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		uh you mean they're not serious they draw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or something you mean
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> don't normally fight serious very long because normally one as big as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siberian</ENAMEX> or as small as a spaniel the spaniel knows its place pretty quickly and that takes care of that
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 		you know it's normally they're at each other just you know snarling and snapping and rolling and thumbing
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then when they're but when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siberian's</ENAMEX> decided that she she's had all that she wants of that hyper spaniel it's it's very clearly stated
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		whack
 	
 	
 		you know there are very clear words spoken in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> and the spaniel and the and the springer goes away
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh that's interesting
 		well this is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> i mean i i never had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> when i was young
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i had roommates at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point and they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and i lived with that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and i kind of liked it and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and uh my uh
 		at the time was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kia</ENAMEX> brought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> out to me when i was leaving alone down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		when i was living out there and you know i agreed to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and it was it was good company
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> would chest as you fall asleep watching TV or something crazy like that
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's why i like them sort of they keep you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		they're kind of interesting to watch sometimes
 		this one's very uh playful
 		he's the for unusual unusual for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> when he was a lot younger
 		he um used to play catch with me and uh i you throw the i catch but i'd throw the ball the whate ver it was and he'd run after it and bring it back
 	
 	
 		uh yeah that's sort of strange for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		in terms of um you know whatever happens to be around he'll he'll you know play then he also likes going hunting for
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh solar fish</ENAMEX> or whatever have you it's pretty funny
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		he likes doing that
 	
 	
 		the spaniel is death on crickets
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		really well were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> you live
 	
 	
 		she'll
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">northern Virginia</ENAMEX> right over right over the across the river from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX> have you ever driven south on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		well you know when you come over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodrow Wilson Bridge</ENAMEX> and you come around
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 		
 	