
 
     		
 	
 		do you ever think that there's a crime that's just so heinous and so bad that the person
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		who commits this crime just doesn't deserve to live anymore
 	
 	
 		that's a good question uh  there would be a point there was a point where i would have said
 		know that no one would deserve to die for for a crime that he committed but uh since i've become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and since i've
 		seen uh things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahlmer</ENAMEX> i really have to question that
 		i really uh i i can't conceive of
 		someone being that
 		brutal to that many other people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		try and figure out what would be a suitable punishment
 		uh
 	
 	
 		of the statements made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> against the the death penalty um i I like the statement made by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuomo Cuomo</ENAMEX> i I believe is um he's he's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but uh he's
 		against the death penalty
 		but um he said that he would he would want to to seriously hurt or if not kill someone if if they did something to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and that's but but even even in that circumstance in that uh
 		uh situation he would be he would hope that there would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around him who would uh
 		keep him from  doing the doing those things
 	
 	
 		oh it's a uh it's a question of your your gut reactions to something like that versus an intelligent reason response
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and that was the thing that uh killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> back uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> when someone asked him a similar question and he
 		he thought for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and gave a thoughtful well reasoned reply when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wanted to see if he was going to go for an emotion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a a gut level reaction and i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are strongly in favor of the death penalty
 		are really working from that gut level
 		uh you know whether it be a biblical force uh you know the eye for an eye a tooth for a tooth a life for a knife life type logic
 		or just uh uh some sort of anger at
 		putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> putting uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> up in federal pens for the rest of their life uh while we foot the bill
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are working at that from more of a uh a gut reaction than a a reasoned humane one
 	
 	
 		see i don't think a decision's ever gonna be made on death on the death penalty until we decide what our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison system</ENAMEX> is intended to do are they reformatories where we're trying to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
 		can't survive or or that that aren't conforming enough to society so that that we work well together or are they is it a penal
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> is it designed is it designed for punishment um the death penalty surely fits in well with uh in a penal situation where you're trying to punish
 		um perhaps not in the manner that we do it but but it it in in theory it fits in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">reformatory system</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">reformatory</ENAMEX>
 		i mean  if you if you put someone to death you you obviously can't reform them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the the other argument is that the death penalty is a deterrent
 		and i really don't uh agree with that i don't think anyone who would commit a uh a crime that would get them the death penalty
 		would stop at the moment and say
 		well i was about to kill and dismember this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but ooh if they catch me they're going to kill me so i better not do it i i just don't think that uh that it works that way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't think it's done i don't think we run it as a deterrent i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say that but i mean if it was really a deterrent i mean i think like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> in the old west you know they saw other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>
 		hanging by their necks every once in a while and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if we really want if it was really seriously gonna be a deterrent deterrent i would think that it would be public i mean i don't think it would be
 		this private thing because nobody ever nobody ever sees it if someone ever if you know like say some young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or something like that that that might be inclined more towards the life of crime
 		had to sit and watch and and see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> burn or or you know something or shot by firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> or something like that i would think you'd make a bigger impact on their life rather than
 		you know telling them that there's there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> out here
 		at the you know
 	
 	
 		well i I don't know if that would really work that way or not uh there's a lot of violence
 		
 		
 	