
 
     		
 	
 		are you a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i guess you are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> aren't you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah yeah i'm a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i'm actually from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and uh my favorite uh college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro team</ENAMEX> uh even though i'm down here still loyal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Lions</ENAMEX> even though they they lose most of the time i'm still a die hard uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Lions</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh they did well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> didn't they
 	
 	
 		yeah they did pretty well i was real happy with them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami Dolphins</ENAMEX> when i'm down here when whenever they don't they don't play <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> very often but when they do i root for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> but uh when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>'s playing anybody else i usually root for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> now that i'm down here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's you that was my favorite since i was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX> i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami Dolphins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> or uh yeah you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marino Dan Marino</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i do yeah i do he he's a good quarterback i followed him more when they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Csonka</ENAMEX> and stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griese</ENAMEX> and this was quite a while ago
 	
 	
 		yeah that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX> that's the seventies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolphins</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not that old i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only twenty seven</TIMEX> but  i just remember them playing a lot we just moved down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> and we use to go see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seahawks</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Seahawks</ENAMEX> that's right
 	
 	
 		they would do well for a few games and then they they haven't made it in the play-offs for a long time
 	
 	
 		well did you go to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> or anything like that or
 	
 	
 		um i worked up there for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huskies</ENAMEX> are pretty good right
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's right yeah they were really good up there we moved right before they took uh
 		well
 		yeah right we watched them down here for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rose Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they always beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rose Bowl</ENAMEX>  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX> always make it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rose Bowl</ENAMEX> but then some uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pac-10</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> always beats them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah they were they had a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i was pretty impressed with them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they had well we followed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> here that's who my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was and that's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second that year</TIMEX> that
 	
 	
 		ah
 		you you're near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		no well they're i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour and a half</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> i never went there i just like their passing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> that's why i like watching them but that's about how far it goes
 	
 	
 		oh
 		do do you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morten</ENAMEX> Syco
 	
 	
 		um i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morten</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i interviewed out there one time yeah
 	
 	
 		oh you did i work in the airbags
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i'm a process <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syco</ENAMEX> is the there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh okay i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Syco</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket booster</ENAMEX> and we do the airbags
 	
 	
 		that i i interviewed with them back in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		huh still going to college end
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right when i graduated yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well do you go see these football games very much i mean actually in person
 	
 	
 		not i went to one <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> i watched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami Dolphins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that must've been fun
 	
 	
 		well  actually terrible they built that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Robbie Stadium</ENAMEX> there in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> and it's not a covered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> and when it when it does rain down here in south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> it just it just comes down in buckets
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that particular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> it poured like it had never poured before and that place was like a giant funnel
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> goes down to the bottom of the field and the field just started filling up with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and in my seats up there they've got little drains but they don't they don't drain fast enough so we have water up to our knees
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh you're kidding
 	
 	
 		and you know warm rains tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> are okay but after a while you get the shivers you get cold
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was just terrible interrupted the whole game and we went to the rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for a while and uh there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> emptying out the trash cans emptying out the plastic bags and cutting holes in them and putting them over their heads and stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		but the but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that</TIMEX> that game they played the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh Steelers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> was beating them at first then they finally wound up losing at the end of the game so it was kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so my my football experience down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> has been very bad when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> i loved to go watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U of M</ENAMEX> play uh i played high school football
 		you know so i you know that's that's why i kept up with the sport but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> it's a lot different because you can go there and it's cool weather you know down here it's hot weather it's hard to get into football
 	
 	
 		yeah it is that fall weather is really nice to watch a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		that really get you in the mood that late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> sun and it's nice and cool you can bring in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peppermint</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schnapps</ENAMEX> with you in the game  you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no it it is true i love that fall weather to watching a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game you can't beat that
 	
 	
 		yep you get the apple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cider</ENAMEX> and stuff on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well how how many does that stadium hold at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred thousand</NUMEX> usually they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and three thousand</NUMEX> normally i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and three thousand</NUMEX> because it's all bleacher type seats and it just squish everybody together but it it
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah but when you're there it doesn't seem that bad because everybody's all all real nice and everything and uh like i say you just take a little hip flask of peppermint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnapps</ENAMEX> or or something like that and everything goes real good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that should be fun
 	
 	
 		yeah you have like tailgate parties there's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> right near there and everybody uh has big tailgate parties you know that's
 		get like a big bucket of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Fried Chicken</ENAMEX> and eat that before the game and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink beers</ENAMEX> and stuff like that and you go on out and watch the game it's really neat then after the game <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann Arbor</ENAMEX> is such a nice town uh it's a big uh it's a football <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the fall i mean it's just an all college town all around it's real fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		did you go to school there
 	
 	
 		i don't go to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan i</ENAMEX> went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Michigan University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh did what did you graduate in or did you graduate
 	
 	
 		uh i graduated at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Institute of Technology</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Southfield</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Southfield Michigan</ENAMEX> uh i went to uh Western for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Tech</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		well where did you go to school at
 	
 	
 		um up here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weaver State</ENAMEX> i don't know if you've heard of that
 	
 	
 		no where
 		
 		
 	