
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what kind of requirements do you think you'll  you'll want for your next car
 	
 	
 		well  uh the the one we bought most recently and and i think that's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> because uh
 		we uh we had requirements our requirements change we we now have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and so we need a little bit more room um the the one that we bought in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in eighty eight</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was a response to the the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> being born and and for that we wanted something really dependable
 		something with an excellent repair record uh something that we were not going have it in the shop a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of all the things that of all the ones that we looked at uh we looked in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> and and asked around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and and looked at our own experiences we went with a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corolla</ENAMEX> one of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> kind so it's not as big as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nineteen</TIMEX> fifties uh suburban tank
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's it's spacious enough for for now we now we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh we've got to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> you know  you got enough room for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX> and and that sort of thing um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the repair record has been really terrific um it's been very very nice
 		so i think that um based on our own experience and how satisfied and and we know what sort of driving um
 		requirements we have we we probably would go with that again it the repair record is
 		is for us repair record and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and the gas mileage is what drives it for us uh not whether it has a moon roof or uh how many CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> you can stack in it but
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but the the repair record is is the thing for us
 	
 	
 		well i i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> that's what i bought and i i guess i originally bought it because of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all because of the price
 		because when i bought it i want you know i wanted something more you know most enough as much bang for the buck
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and i bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> used and i had almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">almost sixty thousand miles</NUMEX> on it
 		and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a hundred and ten thousand</NUMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and since i've had the car i've bought a new battery i've i had a  a fan belt pulley go out and the universals in the drive shaft
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but other than that i haven't had any problems with it i when i bought it i went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> and had them put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears Road Handlers</ENAMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they've been on there for i guess <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">almost forty seven thousand miles</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's good yeah
 	
 	
 		and they look visually they look
 		brand new and it was i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX>  well i i changed my the main thing is is the maintenance as you say and i do that i keep the oil changed with the high RPM motors little you know  and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i get took it to get it tuned up
 		and when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got it i took it i wanted the valves adjusted and i the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> went in and i had to pay for it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> says you don't need them adjusted they're fine and so i waited another <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty thousand miles</NUMEX> and
 		they just adjusted them but they really weren't out of adjustment he they looked at it and he goes it looks like a brand new motor it's because i keep the oil changed and i says well i i wanted brakes changed and he said
 		he looked at them
 		and he says in the back you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fourths of your pads and in the front they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fourths you don't need them
 		and i so i've been driving all these miles and i didn't need them but i i changed the front i had the brakes done in the front anyway just because i wanted the front wheels you know packed
 		the the bearings packed and things and it worked out so i mean i i'm just amazed at the performance and i
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> it just seems that as far as the well i just going interject real quick as a my next purchase i want something with a little more safety features i want the air bags and the antilock brakes that's that's something that i want
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but um i was going to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interject</ENAMEX> say is that
 		when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> they sell their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and there's too much of a i i believe there's just too much of a profit margin
 		and you they're
 		you're not getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> you're you're you're paying for you might say markup where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you you're paying but you you you're getting that performance
 		and so that's i i said i said i'm i'm very very satisfied with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in fact i it's a you know it's a little little
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup truck</ENAMEX> it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five</NUMEX> speed i just don't it's i'm i'm not really that tall and it you know it sits me comfortable i have good visibility i mean it just it just a blast it handles like a little sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> just really satisfied with it
 	
 	
 		i i know it  it it almost seems a shame that
 		of the  the approach perhaps that that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> takes is that if we're going to make an economy car by God you're going to know it's an economy car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whereas i get the feeling
 		
 		
 	