
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		right now i'm at um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> i'm a graduate student
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and the benefits that i get are very minimal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i do get my health insurance paid for but i don't have any kind of disability insurance or um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		let's see no disability insurance no vacation well i get in a way i get vacation pay because i get to set totally set my own schedule
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		not any real significant benefits my health insurance is very minimal
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		um i'm i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at GTRI
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i go to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> and we don't have benefits to speak of we don't have health insurance or paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		you're undergraduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> or graduate student
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		undergrad
 	
 	
 		undergrad yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah here they for the grad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at least
 		in physiology department which my degree degree granting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> is biological engineering but physiology and the biomedical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> at least pay the health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">engineering</ENAMEX> doesn't even do that
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know i think that it would be great if instead of having health insurance and all those things tied to a job the way they are now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can get them and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't and it's like having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> classes of income some that is taxed and some that is not it'd be great if they had
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		everybody responsible for their own health insurance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and either that or what
 		they could be responsible for their own health insurance but if they did take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> benefit then that would be taxed like other income
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so then that would everybody would know what their real income was and that their benefit that they were getting from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was costing them something and that they might want to look around to get something better somewhere else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's a good idea i had never thought about it that way
 	
 	
 		so
 		i guess
 		i would like to see something like that and then
 		i guess the going beyond just the idea of benefits having
 		instead of um a national health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> having
 		a sort of like an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDIC</ENAMEX> for health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> so if if you're health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> goes out of business you don't lose everything if you get sick
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right
 		right that's
 		that would be a wonderful idea
 	
 	
 		but on the other hand in in the current state of the current system i'll
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whenever i get out of here i'll look for
 		a job probably an academic job that would
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know benefits i don't know how important that'll be usually academic jobs you get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIAA</ENAMEX> for your retirement plan
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is a it's a mutual fund that allows you to transfer your benefits with you with whatever job you go to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		a lot of an academic jobs give you that but on the other hand state retirement if you work for a state university can be very secure in taking  good care of you
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> worked for the federal government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he was in the soil conservation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and then after he retired from that he went taught <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for a while and he had taught <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> early in his career so he got the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retiree</ENAMEX> benefits and the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retiree</ENAMEX> benefits and the most important for him has been the health insurance because my mama isn't particularly well
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she has um she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> on dialysis and he was saying that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now that her kidneys have totally failed they've taken her off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> Lasix which is a diuretic it it changes how the kidneys absorb moisture
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and her drug bill is now down to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so and that's the lowest it's been in quite some time and so health insurance can be a real big important thing to get
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yipes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		what kind of job are you thinking about getting when you get out
 	
 	
 		oh i'm i'm just not entirely sure i have only been working here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one quarter</TIMEX> this is my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first quarter</TIMEX> here and uh i'm not really all too sure what kind of jobs are available and uh
 		i haven't gotten them yet i'm going in a few
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i
 		i'm going to be doing research for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next quarter</TIMEX> and see how i like that see uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if research for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> would be something i would consider
 	
 	
 		hum
 		what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> are you working with co-oping
 	
 	
 		oh oh it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech Research Institute</ENAMEX> it's affiliated with the university um
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and uh we do research uh the one i'm in the lab i'm in does research in microwaves and antennas
 		and uh we do a lot of research for the federal government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so a lot of our uh expenses are you know covered by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	