
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't think anybody pays too little
 	
 	
 		no i would tend to agree very highly i think that we're all paying a little bit too much taxes and not seeing too much good come out of it
 	
 	
 		do you get hit up for local taxes there
 	
 	
 		yeah we sure do here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> we pay uh
 		we pay county income tax state income tax we pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> sales tax uh you name it they tax it
 	
 	
 		oh so you you you get the whole smorgasbord
 	
 	
 		that's right we
 	
 	
 		well i i actually live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		tax free or die uh-huh
 	
 	
 		right which is probably pretty nice but i'll bet that means your state sales tax is pretty high
 	
 	
 		no actually there's no sales tax in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		there's no sales tax either
 	
 	
 		no what there is is very high property taxes because that's how they fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the only problem is i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> so they they hit me up for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent there
 	
 	
 		right
 		Taxachusetts
 	
 	
 		yep but it well you know we it's it's only a state taxes no local we've got a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> sales tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um the problem is that so i'm paying state tax even though i don't live here but at least on things like stock options and things like that they don't tax me
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's not too bad
 	
 	
 		no i uh i really think that here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> at least we pay a a whole uh just too much tax i worked in a factory uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> and on the average i was losing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> of every paycheck to taxes
 		and i don't feel that i really get a whole lot of return from that i mean i don't utilize all you know it really any government welfare services of course i drive on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and i you know went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and stuff but i really feel that
 		that i'm just getting overtaxed
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i i i mean i i'd consider twenty percent lucky because just on i mean you know when you figure out just on feds you know i actually hit the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty one bracket this year</TIMEX> which was no fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no that's that's not any fun
 	
 	
 		right and also you know then you figure out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> for FICA
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is taxes where you  most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> forget about them because you've got you know you can't always get your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FICA</ENAMEX> back at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> but so you know and then you know like a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> FICA i'm paying <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">forty percent</NUMEX> tax
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		yeah which is just outrageous and a lot of it and if you look at the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> it just seems like a lot of its going to waste
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i mean i think there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there you there clearly are some things where you need infrastructure and you need
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know you know there are things <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does better you know i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does a better space program
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		than you're gonna get out of private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> but
 		you know i think you know you look at things like you know tax subsidies to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> wants it that way or
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right got to keep those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> happy
 	
 	
 		you know and and just tremendous amounts of you know so much of it is now just going to service debt or you know is going in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		into into programs that you know yeah they are they are fat you know i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is really fat i think that a lot of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEW</ENAMEX> services although they're providing necessary services have too much fat in them
 	
 	
 		right there is there is just way too much bureaucracy and so much of that tax money is going just to keep that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> running keep the paper shuffling around instead of real you know good programs
 	
 	
 		you know like we we
 		um
 		yeah i mean we we spend a fortune for things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
 		and you know then you look at how well they're managed you know i don't think we're getting our money's work out worth out of there i think it's all going into into bureaucrats
 	
 	
 		right
 		and a lot of it's feeding uh just i just i really especially in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election year</TIMEX> i mean i'm really thinking a lot about this the economy and questions like that and and just the whole
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it seems like everything is really screwy right now as far as the economy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> goes and our our whole economy in general and our taxes just are gonna keep rising no matter what happens and especially when you've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> who has increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and expenditures
 		uh beyond beyond what any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War Two</ENAMEX> has done and yet he supposedly
 	
 	
 		well between between between him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		right right yeah i mean i just read something that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thirds</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three quarters</TIMEX> i'm not exactly sure of our national debt
 	
 	
 		the great communicator
 	
 	
 		are was created during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan Bush</ENAMEX> era who are supposedly supposedly fiscally conservative
 	
 	
 		oh oh yeah they think
 		oh yeah and then they go and say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Congress</ENAMEX> they're the fault for it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but you know the other thing is it's tricky though because like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> they say oh all right let's cut the military budget well yeah then you lose half your jobs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> you lose <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grotten Connecticut</ENAMEX> goes so you know it's like
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's very tricky to balance that stuff off because then you hurt you know if the if the if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lose their jobs then they become a load and they're not contributing taxes
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so you know it's it's very hard to say you know this is what we should cut
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really that is the especially that defense  cuts in the defense is really a catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		double whammy because like you say if you cut defense well that's great that's gonna lower our national expenditures but then you're gonna have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on welfare and they're not putting taxes in
 	
 	
 		who who aren't contributing right yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's that's really
 	
 	
 		and uh in our
 	
 	
 		it's i'm glad i'm not the one who has to come up with these policies
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		but what's very funny is in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> meeting
 		they were voting this this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had both for our school district meeting and our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> meeting had this proposal which unfortunately violates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> constitution  for our local <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to do it to uh have you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> line item their taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		they say i want to pay for this and this and this and this and this
 		course the only problem with that is then nobody pays for the necessary services that they don't use
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	