
 
     		
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know my feeling is that uh
 		it's really being used <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it it you know it it really isn't doing any real good purpose for anything because it's not cost effective because of the amount of time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> end up waiting on appeal
 	
 	
 		right i think i've seen some statistics that say that uh it's more expensive to kill somebody than to keep them in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right because you you you've got all all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> expenses plus all the legal expenses
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and you know it certainly doesn't seem to be a deterrent
 		um for one thing because it's used so infrequently and for another thing because i honestly don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are committing the crimes crimes that would be eligible you know really care
 	
 	
 		well that's committing them mostly is you know either crimes of passion or at the moment or they think they're not going to get caught or
 	
 	
 		right i mean it's kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> phenomenon you know i'm invulnerable i don't need to care about this
 		you know i i i'm never gonna get caught
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		yeah but you also have to think whether it's worthwhile on the individual basis for example someone like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX>
 		do you want
 		by putting him in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life there is still a possibility that he will get out again
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> way or another
 	
 	
 		whereas if you kill him  there is not that possibility
 	
 	
 		yeah but but the other side to that is if you put him in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life there's a chance that he might
 		do things in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> or you know and somehow redeem himself
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think he could ever redeem himself but in some cases yes
 	
 	
 		well
 		you you know so that you know the the question is
 		you know the other question problem with capital punishment you run into is what are you gonna do about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are later found to have been innocent you know there are cases where  you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty years</TIMEX> after the fact they're getting evidence
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		especially as new technology comes along that might prove their innocence and then oops i'm sorry i guess we killed the wrong guy
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's yeah once you've made a decision that way it's a little difficult to go back on it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right you you can apologize nicely but you know you know i think you know the the price you know it i've heard quotes you know it's better that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go free than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> be unjustly imprisoned
 		i think it is really the the philosophy of the way our legal system works
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah it's all the benefit of the doubt to the last iota is uh based on the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who is accused
 	
 	
 		yeah and you know
 		the i i think that you know and the way it's being used now it's like you listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s you know well where are we gonna impose drug you know it's like for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> is the new big thing like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tsongas</ENAMEX> is also saying you know capital make it a capital crime to be a major drug dealer
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and again i don't think these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> care they risk their lives everyday
 	
 	
 		yeah that there there they see that the profit margin of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> the profit margin's so high
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that yeah the the risk is almost not there
 	
 	
 		yeah and and you know
 		uh especially you know i live in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> you know we're we're we're gonna get capital punishment here probably after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> coming or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know but you look at our our crime rates and things like that and you compare them to to like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or someplace that does you know it it it's impossible to make a case that it's it's affecting it in any way
 		i think it's mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like they get the vengeance of it
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's also i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and you know the the big thing down there was all right we have capital punishment
 	
 	
 		because you know
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but if you look at who gets accused and who are the ones who actually get executed
 		it's very racially related and ethnically related
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's mainly lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> also a lot of young people
 		you know your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a a  a sixty two year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is less likely to be
 		put on death row from what i've seen
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you know i i think when you listen to like the uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and things
 		they're always talking about you know uh feeling justified or feeling you know like they've gotten something out of it i mean
 		my thought has been once the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> has been imprisoned if he goes to jail forever or whatever or if he gets killed it shouldn't make any difference to the uh
 		to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s family the only thing that should really i mean obviously if someone of mine who was close died i'd probably feel differently but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know the you know what the important thing is that they be caught and not be a danger to society
 	
 	
 		right and that and you know also by keeping them in prison you do have the possibility though we don't currently do this of making restitution
 	
 	
 		right i mean the
 	
 	
 		you you will work your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> job and any money you earn will go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s family
 	
 	
 		right and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other</NUMEX> thing is that you know i was reading through a book on uh
 		genome human genome research and now more and more things like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what if it just turned out to be genetic or biochemical in origin so if someday we can go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Dahmer</ENAMEX> and say well the problem is you you've got an endorphin imbalance and you know if you take this regularly you'll be a sane and productive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of society
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you really get back to the question of you know is someone responsible for their actions
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i think on some of it you have to say someone's responsible for his actions i never like the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> made me do it yeah
 	
 	
 		the defense that well i never liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uh insanity</ENAMEX> defense
 		
 		
 	