
 
     		
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's uh i'll start off here uh i don't know i get probably most of my information either from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> um
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> because it uh you know repeats it well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline News</ENAMEX> repeats every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> and so it it makes it really convenient because i keep a rather hectic schedule
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> provides provides a little bit of depth that you can't really get from
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i think i'd agree of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of a similar method of getting the news with me too it's uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh CNN</ENAMEX> has been a welcome addition to  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> scene here in the last uh number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		prior prior to cable you know you didn't get much news off of normal uh television broadcasts
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh just usually pretty local in in nature and and i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> because you get some world world events too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh which is not too common on on the other format <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and so forth
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i know the my only major objection is that uh i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> spends enough uh attention on on our closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		that that's true you know you hardly ever see uh headline articles about the uh either the economics or or other world news events going on in either of those countries
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		uh whereas if you pick up a a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> paper you know uh it all the surrounding countries <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and everything has uh major news uh articles in them
 	
 	
 		right yeah i mean you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s going through a lot of problems now with with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> and and everything and uh
 		it's amazing that you know i i listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> area and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> you know i mean the most they'll give it is maybe the back of the A section
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm currently living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and it it won't it won't even give it the back section you just never see you just never see anything about it uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		which is a shame because you go to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> uh and and they carry quite a bit about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> on the other hand and if you go up to uh
 		Canada those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are usually pretty uh familiar with the politics going on and and the news events in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we're pretty uh limited in our understanding of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		you just you just don't know what's going on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'd i every once in a while i have to travel overseas and then lately i've taken the taken a little shortwave radio uh
 		around and picking up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> and it's sort of like uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> too you you can tune into some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and you get some like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> minute summaries of of news events uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i occasionally get into some of the middle eastern uh area and that's the only way you can tell what's going on at all
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there's not much in the way of television in some of those places
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um but that's a good point about about the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i hadn't really thought about it but i guess you don't think about it because you don't hear it
 	
 	
 		right exactly yeah i uh spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past summer</TIMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> uh well part of it touring
 		and uh you know i i was amazed because i'd pick up a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and i'd read about all of these you know really interesting things going on there's some serious talk about whether there's actually going to be a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because of the problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> and never i had never heard any of that before
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah you know there was a a what is it called is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Meech Lake Accord</ENAMEX> or or yeah that's just something uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'd say <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here would never have heard of and i think that i heard of it about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time when i was up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calgary</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and
 		you know picked up a a paper and started reading a little bit more detail about it and and came came and it was a big thing going on there and i came back here and nothing in the papers
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and just didn't see a thing about it
 		so it's uh we've got a long ways to go i guess it's improved and like i say with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and and uh the cable news even even there's a uh
 		it's sort it's semireligious in some respects but what is it it's uh
 		i mean its news is not not that way uh oh i'm trying to think of the channel the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Science Monitor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it it surprised me i've caught it a few times and they they do some pretty good news uh seemingly unbiased news broadcasts uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the the title of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is sort of surprising you'd think it would carry mostly religious but it it doesn't seem to so i'll flip through and
 		listen to it once in awhile too uh and catch something maybe a little different than than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> might be covering
 		uh some more interest interest type topics in in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> but it's kind of world world uh network too
 	
 	
 		yeah um i've i guess i've never seen the TV show i used to get the uh
 		
 		
 	