
 
     		
 	
 		to uh  trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and whether it works or not is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hey i like the current system
 	
 	
 		yeah i expect it's um  about as good as one can expect um
 		i suppose you get an illogical verdict <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i figure the answer to that is to educate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> or the uh
 	
 	
 		the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> you mean the people
 	
 	
 		right  just
 	
 	
 		yeah i just got called to my first jury duty uh-huh
 		i never been on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> how about you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i was ever called
 	
 	
 		and were you did you did you show up and do it or whatever it was
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i showed up but uh the case settled before they could uh
 		make us uh actually listen to anything so i have no idea what the case was about or uh you know i didn't get to do anything
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was on some real complex business case where they were um
 		decide to asked to decide the exact amount to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> of fraud in some credit card case you know
 	
 	
 		wait so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> had to like go over
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ledgers</ENAMEX> and financial records and
 	
 	
 		well they went over it in the trial but they didn't give the stuff to the jury afterward it was really bizarre uh
 	
 	
 		wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second</TIMEX> don't
 		don't they have to enter that in as evidence and can't the jury request any piece of it
 	
 	
 		yeah but they have to ask for it and then the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bailiff</ENAMEX> brings it and they can look at it then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bailiff</ENAMEX> takes it away again it's not like they can just spread it out in their jury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and then you know get out a bunch of calculators and pocket computers and add it all up it was
 	
 	
 		right the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> request an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three seventy</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah right would you give me an IDMS IDMS system or something like that  dear judge
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know it was it was a very peculiar case i guess that one was didn't work very well um uh but
 	
 	
 		whoa that i'm not sure that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s fault
 	
 	
 		no no i don't think so either um
 	
 	
 		but i don't know what else they could've done
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um i guess i guess nothing else but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> suggests just giving it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		for sentencing i don't know does that make any sense i mean
 		it depends on what i i don't know what the offense is i guess that's why we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> is to take each case on a case by case basis and that's fine
 		anyway um
 	
 	
 		no i mean the jury
 		there's problems with it as far as finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> as far as weird verdicts
 		as far as just the timing the timing you know it takes a lot of time
 		but uh
 		you know i like it because i think
 		you don't have the abuse or it's a sort of a check
 		if you have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> doing something he can sort of
 		go out of control and it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> before he gets reigned in
 	
 	
 		yeah or if it's an organizational problem you know where where you know the
 	
 	
 		and he can do a lot of damage
 	
 	
 		you know it's possible to imagine a corrupt judicial system where you know all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are are
 		part of the system i guess that happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> once huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or just even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> just before you get a chance to uh
 		you know to uh purge him
 		he could do a lot of damage
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i guess they do anyway i guess
 		the only trouble with the jury system i see is it's really darned darned expensive and and you know time consuming and
 		you know and and all these systems of where you can like
 		ask a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> ask each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> what they think about something then kick them out and
 		you know i guess they can manipulate it a little
 	
 	
 		you know maybe some of the uh
 		like the hype
 		needs to be cut out
 		but you mention expense
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think you get what you pay for
 	
 	
 		yeah it's true no lie
 	
 	
 		you know if you want a cheap legal system you're you're gonna get that kind of
 		Kmart service or uh
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX>'s not all that bad
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there's got to be some sort of cheap
 		what's the epitome of cheap these days
 	
 	
 		beats me um
 		yeah in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> it's the judicial system their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are all falling down
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i guess that gets them the sample
 		good night sir
 	
 	
 		all right good luck
 	
 	
 		take it easy
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	