
 
     		
 	
 		think about
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh taxes
 	
 	
 		well i think they're a necessary evil uh i wish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would operate on the same premise that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> operate on and that is uh
 	
 	
 		you spend what you have and
 	
 	
 		you you don't spend more than you than you bring in
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that
 		the general idea is to spend you know spend uh
 		during a time of recession that you know for the deficit spending to help pick up the economy but they're running under the assumption you know
 		the way they're running it now they're have you know running it under a deficit spending you know while we're not under a recession so there's never any surplus coming in to counter the deficit that we're running so
 		that's kind of a basic thing of economics i guess keep spending keep going into debt you're not going to payoff what you owe
 		so i guess the the question was more like uh do you get what you pay for you know get what you pay for
 	
 	
 		well i it just depends uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> are very expensive uh commodity and so is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> they supply and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and fire department uh you know they need to make a living
 	
 	
 		yeah and there's
 	
 	
 		so  i think for for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> uh we've paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firemen</ENAMEX> who are uh to a great extent public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we have not paid them really what they're worth in what they contribute to society
 	
 	
 		i agree with that
 	
 	
 		but uh then again uh it's the hard to justify with all the wastefulness of money that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> spends on all levels of of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">municipalities</ENAMEX> as well as state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess i'm i'm a student right now and i don't make a whole lot of money and
 		so i i kind of don't pay a proportionate amount of taxes to i guess uh
 		compared to what i get because i you know all my my education is state sponsored i go to a state sponsored school
 		and uh my education all up through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and stuff so i guess i'm kind of in debt i i suppose because i don't you know been paying taxes all that all that long my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i guess however however however have
 		contributed to that you know for the education side of it and everything but uh i usually end up getting money back i will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> anyway from a
 	
 	
 		uh you're very fortunate  we just try not to pay any more in than we have to uh we pay in a substantial amount uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i am i need it too otherwise things
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we don't regret paying taxes we do think that uh sometimes uh we have a reverse of a regressive tax a progressive tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and progressive tax i think uh does not give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> incentive to make more money  and what i mean by that the more income you make the more tax you pay
 	
 	
 		more taxes you pay
 	
 	
 		it should be i think a flat percentage and uh that percentage ought to be an equitable amount
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> isn't
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when they passed the tax laws for the
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nineteen ninety ninety one</NUMEX> whatever nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i added up all the taxes that we were going to pay on all these different specific luxury items and travel expenses and everything else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i totaled them all up and basically uh we were going to be paying seventy or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eighty percent</NUMEX> tax
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		now that was the assumption that you spent that same dollar for every
 		for every item on there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even though there's uh taxes on different things
 		but you know there's federal there's a lot of taxes you pay that you're not even aware of that you're paying uh like when you buy a tire you pay a federal excise tax
 	
 	
 		well isn't
 		uh-huh there's a lot yeah lot of hidden taxes
 	
 	
 		you pay gasoline taxes every time you pump something into your your tank
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the taxes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't think about that
 		yeah the the the income tax is a lot more visible portion of the taxes you pay i guess
 	
 	
 		but you probably pay more percentage wise in other taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		there was that which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> was it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Brown</ENAMEX> one of the democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> had a proposal for doing away with all the the tax codes they have now and implementing a flat i think a flat percentage something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah if you implemented implemented a flat percentage it would encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh to make more money and the what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to understand in my opinion now this is just my opinion okay uh is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> create jobs and jobs create income and income pays taxes
 		and so if they penalize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are smart enough to say here's my break point i'm not going to work any harder and make any more or create any more jobs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		exactly that's because until like eight
 	
 	
 		and so based on that who do you think you're talking to you're talking to an employer
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		up until like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> or something was
 		the
 		
 		
 	