
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> you're from south here you'd have to be interested in music right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh  yeah yeah i my interests have varied over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've been uh
 		
 
 		oh for the last uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> it must be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> now i've been volunteering at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Opera</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which has been real interesting been working there as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super numerary</ENAMEX> which is uh
 		
 
 		a non singing actor
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		so i'm in all these  productions i'm in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or four a year</TIMEX> and it's uh it's really interesting it's really
 	
 	
 		well that should be interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really fun
 	
 	
 		well do you play an instrument yourself
 	
 	
 		well i used to play guitar and sing and about
 		um
 		it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nine years ago</TIMEX> i just kind of stopped i'd done it all my life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		it's nothing now
 	
 	
 		yeah i listen to music and i'm uh i'm singing actually i just started taking voice lessons but uh i am not playing anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		that's  i play the recorder i'm not
 	
 	
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		and i really love playing with the guitarist and i do it for i used to play the elbow
 		and the recorder has about the same fingerings as the elbow so i just i had to have my elbow back in junior high so i just kept up with that
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		but i really enjoy playing that
 		and then the piano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm trying to teach myself that just to keep myself entertained we just bought an old piano that we are trying to refinish
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		so that keeps us really busy
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so do you um practice much in the opera or do you have to go to many practices
 	
 	
 		yeah i have to go to a lot of a lot of rehearsals um
 		it's uh i just did <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> shows in a row i also work with do the same sort of work with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Ballet</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		they uh
 		
 
 		oh i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nutcracker</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> with them
 		at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Center Opera House</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now is that volunteer
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it is in that one i played the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> of the main character
 		
 
 	
 	
 		huh
 		that's really interesting we never got to go we went to the the orchestra up there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Symphony</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh the not the symphony what's the other one
 		there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> groups i can't remember their names
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Symphony</ENAMEX> is kind of the main <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right here there's some small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community orchestras</ENAMEX> around town
 	
 	
 		what's the one that plays with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like there's  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmonic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay that's the one we went and saw
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		so that was that was really interesting too
 		
 
 		are you at work right now
 	
 	
 		no i'm at home
 	
 	
 		oh i heard a
 	
 	
 		it that ringing you heard was a another another line here
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm also uh kind of interested in uh
 		oh uh a lot of kind of ethnic music and foreign music and stuff uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stuff that's marketed under the name of world music
 		um there's this really great band i found uh that's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Mastabas Three</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		who play this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i first heard them when i i was visiting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and he played the tape of them
 		and we couldn't figure out where they were from because they were playing this stuff like some of it sounded like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> other sound like it was eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">European</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anyway it uh uh
 		it was really uh uh really interesting stuff so i came back here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> and found a CD of theirs and was looking for more recordings of their stuff
 		and uh  uh ended up writing a writing them a a  fan letter
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah asking where i could find uh find more uh more of their uh more of their recordings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		um
 		they uh they wrote back and told me when they were coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> so i met them when they were here they were were really funny just a moment
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well that was interesting  did you talk to them at all or
 	
 	
 		yeah that was weird i just
 		uh just put my that's weird i just put it on hold and i heard what sounded like a modem on the other line that was calling us up
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's very strange
 	
 	
 		is the group
 	
 	
 		um
 		anyway anyway yeah i met them it was it was kind of interesting i'd been wondering for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> where these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were from
 		and thinking they might be from eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and what they confirmed was our suspicion which was they were basically a bunch of crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>  no musicologists
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		ooh ah uh uh they were kind of playing a big joke on the world just a second
 		
 
 		
  
 	
 	
 		same thing
 	
 	
 		okay i'm back
 		yeah i never got any instructions with this thing on what you're supposed to do when you get another phone call  how do they deal with call waiting you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh you got you got another phone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no no no i mean somebody else calls you know so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have call waiting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> actually we have a completely separate
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		
 		
 	