
 
     		
 	
 		so it says how do you keep up on news um i suppose i had longer to think about it so i'll just uh answer the question i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i get almost all well the majority of my news from radio and news letters which is kind of unusual but it's a pretty cost effective or time effective way to do it because on TV you have to to put up with all the happy talk and the commercials
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um then on uh like newspapers well they just take too long to read i use to read news papers very faithfully but i just ran out of time so i tape record <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National All Things Considered</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i i when i ride the bike my ride my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> to campus i i have it on on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">walkman</ENAMEX> and that gives me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the news and to get the other side i get a bunch of news letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> which are mostly on the right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and how about you
 	
 	
 		uh that's interesting i've i've never heard of the news letters angle i'm also an All Things Considered person <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Edition</ENAMEX> whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i generally enjoy it although sometimes they have a tendency to do <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minute</TIMEX> features on things i'd just had soon not hear for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		all the all the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> cases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> for example
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right well i mean the the only thing about them is that they the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the their</TIMEX> news uh
 		most of the time slanted tends to be pretty slanted to the left and you just can't tell really what's happening for i mean take for example the economy where they've not not not them alone but
 		most of the news media but probably they more more uh strongly than a lot of the others
 		have all these programs about bad economic news and as soon as the news gets good it just disappears you know just just don't report it to the same extent that they do about the bad news
 	
 	
 		yeah although i think that's probably uh true of most news coverage in general good news isn't news right
 	
 	
 		hm i don't know but i think that for example after the uh
 		after the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran Iraq</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">War</TIMEX> when uh oil oil prices came way down i think it would have been news that oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> profits decreased as i'm sure they did you just didn't hear about it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so um i i get pretty upset with them actually a lot but the only thing is there's no other game in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> except for monitor which is you you know about um about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Science</ENAMEX> monitor program
 	
 	
 		uh yeah on television or radio
 	
 	
 		uh
 		no no on on radio they have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour a day</TIMEX> news program
 		but that's
 	
 	
 		yep oh excuse me i was just going to say up here they they broadcast that i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> AM which is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a little</NUMEX> before i get up so i usually miss it
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry
 		right yeah that it i i don't think they well i mean i know they don't broadcast it here at all and the only way that i can ever listen to that is when i'm in another part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know i mean they're they're really the only game in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and if you want to get different news for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or a little bit more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> that's
 		that's about the only way to do it which i find kind of unfortunate now there is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil Lehrer Lehrer</ENAMEX> news hour but that's on TV and then you've got to be sitting there
 	
 	
 		yeah like like you i often i rarely spend time watching news on TV the uh
 		i gave up on network news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and it just doesn't usually work out i have time to watch something more in depth like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for me it's pretty much a diet of uh
 		All Things Considered and i like to look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> at work which uh i think does a fine job it too has a slant but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well at least it's not the same slant is is All Things Considered huh
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly and
 	
 	
 		so that's that's true yeah but now i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> if i subscribed well let's see if i subscribed to a newspaper i probably would get it it's it'd be that or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> but um
 		they they have good in depth articles mostly on things that have to do with you know credit cards or other things relating to to financial things or or financial planning but they also have some good in depth articles beginning on page one
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh what is it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> column of page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> is uh kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> in it's own right just for human interest stories or business interest stories i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		i was discussing actually one of those stories with i just happen to i don't know how i acquired a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> it just happened uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> there was a story on recycling uh i think actually that was a column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story though
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh that talked about the way that uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> are trying to recycle so much that they don't have anybody to buy the stuff from them to reprocess and in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> locality i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> ended up burning
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the stuff some of it some of it because there's nothing else they could do with it
 	
 	
 		right back to square one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so it was it was you know good to find out a little bit more than than you would in certainly in any story on network news i mean not just
 		that was the only thing but it was it was good uh discussion of the markets for various recycled products
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's that's the kind of thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> does best i find i don't have time to read through the whole thing certainly but i find if you just
 		
 		
 	