
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> this is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like i mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> and i guess we're going to want to be talking about child care uh do you have any experience in uh finding child care
 	
 	
 		well ourselves we have i guess never had to look for child care our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen</TIMEX> and eighteen but uh  and so you know you go back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> and uh we didn't do it very much we i guess we were in a situation where we didn't need to be looking at uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> family income at the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were older but i've had to deal with uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of ours that have used child care and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh so it my involvement hasn't been direct but still have been you know certainly exposed to criteria <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are using how about yourself
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well uh we're kind of lucky i i'm uh
 		i'm working my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> isn't working and she is taking care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> also and and so we haven't had to look for child care either which has been very nice but i do have like you mentioned a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> a lot of uh coworkers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> that are looking
 		for child care and some of the things that they're very critical about is the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are in the child care uh what kind of you know
 		uh guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> or you know
 		uh adult to child relationship how many you know you don't want to have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty</NUMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and only one adult
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		then uh something happens and the adult wouldn't be able to uh accommodate or take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> very well and uh
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		they also want to make sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are being taught and not just playing around all the time so you know depends also upon the the level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> we uh
 		we uh take a very close look at finding a a preschool a good preschool for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and i kind of relate that to that in in making sure that the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are very well educated themselves they have a good curriculum and that they're willing to teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and have a fun time with them and it's very important i feel
 		uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> interact with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> also it's a it's a good way to develop relationships with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> their age and uh get to know and work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		so i don't know i i guess we're kind of in the same boat we haven't had to look very carefully for child care
 	
 	
 		yeah i  i kind of think that uh
 		you know some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or even our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will be in a situation where they may need to look for child care but even you know here i guess we have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forms of uh child care there's where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> will
 		in one primarily babysit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in their own home and that will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from one or two</NUMEX> to maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then otherwise there will be  the majority are cooperative day cares uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> form a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> and put a fair number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		frequently they will hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to be at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care and
 		the emphasis is primarily uh someplace for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to be but at the same time there's some fairly good training programs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and some of them formal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> programs
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		uh so that you know there is some definite uh creative play good social interaction that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		i think it's uh important like you mentioned that's a good idea on the uh parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> because uh
 		i'm very concerned about the welfare of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i don't want to just take them to somebody i pick out of the yellow pages or out of some ad somewhere i want to trust the people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know you hear in the newspaper you hear on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> and you read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> quite often of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know
 		don't treat or take care of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the way you think they ought to be taken care of so and
 		hope to never get into that situation where we have to have to find somebody and we have to trust someone with the welfare of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and hope that we can stay in this situation  for awhile so
 	
 	
 		yeah  you know we've even had some of those kinds of situations publicized here and  i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it are it's uh typically uh whether it's been child care in a home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or in a larger situation where actually it's more of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and you've actually got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would consider problem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and it's not
 		and it's more of a group <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> rather than actually day care  type of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> uh so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true that's true
 		
 
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven it</ENAMEX>'s been
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 		
 	