
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so is your tax situation pretty straightforward or not straightforward at all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah actually actually uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>'s real straightforward um basically uh you know i take my standard deductions um on my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> which i have a mortgage on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that's usually the big the big payoff part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> for me because i get a couple <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> back usually
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		but uh actually i uh i don't really begrudge uh the uh the government their due
 		i do i do think that uh probably just like just almost anybody else that you know there's a lot of inefficiency in how they distribute taxes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't think that they uh they do a very good job of distributing them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really need them  but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		generally i think they're pretty necessary and life would probably be a lot worse if they didn't have taxation so
 	
 	
 		right i don't have any problem at all with income tax some of the property taxes are well i don't know if they're unfair they're confusing and i there seems to be
 		less
 		ability to get those all together
 	
 	
 		yeah we actually we actually had a situation here where uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was appraised you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> by the county
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we have to uh pay taxes on the basis of what that appraisal was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX> we owned the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house um</ENAMEX> that appraisal was something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> higher than we had just bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and so uh despite you know a lot of kibitzing by our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and stuff i decided to go in to uh talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Equalization</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prince William</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">County</ENAMEX> and make sure that you know a mistake hadn't been made and all that kind of stuff
 		and so i just sort of made my case on the basis of um you know analogy to other to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> around us that were similar in terms of
 	
 	
 		you just bought it right
 	
 	
 		square footage you know and size all and and you know general property size and things like that and just just showed that you know our obvious for some reason our property had been valued much higher
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh they bought it they actually reduced the uh reduced the appraisal
 	
 	
 		really they didn't raise the they canceled your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>' taxes
 	
 	
 		uh they didn't raise my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>' yeah they actually reduced mine to be in line with uh a more reasonable appraisal
 	
 	
 		that's really great
 	
 	
 		so i you you know i I realized well the you know few instances you can fight city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> on things like property taxes but uh
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah it was it was an interesting experience because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> before me went in and he had a really kind of poorly organized discussion you know i mean he was sort of
 		mad at the world and uh he he had sort of that that mad at the world attitude right off the bat which you could you know see <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then he uh then he started talking about all the things that were wrong with this property you know like you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> hadn't been cleaned out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and the gutters are falling off and you know a lot of really minor stuff
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that just didn't impress these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> at all and they sort of gave him a hard time
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh you know when i pointed out that that our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was appraised at this and all these similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the subdivision were appraised at you know twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> less i mean
 	
 	
 		right and you just bought yours that's the best argument i think
 	
 	
 		yeah so it it it worked it was actually pretty uh pretty satisfying satisfying  experience
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		but it was it was kind of like going up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX> though you know i mean they they uh were sitting in these you know at these giant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> tables you know like
 	
 	
 		i bet
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh it was a it was a
 	
 	
 		it was like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> that that you
 	
 	
 		really wow it wasn't it wasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> council
 	
 	
 		it was the it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> but it wasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> they have different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Equalization i</ENAMEX> don't know i don't even know how they get on it you know i i'm just guessing they're appointed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> is actually a kind of a well known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">realtor</ENAMEX> around here so you know i I figured if anybody gave me a hard time it'd be him you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right well he did he probably knows it really well the real estate market
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that was probably help
 	
 	
 		but other than that uh i haven't had too much too much problem with taxes actually when i was in grad school i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> also i went to school down at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlottesville</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i had a you know one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> fellowships
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and fortunately it was not taxable at that time
 	
 	
 		right now it is
 	
 	
 		but they actually they actually hassled me over it though
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i had to i had to go to some length you know i actually got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these letters that that said you know you got to show up at the local you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and explain
 	
 	
 		oh you got audited wow
 	
 	
 		yeah and actually explain you know what was going on and
 		you know  i just i said hey i mean it's tax free i mean that's my understanding of things so anyway eventually they they accepted that that it was but actually work i work with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> now who's
 		i I i guess he was right
 		
 		
 	