
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay want to go ahead and start then
 	
 	
 		sure uh recycling in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has uh been a problem for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX> i moved down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that had had recycling
 		band this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> uh does not offer municipal trash services so we are all uh under obligation to get our own trash hauled away
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and when i talk to the local trash <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">haulers</ENAMEX> about recycling they said that uh they could haul it to the recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> but it would be about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> more
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it was uh fairly amazing to me that this thing that they are trying to mandate throughout the state
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was being snubbed in this particular town
 	
 	
 		hum
 		wow
 		do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have like recycling bins
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		for your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		no we don't uh
 		as i said we we are responsible for finding our own trash pick up
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and all the uh trash <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">haulers</ENAMEX> in this area will take the uh the sorted trash and
 		bring the recyclables to a uh a recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> but they charge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> dollars or more a month for that particular service
 	
 	
 		i'll be darned
 		down down here in  isn't too much of a tax burden up here down here it's uh
 		they have uh the the garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> picks it up for us and they what we do is we have to separate this stuff you know papers and and plastic materials and glass
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh they'll they'll come by in a separate truck and i guess it's paid for with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>'s money
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but up there i guess you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are saving the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		well uh it it's interesting because this uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> i live in is a a coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that uh
 		during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> really is a uh a tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> really drops off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> so they uh
 		i guess they figure that they wouldn't uh
 		they wouldn't provide that particular service
 	
 	
 		oh i see yeah
 	
 	
 		uh when i when i lived back up uh closer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> it we had the municipal trash pick up and we sorted the bottles the paper and all of that and uh
 		you know i'd had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year or so</TIMEX> to get used to that whole system and i moved down and i said this is a great you know i like doing this it's not that much of a pain um it sounds good to me
 		what do i do to keep doing this and the answer was you can if you want but it's going to cost you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i i was fairly surprised
 	
 	
 		yeah that's it is surprising but it sounds like you're in uh are you near the ocean and stuff then or
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh so you are in a nice place
 	
 	
 		well i really do like it here uh i
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm close to the ocean myself i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juno</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's it's it's pretty nice  about uh probably <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half mile</NUMEX> from the beach i'm not right on it but uh i'm pretty close to
 	
 	
 		right i'm about i'm about uh maybe uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile to a half a mile</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		yeah that's pretty good
 		that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		but uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other</NUMEX> thing about recycling that had uh that i've noticed is i've seen a few articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> now that uh
 		there's more recycled material than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know what to do with
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh apparently the uh the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> glass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the plastics the paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the glass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't using enough of the recyclables
 		to uh
 		to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> going so there's a a back log of of material that was put in for recycling that no one knows what to do with and it's actually
 	
 	
 		hum
 		was that a uh was that a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverage</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> that uh wrote that article
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i've seen it a couple of times and i'm i'm i couldn't cite the source  right now
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 		well it's true we uh in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> don't have a bottle bill and every time it's raised there is uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> that keeps it down and i it's
 		i i really can't see why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would get that upset about it because once it's in place it doesn't seem all that uh that difficult to manage
 		
 		
 	