
 
     		
 	
 		you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes do you have do i have pets yes i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> what kind
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzer</ENAMEX> and i have a Sheltie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzers</ENAMEX> is it a miniature or a standard Schnauzer
 	
 	
 		it it's a miniature um-hum hm
 	
 	
 		uh i'm going into all this because i used to work i just got done working at a pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		oh okay well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzer</ENAMEX> i'm i'm watching for one of uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> where i work and he's been transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and i'm taking care of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and uh and i had just got the kitten when he asked me that and he says well my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> doesn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and i said well we won't tell him it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> we won't tell her it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because it was a kitten and you know they just they just love kittens they just are fascinated
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so she doesn't know that this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> yet  and they get along real good i said if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> could see his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> lick this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kitty</ENAMEX> he'd flip  so that was interesting
 	
 	
 		that's good they say
 		didn't expect that would happen yeah that's cool that's nice
 		um let's see what was the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> you had
 	
 	
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sheltie</ENAMEX> she's real sweet sweet little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> she's got a very nice temperament uh they're not as aggressive as a Schnauzer you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzers</ENAMEX> are a little aggressive
 	
 	
 		oh a Sheltie
 		yeah
 		they can be nippy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shelties</ENAMEX> are nice everybody seems to be really happy with them they're good temperament
 	
 	
 		they're a good temperament and they
 	
 	
 		they put up with a lot
 	
 	
 		and they just uh  i think they have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on their shoulders i think they have a a higher level of intelligence than other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh dogs</ENAMEX> that i've encountered
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzers</ENAMEX> in particular probably
 	
 	
 		well yeah but also some poodles uh they're kind of um there are some smart ones out there but there's some also some uh not so smart ones  i
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah i get it seems the smaller the are the the worse off they are
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's maybe that's there's uh some credence in that statement
 	
 	
 		yeah they're they're bred down so much it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they aren't the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i'd i really don't know what the best pet is i guess it's up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and how they relate to their animal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem fairly well suited for for uh miniature <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">poodles</ENAMEX> and such
 	
 	
 		hm
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulldogs</ENAMEX>  but i don't know about these uh these um uh these Pinschers these no what are they called <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pit Bulls Pit Bulls</ENAMEX> that are so vicious
 	
 	
 		
 
 		pit bull
 		oh they're nice they're actually very friendly dogs
 	
 	
 		are they really i don't think i've ever seen one
 	
 	
 		uh they're really nice i i have dealt with quite a few of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> that bring them into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and ask me to like
 		they uh  fit collars and stuff on them and they're they're just really nice really friendly um kind of like medium intelligence um
 	
 	
 		well how do they becomes well how did they get their reputation then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um want to train them as
 	
 	
 		oh they train them to be that way then oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah you really can't get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pit bull</ENAMEX> from birth that's that way yeah it takes a lot of training and a lot of abuse to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> to really respond
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		oh dear so the the poor animal is doing it in self protection oh dear
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah they aren't they aren't by nature really nasty critters they are very determined critters and so once you get them going it's not good to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to deal with but they i i really like them i was i was impressed by them they're they're real sturdy little critters and they aren't that big and uh just really friendly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's unusual i was huh well i suppose you were surprised
 	
 	
 		i was i was overwhelmed
 		yeah uh right now
 	
 	
 		after the reputation that you know they have quite an uh uh notable reputation as far as you know
 	
 	
 		they picked up a lot of bad press lately
 	
 	
 		yeah they're banned from in some areas i understand um-hum
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 		but any any  any pet's gonna can can be bad if you train it to be that way
 	
 	
 		you know that they must have just targeted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> and said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> we're gonna
 	
 	
 		well yeah it's when in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> they just outlawed ferrets
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		because they had one incident of a ferret uh
 		attacking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in a house i mean these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had left this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with this loose ferret the the ferret is used to running the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and was kind of wild
 	
 	
 		oh okay uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know
 		they should expect something like that to happen and so basically now it's like ferrets are outlawed in the town
 	
 	
 		uh oh did it attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		yeah it it bit him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		that was that was not a good thing but i think it was probably a an individual ferret thing because it was fairly it was a fairly wild ferret and they hadn't
 	
 	
 		well the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that owned him should have been on the lookout for that
 	
 	
 		yeah i they really should've should've expected it and taken the precautions they didn't it's too bad it happened though
 	
 	
 		none um
 		sure yeah
 		yeah because then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the the animal</ENAMEX>'s in trouble and not the person
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	