
 
     		
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where where do you get your current events
 	
 	
 		i'm i don't keep up on current events very well at all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what i what i do on my i keep up on current events by as i walk by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> stand if there is a headline that grabs my attention then i will stand there and look at it for a minute then walk into my office
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		maybe once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> i'll i'll find something that's interesting enough that i'll buy the paper and then usually i read end up reading a lot of it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh um do you watch any television
 	
 	
 		uh no oh yeah i do i watch i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> and sometimes i watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Equalizer i</ENAMEX> never watch the news
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX> watch the news sometimes so sometimes i'll get
 		get interested in a news article so i guess a little bit leaks through there and uh sometimes on a on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> or in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> i'll i'll be sitting some somewhere and there will be a newspaper next to me and i'll read parts of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't make any deliberate effort to keep up on current events i probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> of the least informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  around how about you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um i used to read the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and uh when you when i did that i really knew stuff you know i mean if you read the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> you walk into work and you're like you want to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about
 		so what do you think about the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Pakistan</ENAMEX>  like this the parliamentary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s not going not you know not going to stay in there and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sort of stare at you uh
 		but now i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and i i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">comics</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i sort of glance at the front page uh i also used to listen to um public radio
 		tried to listen to that every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> for the news and every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and when i when i was doing that and reading the paper i really i really felt informed uh especially having the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different viewpoints uh slightly different anyway uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now i listen to the radio
 		maybe <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes in the morning</TIMEX> and i don't get to listen evening some i'm pretty pretty uninformed uh but those were my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big ones the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and the radio
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> here that i listen to sometimes on the way to work but it's a short drive
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh-huh  yeah oh that was the other thing i used to drive to work i used to have a long commute and i would listen to every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> on uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		public radio there's a show called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Morning Edition</ENAMEX> that lasts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they repeat the main headlines every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX> so i would listen to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> of that and you know really really know stuff and now that i'm just walking and riding the bus um
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		i i miss that
 		uh
 		the uh the well during the during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> we turned on the TV <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times did you watch watch any more during that
 	
 	
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh that i have to say that during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> yeah i watched a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> thing
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really did uh because i was pretty interested in that and i have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so he had on constantly
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i'll bet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and uh so and actually i learned a lot from him about world situations and also i have a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> because of him and so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you probably learned a lot from them yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and they are always telling me about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i have never heard of and political political situations that totally amaze me
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah there's so much to know it is amazing
 	
 	
 		and so
 	
 	
 		um
 		well uh one thing that was interesting during that whole thing was i would listen to the radio quite a bit and uh you know i started bringing a radio to work and i would listen a little bit at work and listen on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and on the way the way there and uh
 		i really felt like i was keeping up pretty well and then i would watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> for you know fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX> and see a bunch of pictures and realize i hadn't really learned anything
 		you know they sort of show <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> taking off and uh
 		like i i got more visual information but less
 	
 	
 		less content
 	
 	
 		real information in a way
 	
 	
 		they were kind of starved for real information i think at that point because all they had was was military clips and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and it's almost as though
 		that was stuff was more available to TV so they used it
 	
 	
 		yeah well they have to show something
 	
 	
 		you know they have to show something and that's all they could show on TV they could i mean on the radio they would bring in all sorts of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> from God knows where and interview them and talk to them about it and speculate
 		uh i think  in part at least because they had to
 		uh which is kind of interesting so i just found that they the information <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per hour</NUMEX> was much higher on the radio although the TV was a little more compelling
 	
 	
 		i never thought about that
 		the information per hour well technically the information on the TV is higher but the actual content is less
 	
 	
 		right it's it's an interesting question about
 		you know the bandwidth of the television
 		
 		
 	