
 
     		
 	
 		okay well um i used to work in a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> i worked in um in all the different areas of the day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and  it is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they can be deceiving to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i did not work there long because i couldn't handle the the treatment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> got and this is supposed to be a very well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler</ENAMEX> who had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> um centers
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all over you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">um city</ENAMEX> and they would um be one way when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were there and be another way when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> left
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um i think you need to make you know if you do do day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> you know you should make frequent checks
 		and um to check in on them when they're not expecting it because they do do things differently when you're not around
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well that i know what the things that we kind of looked at is is you wanna see how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> you have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they have and how they break it up
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because we had  we had one that sounds kind of like what you were in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it was a really good one and in fact it worked out for us because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> we kind of bartered my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> did artwork for them and then you know so we got our
 		uh day care free
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they didn't have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well this one was set up good i mean they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to every room
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and they had a good system like so when you walked in everything looks cool
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the problem i had was that
 		they did not show affection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> enough they did not show them care to these small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are being left
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i picked up this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who was crying and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> came and just chewed me up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side and down the other you know he said you are gonna have every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in here wanting you to pick them up
 	
 	
 		hm
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i said no this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was crying and needed some comfort you know what is your problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		did did they separate them by age group
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		because i'd think you know i think that's one thing that was important
 	
 	
 		right they did they had like um the the crawlers the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> that didn't walk in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> the ones that were starting to walk in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> then they had like the um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three three year olds</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		upper fours lower fours upper fives lower fives you know just like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they really did separate them well it was just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> themselves
 	
 	
 		it it sound yeah
 		it sounds like to me your  your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> would be to make sure that they are loving people
 	
 	
 		right but yeah that they're not
 	
 	
 		affectionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they're they're kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>  maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> themselves or something
 	
 	
 		yeah their system
 		right but their but their system was was great but um the
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		you know the caring just wasn't there the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that taught that did the babies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i worked with her and she was fabulous she loved them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and she loved them and cared for them but um every one of the others that i saw was just screaming and yelling and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know would make me a nervous wreck so you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i think that's probably a really important thing because you can have
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doctorates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD's</ENAMEX> and all that kind of thing and you know know all the technical stuff
 		but if they don't reach out and touch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> then that doesn't do any good
 	
 	
 		yeah these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are just in a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh with no any type of emotional
 		you know getting love getting care they're just there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know going through this routine which is lousy
 	
 	
 		and
 		the other the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that we had was kind of interesting the other one we went to the it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife team</ENAMEX> and we knew them from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it was kind of interesting because she was kind of the strict <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i think you know she would she'd put her arm around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and talk to them and stuff you know but he was actually the more
 		um
 		the more uh what demonstrative type the more loving he would you know laugh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and play with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it it it was kind of interesting to see that that that it was actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that
 		that did that side of it and
 	
 	
 		yeah you don't see that much
 	
 	
 		yeah so they had a really nice balance we liked that one in fact it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humpty Dumpty Play School</ENAMEX> or something but they also did
 	
 	
 		that's cute
 	
 	
 		they also did some of the teaching things and then they had um
 		you know obedience obedience was important
 	
 	
 		yeah that has to be with a day care center
 	
 	
 		and you know so they used you know they used uh
 		oh i think they used the you probably heard where you know where you stand in front of the clock and get your power back to control yourself
 	
 	
 		i've never heard of that that's that's a new one on me
 	
 	
 		and it's it's it's one uh i can't remember what they call it exactly but you you just stand them in front of the clock and you know it has a second hand that goes around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have to stand there
 		
 		
 	