
 
     		
 	
 		so do you think we have an immigration problem right now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it's hard to say there is certainly uh some discussion about that with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to come in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wanting to send them back if there is no clear evidence
 		of uh political
 		uh repression
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has set itself for so long as the uh the haven for people
 		from other places uh giving them an opportunity for a new start but  uh was back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when there was a lot of
 		a lot of land and a lot of opportunities that uh just don't seem to be available now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think i think there's still is a lot of land it's just not particularly desirable land yeah i think i think you know the plains were never completely settled
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you know
 		uh you know i'm i'm sure we i'm i'm i'm sure that you know
 		there's plenty of room for room for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South Dakota</ENAMEX> but i just don't think that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> want to move to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North or</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh that's true the uh
 		i i think the fact though that there is not a standard uh or or an equitable policy in place is causing a lot of trouble
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there was a essentially essentially an immigration lottery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> back
 	
 	
 		yeah i've been hearing about that it seemed like the silliest thing i'd ever heard you know the
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you you can immigrate totally without merit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		because you know you you get the lucky number
 	
 	
 		right
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that uh that everyone was up and arms about was that uh there was a certain preference given to uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming over from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and how
 		how a decision like that is made uh oh we don't have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> in this country
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		just just seems to be be fairly strange uh uh either you know oh if we feel that we've been wrong in in keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> out or whatever it is i i don't understand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how this is all working and i'm not sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are running it understand it either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i probably agree well what what do you think we could do to make it better
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's that's the hard question that that always seems to be the hard question
 		i don't know that there's
 		there's a lot we can do short of either
 		uh not allowing any immigration whatsoever or opening the flood gates i think that any middle ground is going to uh have its
 		it it it's going to have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> complaining about discrimination and uh
 		and other problems like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it's interesting to me to see the uh the current administration
 		welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are who are battling to get here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> uh are are rounded up thrown on a military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> and shipped back at the earliest possible moment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		given the fact that uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> was overthrown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> it it's uh
 		contradictory to the the policy of supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> throughout the world that now we want to turn around and send them back because they don't like the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that overthrew the democracy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it it it seems
 		you know it seems almost as absurd as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> when um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we uh you know we'd welcome uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> for political reasons but you know if they're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		then they couldn't be fleeing to for political reasons because you know we we were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with that government
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		and i i think that maybe that selectivity is is a bigger problem than just the problem of immigration
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that when it is selective like that is fairly visible and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize that uh oh yes we'll let these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in because uh we we don't like their government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it it it's an odd situation
 		of course we haven't touched on at all what happens when these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with no visible means of support come to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> without any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> or any uh
 	
 	
 		were this skills that you know that are really marketable in our country
 	
 	
 		or any
 		right
 	
 	
 		because you know you know of the yeah the the see especially hard to
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	