
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh i just want to know do tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX> get what they get back what they what they uh put into i kind of doubt it because of because of the latest check writing scandal
 		i should have such good uh such such good use of of the public fund
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know what do you think
 	
 	
 		well it seems like its a tremendous pressure to
 		uh reduce taxes and reduce government spending but that uh somehow it just seems to go up and up
 		and  seems like taxes go up and and benefits go down i don't quite understand it all i think it must be a result of centralization
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centralization</ENAMEX> is suppose to um improve efficiency but i somehow i have a feeling it it uh reduces efficiency
 	
 	
 		well it sort of i i thinking more like the purest principle being at work you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager managers</ENAMEX> in particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">managers bureaucracies</ENAMEX> exist to
 		uh seek seek to multiply <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX> and not rivals
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well i think one of the problem is again isn't really the centralization but uh the further removed uh you get from cause and effect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		further removed cause and effect get the the uh
 		more problems you have i remember an incident um
 		
 
 		back when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where there were there was a push to to put in some regional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> and uh
 		
 
 		i don't remember exactly what it was but one of the reason for putting these in was that
 		that they they wouldn't really have to pay for them i think they'd have to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just ten</NUMEX> percent or maybe it was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> or something and they could get federal funds to do the rest
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it seemed to me that that was a crazy reason that it basically if it was not uh beneficial enough to
 		uh the local uh economy and the local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> to have uh regional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area then why the hell would it be uh important to the federal government
 		and to use uh the fact that you could leverage this and really only pay for a small fraction of it by virtue of having federal funds seems to me to be a good example of why
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centralization</ENAMEX> or federal funding is a bad idea and why it causes us to have
 		um increased tax rates and yet not much to show for it
 	
 	
 		um tremendous deficit anyway uh yeah i i don't know i i uh i rather think we're not going to see the end of the deficit for some time
 		although if the entire incumbent mood holds up we may there may be some changes this fall i'm not sure they're they're kind of strange because there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> running as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> now
 		uh running against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> so that's so we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> doing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> bid you know
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		trying to get themselves reelected i was just thinking that's kind of strange i don't think they're going to
 		i don't think i don't know how many of them are going to get reelected that way especially after they after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three hundred fifty two</NUMEX> or how ever many names got published officially
 		you know we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert K Dornam</ENAMEX> who's been a gap fly of a lot of uh he's he's been uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Orange County</ENAMEX>'s um
 		uh  i don't know i embarrassment i guess he's he's really terrible they um never voted down a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>'s package ever
 		and uh he he went out and and uh said claimed that that  that one check that he he uh he
 		he wrote that bounced was to get a uh to get a something like a statue of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> for his for his for his backyard or something ridiculous like that it was it was pretty funny
 	
 	
 		well i think it's easy to you know once you get in the position of power it's easy to just sort of relax and uh abuse that power just naturally without hardly trying
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i very much so um you know
 	
 	
 		it's hard to be ethical i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that must be why we see so many
 		that i mean it's hard to be ethical when you are a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is what i meant to say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that may be why we see so many corrupt officials
 	
 	
 		do you think it's because other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are spending other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> money they got
 	
 	
 		uh no i just think it's because power corrupt absolutely
 		
 		
 	