
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what do you think about caring for older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think um the elderly is a really neat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to care for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they've got a lot of special needs
 		and at the same time
 		um
 		majority of them don't want to give up
 		the independence that they have
 	
 	
 		right very definitely
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and so you've got a real balance to make there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what about you
 	
 	
 		well i'm thinking about it more in terms of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that are starting to get old They aren't really that old but they are sort of wearing out My mamma is a dialysis patient
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about sixty four</NUMEX> but she's had some pretty close calls and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> has to drive her to dialysis now
 		and so she's phasing out and but she's also a very very very independent person
 		and doesn't like having having people
 		uh not being able to do things for herself when she wants to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i know they certainly don't want to be in a nursing home but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> keeps talking about it i don't i couldn't possibly couldn't never see him in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grand daddy</ENAMEX> also doesn't like wouldn't want to be in a nursing home he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX>
 		i think right on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and he's living by himself My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grand mamma</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so but he's you know as long as you can have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'd like to see them stay at home
 	
 	
 		yeah but it gets hard my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> is in her mid eighties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she's uh suffering from a low uh well uh progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so she doesn't remember anybody
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh she remembers things but they are things back whenever she was real young
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so with she was living by herself but my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> has moved in with her to take care of her
 		and it's creating a lot of problems
 	
 	
 		right especially for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> i bet
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes
 	
 	
 		now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who was studying social work here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> worked for an adult day care program for mostly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer</ENAMEX> Do they have anything like that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um yeah i've i've heard of several things and they are really neat programs to be able to do if you can link up with them
 		but sometimes it's hard to either find the connections to get them in or uh to be able to get them there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> program and pick them up
 	
 	
 		right So they are pretty limited
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh another interesting thing another good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who got her degree in social gerontology
 		well had a job for a while where she went around to
 		to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and had them sort of kicked them in the pants to make them take good care of their older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		to make sure that they would take care of their responsibilities
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think that was mainly with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> but just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients people</ENAMEX> in general who were not as independent as they use to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it's it's it's a really day care programs are really neat you know and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are able
 		and and can get up and move and everything like that that is one of the best things to do but i think the hardest thing to do is whenever you've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's mentally very alert and active
 		and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> just hasn't kept up with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think that's in a way somewhere some an area where some of the day care uh programs have left off
 		because you really kind of have to be a little bit mobile to be able to do those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		to uh get there and to participate in the activities
 	
 	
 		right
 		cause i know there's one not too far from from me here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh and they have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX> and pottery and needle work
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and sports
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but if your vision is gone
 		and you have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> real badly
 	
 	
 		that's true You can't play those things
 	
 	
 		yeah you can't do it
 	
 	
 		but you can sing songs and uh
 	
 	
 		well that's true
 	
 	
 		tell stories about the old times i guess you know you were talking about you're was it your grand mother
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> being able to tell old stories You can perhaps get a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that aren't too far along with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer</ENAMEX> talking about the old times and enjoying it themselves that way
 	
 	
 		and they love to recollect i mean they just you know and they will just go on and on with these stories and they have such a memory
 	
 	
 		do they like to listen to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> recollect though
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> doesn't  she she wants to tell to tell you about her story over again so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		which is fine you know so
 	
 	
 		well that is good because we
 		
 		
 	