
 
     		
 	
 		um so you do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> no
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		no um i'm single uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are divorced so i can relate to not having enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> time
 	
 	
 		
  
 		okay um i don't have i'm single  um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> moved around a lot and i was at boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i can relate to not having family time
 	
 	
 		um
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so uh so what do you think it's important for  as far as spending quality time with family
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't have a lot in common and that's that's what really brought on the divorce is just uh growing terribly apart they got married too young and uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> i never really knew my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad um</ENAMEX> he was just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we um he he my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were together until i was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i never i i talked to him but it was just in passing you know we spent well the older i got the less time we spent together
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um we we talked maybe <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> out of a week
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and so so i loved him and we talked well you know we gave each other other hugs and asked how our day had been and that was the extent of it
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh huh
 	
 	
 		everyday you know that would be the most we'd talk about for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just a couple of minutes and</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		what about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> um-hum okay
 	
 	
 		oh well i am very close to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh we talk all the time i live with her now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have been divorced for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years three and a half four years</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		okay
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and we talk all the time we're very close and she is a real personable relationship oriented woman
 	
 	
 		well that's good that's good um my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and i didn't talk while i was growing up so uh they sort of did their thing and i did my thing  so um
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh we they're not divorced but um  they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> and their you know their job
 		came <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> family second it seemed anyway
 	
 	
 		right oh dear
 	
 	
 		so  that's the way i saw it so we didn't really spend much family time together i didn't think um and they you know i was in the basketball and track <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and they never came to any of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so things like that so if if i had a family i'd make sure that i would go to events you know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would be involved in because it's really important
 	
 	
 		
  
 		sure
 		
  
 		sure
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you know to help them to feel like they're special or you know important
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and i know that that God is supposed to be your priority but your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s priority above church work
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		is is what i've always believed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the deacons in our church
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he put time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church church</ENAMEX> uh uh the church burned by accident um uh the you know when i was real young and we were in the process of building another house
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> put working on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> building uh before working with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> kind of left to her
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and really left the family completely behind to work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and to be you know what everybody would consider to be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the church
 	
 	
 		
  
 		wanted him to be yeah
 	
 	
 		right right and and he had more of a desire with with with the rest of the church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to be with us and so that that was definitely a problem
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh
 		
  
 		yeah sounds like it
 	
 	
 		and uh when when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> divorced i i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has trouble staying in church because um she's just she just knows that there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		that you you just have to put that part behind you
 	
 	
 		right there is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX> everywhere anytime you have uh a group of people
 	
 	
 		oh sure sure and
 		oh sure and not everybody is going to get along but uh yeah that that was definitely a a problem in the marriage and they didn't communicate well at all so
 	
 	
 		
  
 		but that's right that's right
 		
  
 		
  
 		
  
 		right
 		
  
 	
 	
 		since they weren't spending time with each other hardly at all you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would come home late from work because he'd visit everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> before he'd come home um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		right
 		
  
 	
 	
 		me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> i have an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> older than me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacy McClain</ENAMEX> oh my word
 	
 	
 		i i think i know who she is
 		yeah  in fact as you were talking i was thinking i know who you are  yeah she's in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> in fact she's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> she's the one that got me into this
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh my goodness oh my goodness what is your name again <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		oh my goodness that's funny  well then she can tell you all about our family
 	
 	
 		and you sound like her yeah  okay
 		well she's told me a little bit but you're you're you're telling me more  i'm getting the whole scoop yeah well that's really a coincidence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		yeah
 		oh yeah  well i have to tell her because i talked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two two nights ago</TIMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> then last night it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and i didn't expect someone
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		oh really
 		
 		
 	