
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well um i know some in some of the one of the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they started curbside recycling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's going really well uh because they i think what happened what what goes on is they get like discounts
 		they get charged not by the amount of trash they do well they get charged by for the pick up of the trash and not for the recyclables
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so it's so you get pay you pay less to have your trash picked up because if you presort all out all your trash all your recyclables
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds great
 	
 	
 		what are they doing out there
 	
 	
 		well  it's sort of a mixed bag up here uh
 		some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> have started off with volunteer recycling uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> near here <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> uh had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> worth of volunteer recycling i never saw it but
 		i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who was involved in the effort who said that it was amazing just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> or you know maybe even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> coming in on the one recycling day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> and they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> sorting things
 		and when the volume reached a certain level the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Public Works</ENAMEX> finally decided to do a curbside program
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my town <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>
 		has had a uh a similar volunteer program and they just got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Public Works</ENAMEX> to do a uh
 		a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> drop off at their yard where you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can bring in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and
 		and uh paper and and whatnot and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and tin and some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> around here fact just about all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> that border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> where i live have gone to the curbside recycling and
 		i really wish we'd do it here it's just so much easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i think it's it probably results in a larger volume of stuff being recycled if all you have to do is put it out by your curb once a week
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		as it is here i sort of resent the effort to you know collect everything until i have a chance to get down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DPW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> and drop it off you know it's not a huge inconvenience but it's just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more thing to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and it's hard to find i know at least here it's hard to find places that will that recycle and so many things are recyclable like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shampoo</ENAMEX> bottles and water bottles
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but no place will take them
 		and you know i mean they're real specific you know you can do your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> but you have to take all the slick stuff out
 		you know and well what do you do with the slick stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean they're so specific i mean in i know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they're having a real hard time right now because the drop off sites
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't there's a you know what they say that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can mess it up for everybody
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are not sorting out uh like their slick stuff out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and uh all their plastic bottles or their brown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> out of their clear glass
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that recycle the stuff won't recycle it then
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		and they'll just trash it so that all the effort goes downhill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's a real problem that
 		really hate to hear that just regarding the newspapers the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> curbside thing we do have in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> actually is every other week they'll pick up newspapers
 		which is nice and the rule is that anything that comes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> even the slick uh ad inserts they'll pick up and that's great
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that is great
 		gee i i didn't i i just thought there was something in the slick stuff that that made it so they couldn't recycle it well that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah i i guess it depends on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> it's going to the thing that i guess the flip side of that and
 		in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> anyway is that they won't pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> now and even when they were here and in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> around here they won't take the so called injection molded things which
 		i guess basically are containers that are bigger at the top than at the bottom like yogurt containers typically
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i don't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> eat a lot of yogurt so there's just a lot of lot of containers that uh that wind up getting tossed you know without being recycled
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i don't know what's going on with in terms of capacity it's my impression although i haven't really read anything about it that
 		so many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have started recycling with there might not be enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> out there
 		that are willing to take the uh or you know that'll pay decent money to take the materials
 	
 	
 		right right i know well i know here at uh i i'm in i'm in college and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and i'm on the kind of like an off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> campus
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and on the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> they've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that comes in and takes out all the recyclables all the copy paper and all the cardboard boxes i mean everything that's recyclable
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 		
 		
 	