
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little girls i have um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one seven</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one five and a half</TIMEX> and um i'm divorced i'm just now i'll be divorced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> so i'm pretty much raising my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> myself
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh okay
 		
 
 		that's a hard task
 	
 	
 		yeah it is but they they're wonderful they turned out wonderful and they're obedient and smart and bright and well adjusted and so i'm blessed
 	
 	
 		right
 		um that's that's fantastic yeah um a lot of times well i guess the majority of their of their early growing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they had a full family right
 	
 	
 		um not really because he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so he traveled around a bit and was on duty
 	
 	
 		yeah he was gone a lot and and um stuff like that but um
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah i i find myself comparing it to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> because both of them have been divorced um one had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and the other had three
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and i have been determined not to ever have them in day care though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have never been in day care never um
 	
 	
 		good job
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i uh have always been home with them and then when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> decided he wanted to be free and uh left i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's a euphemism huh that's a euphemism huh
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yes and um he i uh prayed and found a way to make money without putting them in day care so i clean houses
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i do it while they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and i make my own <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and i'm home when i want to be home and
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		um so i have plenty of time and um we read
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		quite a bit and um we bicycle we all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us have bicycles
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		great that sounds good sounds like there's some quality time being spent there
 	
 	
 		so that's our
 		there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> is is um <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> are bicycling and um try to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		right it are you calling from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah can't you tell
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah i i noticed a bit of an accent there where about are you calling from
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um East Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">round Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		that'd be about the biggest place you know that i'm from and i'm from a small a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> though it's not not that big it's big but it's not that big
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">okay uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		but it's warm enough to where you can do that kind of bicycling stuff generally pretty much <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh for the most part
 	
 	
 		pretty much pretty much because we've had pretty weather
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		not too much rain right
 	
 	
 		oh it's been awful lately it's rained a lot
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but we we watch TV we watch in in the evenings we sit down and watch TV together um like from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or something like that we watch TV together before they go to bed and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> frown on that just on on TV in general but i don't know i i think my own personal opinion is that it it helps to instill a sense of values and moral as long as it could be explained explained and as long as there's good monitoring going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> know what they can watch and what they can't and if they see something that does not
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		sound right from the way they've been raised they will say something about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		so um and i will tell them that's not acceptable behavior that's not right we don't do that so um and we don't watch um
 	
 	
 		no right okay
 	
 	
 		you know really adult bad you know we watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby Show</ENAMEX> i mean  you know that type of
 	
 	
 		sure
 		um yeah well that's that's good family moral type stuff you know which is good great
 	
 	
 		right right so we enjoy that and um heavily involved in church and um go to that you know together and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		did they see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> often or
 	
 	
 		no um because i don't mind are um passed away and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s are out of state so they're not they don't they just mainly have me
 	
 	
 		oh sorry
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well that's that's important for you to be there then for a lot of the time
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's good i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> my closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is the same way in terms of day care pretty much to where she really tries to not have them in day care because you tend to pick up bad habits that way and other other people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you do and they're treated um wrongly a lot of times and you don't know it
 	
 	
 		right you don't know what kind of moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are inflicting on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and things like that so yeah that's a good thing i'm i'm myself am am not married but am beg your pardon
 	
 	
 		right right
 		how old are you
 		how old are you
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i've kind of devoted myself to school but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh right now i'm i'm getting closer to marriage and things are getting very serious and we're talking about these kind of issues and things so good to hear a viewpoint from someone who is actually in the situation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i think it's important to really think really hard before you get married and before you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and when you make that commitment to stand by it not to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years later</TIMEX> go well
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	