
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		do you live in a high crime area
 	
 	
 		oh it's uh yes and it's the crime mostly in this area is uh burglary house break-ins in fact our car our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was broken into about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weekends ago three weekends ago</TIMEX> they stole a stereo i mean it was parked out in front of our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it happened overnight but there's a uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we we had a break at our place our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> bought an alarm system about within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> after that
 	
 	
 		do you think that that will do it
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think anything is going to be uh foolproof i think it's it's a deterrent i think if they have a choice between our place and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that's not protected they'll go to the other place
 	
 	
 		they'll go to the  yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh it's uh  we live in uh well i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> actually you say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> do you mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		okay
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and uh the crime out here is mostly of the break in type and vandalism and sort of stuff like that i don't think there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you don't have much street crime
 	
 	
 		no no as far as uh muggings and murders and stuff like that no that's pretty isolated pretty rare i think would knock on wood
 	
 	
 		right
 		um
 		that's what i would think in that area yeah so what do you think you can do to uh
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		oh you know i think a lot of the crime is committed committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are trying to uh finance their next fix and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's you know that goes back to a drug problem and uh nobody's been able to solve that yet i think it's uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		drug related and then a lot of it starts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and uh the the uh breakup of breakup of the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>'s caused a lot of the problems i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is gone for one reason or another the mother's raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		family unit you mean
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they just get there's no discipline at the at the home so it just goes from bad to worse it just starts there and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads leads</ENAMEX> from that into the drug situation and then as i said they're trying to finance their next uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		fix
 	
 	
 		next fix so they're desperate uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and that's what
 		the uh seems like the uh genre of the crime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is
 		a lot of desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whereas i think probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years ago</TIMEX> the crime wasn't quite so intense that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 		probably wasn't as personal as it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i mean break with the uh muggings and the break-ins of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and so forth then there there just wasn't as much of it i i imagine as as there is now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		with the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i mean i think the reasons were different back then more than they are now like you're saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> can make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really desperate so that makes them also very dangerous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah well i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are to blame i i i just think they're they're overly lenient on these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i was watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live</ENAMEX> there and they were they were talking about rape and castration and so forth and
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's always so much concern about the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the burglar</TIMEX> and so forth and no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> at all about the victim
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's really disgusting
 	
 	
 		yeah so uh it i think the whole thing just needs a complete overhaul but it starts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but it's everybody's to blame i think at least a lot of probably a lot of apathy on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that haven't been uh victimized
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah because they have no idea what it's like
 	
 	
 		right so uh it it it's just a big problem and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's so many other problems to go around and economy's a problem and i guess at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was a problem and uh every there there's always one problem or another seems to be uh ahead of the crime problem but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's probably that has to be one of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> i think basically from what i've read that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> has one of the highest crime rates in the world so i think that's a priority
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah you know i think we think we're real sophisticated we're really not when you come right down to it there used to be a lot of stuff on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> when you're driving around dropped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are
 	
 	
 		we're not
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		that you makes makes you wonder whether they're not just jerks or not i mean they just do crazy thing they they're not breaking the law but they just do some crazy things and
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know it's it's kind of disgusting but they we're really not all that sophisticated over here
 	
 	
 		no if you come down to it if you look at uh the statistics on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh violence against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and uh the drug wars and uh also um
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		let's see i think with like with rape it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> rape the the amount of rape and uh
 	
 	
 		what's that yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		uh like with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i think that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> solution that i know i hate to say it  but is legalization
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because that's where all the drug the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> get their power over the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> because it's illegal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i there's a lot of complications that go along with saying that but i just nothing else seems to be working
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i was going to say it's worth a
 		
 		
 	