
 
     		
 	
 		well i think um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for at least for me uh because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is looking for day care one of the things that we talked about as being very important is the um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> to uh the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because if you've got a lot a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> just won't cut it
 	
 	
 		right even if it's in the home i think this is important even if it's a private home situation
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and not a day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um probably number one too would be close references
 		if you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have had the experience at they hands on experience of one
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		would be very important
 		word of mouth
 	
 	
 		word of mouth is good uh something that i don't think many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know about and i this is just something i've heard not something i've actually experienced um checked into is that um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that uh that license
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies agencies</ENAMEX> to care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like home either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or day care you can you can request to see if they have had any problems in the past
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is what i've been told
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that would be a good a good resource to check
 	
 	
 		right right and all of course better business i would check any of your business um  any type of thing references of that type
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as well as your word of mouth if you were putting them in uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or any day care type you know that's public
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know what i mean like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> or a school type thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i would check that awfully close
 		um i'd go in often
 	
 	
 		yes and in and there's some places i'm sorry go ahead
 	
 	
 		unexpectedly
 		unexpectedly wherever they where
 	
 	
 		right because then there's some places and i would and i would don't this would be a a big minus for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> there are some places that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that you cannot come in unannounced
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you have to have an appointment or you know or whatever and i don't think you know if there hum-um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i wouldn't do that i mean i wouldn't not put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in there though would you
 	
 	
 		no no never
 	
 	
 		you know i would never have a controlled situation not with a little one especially
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know that's not a not a good situation on that
 	
 	
 		and i think you've also got to look you know whenever you go in and you know talk to the talk to the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and look at the toys that they have and the environment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>'ll be in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum right that's real important i believe so too to meet the and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> as well and really kind of
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		research it and get an idea of how they feel about things you know have your questions ready on their feelings on things and all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of how they basically anyway because they you know that's
 		um seventy percent your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know is developing is there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's real important do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in it yourself
 	
 	
 		no um i like i said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s in the process of trying to find one for hers
 	
 	
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is um-hum
 		yeah it's a scary thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and had to do it you know just out of the cold she's had to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but she's been real fortunately in finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in their homes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		and and that's a good situation but it can it can it can turn bad with older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i was in a day care until i was thirteen just during like in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what we found was and what finally got me out of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> was the fact that she would go off shopping with some of the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and leave me there to care for the little ones
 	
 	
 		oh wow yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and i mean this went on for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> for a you know good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX> months
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and it's her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> thing you know and so if you've got older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that you just don't want to leave at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes a day care a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or a day care setting is not the best
 	
 	
 		not the best situation yeah yeah that's for sure
 	
 	
 		right  right
 		so but oh and another one is is how they discipline
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i know depending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of the day</TIMEX> cares that that i went to whenever i was younger um one of them disciplined whenever we were outside you hugged a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and you had time out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whereas you know i've heard of some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> you know that get into the physical discipline
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you you really have to find a discipline that that matches your beliefs
 	
 	
 		yes right and what you would want done right yeah
 	
 	
 		or yeah
 		right because it gets it can it can become very confusing for the child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i would think so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hm
 		what about um
 		well i'm in i'm in nursing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so one thing i would look at would be um
 	
 	
 		the cleanliness and the care health care
 	
 	
 		the cleanliness and the care
 		the health that's right the certification of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		because there's a new state law mandating that everyone that works in a day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		knows knows infant and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> CPR
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but there's a lot of places
 		
 		
 	