
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay so
 	
 	
 		well what kind of uh programs do y'all have up there for recycling
 	
 	
 		um around here we can recycle almost anything um we have paper and cans and uh newspaper i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and then i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> it's a little harder to do but you we can recycle those as well
 	
 	
 		is there a curbside service or do you have to take it to a distribution or a collection center
 	
 	
 		there's curbside but um for items like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and and plastic it's only like once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> or something crazy like that
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so you have to know what night they're doing it and you're not allowed to put anything out any other night so
 	
 	
 		right well we have it once a week they just started it not too long ago and we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and then like a very select group of  plastics
 		um but it's not real convenient like you said for lots of other things um and
 		it it is kind of nice though because you can put everything in together and you don't have to sort it out which is nice
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh yeah so you don't have to split anything up
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh you just they gave us a little bin and you put everything in it there's a little separate top basket thing for the newspaper which is convenient but if you want to recycle anything other than their list you know good luck
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um we have a couple of collection places around but they're pretty inconvenient to get to and and those you do have to sort and and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have room you know in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> different bins
 		for all the different sorting things you have to do
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i uh the last place i lived was really it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> as well but it was um
 		it was really a lot hard harder to do it because um it's different depending on what town you're in basically every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is different which i think that that's crazy that it should be coordinated by the state or something but
 	
 	
 		right
 		well what's kind of interesting is here when the program started they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		made a big deal about it but they only gave it to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like five thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> which in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> is nothing you know and it was interesting because it was the only reason we got it is because we're sort of on the outskirts of this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		rather plush area so  you can tell where they put the recycling uh program in place so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta</ENAMEX> really hasn't spread it out very much at all yet i don't think um i guess
 	
 	
 		are you
 		are you
 	
 	
 		budgetary restraints
 	
 	
 		oh yeah are you living at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or are you outside of school
 	
 	
 		um no i live off campus
 	
 	
 		oh okay so it's not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that's doing it or
 	
 	
 		yeah pretty far off
 		right no it's it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> has it's own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> has been trying to get it's own recycling program uh uh operated through the student government
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but there they've tried and tried to get an area allotted to them for a collection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> keeps saying no because uh there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in in town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless people</ENAMEX> who collect cans
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		for a living and they're afraid that that's going to attract crime onto campus having a ready supply of cans
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay i thought they were afraid of putting them out of work or something
 	
 	
 		no well i don't know what what you know what their their philosophy was on that
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but uh that so they it's kind of a crime that we have all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> wanting to do this and no no cooperation to to get that program going
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but
 		a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine and i had also thought a while back about doing some recycling on our own to make some money and i think it was interesting i found out that glass
 		is only worth like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> a pound
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when you start figuring how much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> you need to make you know if you figure you can fill a big trash can with glass and get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> pounds well that's great but that's a dollar
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it's not a real profitable thing for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> but like my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> uh started doing recycling because it became mandatory in the state i i think it was mandatory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> but they did it and they started a recycling program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just of paper i guess
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> they saved like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four million dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		um they that's how much money they got paid for their paper
 	
 	
 		yeah well now i know that i know that the same thing applies for aluminum it's much more profitable than glass
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i just thought you know we had thought wow this would be a nice little sideline because there's every we'd been going out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> around here and we'd asked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different places and nobody recycles
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we thought well you got this ready market you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> with all this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and beer bottles and yet there's there's almost no way you could make money at it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because the labor and the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> would eat up any profit you'd make because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> is you know but i'm sure that as far as aluminum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	