
 
     		
 	
 		all right uh i think we pay a little bit too much in taxes and we don't always get what we pay for
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i agree i'm particularly worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> since i'm at the
 		end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomer generation</ENAMEX> and there's not gonna be any money left when i get through
 		so i kind of feel like i'm supporting a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that it's just gonna go into a hole  i don't think that i'm gonna get anything out of it when the time comes from
 	
 	
 		yeah no
 	
 	
 		it
 		other than that yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i i kind of feel the same way you know you pay all this money into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and then you're not gonna get anything back out of it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because you're paying for everybody that uses it now and it's not gonna be there when you need it
 	
 	
 		right everybody there's not gonna be enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to support us when we get our age  up that way but
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		we'll be supporting
 		we're they're we're a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> right now supporting a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and then when the time comes and it's a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> supporting a lot of people it's not gonna even out very fairly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that way i don't have to i don't worry about the other i don't have state taxes really because i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so
 		i'm happy with that  i'm worried about it though because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they sit there and try to put more taxes in you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they're trying to get property tax in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>  but
 	
 	
 		yeah well well  well well i think some of the taxes that pay you know you're paying more for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
 		to disburse the money out than you are for uh the money to be spent you know like on education and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		there's so much administration and nothing  when it when it comes right down to it
 		the overhead is it get everything gets eaten up in overhead and doesn't actually  do do much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so i i feel like
 		some of like i said some most of the taxes that we pay are not being used for what they're supposed to be used for
 	
 	
 		yeah i was thinking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> you know it was like no taxation without representation and so long ago and now we're just eaten alive by
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that can't pay for itself and goes into debt more and more and more and more and we don't have much say about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to do a  be doing a whole lot of things i like either
 	
 	
 		uh  yeah and and they like they use taxes to to make grants to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		they're going
 	
 	
 		you know they wanna find out how come <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX> do fly and all other kinds and i think that's kind of stupid
 	
 	
 		yeah and then this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX> thing where they they put pornography up in the in the name of art you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and make me pay for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my you know i i don't exactly appreciate that either i really get frustrated when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> starts to do things that are immoral and then expect me to support them on it
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 	
 	
 		first you get to the point where it's like you feel like protesting by not paying just to make  them understand that they can't do this just because you know it's our money they're using
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		for it they can't just think well it's ours now we got it we can do what we want with it
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		it says that i'm standing it it says i approve if i sit there and pay it and i get kind of upset about that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i can understand that because
 		and uh it's
 		it you know like you said it makes you upset and it makes me upset too when i hear stuff like that and i just heard on the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> where they all them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> overdrafted themselves and they
 		you know finally gonna come out with everybody's name now saying who done it
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah you start to feel real powerless
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		but on the other hand at least we're  we're powerless in a lot of ways but then there's so many other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that i'm glad i'm not in
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it seems to me like the minute you starting putting in any radical changes in anything you end up with something like um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX> or  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> you know i mean it seems like
 		i'd rather try to work from inside the system to change something than to throw away what we've got now
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it would be pretty frightening the other way around it's kind of scary now seeing the way
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		they're going over there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		uh that and you know like a lot of our tax money goes to helping other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and stuff and
 		i think we ought to use a lot of that money here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> before we send it to someplace else
 		
 		
 	