
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh how you how do you find out what's going on
 	
 	
 		what's new
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh
 		quite a variety of ways i guess uh like to listen to the radio back and forth to work at least back to work and in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you listen you listen to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> or do you switch back and forth
 	
 	
 		well i have one station i listen to when i get up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> then i listen to another one in the car
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i listen to i actually i listen to the radio most of all i don't i don't buy papers and stuff i i listen a lot to national public radio
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which is i know pretty much it's got in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> it has like an all news format
 		and then uh toward it it changes like it goes onto classical then onto jazz later on but on in the way to work that that's what i do is i listen to to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> and what it says about about what's going on
 	
 	
 		hum
 		well we don't have uh well let's see i guess it might be available i just haven't heard of it on that one i i guess i have come to think of it but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i haven't made a practice of listening to that one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		watching some TV in the evenings
 	
 	
 		uh what  it's it's funny i haven't seen do you watch like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> or do you uh or the
 	
 	
 		well i usually catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and i will occasionally watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> too depends on what you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> do you listen i don't know do i i like it when i watch TV i don't really watch TV news all that often but what i do is i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> i think i think they have the best news network
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		i generally uh i don't know i go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		have you ever watched <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> with with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Coppell</ENAMEX> or is that i i i get to see that i get that occasionally but it's like i i he's a i think he's sort of like an upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geraldo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i watch that
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know he i digs he he digs just a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">digs</ENAMEX> just like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a little a little too much i i wish i could actually stay up late enough to to see some of the to see some of those things
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Magazine</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 	
 	
 		uh i don't take them i read them sometime i read them in the barber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		dentist office material
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i actually i i kind of gave up on on news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> they they haven't they kind of pile end up piling up
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what i was just about to say about the newspaper i uh i take it then i quit it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 	
 	
 		gets there laying around and don't get to read it's does get to be quite a volume of
 	
 	
 		oh well i tried like uh i like i read the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> paper you know i that one i can probably i can find time for you know like on a i i really like to on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> get up and uh listen uh get up
 	
 	
 		material after awhile
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and read the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> like first usually i try to read it from like from cover to cover you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that same here
 	
 	
 		and that that pretty much gives you gives me an idea what's going on and in about like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> it takes me to run right through it i can figure out exactly what what what's happened in like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>
 		but that's about the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that i really listen to
 	
 	
 		our <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> throws you a curve they uh you know that's what i would like to do i say well i'd just like to take the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> paper well
 		we'll uh we'll let you have the rest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> for free
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 		what do you what do you do
 	
 	
 		so you end well you end up with like a big stack of papers anyway on the on the way out huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		but i say well the heck with it we'll go buy it from that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the street
 	
 	
 		well one of the things that i i can't do is i just can't find the time to read the paper all that much it just
 		if i were to if i were to it would take like what <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		to to to find the time to read the paper
 		and that's why i like the radio the best especially especially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because i when i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and i'm on my way to work there's nothing else i can do other than like watch the road you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i've gotten into some uh
 		you know we have a uh
 		news service on our uh
 		network here on the computer
 	
 	
 		oh and it its it slides in a window across the bottom
 	
 	
 		well we have that at at lunch in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> but we also have uh one that you pull up on your screen you know we have a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> here at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> that you can go to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so do you is it is it Dow Jones
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and get the national
 		they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> segment there where it covers us uh you know some most active stocks uh general average
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine at other at other uh at other locations they have they have that and it's like you can actually see like the ticker run you know you can open a window on your work station
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and you can run and you can run the uh the ticker across the bottom and it it actually you know they they run a ticker for for news items as well as stock
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's actual that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJNS</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		and so you can see you can see the uh you can
 		
 		
 	