
 
     		
 	
 		do you have any
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes we do have a pet we have a  a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that we got from the uh
 		well we call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P C A</ENAMEX> it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh animal</ENAMEX> from an animal shelter uh he'd come in there as a stray uh he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pomeranian</ENAMEX> and Sheltie cross uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		all right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well he was very well trained when we got him uh he's
 	
 	
 		oh that's good you don't often find that i don't think
 	
 	
 		no uh we suspect that he was hurt in an accident you know got away from somebody traveling through and hurt in an accident because
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that looks as good as he does and is trained as well is someone that has lost him and not have been able to locate him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh if they were local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they would have been able to find him
 	
 	
 		sure there's a okay uh that's interesting yeah the only pet that i've had uh i'm a i'm a doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in my in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier days</TIMEX> as a student  i kind of time shared on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> with a a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh it was an amazing dog it really was they had he had gotten it from the pound and uh it it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish Pointer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domino</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		kind of looks like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatian</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatian</ENAMEX> and we trained it from a pup and basically it right now it it's fully trained and it can do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of things it will get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> for you out of the fridge and it will get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and do all kinds of stuff
 		so it's really  it's it's kind of a show piece anymore and whenever anybody comes over we all have to show him Domino you know
 	
 	
 		oh i think so
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh she's been a real good a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and uh just it's kind of a shame that i'm i'm gone i'm away from it now i i just i actually live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i'm on an internship up here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and then i go back down but uh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domino</ENAMEX>'s a real good dog uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what uh possessed you to get the dog
 	
 	
 		well i i guess in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense we felt that it it's nice to have a dog
 		even though there are you know complications come with it and then with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh at the time they were oh grade <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and and grade <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was an age where it was uh we thought it was be good for them to have the  discipline that goes with with having a pet uh
 	
 	
 		sure sure learn a bit learn a little bit of discipline and how to care for it and things like that that's good that kind of builds some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		
 
 		uh well that's the idea i think the reality of it is that they perhaps uh
 		it depends on the on everyone's discipline
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh from that aspect i'm short on the discipline because i don't uh enforce that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> look  after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and uh we've had him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but i think it does it it you know it's necessary that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> have the discipline to look after the animal properly uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's something that's important for sure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think uh do you live in a in a in a fairly rural part of the uh  or
 	
 	
 		uh actually no we live in a in an area that's oh probably <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two and a half miles</NUMEX> from the university
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		uh we live right might say we live right in uh in the middle of a residential area
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so that is not as good uh  you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> being a small dog it's uh more you more acceptable but again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's not that big of a problem With Domino she was full grown i would estimate seventy pounds
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know we we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oviedo</ENAMEX> which is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but  there's not there wasn't a lot of room for her to run around and she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that loved to run
 		so that was the biggest problem i saw and i think that's one of the uh the issues <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to think about before they get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> is you know do you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> to run around or can you know i guess you can't really say for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 		me and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> don't get along too well uh  but you know that whole space issue i think is real important
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh that's one of the biggest concerns it's like
 		uh there's a lot to be gained from a relationship with an animal but the same time
 		one has to recognize the reality of physical requirements of of the animal
 	
 	
 		right yeah that that
 	
 	
 		and the larger they are the more room they need to exercise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> and that's all part of your of keeping your part of the relationship you know showing the maturity and responsibility to recognize those uh those issues
 	
 	
 		right
 		well
 	
 	
 		you know and also the whole whole thing with noise my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> oh she <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> out because she's got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> that have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> that don't train them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know we had we had a neighbor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> when we lived there that had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Spaniels</ENAMEX> and they're very high strung <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> to begin with but uh
 		
 		
 	