
 
     		
 	
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway i uh
 		i uh oh i i did forget to ask you what is your name by the way
 	
 	
 		um i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX> hi
 		but um
 		anyway i uh lot of lot of stuff interesting procedural things i think we could we could change if we're going to
 		talking about the subject <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight tonight</TIMEX> which is some i guess criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> courts yes
 	
 	
 		yeah the  the one of which was uh
 		something something that's been going on because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX> trial here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and that is uh and that is the exclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> because of or in spite of their race
 		uh yeah yeah well the the uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		the the the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that's trying uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in that case is is an all white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> and there's been a lot made in the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> of that fact
 	
 	
 		right
 		how is it i can't i'm a little surprised they didn't get a change of venue on that one
 	
 	
 		they have they have they moved it up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> north of here
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> and there's there's still quite a bit of publicity obviously and it's kind of it's kind of debatable whether you could get a fair trial almost anywhere because that uh that
 	
 	
 		well that videotape was just horrible
 	
 	
 		yeah it was everywhere
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know and i i think it would be very difficult to find someone uh find a panel that would be not have seen it and and known of what was going on
 	
 	
 		oh i agree with you but i can't imagine that they would do an all white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> without having some sort of of discrimination or or
 		you know uh appeal on not having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and all of that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		exactly you know um the
 		you know i i'm kind of torn on this issue it's like they're saying well on the one hand they're not he's not getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> which is in some ways i think true
 		but on the other hand is it's also saying that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> are not going to are not going to convict
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know they're not going to do their job which is the whole the whole point of being on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is to convict or or or uh let go based on whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whether or not the evidence says that there's enough
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		based on fact right
 		how interesting ooh
 		so what's the prevailing thought within the community
 	
 	
 		i um
 	
 	
 		i mean you know what the news media's gonna make of it but what about the community
 	
 	
 		they well i guess it depends on who you talk to i haven't talked to uh i haven't talked to a whole lot of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on it but i i rather imagine there's  there's some snickering about it and a lot of the usually fatalistic
 		oh here we go again <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my goodness that can't be good for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		no no i you know on on on one hand you on the one hand you almost hope that they convict them because it's they they have that very strong piece of physical evidence showing these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> beating the heck out of this guy
 	
 	
 		oh exactly
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		unfortunately that kind of thing is not
 		limited to
 		uh a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> you're going to have it
 		just about anywhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there but that's that's interesting
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who's hearing the case is he gonna be impartial is he going to be a good a good adjudicator
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't know you know and and again there's something else that you know there was a
 		uh it something else along those lines there was a girl
 		out here named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latausha Harlins</ENAMEX> i don't know if this this got this got as much notoriety but it's rather almost as infamous here as it was as it was with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX> problem um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> walked into a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>  and uh they she had a dispute black girl
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she she had some kind of a dispute over some orange juice with the with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> popped her
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and and well of course the you know the criminal case went up and  and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who shot her shot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> a uh
 		uh practically a suspended sentence i mean it was
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		it was just she gave her no time in jail and and you know all of these things and then oh there's uh we have these we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wandering around to with petitions trying to get the judge
 	
 	
 		to get that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> recalled i would think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		hm that's almost when you kind of wish that there where standardized standardized sentences
 	
 	
 		yeah it would make it would make life easier yeah but
 	
 	
 		it would uh you would know the whole world would know what you were facing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then it's a matter of of deciding guilt
 		
 		
 	