
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so how you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's pretty good you know you get uh
 		closer to the uh coast here and you do get a good bit of uh smog and stuff especially from all the uh fuel cracking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> and chemical plants
 	
 	
 		right i guess uh i don't know what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> you're in but i guess it's uh fairly industrial
 	
 	
 		yeah it's when you get further east towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> it gets very industrial
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but i'm i'm <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about uh thirty miles</NUMEX> west of there so you have uh actually green <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and such that you don't notice that that other part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> exists actually very
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah you you go even a few wide miles out and you got uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and everything so you relatively clear air
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well i don't know about you but i've always considered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> to be probably the the prime contributor i mean there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> but it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> would probably do more than their fair share of that
 	
 	
 		oh definitely definitely it's uh you know there are a large number of them on the road they're all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah going and a lot of them are in relatively poor repair
 	
 	
 		that's yeah that's that's a big issue is you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> don't have a uh inspection law so you get you get a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there without ETR emission control systems on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		oh even even where you do have the inspections you know the inspection is once a year
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's like
 	
 	
 		you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that's in the accident and muffler falls off or something and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> keeps driving along for long period of time after that
 	
 	
 		sure
 		right i guess from what i hear though uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> is coming out with their electric <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> they're actually coming out with the first prototypes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that and i think also some of the uh car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are coming out with uh gas powered fleets
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you natural gas powered rather than uh gasoline
 	
 	
 		right i hope i i'm hoping that comes along quick
 		
 
 		uh i was reading a an article in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Time the other day</TIMEX> about the ozone layer and how fast that's going and i guess it's it's really disappearing a lot quicker than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize and i know that's not due to uh
 		it's not due to to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> or to you know carbon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoxide</ENAMEX> so much as the CFC's but
 	
 	
 		it it is coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i think that's a that's a contributor definitely
 	
 	
 		i mean the uh car air conditioners is one of the major leaking sources of uh the uh freon which is one of the major fluorocarbons chlorofar <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorofluorocarbons</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		yeah i guess right now what they're what they're primarily worried about is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world countries
 		because i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> have kind of taken the lead in terms of eliminating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CFC</ENAMEX> production but
 	
 	
 		well it it
 	
 	
 		it
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		no it's the type of thing there that uh you know the Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are less industrial and they want to become industrial
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they're on the different part of the cycle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US the US</ENAMEX> used you know all the air pollution stuff
 		and air polluting technologies to get where it is today
 	
 	
 		right and that's one of the arguments that the Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have been using is that basically they don't want to have to pay for our mistakes
 		
 
 		if if that makes any sense uh in terms of
 	
 	
 		or or they want the right to make the same mistakes themselves to bootstrap them up to the way where we got to
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly uh those of kind of yeah those are joining arguments but uh
 		i don't know that's that's kind of an interesting situation there uh what they don't realize
 		those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">third</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> what they don't realize is how quickly the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> is depleting i guess the latest figures are up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifty percent</NUMEX> at the poles
 		and it's it's increasing even as far near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equator</ENAMEX> as like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and those places
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's kind of an interesting situation it's not
 		
 
 		not a real good one actually but
 	
 	
 		no well you also have the very close related thing of the uh rain forest destruction
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which is the main source of what's clearing out the atmosphere and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		replacing some of the pollutants
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah you don't get that that source of cleansing anymore are have you been in big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> a long time
 	
 	
 		mostly i've mostly been in the east coast so that's going between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		okay so you've got yeah those are actually areas that are hit pretty hard i would think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well not not as hard as some places out west because you don't get the uh major pollution <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as you do out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> with the with the inversion and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and all rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> which is just terrible it sounds
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>'s definitely yeah that's one of the worst
 		sure
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>'s that that real good uh that real good uh example of sitting in a valley
 		kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> does i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> is historically been one of the worst in the world for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i've been pretty lucky i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that really haven't had that much of a problem although uh i'm really kind of based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando Florida</ENAMEX> and
 		there you can tell that it's getting worse i mean it it definitely it's not at a level comparable to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> but you can
 	
 	
 		yeah there it's almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> because there's not that much in the way of heavy industry you know that would be causing it
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		yeah and there's not that much in terms of of public transportation down there there is but it's kind of it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	