
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right uh yeah we we spending quite a bit of time on me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> spending a lot of time with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 		we do a lot of games and stuff with him
 		uh
 	
 	
 		okay how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		just one
 	
 	
 		okay must make it nice to be able to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> child
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and uh we you know we take turns taking him back and forth taking him to day care and stuff so
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		he gets both of us
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and
 	
 	
 		in our case we have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are a little bit older than that one of them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		being a teenager wants to take care of himself more than he wants us to take care of him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i do believe that it's it's nice to have opportunities to have the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> together
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and uh it's pretty nice for us you know a lot of times we just sit out front and watch him ride his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		those memories can be really nice i guess uh especially looking back toward them i have several memories like that
 		and that was brought home even  more distinctly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about  two weeks ago</TIMEX> when a a very good well a a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> age fifteen was killed in an automobile accident oh suddenly
 	
 	
 		hm yeah
 	
 	
 		that's when you look back and think oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		yeah what could i have done to change you know something
 	
 	
 		right or
 		uh be glad that
 		uh be glad count the blessings that you receive every once and awhile and don't take it for granted
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yep that's for sure i can understand that part
 	
 	
 		oh what sort of do you do activities as a family go out and do things
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we go out uh
 		sometimes we got to like a wet and wild <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> it's uh kind of you know
 	
 	
 		ah yes
 		yeah we've we've got a big one coming up this uh uh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> we hope we live uh in the western part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and we're thinking of going to the south west and doing some hiking and camping and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 	
 	
 		that i hope will be an experience that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> remember for
 		i well the rest of their lives
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and maybe pass on to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> did with us you know
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah we went camping and stuff in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Horn</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teton</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah i know uh there's some good memories
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		and
 	
 	
 		that's one of that's one of my favorite things uh thinking back to those shared activities and
 		all the little things like the the tent leaking and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		running out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> or things like that tend to uh disappear in those fuzzy warm fuzzy memories from uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and one we went camping and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX> we woke up and there's snow on the ground so
 	
 	
 		yeah i had an experience like that in the in the mountains here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> in which uh
 		yeah it was just raining a little bit <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> and when it turned into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> we said no let's move down <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few thousand feet</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah i kind of miss that and we hadn't really had a chance lately to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camping</ENAMEX> or anything but
 		we're thinking about doing a big trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> to go camping
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and it's kind of hard to go and do anything when she's in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and stuff so
 	
 	
 		well
 		right
 		right well that kind of works out for us too and uh we also have commitments with the rest of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in that uh as well as being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> we're also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s parents
 		uh want us to get together for family reunions for instance
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		unfortunately the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s on the other side of the country
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's mine my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is up north and they are kind of all over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		most of them are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> and then i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> that's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		so you can spend a lot on travel too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah because i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> right now  so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		but you know we like i said we do a lot of activities with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and stuff
 		we play games with him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and
 		everything
 		uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum  there are times when i wish that i had more time to spend with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i was busy working well well i try to get over and visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's doing some computer stuff at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
 		uh help out with that and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning about oh fifteen minutes</TIMEX> after i knew they'd started that i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	