
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy</ENAMEX> i guess we get to talk about budgets <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> or lack of budgets if uh if that may be the case and any kind of long term financial planning or anything like that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		let me ask you the question do you have a uh budget or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> budget or a long term budget that you stick to
 	
 	
 		right now i'm in college and i'm on work study and so my budget comes from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s help
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he helps me out a lot and i get paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> so that's kind of hard to have a budget my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh doesn't get paid much money so her budget is um  just uh planning for IRAs
 	
 	
 		i see i see well good i'm i'm kind of in a different situation but i i i went through that too when i was in school
 		but uh i was i was working to get through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and and uh trying to make it through that but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm married and have uh a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and we have to uh pretty much stick to a budget i'm on a salary so i don't get any overtime or anything like that so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but we have a fixed income and we have to make sure that uh every dollar we have is is spent accordingly
 		and um
 		what we try and do to to stick to our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> budget is we pretty much have you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> payment we have the insurance premiums
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um utilities and so forth and we do sit down at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of every month or the end of every month</TIMEX> and write down how much we know we're going to spend
 		and set that money aside and we also try and set aside money for savings set aside money for the college the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' education college education the future and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		set aside money for bonds and and we also set aside an emergency fund because
 	
 	
 		that sounds good
 	
 	
 		we've uh  we've been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten years</TIMEX> and we find out that you know no matter what kind of budget you stick on there's always going to be an unexpected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> repair or something happen with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that you have to have money for and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's not enough to go in to take a loan out but uh you have to have money for
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh then we have you know whatever's left over is disposable income disposable disposable yeah discretionary income
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that we use for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the month</TIMEX> so and it's worked out very well it's uh it's helped us so that we haven't been
 		you know too long on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> and too short on the money and uh try and stick with that and nice thing about it i uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		is excellent in that we both work together we both have a budget and we stick to it and there's no surprises in that
 	
 	
 		well good
 		with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that could be hard
 	
 	
 		well actually i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		so  yeah i said a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i i guess i should have specified i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> oh my goodness it's just me and my sister
 	
 	
 		you bet you bet
 		all right
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> divorced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> had gotten through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> but i was still in high school and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> paid for a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s college while my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and then uh before the divorce she had saved for my college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh when we had the divorce she just didn't get much money out of it and had to spend it all on getting another house
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s paying for all of my college  and financial aid and scholarships i'm a music major so i have auditions coming up
 	
 	
 		well good good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes well what year are you in college
 	
 	
 		i'm a sophomore
 	
 	
 		you're a sophomore so you have a few more years
 	
 	
 		right right i'll i'll probably have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two two and a half years</TIMEX> left
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well good for you good for you yeah i imagine it uh is a little difficult to stick with a budget during uh during school and so forth
 	
 	
 		oh it sure is i i know how much my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is going to give me every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> and i and i don't spend over that
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well great great and sometimes that's a little hard with books and music and and sheet music and stuff you've got to work on too
 	
 	
 		oh sure there's there's always music books to buy
 	
 	
 		lab fees  oh yes oh yes well you're not a starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> yet are you
 	
 	
 		oh no no no i don't plan on being a starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>  that's why i'm in college
 	
 	
 		good
 		well good
 		there there's enough of those in the world huh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		good good i'm glad to hear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX> well
 	
 	
 		that's usually because they're not real educated they can't afford to  have a really good job
 	
 	
 		who's who's not very well educated
 	
 	
 		the starving ones there's enough out there that if you have if you're educated enough then you can make money
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes
 		that's true that's true i've found that out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so that's why i'm planning and and preparing for the uh education of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> also try and set that money aside
 	
 	
 		right what did you major in
 	
 	
 		i majored in business administration
 	
 	
 		well good you know plenty about planning a budget a budget
 	
 	
 		and um
 		yeah but uh once again
 		
 		
 	