
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hi</ENAMEX> so do you think you get good coverage from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> that you have
 	
 	
 		uh actually no because because i'm in school i i kind of miss out on most of the current events i just catch the major ones off the news or if someone starts to talk about it
 	
 	
 		do you watch a lot of TV to get the news then
 	
 	
 		uh i i don't watch a lot of it but that's the only basically that's my only major source of information
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		what about what about you
 	
 	
 		well i read um i get a bunch of different things i get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and i try to at at least have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> to look through that
 		and i look through uh
 		i get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> which i i pretty much read that cover to cover
 		and i as far as you know that satisfies most of the short term news i get
 		uh don't watch much TV don't have enough time
 		and uh don't listen to the radio too much especially the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> or anything like that you know they might give you a little blurbs like this happened or that happened and that's about all i ever hear of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but most of my news probably comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and for the longer term i i read
 		um
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American</ENAMEX> and and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> and some of those other types of magazines
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		that come out which they the news isn't like immediate what you'd generally think of as news but it's recent material
 	
 	
 		and it's more in depth
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's more in depth less broad well actually it's probably isn't less broad but it's just more in depth and uh
 		it's it's more significant it's more just significant information you know it's the big events not the little events
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not the fact that there was a big auto accident down at the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broad</ENAMEX> and Main you know
 	
 	
 		i know it when they're just trying to fill in
 	
 	
 		yes or they're making making time because they have to fill in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>'s worth of news
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i get kind of bored watching TV actually when i watch the news on TV because
 	
 	
 		i know i do i do too
 	
 	
 		it goes so slow and then there's nothing that you know really is like oh so exciting
 	
 	
 		yeah you may find one little
 		uh news item interesting so you have to wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> to to hear about it
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's about what it ends up being listen to the news to hear the traffic report or something
 	
 	
 		yeah actually you you mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> i i i do like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News and World Report</ENAMEX> i don't get to read it as much as i like but that's i think that's a good magazine
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they're about the same i you know they they certainly have a very similar uh charter at least in my mind
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		uh what what kind of um
 		what kind of news normally interests you i mean what do you what what do you find interesting versus what do you find boring
 	
 	
 		oh well right now i'm trying to keep abreast of uh what's going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 		you know with all the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX>'s satellites breaking off and trying to become independent and then you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> coming together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's gonna affect our uh economy quite a bit
 	
 	
 		i think it will um
 		they they keep claiming it's going to have a big influence but
 		we've yet to see it
 		it's real short term yet though i mean it's only been
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> or something like that since that happened so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah definitely
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they like to tell us that it's going to be important
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm pretty sure it is because uh
 	
 	
 		i think it is too
 	
 	
 		once once <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> becomes unified
 		and uh their economy becomes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big economy
 		we're gonna be uh
 		kind of hurting
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think that's a possibility um
 		it we might also be helped though because it it'll be easier to do business over there too
 	
 	
 		yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that already have a presence over there
 		and uh i know of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
 		specifically went over there and established a presence before nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> so that they would have it when it came time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah so they have a toehold a good toehold
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> because once you're in there then you can easily expand but getting in after nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> is more difficult
 	
 	
 		yeah because
 		when they first start off they're going to be highly protectionist
 		so
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there's already a lot of evidence that they are being very protectionist even amongst themselves they're being somewhat protectionist you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> doesn't want to do one thing and
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> doesn't want to do other thing and they're they've all got their own reasons which have to be resolved yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and some of it i mean is i'm sure within those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s minds it's quite justified
 	
 	
 		yeah i i can understand their viewpoint they're just they're starting off and their economy's a little bit weak so they want to get established before they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		before they open up their borders to everyone
 	
 	
 		compete
 		yeah totally
 	
 	
 		um what is the um do you watch anything like with sports or anything like that
 	
 	
 		actually i'm not really into sports my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX> are so unfortunately i am forced to watch quite a bit of sports
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		against your will
 	
 	
 		yeah we have to  fight over the remote control
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah at least you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have a remote control
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's sometimes better to not have one of those course you can always mislocate it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or misplace it i mean not mislocate it but misplace it and
 		
 		
 	