
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		so what do you think
 	
 	
 		um i lived i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> they have socialized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and so i saw some of the good  and also i saw some of the bad that results from such a program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh some of the some of the good obviously that nobody has to worry about health care
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it's a very it's a very uh comfortable i mean our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very comfortable in the sense that you know there's no medical emergency that's going to make you destitute for life
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um the bad was more apparent i think at least for me because i think it affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives on in a way that you could see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> thing that i noticed is it's very very convenient to be alcoholic in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		because it's treated as a disease now i don't know if that necessarily has to be part of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">socialized medicine</ENAMEX> but
 		uh if you're  if you're alcoholic then you're treated as if you're on disability long-term disability and so there was very little incentive for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get out of that
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		also um another thing that that i noticed that was very strange i was uh i would go down all these uh
 		i remember this one row of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and they were uh row <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouses</ENAMEX> all connected together so it was like lower middle-class housing well it'd be lower middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> here it's probably
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		middle-class housing there um and there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> that lived in one of these and there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that lived in one of these the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and one was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		their their incomes were about the same
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		whereas here there's a great incentive to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> because there's a great financial reward and that that didn't exist in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh overall i guess their their health care suffered a fair amount from just the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> salaries were lower and it was it was
 		less professional and it was treated more like a like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> type job then a then a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> type job
 	
 	
 		yeah i that is uh that is something i've heard i i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> uh that i worked with that was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> and that was
 		uh probably the major the major concern i have is that you know we are leading in the technology realm of
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> just because it is such a great incentive to to get into uh the medical field but at the same time
 		um it's real hard i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that provides insurance and so
 		you know i'm real you know it's like well you know you know there's got to be better ways you know to do some things but you know i hate to
 		uh the the competition in
 		in a lot of ways is is wonderful just because you can choose your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		they have to compete to be to be good and to be knowledgeable but at the same time there's a
 		you know they're regulating themselves and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> are charging just enormous amounts for products that they don't have to pay very much for
 		my i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> and for something that he can get you know wholesale and i'm sure they can get a lot cheaper because they they <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> buy in such a bulk rate um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know they could charge you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> dollars for a dollar fifty item and that's ridiculous and i don't think that is that is um abnormal in any means to be doing things like that and
 	
 	
 		you don't think it's abnormal
 	
 	
 		i don't think that is that is uh abnormal for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> to be doing that at all
 	
 	
 		oh i see you're not saying it's right you're just saying it's common
 	
 	
 		it yeah and so it it it's i think i to me i think uh something that's going to help our medical uh arena is for um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i don't know how to i don't know how to do this but i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are too lawsuit happy and i mean things will happen and and you've got to
 		uh keep up or you've got to realize that you know uh it is just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are that are making um decisions and they will make mistakes and
 		
 
 		you know if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know uh there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i'm sure make mistakes because they just
 		don't keep on top of it but there are other things that just happen that you can't you know you can't
 		say you know well if you had just done this you know things would have done differently and um
 		i don't know i i think the fact that malpractice has gone up i think has raised our prices just dramatically um
 		in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the in the last number of years</TIMEX> and i think that's something that if if they could work on
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		the cause of that and
 		
 		
 	