
 
     		
 	
 		any
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so how do you get most of your news
 	
 	
 		well  i kind of uh
 		i watch the um national news everyday for one i also read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> a day
 		and i'm a i'm pretty much a news junkie and i tune in to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		oh wow so  when you say <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> news or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> news or  national news is when
 	
 	
 		uh every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six thirty</TIMEX> i believe i watch the national news
 	
 	
 		oh okay well i would probably be a junkie or something watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> a lot but i don't uh
 		i don't uh subscribe to cable because because of the poor service and also uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because well i uh i give to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> and so i figured that amount of money i just donate to that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> as opposed to paying for cable
 	
 	
 		yeah i take away a uh a addiction  or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i
 	
 	
 		uh overall i i the quality of the news you get off off of most uh
 		sources i would say is pretty low it's usually you get pretty incomplete coverage and that's one of the reasons where i why i try and get
 		as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as possible because if you hear the same story from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> then you get a much clearer picture of of what is going on you would hope it's still you know hard to say that what you've heard is what really is
 	
 	
 		oh
 		what what uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> do you read
 	
 	
 		well i read uh the local newspaper and i also try and read one of the uh major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		uh for a while there i i i uh subscribed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
 		actually actually a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> because uh you know my fiance well she was unemployed for a while so she you know really needed to look at the
 		the want help wanted ads and so often they they try the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are trying to compete with a lot of other sources of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is okay but um i don't know when you read a lot of this stuff the the quality of the writing is definitely gone down in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years or so</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i mean they they say it's like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade reading level but i swear it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least second</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade sometimes
 	
 	
 		right
 		pretty low
 	
 	
 		but i don't know um i think if if you listen to like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> or something like
 	
 	
 		right i i really like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		that's pretty good um and i like listening to that on on uh when i get a chance when i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> a long enough time to to listen to it because i
 	
 	
 		right yeah i miss <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">NPR</ENAMEX> a lot also i really like them because they give uh instead of being as your newspaper or your
 		TV news where you get a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minute</TIMEX> blurb or a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> paragraph blurb they go really in depth on topics which i think is good and they also
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		their editorial stand point seems to be a lot better than say your major network news and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil Lehrer McNeil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> i guess he's leaving one of them is leaving
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they're they're pretty good too um
 		i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> you're probably watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> a lot right had that invasion or whatever it is
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		sure was
 	
 	
 		uh but i i don't know i guess a lot of it's still a lot of hype look at the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> trial i mean that was a joke uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that was
 		but then you also have things where you uh where they broadcast the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> hearings basically the whole length of them which i thought was really really good
 	
 	
 		oh yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> doing that yeah i know the i had uh
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> and he was just in just i don't know fixated on that you know just listened to it constantly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i guess that's good when it's live if you if you'll really want that but that's not really providing you news it's it's more like a media event rather than reporting
 	
 	
 		right
 		well but the but the news news
 		news that you would get from any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> is being generated from that event which is something that's good also about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> which i i tune into every once in a while
 	
 	
 		oh really that's kind of boring to me i think
 	
 	
 		yeah it it is really kind of boring but you know that's
 		if if you don't watch it there then you're going to hear somebody else's canned uh report somebody else's view about it and that's what you're supposed you're supposed to
 		if you watch the news you're going your opinion is going to be formed about on what somebody else thought about it as opposed to actually watching it yourself and forming your own opinion opinion which i haven't would be much more in favor of forming my own opinion as opposed to following someone else's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i guess that's true but uh one of the ways that i get information is uh everyday when i log in on the computer i subscribe to this this thing it's free inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
 		it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Intellect and</ENAMEX> and they basically uh type out abstracts which are really really literally
 		i've i've actually read the actual articles they're pretty good
 		
 		
 	