
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay uh let's see when it comes to to uh sentencing i i'm a little confused because the the only things that i read about sentencing
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> well the only things i know are the things that i read and the things that i read are are either how should i say it they're
 		they're written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that have an axe to grind so if somebody thinks that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are too lenient why i read all kinds of let's throw them all in jail and then if i i've
 		you know i've i've read other things that i i wish i could see a uh an informed
 		uh discussion as opposed to just
 		what i see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side you know some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side's mad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so i uh
 		i i guess what i'm trying to say is uh i have mixed feelings because sometimes i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> um
 		are overstepping their bounds and they shouldn't be the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> should be the only ones that uh have a say in it and other times i think well no the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> are out of hand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> need to step in
 	
 	
 		yeah uh you know the it comes down to a hard call because um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i now i'm personally have never served on a jury
 		uh i've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and so that's waived my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty and so exactly some of the procedures that they go through for the jury uh as far as sentencing goes i'm not real clear on
 		but from i understand there's sometimes whenever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> make the verdict i mean the uh the sentencing and sometimes they don't
 	
 	
 		on the case i've remember reading a a discussion about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that that uh heard a case and they and they awarded
 		uh
 		uh how should i say it they agreed that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was guilty and they and they agreed that the fine should be so much and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> came along and set aside the judgement which
 		the way the article was written was a terrible injustice
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh but like i say i uh
 		there's i rarely see uh both sides of that i just hear about it from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side i don't hear the other side the the one thing that i am kind of upset about is the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> are selected
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh to be the lowest uh how should i say this they have any opinions at all they're weeded out been one or the other of the uh of the lawyers
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and so
 		to be honest with you i've i've uh
 		i don't think that's right and if i ever am called to be a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX>
 		and they ask me if i have strong opinions i'm i'm just
 		i'm not
 	
 	
 		you'll
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you'll probably be weeded out huh
 	
 	
 		well i i i if i answer honestly if i answer honestly i'll be weeded out if i if i just like looked at him and say uh no i don't have strong opinions because i feel like you know i want to be part of the process
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh like i say it bothers me that that the
 		that the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>
 		can
 		weed anybody with a college education or anybody uh
 		oh let's say with a with any college educations you know much schooling or certain  uh uh backgrounds like for instance if you're a
 		if you've go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> once a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a a month</TIMEX> or something like that why they don't want you on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> or you know things like that it it bothers me that that that we're judging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the basis of
 		of uh what do you call it uh
 	
 	
 		on on on what they do and and
 	
 	
 		no well what i'm trying to say is the jury <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> are selected to basically be from what i've been told <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> toasts if they have any opinions if they could understand anything an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> could never be uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> for instance because he's
 		he's uh
 		he's not easily uh persuaded or or or how shall i say this this it's easy to hoodwink or it's it's hard to hoodwink him that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		persuaded
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's what i'm kind of worried about
 	
 	
 		well i think in a way it also depends on what kind of trial it is
 		um because sometimes you know if if it's dealing with with a more technical thing such as like a malpractice not not like a criminal suit you're going to have to have somebody that that can understand the uh like the medical or the legal implications
 	
 	
 		right uh that's what you want but on the other hand if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> thinks no i don't want a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in here who are going to be able to weed their way through
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		uh you know to weed the good from the bad they will absolutely go for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who uh how should i say it the scrub the scrub <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the janitors</TIMEX> i'm i'm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		trying not to be prejudiced against them but you know any any education will disqualify you in in many cases i've been
 		
 		
 	