
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it seems to me that the the benefits of working for a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> tend to be the the same things that that are to their determent
 		um they aren't as as responsive both to like bad economic times you don't have to worry about your job all of a sudden disappearing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but when you see a job when you see a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a job</TIMEX> that needs to be done sometimes you have to fill out the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> forms in triplicate in order to to get it done you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah see i work for a really small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's just me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		so it's really small and i think it's really nice because you know it's it's real easy we don't really have much to do but it's just me and him so if he needs something done i do it or
 		you know it just goes straight from me to him and we don't have to go through a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you're saying but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but sometimes it's kind of bad because if i'm sick then i kind of i usually have to go in unless i'm you know have to stay in bed because i'm the only one there yeah
 	
 	
 		there is that i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> and then i guess again i i guess like i said when i when i started off that the advantages tend to be the same things that the disadvantages i mean if i don't show up for for work there's probably somebody else that could fill my spot but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i imagine and and that's nice but uh it's would it's also nice to be able to uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		know that that you are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that that makes things get done you know if if you're not there it doesn't happen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and also also in big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> they have uh like vacations and all no if i take a vacation i've got to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> or someone else to come in for a temporary to come in for a week
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh wow oh wow
 	
 	
 		yeah so  so it's pretty nice being able to take off and have someone else take your take up your time and all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		you know one other benefit that that just occurred to me i didn't take it as much advantage of it at least not yet in  sometimes big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will pay for like education
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine uh get sent up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> for a year for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> or for like for grad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and i guess getting stuck in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> is is not such a bad thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but uh
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine works for a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockbroker</ENAMEX> and um it's a really it's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and they said that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as a after she works there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> as long as she takes business courses they'll reimburse her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's pretty nice so that she could move up in the company
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's pretty nice my job won't do that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but i would think that a a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you would have a i mean if if if a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> hits some niche in the some niche market that that it is uniquely qualified to
 		um take care of it has a chance to to grow really fast
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and if you can get on top of it before before it goes up i mean you know if all of a sudden the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> expanded to like you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you would probably be one of the top people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of course i guess if there's only the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you you'll i mean i guess you're you're one of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but you are also in the bottom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh um the only other thing i can think of is uh uh stuff for
 		things like uh like if if there's some kind of child care if if someone were married and had kids
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> might have something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be nice
 	
 	
 		and uh um  like like it's their i guess another advantage might be that uh if they if it's big a big enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and it has multiple sites
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um if you wanted to you could stay with the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and decide you wanted to live in another part of the country
 	
 	
 		yeah they moved uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> worked for i'm not even sure where but they moved us from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and then back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 		we kind of got moved around but it was pretty nice because you know we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> for a while and all
 		i mean i guess it's nice if you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that lives somewhere else and you want to be next be near them you can see it switch through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to over at that state or whatever
 	
 	
 		which i guess i being with a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you wouldn't get forced to move but do you think uh do you think it was good to to move around or not
 	
 	
 		yeah i do i mean i think it kind of helped us because you know we weren't just living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and didn't exactly know just everything about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and you know i mean i doubt seriously that
 		if we had stayed here that i would have been able to move to to get to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> very much so
 	
 	
 		oh you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and we were kind of like everybody else is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so but i guess it was pretty nice because you know we got to experience living down there somewhere different
 	
 	
 		see i'm trying to decide my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was in the military which is i guess if you figure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> would be a pretty big company
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but uh although it's getting smaller every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> um
 		and we moved like oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> we used to move like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every every three years</TIMEX> at least
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and like i don't know
 		i mean there's well there's i i've kept in touch with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> but but i don't i mean i don't really know
 		i can't i wouldn't i couldn't
 		
 		
 	