
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we just had a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> as it turns out
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		and uh the way it usually works is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> which is all my aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> uh have traditionally had this rotating schedule sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh would go to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> or my aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and they'd plan it and go somewhere exotic and invite all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and so that's kind of the framework that we've been working under
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well ours is similar to that although it does not fall on anybody in particular uh
 		of course back when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> were alive they always did it and then it seems like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> kind of let it slide so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		cousins myself and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> have started taking this up recently and we've had one oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and what we did was uh
 		since we didn't weren't sure of all the addresses and what have you that we started sending out flyers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> beforehand and uh
 	
 	
 		so a pretty big adventure there
 	
 	
 		yes you know trying to see who knew where who else lived and what have you and also gave them a little questionnaire to fill out as to what would be the most convenient time
 		we gave them a couple of choices there uh time and place whether they would like to go back to our quote old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> or
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">someplace</ENAMEX> in between  for all of us
 	
 	
 		so so how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> were you trying to round up was this just like from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> on down or we you trying to get <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 		yes just you know anybody that was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> mostly cousins second <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and what have you and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and anybody that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know wanted to we wound up going to um since i was i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> and that's what we considered our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> we wound up going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biloxi Mississippi</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we uh of course called ahead and got reservations for everyone
 		and uh
 		it turned out real well because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> then had a swimming pool and what have you and it gave us a chance
 		to get reacquainted without all the burden falling on somebody else
 	
 	
 		that sounds like a good way to do it because what happens with with our system is you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who's turns it comes and and they come every oh let's see every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years every three years</TIMEX> something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  generally finds themselves really doing a lot of organization you know they wherever they decide to go they're responsible for deciding what games that are going to be played and what food the and who's going to bring what and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they don't bring everything but just making the assignments and everything turns out to be kind of a chore
 	
 	
 		yes it i
 	
 	
 		and uh was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s shot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this last summer</TIMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> ended up doing most of the work
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh we've decided
 		all the all the my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> are pretty much grown up now we're all married we all have our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and it's kind of looking like this business of getting all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> together is just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not really working out so well
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well that could be
 	
 	
 		because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are are now have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> of their own that they'd rather get with and and so i think what's going to happen in the future is it will be from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> on down and and all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> and and those those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're we're kind of dissipating as we get bigger and bigger here
 	
 	
 		well we have a pretty small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> anyway so uh we're only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty two</TIMEX> you know with our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and so forth and like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have no cousins
 		no <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> cousins
 	
 	
 		well that's kind of sad
 	
 	
 		so it it's like i say our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s dwindling here
 	
 	
 		that's
 		yeah well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i'm one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh all of my aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> all have lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so we had lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> by the time you get all of them and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> together it's
 	
 	
 		oh i bet
 	
 	
 		it's a big undertaking
 		you know we have to find a a big substantially large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> just to get everything set up
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what we did this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> used to work for uh
 		uh kind of uh a canyon retreat for uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh since she was an employee she knew what the schedule was and knew when it'd be free signed up and and reserved and paid for the place so so we could all show up and it was nice you know there're several cabins there
 		swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and all that and it and we filled the place up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well that's that's good that's well like i say it uh
 		we  have been talking about again this well another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> and i that seem to want to do this all the time that um
 		we've been talking about getting together for another one because it has been quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> now and we'll probably go the same route that we did before because we had a good response
 	
 	
 		back
 		back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i don't know we're going give them another choice
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	