
 
     		
 	
 		right okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		i think we i think we're going to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> spending time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven nine</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so this is a big issue with us although i don't recall marking it on my little things to talk about but  perhaps they are looking for uh words to be said like day care and quality time and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anyway  you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but you're married
 	
 	
 		yeah we we been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years</TIMEX> we've been trying for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> but no luck yet  hopefully
 	
 	
 		oh
 		you know i know we're not supposed to do this long distance but actually i'm getting a call i wonder if i could possibly take it on call waiting could i ask you to hold one minute i'll be right back excuse me just a moment they're gonna get mad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> had
 		
 
 		she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven nine</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> i'm so sorry that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brownie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> telling me that there is a meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> Brownie meeting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's all right
 		okay so it keeps you busy do you have a lot of activities with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't wanna i don't want this to be a unilateral conversation but  yes we do both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i work and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth fourth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school years</TIMEX> are wonderful they're just wonderful the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they're real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they're interesting and  they they have all their own activities and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> we really enjoy them and in our own personal situation our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have not yet decided to rebel  i'm sure i'm sure that's coming though but they're wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so they're pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> huh
 		yeah
 		well we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> growing up i guess i can talk about us uh we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and one girl
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad um  yeah</ENAMEX> and the time that my we spent with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was he owned his own business so we worked with him most of the time
 	
 	
 		you had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and one girl
 	
 	
 		so that's how we spent most of the time with him yeah
 	
 	
 		are you Mormons
 		because with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and the large family
 	
 	
 		that was the dead giveaway huh
 	
 	
 		well we're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> i came from a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> the only girl
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and everyone always asked if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> got spoiled
 		i never felt spoiled in fact i always felt my toys were destroyed
 	
 	
 		which that
 		i was gonna say my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> wasn't spoiled very much
 	
 	
 		no usually busy fighting for survival
 	
 	
 		yeah that's exactly what it was
 	
 	
 		well i do think with working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> it is i mean there are some real issues here um
 	
 	
 		but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i think um
 		i don't know it's an interesting phenomena i happen to um  i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pediatrician</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i i teasingly i talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> about this a lot uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i i think working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who choose to work outside the home
 		um need very early to come to grips with any guilt that they feel and decide what's best for them and their family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i feel when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were very young i had jobs that helped me be flexible with my schedule and spend time with them and all that sort of thing and i long ago decided i'm a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> because i work outside the home i really believe that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it has um
 		helped us to afford some things for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that we couldn't otherwise that i think are wonderful particularly at this age and i think our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are real secure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and have a real sense of priorities and that they can do anything and be anything both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and female a lot so i know it sounds like a rationalization but it's
 		i really think it's true for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i think it has worked very well
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah it's like you said it's you know to each his own i mean we're planning on having my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> stay home and but
 	
 	
 		there's no question i think that's really the best if if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is happy doing that i hate to put it quite that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty nine</TIMEX> when i had my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and um i would not have
 		been real fulfilled i really would not have been totally staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> it's a wonderful it's wonderful to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i liked i like the way i did it i sort of worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half</TIMEX> time i had very flexible hours
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i nursed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> till they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a year</TIMEX> and i you can do that despite working very easily which is one of the things i preach all the time to to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		and i think we choose very very carefully the um alternative situations that we had them in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some babysitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> again i know it sounds like a rationalization but i really do think sometimes they very early on are around lots of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they  they learn to share
 		and they learn not necessarily to be the center of attention but that at the same time we have to be sure they're secure  i think that helps
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's good sounds like you're have a handle on it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah hope so so your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> does she work right now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um no not right now right  right well we just moved down here we used to live up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she's out
 	
 	
 		for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you're still trying to dry out
 	
 	
 		it's  it's no problem here  yeah we really liked it up there but then when
 		
 		
 	