
 
     		
 	
 		live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and capital punishment is illegal in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's just coincidental that that's the way it is but my feelings happen to be that i'm against capital punishment uh and
 		i feel that it's barbaric actually it seems out of date with civilization as
 	
 	
 		really even if the the crime is extremely extremely serious
 	
 	
 		i think so because i think what we're talking about is is uh life making and life taking decisions and i i don't think any
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> has the right to take away the life of any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> not that it's a a religious feeling or anything like that
 		but it seems hypocritical to me that we'd say in the case of murder for instance that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because you took away somebody else's life and because that is so very wrong we are going to take away your life i don't see that that makes any sense really
 	
 	
 		well it's not necessarily someone has the right but we do have the responsibility to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>
 		so if some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> just <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">blatantly</ENAMEX> slaughtered painfully killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> people
 		does he really have the right to  continue living and be a burden on society
 	
 	
 		i don't think it's a matter of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>'s rights i think it's a matter of our uh
 		penal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s rights and i don't think they have the right to take away a life no i think definitely there should be uh severe punishment uh to deter other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from
 		doing such heinous crimes uh for instance i think life imprisonment should be necessary for anybody who commits any murder of any sort
 		and i also think that uh other things that are currently not legal in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should be made legal such as putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> to work and making them earn their their pay
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree with that part yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		but i think life imprisonment is a much better alternative
 		to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that perform crimes i think also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are prone to commit a murder are not going to be deterred by the thought of being put to death i think that if they're
 		uh the sort of mentality that they could do such a thing that it doesn't matter what threat you pose to them that that wouldn't change things as far as what they were capable of doing so i don't see it as much of a deterrent either
 	
 	
 		well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> would see it as a life in jail doesn't particularly sound too harsh to someone who's been living on the street you know for all his life and then
 		uh jail jail time would seem like uh you know a break or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a paid
 		paid sustenance for the rest of his life
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think that's unfortunate that is probably the way it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and i think that ought to be changed uh
 		i think like i said i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ought to be made to pay for their stay and not make it pleasant for them i think hard labor should be required even among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are are are not able
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		make it make it harsh as possible
 	
 	
 		to perform hard labor you know if they if they died naturally from working then i guess that would be okay because that wouldn't be uh putting anybody to death forcibly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i i can't see i can't see executing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it just seems so barbarous barbaric in these times
 	
 	
 		uh well i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i'm not really up on it i
 		i think we don't have capital punishment either
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i i thought there was but i could be wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what amazes me is how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> speak out in favor of capital punishment even here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really want to see it uh be put into effect it seems more so than those of us who feel the way i feel uh uh at least are vocal
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		saying that no they want things to stay the way they are lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to see capital punishment made legal
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay um
 		i guess uh i guess we did what we have to do and i don't see any instructions as far as doing anything else so i uh it's nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		okay
 		you too you too bye bye
 	
 	
 		okay take care bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	