
 
     		
 	
 		a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh that's one of my favorite kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> how long have you had it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		is it really
 		we've had him for let's see he just had his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> birthday
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> birthday
 	
 	
 		yeah and we got him when he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight weeks</TIMEX> old
 		and uh
 		he's pretty okay we like him
 	
 	
 		does he shed a lot
 	
 	
 		he does that's the one thing we don't like about him in fact we threaten him in the summertime that we might just shave all of his hair off
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he'd probably look pretty funny if we did that
 	
 	
 		how much does he weigh now
 	
 	
 		he actually he just went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to get his shots and everything and they put him on the scale and he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to ninety four</NUMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but he's not a real he's not a real tall uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever</ENAMEX> he's kind of stocky shorter and stockier
 	
 	
 		hm
 		is he good with family
 	
 	
 		he is it's uh just me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and uh he's kind of our temporary substitute for having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i guess we treat him like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> right now so he's spoiled rotten
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i can understand that
 	
 	
 		because i you can get away with that a little bit more with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> than you can with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  how about you
 	
 	
 		um-hum well we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> who's also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years old</TIMEX> and  he's our spoiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> right now too  and he also sheds a lot
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but we uh we hope to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever</ENAMEX> someday but we figure we'll get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and then the the dog
 	
 	
 		that's probably a good idea they're good though uh have you ever had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retriever</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		no but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when he was growing up
 	
 	
 		because i i find that they're good around other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> they don't tend to get real jealous or territorial they like to play
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and especially with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they love to play with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		is is your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> an inside and outdoor
 	
 	
 		no he's pretty much an inside dog
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		he stays in we we're kind of in a not a real busy neighborhood but more so than i'd want him to be out too much and he doesn't like it if we tie him outside he's he's really a wimp
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and when it comes to being alone uh now if you give him the freedom to walk around and go wherever he wants he likes that but he does not like to be tied outside he'll he'll just bark and bark and bark
 	
 	
 		huh when he gets outside does in does he run away and then eventually come back or
 	
 	
 		no he's uh taken to the training pretty well and uh he knows where our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> is and we have a pretty small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> but he seems to know the boundaries
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and he usually is good about staying within them although our next door <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> too and uh she she is good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with my dog
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and so he often gets
 		to smelling her scent and will go over there to sniff around and stuff but he's pretty good he stays out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and uh if i catch him i call him and he comes back
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so he he's pretty good about taking to commands and things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> did you bring him to a doggy obedience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or just train him on your own and
 	
 	
 		no we never did
 		i i trained him on my own and uh this is the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> i've had all my own as an adult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or we've had dogs when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> but this this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one that i uh took in so i wasn't sure if i'd be able to get it all right the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 		but uh he he seems to have picked it up pretty well i never really had to hit him or anything just you know firm tone of voice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		amazing
 	
 	
 		and those sorts of things i i see other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there and they hit their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and try to and and those horrible collars that they put on them with invincible invisible fencing least i think it
 	
 	
 		invisible what
 	
 	
 		invisible fencing have you heard of that
 	
 	
 		no what is that
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's a system you can put in your yard where you bury these little uh transducers or emitters in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> at the perimeter and then they wear a collar with a special little attachment on it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and if they get too close to that perimeter it it zaps them yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		huh
 		boy i'd be afraid to walk around if i was that dog
 	
 	
 		yeah well a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine at work here said that he tried it with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and he wanted to see what he was subjecting his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> to so he held on to the collar and he walked out to the perimeter he said it was a good jolt
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah so i i don't take too well to to those sorts of training techniques i don't think they're always necessary if you put enough patience into uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah just be consistent and diligent with it and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it's uh is your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat an indoor cat</ENAMEX> or an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">outdoor cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah he's indoor and all declawed because i know the uh average life span of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">outdoor cat</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		somebody just told me that because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that and also just um getting hit i guess or getting beat up  and the average life span of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">indoor cat</ENAMEX> is eighteen years
 	
 	
 		wow quite a difference what uh what kind of climate do you have
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 		well um  it's we just moved recently  so now we're in the um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area and it's very very nice and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		
 		
 	