
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you want to start or should i start
 	
 	
 		uh yeah you go ahead
 	
 	
 		okay let's see uh i think that uh i i think that trials by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> are a good idea i just think the concept of multiple attempts
 		uh at trial is when uh with when they're always saying oh well uh uh i want to appeal i want to appeal i want to appeal i
 		i think multiple appeal is what our real problem is it's not the not the the twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> jury trials uh
 		think that that i i would not be totally adverse to the concept of of uh
 		of uh i guess uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> trials either uh i think our our we have a real big problem with litigation we we spend too much of our time litigation in our legal system and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's it's just incredibly incredibly complex uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i i don't have any problem with the idea of having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> although it is a bit disappointing to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> manipulate the process by
 		uh raising so many objections to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> so that they can try and get for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> um a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> slanted one way
 		or the other i mean you can sit there and dismiss <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for for trivial reasons and and that takes up a good deal of time too um the the thing i find sort of disappointing about uh a lot of this is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		often a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> uh and and you hope you get one that's that's really rational and and looks at uh each case separately you'd like to be able to give them some flexibility to be able to sentence
 		uh if it's a really awful crime to really put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> away for a long time uh or if there's a lot of intent there and it's obvious put them away on the other hand
 		you know maybe to to change the sentencing slightly uh
 		that you'd like be able to see them give a different kind of punishment uh not necessary community service that's getting a little bit overworked but but but rather some of other sort of of restitution rather than simply putting them away behind bars
 	
 	
 		um-hum uh trial well one thing is we do not have a trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> anymore uh that's that that is gone gone gone out gone out the door for one thing
 		the very first thing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> attempts to do is get an ignorant jury
 		as part of in fact as part of the process they're not supposed to know anything whatsoever about the trial
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so particular so particularly for famous trials what that indicates is that the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are really at that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> are idiots
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have been on the moon
 	
 	
 		right only ignorant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that means low IQ generally  wherein that's not that's not trial by jury
 		now i guess that's that that's become less so i've noted that um uh the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple</NUMEX> times that i've had to go by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> they've actually selected intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>
 		now i i i'm not so sure that would be true if it were a trial of uh of uh some notorious notoriety notoriety notoriety
 		uh but in the case of the normal trials it's much much harder than it used to be to than to get out of it so they do try not to let uh excuses get you out of uh trials now
 	
 	
 		oh yes my my
 	
 	
 		you can delay it but you can't get out
 	
 	
 		oh that's that and and that's actually pretty good my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> recently uh uh had jury duty uh down in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> would not hear any excuses i mean from anybody
 		uh he didn't care if they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s appointments or anything he said you're you're here in the pool and you're going to serve but when it came time for and and it turned out it was a rape trial
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> well uh how do you feel about this and she told him quite frankly that she thought that the punishment should be extremely severe for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> began to ask um what does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> do for a living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> he's retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> ah was he retired law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
 		they they dismissed her on the grounds that they didn't want her that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> could have been seen as being in law enforcement even though he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX>  in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they wanted to stay away from anybody that might even have a smidgen of law enforcement so even though she was there to do her duty to serve
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she was dismissed on the grounds that she might possibly remotely have some prejudice and that's
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s fairly well read she didn't actually know about this local case it was of rather small import uh but i would agree with you that that not necessarily does somebody have to be ignorant not to know but they'd have to have met
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	