
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello Larry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sounds like you've got this uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		sounds like you're ready to take a stab at it so why don't you go ahead
 	
 	
 		okay well i you know i think that uh i think it's fine to do that but i don't think it should be mandatory i'm not
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm not for having the equivalent of a draft
 	
 	
 		yeah i happen to uh this will be a real short one cause i happen to agree with you uh  i think in principal it is a very very good thing but when you make it mandatory uh now you're talking about slavery
 	
 	
 		that's right it's uh
 	
 	
 		it comes down to um
 		the uh it's kind of fun because i had picked the same topic uh last time i dialed in and uh you know which i didn't know it would do um
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		you know one of the uh things they're trying to think of is ways
 		you could create or maybe create is wrong but advocate a societal imperative that would have the same goal how could you make it uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		more desired and respected in society for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to voluntarily uh engage in public service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i'd say as far as government jobs uh they could uh have some incentive for instance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> get a preference when they're applying for a government job and i'd say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		had voluntarily served in such a thing as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> or or something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		could also get that
 	
 	
 		yeah the uh what do you call it um
 		not sure how you would do that outside of a government sector though and uh
 	
 	
 		i don't know either
 		and i'm not sure we'd want it
 	
 	
 		you know i i kind of hope against reality sadly that uh that government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> will get smaller with time but every indication is that it won't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i feel the same way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i think that uh i have nothing against the draft when you know when when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> needs it
 		uh but obviously when you don't need it you don't have a draft and i feel the same thing with universal service if there was a need for it
 		then i'd say uh possibly i mean but it would to be an emergency type thing and i and i don't see that ever happening uh
 	
 	
 		you know my uh my interpretation of history is is is that uh
 		when there's a real need there's usually no shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> you know you look at what happened uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> with the earthquake there were plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> volunteering you know you look at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> Two there were plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		uh you look at from the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> all of a sudden there weren't a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know the question of when do you quote need unquoted on a say for example a draft uh maybe it should be the other way around maybe
 		the willingness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to volunteer should be determining whether you need it or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah cause uh you know if all you got to do is uh print up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few million</NUMEX> draft cards to start a war you know  you it may be a powerful incentive you know what do you call it um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer</ENAMEX> may be a powerful incentive for keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of uh you know keep keeping us out of may make it a little more difficult to get into war you know there are times you need to
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't perceive myself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> by any means
 		but um
 		you know there are probably there are places we've been over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that perhaps we shouldn't have
 		ah i don't think every time we uh wandered into some place it was honest just in itself i think we've screwed up a few times just like everybody else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		i think about on on public service too i think it has some
 		some thought has to be given to what do we want these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do in public service and and that would have a bearing on what training should they have because if you wanted to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know as an incentive you can have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go in after high school
 	
 	
 		indeed
 		um
 	
 	
 		and then offer them assistance with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and that way you'd be getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really didn't have any expertise in any particular but uh any particular field but they'd be willing hands so so to speak on public service projects
 	
 	
 		um well you know i i will say i given a choice between somebody with expertise and no interest in working
 		and someone who is enthusiastic but lacks the skill i'll take the enthusiasm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> cause you can train that person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but somebody that's got no incentive i i'm not really sure what you can do
 	
 	
 		are you familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civilian Conservation Corps</ENAMEX> back in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no that was before my time
 	
 	
 		okay well i mean it's before my time too but i i read about it but you know in the height of the depression the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> employed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go work on public service projects
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		was it like uh WPA
 	
 	
 		that's right like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WPA</ENAMEX> it was the same thing and there were many uh a lot of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> were built up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civilian Conservation Corps</ENAMEX> and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WPA</ENAMEX> projects are still
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		serving the the nation
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh something you know uh unskilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could could do things like that as long as they had a positive attitude
 	
 	
 		hm yeah my only concern about projects like that you know there  my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is uh
 		you've got this resource whether it's uh
 		unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> what have you you've got this resource and what is the best way to target where you're going to point it uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i don't know the answer to that i'm not automatically
 		
 		
 	