
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		alright what do you think
 	
 	
 		well uh i think air pollution is a pretty big problem right now and it's i mean i think it's a real bad problem i don't think that a lot is really being done about it at this point
 		and there's just things like uh for a i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> especially here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are just a major source of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> when you consider that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobile</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drive around all the time
 		and i think you know if you just totaled up i don't know any of the exact figures but all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that are driving around spewing out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon monoxide</ENAMEX> all the time i think you're going to end up with a pretty big uh number
 		
  
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and if you look at other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world and stuff where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ride <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> and all that i'm sure that their uh
 		air quality is much better than ours just as a result of their lack of having <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> like if you look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> i mean they've they said that the major reason that it's so smoggy there is because they all sit and drive down the freeway everyday
 	
 	
 		hum okay well um i i mean also along the same lines i know that there's somebody i i read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time about um somebody's developed uh a test to look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from um your car
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know you know i i just don't understand i mean everybody's so concerned right now about recycling and everything i think that's pulled away from the focus of air pollution
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we're making all these changes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and everything and and and battling to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> built <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> versus other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and we're not looking at  um the air quality that we're producing from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		right and there was just i just saw <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> they were had new a new regulation out that was going to put a canister to collect some of the exhaust fumes on most new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and he uh
 		is not going to let that regulation pass through because he says that well it's going to cost too much money and take too many jobs away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
 		and i just think that's ridiculous that i mean if they've developed the technology to remove some of the harmful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> that come out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s exhaust pipe and not implementing it is just seems kind of ludicrous to me
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i hadn't heard anything about that
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you know until these older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model cars</ENAMEX> i mean granted i have an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model car</ENAMEX>  but i mean some of the some of the really older ones that you know the mufflers falling off you know and they're not quiet up to specs but they're still being driven around
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and you can i mean i'd go behind somebody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and you mean you saw this this huge amount of smoke pouring out the back of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and you had to change lanes to get away from them
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i mean if you can see it and smell it that badly on that vehicle think about how many others are pouring out that you can't see and smell
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		right exactly uh the another thing i don't know here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> at least we produce most of our energy burning coal
 		and if you just look at some of these there's a coal burning electricity <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and you can just sit there and watch the the smoke stacks and the amount of pollution that just pours out of there
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		i use to live right next to this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX> you would go out and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> would just have you know it's not like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three inches</NUMEX> of dust or anything but you can see the dust that had come out of this smoke stack and just fallen right down on your car
 		and you know they say that the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> we burn here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> is responsible for a large part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> that they have up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and all that
 		and it's just you know it's ridiculous when we could be spending the money to develop the technology to you know clean up some these uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of pollution like the smoke stacks but then the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> say well we can't do it because it's going to cost us too much money and it's like well we kind of got to think a little bit more forward instead of
 		you know we're not going to make as much money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because we're trying to clean things up i just it kind of
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's
 	
 	
 		bothers me
 	
 	
 		well i know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um i'm i i live pretty close to downtown to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and you know and there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> you just you open the door and just go huh i'm not leaving here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and i mean there's uh there's a place that used to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Concrete City</ENAMEX> and they have all these things where they used to burn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um</ENAMEX> and and what they would burn off would be lead
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now you know i mean here they've been spewing this stuff out for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> or more and they're just now beginning to figure out that you know that what they've done is is wrong
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and now we're trying to clean that up but you know we've seen the visible effects in the soil but it makes me wonder what kind of effects that it's had on the atmosphere that we don't know yet
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and so many of these things takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> to develop that we've never you know it'll be past my life time before i see the effects of some of the things that we're doing now
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right
 		
  
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah all and all i think that we really i mean almost if you look at almost any industry it's it's producing so much pollution i mean they're spewing out just tons of this atmospheric garbage every single year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and something really ought to be done because it it's basically we don't see the problem right now and like you said even the pollution that we're putting out now is not really going to affect anybody for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty years</TIMEX> so i don't think it's got i mean the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the past</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		
 		
 	