
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so uh what are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camping</ENAMEX> experiences like
 	
 	
 		lately they haven't been much but as a child i used to
 		go camping a lot with my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> we would uh we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX> then and we'd go out and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we camped like in tents not in uh  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile home</ENAMEX> or the
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you roughed it
 	
 	
 		right  that's what i consider really camping
 	
 	
 		basically
 		yeah i the only really camping experiences uh i've had i guess was probably with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cub Scouts</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> when uh i was younger uh we used i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we went to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there's a lake called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Lanier</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> that we went to and we camped out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and we kind of
 	
 	
 		got familiar with that lake
 	
 	
 		yeah we setup we set up all our you know we we canoed out to some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and uh that was a lot of fun set up because we were all we were isolated from everyone else but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's pretty much
 		i haven't been  lately i have i've i've wanted to lately but there's a i'd like to i need to get some equipment <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and i don't really have the money for it now i've i've been looking into like buying uh
 		uh a tent of some sort but they're really expensive like the good ones
 	
 	
 		they are uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so that's kind of put a cramp in my camping style so late lately i've just kind of for outdoorsy type stuff i've pretty much been you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> trips where i'll i'll maybe drive up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> somewhere like in a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northern Alabama</ENAMEX> i'm into rock climbing a little bit so so if one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX> has some ropes ropes and stuff and sometimes we go up there and
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat
 	
 	
 		climb around on the rocks and stuff but usually it's a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> affair it's not a overnighter type thing but i'd like to i'd like to really get into that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah well lately about my only halfway experience with camping is we uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> races <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in fact we come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten days every year</TIMEX> and and that's part of my camping experience is we camp out there a little bit sleep in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> or  what have you for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few nights</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> out of it and what have you but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the last the last true camping experience i had is when uh
 		i drove across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine he lives he goes to school out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and we drove his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> out there and uh we drove you know we took kind of a scenic route we went through uh
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh sounds nice
 	
 	
 		and uh someone one of us had a tent but not all of us had sleeping bags and it was kind of a it was late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> but it get it got it got really cold at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> a lot colder than we thought it would so the sleeping bag was just big enough to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was just small enough so that it didn't actually cover everyone so it was kind of uh a wrestling match for the  for uh
 		you know warmth so we we we we roughed it until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about four in the morning</TIMEX> and we were all just freezing so we got up and
 		got in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and uh drove on we were on a kind of a schedule tight schedule anyway so we couldn't stay too long but we drove on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that morning</TIMEX> to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> so  i think that was probably my last uh
 		true camping experience
 	
 	
 		yeah well well whenever i mention camping anymore to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he says i'm too old for this  he says i i like my luxuries anymore but i think i'd still like to you know do a little camping that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like i say i it brings back memories of my real young <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he said he'd lived on a farm too long and that was too much like camping anyway true camping
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of year</TIMEX>  it's gets really beautiful down the springtime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> with all the dogwoods and
 	
 	
 		i bet
 	
 	
 		there's all kinds of
 		it's real north there's really some real beautiful spots to to hike and stuff in north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> you know up in the kind of getting up the mountainous
 		you know the the
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i know when the leaves change there too would be a pretty time except you can't really depend on your weather
 	
 	
 		yeah it sure is
 		that's true like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's it's pouring it it takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> around here i mean it's beautiful when they uh when they change it it seems like it happens so fast that if you don't get there at the right time you're gonna miss everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> we came up there the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> were changing and since then we've been coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> or so too early  but uh i would think that that would be a really nice place for camping
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they're getting
 		they're getting started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this year</TIMEX> i'll tell you that much the so the dogwoods are already starting to bloom
 	
 	
 		
  
 		have they oh well that is really nice
 		well i'm sure there are a lot of camping places around here but we get so wrapped up in everyday life we don't get take time to
 		go out and enjoy them um
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> when the bluebonnets
 		are pretty here i think that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our biggest</TIMEX> deal there's just fields of bluebonnets and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that'd be nice
 	
 	
 		what we call <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> paint brushes it's it's really nice
 	
 	
 		i haven't been through that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so i don't really know what i don't really know what it's like over there
 	
 	
 		mostly nothing
 		
 		
 	