
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well the health care
 		several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> i think in particular i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> wanted to do national health care we're we're in  we're in a disaster we need we need some
 		sort of health care that's available to everybody and the prices just seem to be really escalating the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> is is so exuberant
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just can't afford it and insurance is is so expensive
 	
 	
 		well uh even even for older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> does not cover enough of what they need
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and social security as far as helping them in their retirement is not going to be adequate by the time we're
 		ready for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor doctor</ENAMEX> visits medicine hospitalization
 		if they increase at the rate they are now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's not going to be anybody that can afford it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well you know i just
 		i don't have
 		i'm an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> but i'm going i went back to school and like i'm just finishing up but so my finances are kind of shaky at times and i can't afford dental insurance
 		and
 		i had to have to have a tooth extracted and i had to pay cash for it
 		and i asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> how come you know the price is so high i said i said i i thought because you know the prices of medication you know like it costs them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ten cents</NUMEX> to to make a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> and they charge you two dollars and
 		he said one of the reasons is the litigation for um claims against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> so they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have got their their fingers fingers in the pie too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that's it's sort of like trickling down for the overall cost
 		and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 		have
 		um
 		
 
 		might say a production line and just like i i said well how much is it going to cost he goes well it'll cost you
 		um seventy dollars he no he says it'll cost you seventy dollars and then i require an x-ray okay
 		and so it'll cost you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and two</NUMEX> dollars well
 		i knew which tooth it was and he knew it was too and all i needed was extract it but he wanted he wanted to make the money so they're they're they're taught that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should have certain services whether regardless of whether they need them or not
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		and they're making it
 		almost impossible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go and get well routine care shall we say insurance now won't cover uh wellness visits
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children baby</ENAMEX> visits your insurance won't cover that anymore
 	
 	
 		but
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i thought well does it pay for you to be a fit well individual when your insurance doesn't even cover things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the thing is just like dental hospitalization and dental it's unbelievable
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i haven't
 	
 	
 		you can go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and you'll pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i haven't been in the the job market for
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years</TIMEX> i mean i i've worked and things but i haven't really had you might say a full-time job health coverage and things like that but i've uh done you know i've done readings and and things
 		and in fact i was watching on the TV
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is that if you work for a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> just say maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and you have they're insured and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are sure are insured under what's called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> plan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well if one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in that group
 		happened to have a chronic illness where it it you need they need care all the time like say they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that that needed uh a lung machine and a respirator and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> to come in and things like this
 		well what they would do is they would just cancel everybody's insurance and say we're not going to cover you and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are out uh health insurance
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		our our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> medical plan has increased <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX> uh i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward D Jones</ENAMEX> stockbrokerage
 	
 	
 		where do you work
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> is just a little bit more of course our you our cost um aren't hardly anything compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have to go out and get their own because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> plan but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		it is the costs have increased every year
 	
 	
 		then plus the coverages they they decrease so you they don't want you to see the the the deductibles increase too
 	
 	
 		um-hum exactly
 		we did start a plan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> there's an insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Life</ENAMEX> that has started a flexible plan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and with that they will take out pre tax dollars
 		and build it up and it will cover things that your regular insurance won't eyeglasses uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> visits
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> wellness care prescriptions that are not covered through your insurance and that's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i have seen any
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		effort effort at all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to make a change in the
 		
 		
 	