
 
     		
 	
 		so do you work for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> who uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		gives you health benefits
 	
 	
 		yeah we get um i have i have good health benefits actually
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i have uh all of them and they're it's pretty cheap per month and they
 		i get to pick my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and they have really good benefits
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh um
 		do you have any any interesting benefits aside from basic health coverage
 	
 	
 		uh besides basic uh no i have um some
 		a little bit of uh life
 		insurance benefits
 	
 	
 		um
 		do uh do you get any kind of dental or optical coverage
 	
 	
 		uh no <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX>
 		uh no optical the dental is fully covered um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		except unless it's major
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but anything minor or just checkups that's all covered
 	
 	
 		and uh is your whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> covered or do
 	
 	
 		no that's just me but they can be i have that option but it's more money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they're not they have their own
 	
 	
 		i see so through your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		oh no me i'm single it's just through me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		it's it's uh so it's and it that makes it cheaper too since i'm single
 	
 	
 		okay do but do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		oh okay so that's real simple yeah here uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's just for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and if you want to cover your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> you pay a little extra but not much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		not much not for the good but it's really good the benefits are good
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah i think it's pretty significant benefit uh really uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		makes you wanna stick around
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they have they uh it does
 	
 	
 		yeah that's just what you wanna hear about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are individually insured you know once you get sick you can be booted right out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh which seems kind of unfair
 		uh
 	
 	
 		do do you work where you have benefits like that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we have we can choose uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> different plans they made they try to make it real flexible where if you don't use much you actually get cash back
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		um so you can choose all these different plans some of which pay you know like everything and some of which pay very little uh you can also choose an HMO
 		uh well i used to have that when i was single and i was i found it very convenient uh and we have some optical and dental coverage that's i guess it's optional but i think we can get one pair of glasses a year
 	
 	
 		yeah the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		really well that's good
 	
 	
 		that's so yeah it's pretty good actually uh i think a anything under a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> we can get one pair of glasses a year
 		but if you want something really fancy you pay the difference
 	
 	
 		uh-huh see that's see i wear glasses not all the time but when i read and stuff and um i wish we had some kind of optical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		coverage but there's
 	
 	
 		yeah it's nice
 	
 	
 		there's none whatsoever and it can get expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah it can uh at least it's not like medical where it can really go through the roof you know at least somewhat limited um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		let's see you have any kind of uh
 		child care benefits or
 	
 	
 		um yeah for the um actually if you're i believe i i read up on some of it if you're pregnant
 	
 	
 		anything in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they have really really good coverage they have um like well baby care it's it's pretty much covered
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's a problem sometimes i understand when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s not sick but you know you have these periodic appointments and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		especially when they're younger
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> end up having to come up with some ailment to cover the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the appointment even though there's not really one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah some seems more honest
 	
 	
 		and though and the
 		pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has
 		uh full coverage for well mother care
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well that's good that's good and do is there any kind of interesting uh what i mean what happens after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s born is there some uh some maternity leave policy
 	
 	
 		um that's what i was trying to i think there is i don't really remember how long it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they do give you a certain amount of time to be home and get adjusted i guess
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and um
 		most of the benefits are pretty good the hospital benefits and and they let you pick your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> you have your choice actually if um it's better they give you a list
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if and if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s on that list then most of your benefits are better because those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> that works with the insurance company
 	
 	
 		i see so they they're preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> or is that a
 	
 	
 		yeah but you can have your own doctor
 	
 	
 		right and you pay a little more or certain things aren't as well covered but at least you have that option
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		that's nice because once in a while you find someone who deals specifically with
 		you know what you have or or somebody just somebody you've dealt with already a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and and a lot of times because we just switched my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> just switched insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and before
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we did not have that choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	