
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		from the from the scale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i i lean more towards no restriction
 		we by the constitution we have the the right to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and
 		i believe our freedoms are being constantly eroded all the time and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> just signed a law that that banned
 		a lot of automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and and such where they wouldn't do any more damage than
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winchester</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> or things like that what do you think about that
 	
 	
 		well i pretty much agree with you uh i wouldn't say that i'm a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> because i do think that there are some types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that
 		should be restricted because of their extreme potential to uh  uh to produce collateral damage if you know what i mean
 		i don't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should have nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> or or biological weapons but i'm probably uh on a scale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i'm a i'm a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
 		in that i think that any any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> that can easily be carried by hand
 		should certainly be uh protected for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to own and uh to use uh in particular i'll express my opinion on this uh this there's there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that think that
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> amendment is you know only a collective right that it applies to the militia i don't believe that i think it it applies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> also uh i don't think that the our founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> had anything in mind anything to do with hunting or even defense against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> or
 		or target shooting what they had in mind was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to be armed in order to protect themselves from the government becoming too strong and taking away our liberties
 	
 	
 		well that's a that's a that's a good point also we have to we have to be cognizant cognizant that our society's becoming more and more haves and have nots
 		and the main the main purpose say for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> is to keep the have nots from taking from the haves and that is the purposes of of the gun control
 	
 	
 		well the thing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> is that they're only good to pick up the pieces after the crime has happened we have to to take precautions to defend ourselves
 		uh if someone comes after you with a gun there's no way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are going to stop them uh even if have an opportunity to call the police uh because someone has threatened you
 		they won't come out and protect you all they can do is investigate a crime after it's been committed it's very rare that they prevent one
 		so it's important that we each as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> have the means to protect ourselves and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> that means having guns
 	
 	
 		oh i i i agree i my point was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> want to get rid rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and what's happening is that i see i i i view this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as as as we have
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peoples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> and cultures and things that are be oppressed that are oppressed and so that to
 		to take the way the those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> so they can protect themselves is that's what the means and that's what they're trying to do and by enacting all this legislation
 	
 	
 		i i agree with you i think that uh  although to to a large degree what the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are doing is just responding or reflecting
 		what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> seems to be telling them the problem is of course is that the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have no idea what the right to keep and bear arms means or what it's for
 		and all they see is rampant crime in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and they think that banning <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> is going to stop that but that's that's simply not the case uh
 		you take away the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> uh from law-abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh i mean it it seems like a trite phrase but
 		if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are outlawed only outlaws will have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> they're not going to stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> from from getting uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> of any sort and what they really need to do is attack the root causes of of crime
 	
 	
 		that's true yeah
 		well you know i another perspective is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i'll just for not lack of a better word i'll say they're spoiled
 		they haven't been except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> have come to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they're not cognizant of war and and chaos and terrorism like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have been invaded
 		and if our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> needs if our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s invaded we need the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to rise i mean the the military and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> isn't going to do it all for us and if and if we don't have the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">goverment</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	