
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh have you ever thought about joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh for not for any longer than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about ten seconds</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah was that was pretty much my thought too
 	
 	
 		no i have no  i have no real desire to do that
 	
 	
 		i i've i've i've actually i've talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh have have joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> and uh
 		the idea of like you know spending spending like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> is you know teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how to like you know
 		plow a straight furrow is just not my idea of something i want to do with my life
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i don't doesn't appeal to me either
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where i work uh there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who actually joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> he worked here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> and then he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		what did he say about it
 	
 	
 		well he hasn't come back yet
 	
 	
 		oh you mean he he i he did this just recently
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah he went just recently
 	
 	
 		i you know i i thought that joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> was something that everybody did like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> you know in
 	
 	
 		well there's yeah but there's actually been a resurgence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting into it i guess part partly for economic times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't know any other reason but lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are been getting back into it i think
 	
 	
 		i yeah i i i talked to i was talking to somebody uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and they they said i think they went they were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> and they ended up going to like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> or something and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they ended up in this place where they hadn't seen a white face in like you know seventy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they had to go on the it's like they had typical it it's the typical <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world story you know they they had to every every once a week they had to get on the bus and then like drive up into and
 		take drive up into the mountains and stop at each village you know and and have like give lectures on like public health and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's like don't piss in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>  that that type of stuff  and uh he said that they would get on the bus
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would come up and like touch him because you know they had never seen somebody that light you know a gringo and that it was it was pretty it was really pretty strange
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i it was it would seem to me like if joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> is like you know going to another signing up to go to another planet you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i don't i'm not sure i mean i guess the motivation is partly you want to help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but i think
 		it's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> join it just to go to another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and kind of for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> of it i guess
 	
 	
 		i would really be afraid of i i don't know when i i went to school i i uh
 		i took a course in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parasitology</ENAMEX> and stuff like that i would really be afraid of like you know of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> and stuff that i could catch and like and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> it it seems like a hell of a way to lose weight
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh yeah
 		yeah seems a little rough for that
 	
 	
 		you know  oh i don't know
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i don't know i kind of you know i don't mind going to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> you know traveling and seeing the sights but i don't want to  have to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i
 	
 	
 		no the maybe they they'll they'll fly you over there and back for free but doesn't seem worth it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no it it doesn't seem like the kind of job that i i'd really be interested i'm really interested in either
 	
 	
 		what type of work do you do now
 	
 	
 		oh i'm a i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		okay for who do you work for you work for
 	
 	
 		uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really i didn't know they had an office up there
 	
 	
 		yeah uh we uh they have a we work for some uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockheed Sanders</ENAMEX> we we don't build the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> per se we work on the uh like the avionics yeah we work we put the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> avionics
 		okay yeah i've heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanders Corporation</ENAMEX> were they bought out by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and all of that okay
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they they were bought out by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and it's a they were they were involved like in in radars and thing and uh and things like that
 	
 	
 		right that's that's kind of the work that i do so that's why i've heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> i work for i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> who do you work for
 		oh okay uh-huh
 	
 	
 		in research
 	
 	
 		yeah we it it's it's not bad it's not bad work although i'll tell you it's like
 		uh i being in the defense industry is not is not really the thing to to be in right now
 	
 	
 		right that's right
 	
 	
 		it it's sort of like being in steel like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah you're just kind of biding your time
 	
 	
 		right you you know that uh  i was just talking to somebody about this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> is that uh i
 		i haven't seen a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a new hire uh somebody you know just fresh out of college brought into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in like a year and a half
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what's happening is that you know we're just like kind of getting grayer and grayer and grayer you know the the there's no growth here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it we're essentially the same although some some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> are hiring if if they can find new technology uh you know or make an efforts to get into the commercial markets
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're kind of getting smaller through attrition but there in some cases we're hiring also
 	
 	
 		yeah  this the this attrition thing though i that that that's like death itself in my mind
 		
 		
 	