
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well
 		lets see i i guess i'll i'll mention it i always one of the things i always considered was real important about job benefits i always uh i know they can't do anything about it but i always thought location and quality of life in the region was important towards
 		a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a job</TIMEX> benefit at least it had a lot to do with what i chose is
 		in in my job and and and besides uh you know uh i guess uh uh salary and uh the work
 		but see those are the things that they can't really do much about
 	
 	
 		that's true unless it's a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that has a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> uh it was important for me to pick a job uh to choose a job that
 		was in the northeast uh because i like the region and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is here
 		at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point i'd interviewed for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that wanted to send me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boise Idaho</ENAMEX> and that really seemed like a negative benefit to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah the uh  i was uh
 		i actually was from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">midwest</ENAMEX> but i uh i always liked the uh concept of going to a warmer client climate uh so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i generally leaned towards the sun belt
 		uh i've worked in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> and i've worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> so you can see that i've moved
 		moved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> south since then  uh i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> when i when i was going to school
 		and uh it's still it it becomes a very strong benefit i uh i interviewed with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 		and uh just the the amount of time that it shuts down that that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> shuts you down for activity
 		always used to bother me because i really never got into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> sports
 		but i like to be very much into the active intramural sports that was important to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh other job benefited uh job job benefits uh uh i like the idea of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> being flexible
 		uh uh with uh time schedules as much as possible i mean i you can't do too much and i understand that
 	
 	
 		i agree with that uh i found though that
 		that uh it it will benefit both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that does have a very flexible schedule
 		and i can't remember the last time that i just worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty hours</TIMEX> a week
 		so the uh it it works out that if i have to go in late for a reason or i have to leave early for a reason
 		no one raises an eyebrow but because of that i'm not a clock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX>  if i if i knew they were expecting me there
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight thirty every day</TIMEX> and i couldn't leave until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five</TIMEX> i i think i'd be uh
 		uh have a greater tendency to wait until the clock hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and then say i'm out of here
 	
 	
 		you're out of there yeah  you then you then you punch in a clock and all you are is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hourly</TIMEX> as needed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and then you say well you know why should i give them anymore
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but what they uh if they respect you as a professional you treat them like a professional at that i i i take it then that you are also a professional
 		a salaried employee
 	
 	
 		yeah that's correct that's correct
 	
 	
 		uh it
 		usually they end up getting a lot more hours than i i i uh than the classic <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty hours</TIMEX> a week sometimes i hate to think about it if i would actually add up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i figure if i were getting time and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> what i was really making <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per hour</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oops  but uh well let's see what other i i've always liked i've always liked some vacation i i've i've been fortunate i actually had a
 	
 	
 		
 
 		another
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i just just transferred jobs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> ago
 		so but uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX> i was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		now that was a real nice benefit it gave me a lot of flexibility
 		uh but of course now i've gone to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> amount of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so now i'm back to the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to the uh original <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>  that was a tough benefit to give up
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i'm working for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> starts everyone out at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that is a good benefit
 	
 	
 		and i i thought that was great except during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> i ended up only being able to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> of it
 	
 	
 		right because of the amount of amount of work that you had to be done
 	
 	
 		right i was i was so busy uh
 		and it we've got a very small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and i was just uh wearing so many hats that it was very difficult for me to take time off and when i
 		did take the time off i'd uh get calls from work anyway
 		so it's only been uh in the
 		
 		
 	