
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so um i pretty much read the paper
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		yeah read i catch the news sometimes uh but we're so busy usually i just grab the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we we and we get the really local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> here so can find out what the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s doing and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh i don't watch i don't watch any TV really um and i i don't subscribe to the paper but a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who i work with do and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i i like grab the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> like to see how my stock is doing and things like that because i don't always call my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but actually now that i think of it the thing the place where i get most of my information is i have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour commute in the morning</TIMEX> and in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so we listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> a lot and we hear we listen to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Morning Edition in the morning</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fresh Air and All Things Considered</ENAMEX> in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh and even if we're not listening to the feature stories we certainly tune in at the top of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX> because you got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six minutes</TIMEX> of good news and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i guess i get most of mine um just from word of mouth just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> chatting at work and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah i i'd like to get you know things little straight a little more from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>'s mouth although i dislike the way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for instance distorting the the campaigns like oh big surprise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> won in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know this must mean he's the frontrunner now why because you know all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> votes on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 		but you know i i find especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> is fairly unbiased you know i use to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> a lot when i got cable
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because uh they also seem to not lean one way or the other in their reporting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh our local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> you know where you we have you know you've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> which is extreme in one way and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> which like supports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them you know it's not a lot of and then you've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Phoenix Weekly</ENAMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine hundred</NUMEX> ads in the back you know but other than that there just isn't a lot of you know unbiased local print reporting
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the the constitution</ENAMEX> is is pretty bad too and and they it it just seems like they spend a lot too much time on trivialities and things you know they they emphasize the wrong things especially in the campaign
 	
 	
 		yeah and and i i don't even bother with local news because it's it's like you know um i'm a pilot so i'm aware of how how they misrepresent you know it's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> would do a gears up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landing</ENAMEX> and it'd be there was a crash landing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and our camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> was there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know they they or and then of course on sweeps it's how you can get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> from eating common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> but we're not going to tell you during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> spot you know tune in for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty seven</NUMEX> part report over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 		i really think that um
 		you know you have to go to some uh place like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> that doesn't have a vested interest in you know they don't really care about you know getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to watch their shows because they're funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do want to hear this kind of news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the other nice thing about my local uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> is they also got monitor radio and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		through yeah they do  this this is basically our all news AM station 10A
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so what you get is you get uh they they've kind of picked up so you get like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> AM they give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> then you've got  uh you've got <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Morning Edition</ENAMEX> from like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> till <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> then they pick up again with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> you get uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>'s talk show and then you've got uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fresh Air</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> All Things Considered till <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> then you get Market Place then they give you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what
 	
 	
 		so it's really you know for they they've got a bunch of classical music in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> but other than that it's just straight news reporting from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> different sources
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		and you know it's kind of neat to see how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> reports things differently you know they they've got a much different view like reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i find that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> has a much more global view than like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> or one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> ones
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		but you know because you know i find that um a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> uh electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is so uh ethnocentric
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where
 		you know they they they don't realize for instance that there's a recession happening in the rest of the world too it's not not just us lucky people
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 		so you know that's pretty much where i get my information from uh and you know i'll i'll glance through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> to get the local news there and i'll glance through the uh like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Milford Cabinet</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Telegraph</ENAMEX> to get the really local news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> gives you like regional news uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like my fiance is telling me the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> sucks uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and then you get like uh you know the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> is giving you like how your high school football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> did and what's being voted on and you know we got our picture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> because we went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> board meeting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so you know that that's the kind of level of stuff you get there so you get a real diversity of coverage
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	