
 
     		
 	
 		so you don't oh uh random drug testing is kind of tough because it it involves this kind of uh trading off of of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> civil rights for some kind of concept of uh furthering a common good almost
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know there there's a there's a there's a trade off of our civil rights
 		against i guess our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s right to to having a good job or something
 	
 	
 		uh i don't don't really see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> as having a whole lot to do with it i've already it the um privilege of being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of random drug testing i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> and had to pee in a bottle on command
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was really a really aggravating and time wasting thing to do um the thing that i really hated most about it was the total waste behind it all they would get maybe
 		between fifty and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred and fifty</NUMEX> of us together and it would
 		you know we'd lose the whole morning what is that that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">man hours</TIMEX> uh to go go through this and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> they would just be shooting for trying to catch a few specific people it really aggravated me
 		i wasn't happy with it at all in fact after i got out i made the decision that i would not work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that did that um it just doesn't seem right that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would do something like that i can appreciate
 		um concern over somebody being under the influence while they're at work but they could easily be under the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or any number of other things as well
 	
 	
 		yeah uh well that's that's a good point the only uh the only thing i really disagree with is and and this isn't this isn't exactly disagreement with
 		i'm not sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing is strictly aimed to catch people
 		but i would think that it also acts as a deterrent if someone if someone knows that there's a threat that that they might get caught it might be that much more of an impetus to to stay away from from whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is they're they're on
 	
 	
 		now that's implying that um as a punitive kind of a thing as well you definitely want to discourage that is that kind of what you're saying
 	
 	
 		well i mean i would think that uh if someone knows that there's there's an even greater chance that they're they're going to get caught um having <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that
 		that that that would act to discourage them that it would um you know if you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s in the other room perhaps you're going to be less likely to steal the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> out of the cookie jar because he might be coming in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any minute</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well i guess that's a good policy then if uh you're definitely for eradicating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> from society i'm not so certain that that's a a worthwhile goal right now
 		it looks like there's a lot of problems with um you know keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> illegal things that are really scary a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are dying and there's a lot of bloodshed and that that disturbs me i live downtown and uh man
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right diagonal across from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teakwood Homes</ENAMEX> it's the oldest housing project in the country <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> opened it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> there's shootings in there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> and if it wasn't for the uh
 		you know the the high profit margin i don't think it would be going on i don't think that uh we'd have the crime over there that we do and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> it really spills over into the neighborhood here as well there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> nasty bloody
 		violent crime per year um over here where one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> is a victim
 	
 	
 		well the the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes Scholar</ENAMEX> and i i forget his name but one thing that he suggested doing was
 		taking the money taking all the money that he gets for uh uh fighting the war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and use it for like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> education to to open up the methadone programs to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that that wanna be off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in thinking that that it's we're not doing a good job at fighting the war you know in in trying to crack down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> maybe legalizing them and and trying to help those that you know having the resources there to help someone
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> would be a better idea but and and i agreed with him somewhat i could see his point but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> opened up a um uh a park
 	
 	
 		is that the park yeah
 	
 	
 		and and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> it just kept getting worse more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kept coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and it just kept getting worse and worse and worse until finally the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> have they decided to close it down
 	
 	
 		yeah i just saw that in the news here recently
 	
 	
 		so uh i don't know it mean it sounds like it sounds like there aren't going to that there isn't a perfect solution
 	
 	
 		yeah it really is a dirty mess very difficult to come to conclusions
 		i guess one uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other data point is the old um prohibition here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> the consequences of that and it's ultimate uh repealment
 	
 	
 		that's a good point that's a good point and although although alcohol consumption did jump right after prohibition it did come back down
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and it's funny how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in movies and all we really glorify those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> and that lifestyle it's kind of spooky
 	
 	
 		yes we do we do
 	
 	
 		i guess i guess even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s movies a lot
 		
 		
 	