
 
     		
 	
 		ever um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah okay so we're started i guess i'll press press <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there
 		uh i'm surprised it's not telling us that that uh
 		we're going but at any rate um had do you have such a program uh where you work
 	
 	
 		okay
 		no i don't and uh
 		i can't say that i'm unhappy that we don't uh or happy you know either way i guess not being not being involved in it
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well i'll tell you the truth when it uh when it was introduced to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> it was a lot of hard feeling now my initial reaction was
 		benign i uh really didn't feel as a matter of fact i was sort of sympathetic in the sense that uh
 		uh you know we we want to stamp out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um drug</ENAMEX> use
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and uh the it's certainly no good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who are on drugs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		and i don't really consider it uh an invasion of privacy uh in the sense because uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use is
 		uh a dangerous influence on other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in society
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um there was i was in with a group of fuzzy heads however who um
 		were rabidly opposed to it and i i gradually became
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		proselytized uh by this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and the to me the big sensitive thing is well there there're couple things one is the is the insult of it
 		perhaps as a um
 		preemployment test is one thing but to come in post facto and say to
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who are tried and proven uh that they've been asked to do they're gonna have to submit to drug test is sort of a slap in the face
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah you know i might i might see a case as well where it might be warranted in um
 		someone who obviously had a problem with it um someone who had um well i won't say behavioral problems but uh
 		you know noticeable signs or you know got caught on the job you know uh in that case if they really wanted to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> it's sort of an enforced uh
 		enforced clean period um but you know
 	
 	
 		and of course there're problems with doing that you realize because
 		uh this requires a very strong minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and uh uh a supervisory it requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> to be brass balled in in a sense
 		to go to a an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> who appears to possibly be under the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and say  you've got to take a drug test
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'd
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as opposed to just randomly requiring it of everyone
 	
 	
 		that's true that that sort of singling singling a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> out i guess i could see that side it of it as well well you can see i really haven't given it a whole lot of thought i'm i work for a privately held uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems integrator</ENAMEX> and uh
 		we are family oriented as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and uh we we don't have uh
 		any any problems that uh anyone knows about if you know what i mean there may be problems but no one is aware of them so it it's sort of a an invisible thing for us um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		there's no real requirement for it um  i did work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> where i had to take a psyche profile once but uh that's another story
 	
 	
 		was that on a need on a need basis or
 	
 	
 		no all uh uh um everybody had to take one
 	
 	
 		oh i see all right
 	
 	
 		but uh  thank you very much that's uh that's another that's another matter entirely but yeah i guess uh i guess i would say now now that now that uh you've presented that case i would have to say that
 		uh random if if it were gonna be done random would be the only way to do it otherwise you're unfairly singling someone out
 	
 	
 		uh right um i guess the other objection that i was exposed to at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> was the um
 		unproductive unproductive nature of it that basically uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is not a problem at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and the corporation i think are going through this exercise mainly to remain in the good graces of their customer the government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh rather than to improve their productivity by stamping out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use because the the likelihood of finding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is very very low
 	
 	
 		oh sure you have to be sharp
 	
 	
 		and um and so
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saw it as actually sort of a passing on of the the testing uh requirement from the government
 		
 		
 	