
 
     		
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what's our topic
 	
 	
 		taxes do we pay too much
 	
 	
 		taxes
 		right um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well do we
 	
 	
 		what do you do
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i guess that i mean it all depends really on what kind of bracket you're in
 	
 	
 		my tax bracket is is pretty high up there i pay the i generally pay the maximum tax bracket and uh i think that we're paying too much because i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i pay a lot on property taxes
 	
 	
 		um sure
 	
 	
 		i don't have any um i don't you know i don't use an awful lot of city services it it you know  it's like i have to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i have to work all the time just to make enough money to pay the taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um you there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wanted a dib of the federal money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or the state money or whatever it is and i just sometimes many times i end up feeling like i'm paying too much in taxes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		how about you do you pay too much
 	
 	
 		uh well no i can't really complain i'm a student um and i  i work as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech Research Institute</ENAMEX> and uh
 		i'm gonna get back most of what i earned i mean most of what i pay in taxes and uh
 		and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> is still claiming me hm
 	
 	
 		well when you
 		when you go out into the uh
 		when you go out into the working world it it it changes quickly um you look at your paycheck and you go oh my gosh where did it all go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i'm sure
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um what kind of what kind of uh
 		well have you paid a lot of in taxes have you been out working and then gone back to school or are you did you go directly from high school into into college
 	
 	
 		i went uh well i did work um
 		just various jobs for some time but i i didn't make enough money to really
 		make too much of a difference right
 	
 	
 		to worry about it
 		have you have you been active in in politics trying to
 		concerning this have you like worked on a political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		no no i haven't
 	
 	
 		i uh i haven't done any of that type of work myself um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but every once in a while when i hear up here at at um in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> area um one of the radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> has been talking about the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has added too towards a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> Bank there you know there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that they all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> with and i guess it went defunct recently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressmen</ENAMEX> has has written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years almost about a thousand bad</TIMEX> checks
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and we we the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> float him a loan for all those all those bad checks no interest no repayment schedule
 	
 	
 		really
 		really
 	
 	
 		and um it's causing quite a stir up here because we're so close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> anyway it's really kind of curious to watch this thing occur
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		um i i i think we pay too much and i've i look at my paycheck and i make
 		well let's see they take out in state and federal taxes i think i pay
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty two</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty two cents</NUMEX> out of every dollar i make goes to
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and then they charge me sales tax and they charge me gasoline taxes and they charge me all these others and it's just too expensive i can't believe that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		taxes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i'm just thankful that i don't get all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that i pay for
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you have you used um student loans and things like that that were guaranteed by the government
 	
 	
 		no no i haven't uh i uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> pays for my my schooling my tuition
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		so uh i'm i haven't made use of that
 	
 	
 		what are you studying down there
 	
 	
 		physics
 	
 	
 		physics ooh that sounds like a fun fun field
 	
 	
 		everybody says that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		scientific  heavy science are you like in the particle particle research or
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anything like that or is it more um applied physics
 	
 	
 		um i haven't i haven't gotten too terribly much into my major yet actually um
 		the the degree i'm getting is physics there's a different one for applied physics so i guess you could call it more straight stuff
 	
 	
 		okay well maybe maybe you can figure out how we can stop this inertia that's  rolling towards whatever it's rolling toward
 	
 	
 		than applied
 		
 
 		i doubt about that are are is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> i mean are we pretty
 		pretty steep compared to most countries
 	
 	
 		actually i don't think we are
 	
 	
 		nah i don't think so either
 	
 	
 		um like like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know the taxes are a lot higher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they do have socialized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um i know that i was reading in the paper i believe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that um
 		they're talking or maybe it was on the radio
 		
 		
 	