
 
     		
 	
 		let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>'s pretty easy actually uh i just got done reading a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> or a couple magazine articles about the uh new Saturns
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and although i can't afford it right now i would just like love to have one
 	
 	
 		oh really you like uh so you're an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 		you want to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		no regardless of that fact it's the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> for the best cheapest amount of money
 		i'm interested in having it for uh doing a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> cross racing uh closed circuit racing and uh it seems to just blow the competition competition competition away
 	
 	
 		um
 		in terms of handling uh acceleration
 	
 	
 		handling power everything yeah it just got like the top rating it was compared up against uh
 		let's see
 		there was like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M X three</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX>'s whatever their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N X</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX>
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic S I</ENAMEX>
 		and it just you know it it dominated over all of them everybody all the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">raters</ENAMEX> loved it i like the i like the styling and i seen a few of them actually race and they seem to be really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for it
 	
 	
 		what about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mustang</ENAMEX> GTs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mustang</ENAMEX> GTs uh can't afford it
 	
 	
 		those so you're talking about ones in a lower lower end price price range
 	
 	
 		right yeah i'm a graduate student
 		let's face it i don't make any money so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well you can wait till you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and you'll have plenty of money you can buy whatever you want
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah we'll see then
 		yeah right now i'm stuck i i've got a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sunbird</ENAMEX> Turbo
 		that it's fast but unreliable and trying to get it prepared for racing but it's it would be nice just like scrap it and go for the go <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right would you use that for city driving and racing
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i'd do it i'd use it for both the nice thing about auto crossing is you can you can do both
 	
 	
 		auto crossing is what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> is that
 	
 	
 		uh just like a um
 		um
 		set up a lot of times and it's like really large uh parking lots
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and you put up set up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> pylons okay
 	
 	
 		and pylons and things
 		tight turns hard acceleration i've seen a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mustangs</ENAMEX> uh compete
 		and
 		it's interesting they get dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corvettes</ENAMEX> that are also in their class
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah i would guess so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh what are you thinking about buying
 	
 	
 		uh i think i'd like to get uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> or if i go the German route which i'm kind of leaning towards right now but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or maybe a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> i mean a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">a Acura Legend</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legend</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh S C <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> maybe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something on that order i haven't really determined if i like the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> or the if i like them enough to purchase one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMWs</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> have good reputations i think
 	
 	
 		yeah well i was i was actually in uh a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>'s are produced in uh  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stuttgart</ENAMEX> and uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> and i was i was there this uh summer
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i i was really impressed by the uh the uh factory uh tours and such for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the
 		yeah they their they have the whole philosophy i mean they they kind of even brainwash themselves into thinking they're better
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		which is kind of hard to take
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		i mean as you're walking through that little tour in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> it's kind of  they're trying to brainwash you too
 	
 	
 		oh of course of course they are they want you to buy their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> yeah there it was it was interesting i was at i i also went to uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX> and uh it was it was amazing how they were completely opposed
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah the uh
 		yeah the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> is really oh like oh we have all these like high tech things and everything is put together with exacting tolerances and
 		and then you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX> and it's like well uh these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are completely handmade and no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them are alike
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		and so it's like completely opposed i don't know which do i like better i think i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX>'s philosophy a little bit better although it's not really practical
 	
 	
 		no it's not realistic
 	
 	
 		unless it's it's a toy
 	
 	
 		yeah if you can afford that kind of a toy then i guess so
 	
 	
 		let's face it
 		yeah yeah but it it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>'s good for that what kind of driving just like commuting you'd want to do it use it for
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah just work short trips no mileage no heavy mileage i'm putting on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than fifteen thousand miles</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		wow yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's pretty minimal
 	
 	
 		that's cool
 	
 	
 		lasts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> that's mainly what i'm looking for
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good i also i was impressed by uh
 		by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i really i really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> was nice and
 	
 	
 		but
 		but if if you have a problem with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> you take it into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> they're going to they're going to hit you up for just all kinds of things
 	
 	
 		and is it different for the for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think well something on the order of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> series it's probably different once you get up in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> series and higher then
 	
 	
 		probably
 	
 	
 		all your repair costs go up significantly
 	
 	
 		right  i  can imagine that
 	
 	
 		so i'm kind yeah i'm not sure if i really want
 		
 		
 	