
 
     		
 	
 		what what were you saying
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay i i think we're started now
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh do you wanna go ahead and start
 	
 	
 		um well i haven't really been up to date on a lot music i have been in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and i haven't really gone out and  bought any or listened to much on the on the radio except for classical and
 	
 	
 		well you like classical music
 	
 	
 		uh yes
 	
 	
 		uh i like classical music i like rock and roll i like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i i like all kinds i like i like different things about each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well i like most of them except for country
 	
 	
 		oh you don't like country
 	
 	
 		music no i think i i might like dancing to it but i don't like listening to it
 	
 	
 		the the kind of country i like is kind of the older country music not the not the kind like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny Rogers</ENAMEX> and stuff like that that's uh
 	
 	
 		which
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that's a little bit to uh it it's like they're trying to make it too much of a crossover thing you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what what's the old country music like
 	
 	
 		oh like like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX> like the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX> even even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams Junior</ENAMEX> is real good stuff the kind that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		this stuff makes you cry it sounds so sad  i mean you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		that's the kind you like you mean
 	
 	
 		yeah sometimes sometimes i do i mean not all the time
 	
 	
 		oh oh okay well i guess i i like the blues a lot and i guess you could say it's similar as far as
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes and i
 	
 	
 		the kind of  the way they do it
 	
 	
 		i i do too i also like jazz
 	
 	
 		yeah me too too so i guess i like except heavy metal and uh
 		most rap i don't like
 	
 	
 		yeah you're you're about like i am then uh i i can't watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> anymore i used to love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and i can i can barely watch anymore because uh they have this heavy metal stuff on there and and i can't even  you know i can't like that and and i liked uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aerosmith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Led Zeppelin</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you know and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jeez</ENAMEX> who else is that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Halen</ENAMEX> now i like i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like that but when you get uh
 	
 	
 		okay yeah
 	
 	
 		i i even like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Guns and Roses</ENAMEX> some of their stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> now like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slaughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i have i really haven't listened to that
 	
 	
 		some of them are just really rough so so you went to school then in i'm surprised you didn't go to to any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties parties</ENAMEX> or anything where they were playing a lot of music or stuff or
 	
 	
 		well um i used to a long time ago but since i've started back into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> now i haven't really done that much i've been pretty busy
 		um but um
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so no i haven't i you know i used to go out and dance a lot but i don't do that anymore either so
 	
 	
 		oh i see are you married at all
 	
 	
 		no  i've just been real busy with with lots of other things
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		well how old are you
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay so you you were out of school you went to school for awhile then quit then went back
 	
 	
 		well no i i went to school and got a degree and then i worked for awhile and then i just started i started back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half ago</TIMEX> changed direction
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah how old are you
 	
 	
 		i'm uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty eight</TIMEX>  i was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty three  so</TIMEX> i guess we're the same age then huh
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		all right
 		yeah and uh i didn't really start getting into music until i went to college because uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't really have music in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> put it that way
 	
 	
 		oh really were they religious
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		ah i see i
 	
 	
 		so i'm always behind i'm i'm not i'm never really up to date on all that stuff but i know what i like when it's uh when i like a sound a certain kind of sound yeah
 	
 	
 		see my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were very musical my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had a piano in the in the house
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> likes uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> western music
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		he's from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> so that's what he grew up listening to and he's always liked it and and you know he's probably about fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX> now so he grew up like in the late fifties and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you know when they had that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> music and stuff like that and the and that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> and roll so he likes that and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> always liked that kind of stuff my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> likes like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Day</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		um
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		you know she always had those these old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Day</ENAMEX> records and stuff like that though so you know i i grew up listening to that stuff but uh
 	
 	
 		oh row
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i could see why you went uh you know i could see why you were kind of sheltered i guess from from music
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i do play the piano you know  but um  i i like the um early seventies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late sixties</TIMEX> rock
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		kind of stuff the old stuff
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah so do i do do you like uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Van Halen</ENAMEX> or anything like that or how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan Adams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan</ENAMEX> what kind of music is does what songs does he play
 	
 	
 		it it it this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Cuts Like a Knife</ENAMEX> uh Summer of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">69</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think i've heard Summer of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">69</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he sings that he's he's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay i'm not i am not very good at remembering the uh titles yeah but i can  remember the the song yeah
 	
 	
 		titles and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> yeah
 		well do do you watch music television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> at all or VH1
 	
 	
 		no no i don't watch TV much at all
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah do do you get cable
 	
 	
 		so
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh okay that's that's you have to get c able to get those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> anyhow
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah i like to watch rock and roll videos and any kind of videos i like watching that kind of thing it's
 	
 	
 		um-hum do you like um
 		like someone recent like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enya</ENAMEX> have you ever head of her she's not rock but
 	
 	
 		no i haven't heard her
 	
 	
 		she she's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and uh she's gotten some uh she's been on like the top
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i guess or whatever
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		she she did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orinoco Flow</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	