
 
     		
 	
 		so um are you working right now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh yes i am i'm working in the computer science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> here uh at CMU
 	
 	
 		uh
 		what kind of what kind of work do you do
 	
 	
 		uh i'm doing basically system system design work and uh implementation work for the speech
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the speech group uh here
 	
 	
 		ah
 		what is that how you heard about this thing
 	
 	
 		yeah actually through electronic mail
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh-huh me too i work at uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech Research Institute</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> so i work and go to school <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about halftime</TIMEX>
 		and uh i really don't have any job benefits to speak of we're kind of
 		um
 		i don't know they just kind of forget us on that end we don't really have any vacation or
 		you know sick <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> or health care or anything really so
 	
 	
 		right so your pretty they're they've got you slaving away at at this point  yeah well um
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly what about you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> so what they they have uh
 		um okay benefits package it's not quite as good as industry but one of the significant um
 		benefits here is that you can take uh up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> um
 		and they pay for you know pay for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> so for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Mellon</ENAMEX> that works out to be um a reasonable a reasonable benefit
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah
 		uh they do that i think if you're uh research title <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> here then i know of some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have gotten their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> and i think that
 		um they might you know pay for that pay for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> and stuff but i know they let you they'll let you decrease how many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> you work by any kind of percentage you know they'll let you work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">halftime</TIMEX> if you want to if you wanna finish you wanna
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		if you wanted to do it quickly
 	
 	
 		yeah if they'll let you work decrease your number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> by any percentage just just about so if if you wanna get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> and then i think of course you get like a with your extra degrees you get a pay raise due so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that'll probably help out but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so i
 		i don't know in in terms of other things
 		other benefits other than sort of monetary i'd
 		you know i
 	
 	
 		do you get any kind of health care type stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah we we do we have to contribute a certain amount
 		uh to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's kind of split between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMU</ENAMEX> and
 		and you know the employee
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think i mean that's pretty important that's a pretty important uh
 		part of it there because that that can be really expensive if you ever have any health problems my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> i think my i'm still covered on
 		with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s uh health plan at his where he works but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it definitely be something to look into i guess once i get my own
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and it's also right now it's uh
 		the like everywhere else uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> the health care
 		uh rates are are going up pretty quickly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a whole nother topic
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		to begin with too but
 		yeah but it's you're right i i i really agree that that that's pretty important
 	
 	
 		the only i think the i guess the only real um benefit i guess you could say working for me working here besides i mean
 		i'm learning and stuff because i'm at you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		there's there's some weird law where um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> working for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> don't have to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		oh now that's a big win
 	
 	
 		though
 		that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> percent right there so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh that's
 	
 	
 		that's about the only real bonus
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i have so i have to take that into consideration when i evaluate like how much i get paid relative you know because if i was working somewhere else i'd have to
 		you know pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an extra five percent</NUMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		yeah i figured for  and they've just raised the
 		um income caps on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> to the point where you have to be pretty you have to be pretty well off before you stop paying
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		paying that as well yeah well if you could call it a benefit that CMU
 		i mean the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other</NUMEX> thing
 		that they allow you to do here while you are working is is consult for um you know other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um so that's
 		that kind of helps out in terms of you know keeping up-to-date with  contacts in industry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i imagine that'd help a lot
 	
 	
 		you know in case you know in case you ever need to  bail out
 	
 	
 		yeah see around around here it's like uh we pretty much work from project to project on well you know with different sponsors
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a there's not there's not a whole lot of you know funded research from
 		
 		
 	