
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toby</ENAMEX> have you ever served on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in a criminal trial
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i've always wanted to and uh but they never uh my name never seems to come up
 	
 	
 		well i'm not sure whether you're the lucky one or i am  because i have done it and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what did you think of the process
 	
 	
 		well we had a hung <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> so i i came away really disappointed in the process or the least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved i was very frustrated about that
 	
 	
 		how hung was it i mean what was the vote
 	
 	
 		i i think it was something like oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three ten</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which really means that if if we hadn't of had to have unanimous decision
 		we would uh
 		would have completed our mission  if you will
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but it's
 		i don't know i i've always thought that the fact the the fact that it has to be unanimous means that there wasn't any doubt in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s minds
 		and if it uh if in like in your case if there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who weren't convinced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> was guilty
 		then or innocent i you didn't say which way it went
 	
 	
 		i think it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> people
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no it's the funny
 	
 	
 		it can go either way if there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that aren't convinced one way or the other then that's
 		um you know i don't i think one one change that might be worthwhile would be to say that you need unanimous verdict to find somebody guilty
 		but but if you don't get a unanimous guilty verdict then they're innocent
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX> didn't prove their case to all twelve people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well the the crazy thing about this trial was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> said yes i did this i did this armed robbery but he wanted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to decide his sentence
 		and we couldn't even agree on a sentence
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i i mean i was ready to put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy guy</ENAMEX> away forever but i was dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who said well if it were my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> i'd want him to have another chance
 		i know
 	
 	
 		that's ridiculous
 		um here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> the only time that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> gets involved in sentencing at all is in capital punishment cases
 	
 	
 		oh is that right otherwise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> does it
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> does all sentencing for everything except capital cases here
 	
 	
 		do you think that's appropriate or should it be changed
 	
 	
 		i think it is appropriate i think that the judge
 		probably has a much better uh feel for uh what sentences other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have committed comparable punishment crimes have received and what the guidelines are and uh
 		i i think that by the time you get to that point all the facts have been settled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s been convicted and the punishment should be
 		well a fairly objective uh thing uh i don't know if there really needs to be all that much discretion in sentencing once you've determined what crime the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is guilty of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well and i do not know if it is this way it all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> or not but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> there are severe limitations on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> can know know about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the prior</TIMEX> history of the alleged criminal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and also what they can be told about the effects of sentencing Like if you give somebody fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they'll be out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> or something like that
 		i maybe it's not quite that radical but but those things are not those are things are kept from the jury
 	
 	
 		yeah here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> when they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> involved in sentencing like in a capital case the prosecution is not allowed to say that if you if you give them life he'll be out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> that's against the rules
 	
 	
 		yeah why
 	
 	
 		uh but in with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> making all the other sentences
 		uh course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has open to him all of the previous criminal history uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and uh obviously the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> knows what all the guidelines uh or what all the effects can be of parole and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um well i think the
 		the the reform of the jury process that i would like most to see
 		is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> to be required to be informed of their right to judge not only the facts of the case but also the law itself
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> and lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not aware of this but it is
 		it's part of the common law and it they really is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> it is part of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX> and it is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that if the jury
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> believes that the law that someone is being tried on is unjust the law itself is unjust the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> can refuse to convict the person
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and this is sort of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s uh last line of defense against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		
 		
 	