
 
     		
 	
 		personally
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		prefer sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i like to uh to drive kind of fast i guess but i'm finding that as i get older
 		i'm thinking that it would also be nice to have kind of a a nicer bigger maybe more luxurious luxurious <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to have in addition to the one i already have
 	
 	
 		um-hum what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you have right now
 	
 	
 		it's a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Daytona</ENAMEX> it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby</ENAMEX> Z they only made them for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> it's really just a variation on the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daytonas</ENAMEX> that they have out but i'm real happy with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's uh an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> and it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> turbo charge car i ever owned and i was a little little reluctant about that because i heard things about
 		uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that owned turbo charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that the turbo would break quite often be very expensive to fix but i haven't had any problems with it
 	
 	
 		yeah i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> has have a has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">turbo</ENAMEX> charged uh engine on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and he's had some some problems with that
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but um he put the turbo on himself and uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		there was some problems right from the start with that
 	
 	
 		uh-huh how old is uh how old is the truck
 	
 	
 		well i think it's probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about an eighty seven</NUMEX> also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		excuse me but i guess my tastes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> are just a little bit different um um i've been more into just kind of a family car small
 		uh not real big car uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but lately we've been uh trying to get something that's a little bit more reliable so we've been going with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> vehicles lately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm more into pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> lately i i got myself uh myself a pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i'm more interested in the the off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that kind of thing hauling things around
 	
 	
 		oh sure yeah we just recently bought a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and we ended up getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wrangler</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's funny though because it's this is actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s car the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> and uh
 		but it's fun having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheel drive capability and a rugged suspension like that to go out and do things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we're still finding that when we end up driving other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> places that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it would be nice to have something where something roomier where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't have to duck their heads or scrunch their knees up and
 		something that would ride a little more smoothly especially when when you travel
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		which we do a a fair bit of traveling
 	
 	
 		yeah i know we do a lot of that yeah on the road traveling and we we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camry</ENAMEX> for that kind of traveling
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that's a little bit more comfortable it's it's not real fancy but it's a lot more comfortable than a lot of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> we've had prior to that
 	
 	
 		yeah sure
 		it's uh
 		i don't know when you're when you're used to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing i guess something different always seems like it would be fun to have or nice to have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		are you pretty satisfied with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> as far as repair and reliability on it
 	
 	
 		yeah we haven't had it for very long we got it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> right around uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> i guess it was and so it doesn't have a whole lot of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> on it yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester New York</ENAMEX> it's nice to have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheel drive capability especially on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> where we have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about six inches</NUMEX> of snow coming down out there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we just got that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah i was a little uh surprised to find i i'm not the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's going to go out and shop for exclusively for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> built <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but i am the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that feels good knowing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> they like the best is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		made and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> built but i was reading in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that uh
 		surprisingly enough a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that you think are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> aren't always and in fact they listed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wrangler</ENAMEX> as being almost exclusively made in either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> or Canada
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which isn't that far away but i it surprised me i always thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> was about as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> as you could get as far as manufacturing goes at least
 	
 	
 		well it kind of goes the other way with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> that we've had because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> we have now was built in i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and the uh
 		before that we had a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen Jetta</ENAMEX> which was made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so but you wouldn't think that just off the top of your head you'd think they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> made
 	
 	
 		no yeah
 		yeah i guess you never know in fact they had a whole system uh decoding the vehicle identification number
 		so you could figure out even right down to where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> was which state the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> was in where it built
 	
 	
 		yeah i read that in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		found that interesting
 	
 	
 		but
 		
  
 		it was interesting
 	
 	
 		we used to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX> when we were first married and i i swore i'd never get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> again because we had so many problems with it it was just a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a never ending uh stay at the the repair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> it just
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh no
 		oh really what sorts of problems did you have with it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well the carburetion never really worked quite right and there
 		
 		
 	