
 
     		
 	
 		how do you get your current events are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">po couch potato</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well actually no uh it's it's multifaceted for me since i'm married to a news junkie
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		uh yeah we we get the you know about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> a day plus there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different newscasts that we watch and of course if there's nothing else um
 		worth doing or watching on television we'll watch either headline news or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> itself and uh plus i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a an electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and i get a lot of news that way so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's really pretty hard to not be informed
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well i start out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> listening to the radio on my you know as i'm getting ready for work
 		and in the evenings and and i'm in a vacuum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> except what news i get electronically we have uh electronic news at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the lunch table discussion usually brings up a few things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and i haven't had time to read
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh some more radio on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and
 		it's usually too late to watch the news by the time i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but i can uh read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> then the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> news of course
 	
 	
 		um-hum and of course everything's changed by that time and
 	
 	
 		and
 		oh of course of course and then uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the ten o'clock</TIMEX> news at bedtime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's about it i don't have cable TV now i used to do like you did and the default was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i could just i'd have that thing going for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they really have some fascinating stuff especially on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> uh
 		we kind of uh we kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> i don't know if you've ever seen it but it's a it's a cable well you don't have cable cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and it's sort of like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> on cable television
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		so they go into all sorts of neat little off the wall kind of topics that you normally wouldn't get
 		in uh in uh  in a conventional news broadcast or even on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> it's sort of like socketed little special interest kinds of things and it's really fascinating to see you know they're out there covering it
 		um one thing i wanted to ask you about was the you're you said you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> the quality of your local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> do you do you see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pandering</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well the the most noticeable thing about our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> is that we now have one local paper
 	
 	
 		uh no
 	
 	
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Times Herald</ENAMEX> went out of business
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it was always the weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> of the two
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> uh
 		managed somehow to acquire nearly all the comics and features that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> had been carrying
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i mean they just they just plundered  the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> i mean it was financial you can blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicates</ENAMEX> for going where they're you know they got bigger bucks or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah well see we're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX>
 		city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chronicles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Union</ENAMEX> are our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> they merged editorial boards
 		however they still continue to publish they put out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> additions well it's actually <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> puts out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two one in the morning</TIMEX> And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Union</ENAMEX> puts out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but they're virtually the same paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's an there's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> edition which comes out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> and and the late edition which comes out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and just to give you an idea of what i meant by pandering it's like sometimes they their news for the news for the incredible stupid or comatose
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two days</TIMEX> the headlines have been massive storm hits area
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it's like
 	
 	
 		in case you're brain dead
 	
 	
 		well you know oh well that explains all the snow you know  as if someone was worried about it i just you know i i have to wonder uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh how how well they're serving us because uh
 		you you they've they've got a lock on it they don't there's not that many there's a few alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> but they all all the alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have this sort of an underground feel to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you you know you really can't trust them they're not i i think i need conservatism from my news i don't know i'm funny
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		just the facts please
 	
 	
 		yeah just the facts and and i don't want really much of a slant on it at all i just want the news
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i don't want uh someone judging the news for me
 	
 	
 		that one of the most famous headlines and i think this was on the editorial page and i don't remember it exactly
 		of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> was was some story about how well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can read and the fact that they can't and the headline was something like Let's Ban Literacy
 		and wait a minute that sounds fine at first
 		they want to ban illiteracy i think think
 	
 	
 		i think so Let's Ban Literacy but that's going to put you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> out of business don't you think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 		
 
 		
 		
 	