
 
     		
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> uh some of my things i i'd like to have a short work week
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		you know and and we need you know better health insurance and you know cause
 	
 	
 		okay we can start off there let's just get started i don't wanna well you know uh talk about it now and then be bored when we get to it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 		okay  so i just press <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> then right okay ready
 	
 	
 		right
 		yep
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so so you think uh i i think  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short work week</TIMEX> is real nice uh i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">work week</TIMEX> how about you
 	
 	
 		well right now i'm i'm just a student i only work part time but i i've work in the job <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> before and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> is just too long you just don't have any time to do anything it it seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> you you get off but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> you're getting ready for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
 		and if we could have us if we could have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">work week</TIMEX> well that'd happen is that for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we'd give another job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then that way that everybody would have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three day</TIMEX> holiday okay and that way that more that that would make a a bigger market we'd have uh
 		more recreation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have time to do it there'd be less of a stress level we'd have less we'd have less crime we'd have to we'd have to build <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> we'd need you know less police force
 	
 	
 		yeah it all makes sense to me although there may be more crime i mean if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have more leisure time it's not clear in that
 	
 	
 		it it that's that's that's a that's a possibility one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the problems they're facing now a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now is that the health insurance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is that the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> can't afford can't offer us health insurance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it it it's too costly and then what is what is happening is that they're on um
 		a policy where they have so X amount of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> in it okay and so they get a specific rate well what happens is that if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start becoming having chronic illness and
 		and and things like that
 		what happens and they where they have to spend out a lot of money for one particular it's called a a group well what'll what happens then is that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they cancel because they just can't cancel the indivigal
 		so that they have to cancel is just like life insurance they have to cancel everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so what they do is is that they they cancel the insurance and then all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have any insurance coverage
 	
 	
 		right
 		so
 	
 	
 		but i'm i'm you know i'm i'm satisfied with my job i'm i'm an engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and i work for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> and i'm
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'm not a typical student i'm i'm older i'm i'm in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> okay and so i have a lot of job experience and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> thrives on that because he can just tell me what he wants and he can give me access and tell me what to do and just turn me loose but in the in the same token
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's a really really enjoyable for me because i don't have to have you know nobody breathing down my back and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that i i really hate about jobs i don't i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> that that you know wanna
 		yell at you and you know and are are down your back and all this and that i i just really can't deal with that so
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		what kind of what kind of jobs have you done
 	
 	
 		well i do work uh research in computer science and i've just been doing that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> now so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i my job has most of the benefits i want um
 		what i really like is i like being like they send me to conferences for instance but probably not as much as i'd like but uh
 		you know that's just nice being you know having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> being able to give you time to do that sort of thing and sort of
 		uh they also a really important thing to me is when they uh
 		they pay for continuing education like i i get night <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that they're they'll cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and that's really good
 	
 	
 		yeah that's great you have what you might call knowledge power you know when when you work at a company
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		whether you know it or not is that you're categorized some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can be let go and replaced like uh say uh a a typist uh somebody who does data entry or answers the telephone a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receptionist</ENAMEX>
 		but if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's doing computer type things and you have the you have the knowledge you know what the system you've revised and revamped the system well then you're you're vital to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and you get more of the benefits so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's where i'm that i'm i like i'm into computers too and that's one of the things that i've found in in any one one of these jobs and anything i've done
 		is that to have knowledge when you have the knowledge you're you're not gonna um you know be let go you know be one of the last ones to let go anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but what i
 		
 
 		
 		
 	