
 
     		
 	
 		okay so uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> what are your opinions on uh trial by jury
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i work for an insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so i see a lot of uh verdicts that are pretty crazily decided um
 		by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> particularly and i know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> set all of the awards you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> will decide the guilt or innocence
 		but then they leave the
 		awards up to more learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i think maybe that avoids some of these totally ridiculous you know like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah that that seems to make sense that leave it up to the more experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who knows how it fits into the uh kind of the rate for different incidents
 	
 	
 		oh exactly  each individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> really doesn't have any perception of what um
 		the going you know if you will the going uh award should be for a certain type of case you know within some kind of range
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when you get one way out like that
 		that then really doesn't penalize wind up penalizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that they went after who it really penalizes is their insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> which then translates into higher rates for all of us
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if they get some of those mega awards against them you know they're not going to sit there and lose money if they're losing money then they're going to raise rates
 	
 	
 		right that they have to
 	
 	
 		so it all comes filtering down to us all individually individually individually
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh granted some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to be compensated if they have really been wronged
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about setting like well for example a a car type accident where
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or some incident where someone loses a limb do you think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> should have a dollar figure for losing an arm a dollar figure for losing different body parts it
 	
 	
 		i don't know you know some of the health insurance is written that way you know that uh
 		if you buy an accident and death or dismemberment policy you know it specifies pre specifies in the policy uh so much but i don't know that you can necessarily put a  a value on somebody's limb
 		uh arbitrarily that is always going to fit in all cases i think maybe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you look at uh the age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in life and and uh how much longer they have of work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that they would have to put up you know with
 		with that i mean maybe you don't award an eighty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> the same thing that you'd award a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hm
 	
 	
 		i i think it has to be some kind of common sense applied there and that may be where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX> is a little more
 		learned about that stuff type of thing because they can be schooled in that kind of thing and it could be part of continuing education maybe for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>  i don't know you know to get into the economics of things uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		because if they wheel somebody into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s heart goes out to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and they do one of these mega awards it really you know ultimately is not penalizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that they're trying to get anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		if it's a company you know that they're insured unless the award is so staggering that it goes all beyond their layers of insurance
 		which is another pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeve</ENAMEX> of mine when they do award punitive damages i think those should be uninsurable
 		i think those should have to be paid by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> itself that that did the damage
 	
 	
 		hm
 		oh out of their
 		as opposed to the corporation insurance paying the bills
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		type thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well we're
 	
 	
 		for for honest mistakes where they've done something and and something happens one of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> causes damage or something sure that's what they buy insurance for but
 	
 	
 		what
 		who who do they get they get insured they get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insured</ENAMEX> from other insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or how does that work
 	
 	
 		well i was just talking about any company
 	
 	
 		oh okay your talking about corporate
 	
 	
 		uh let's just say a lumber manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and uh somebody is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> actually is driving by with a forklift and he pushes the wrong button and he drops a load of lumber on somebody and it injures them sure insurance should pay for that
 	
 	
 		sure
 		okay
 		well
 		but in some instances you're going to put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> out of business by taking that stance if they have to take it out of their own retained earnings
 	
 	
 		well i'm not talking about any loss i was talking about only losses that are judged for a punitive damage which is another category of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> are awarding damages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s actual injuries and what they're due
 		and then they're awarding a second amount as punishment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> which is a lot usually a lot less but it's uh an amount their designed to sting them a little for their negligence for gross wanton negligence in a claim
 	
 	
 		okay
 		for oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and unfortunately the jury the lately the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have been deciding that those could be paid for by insurance too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so again it never really penalizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> doing the wrong they can go right on doing the same old thing they always used to
 	
 	
 		right they don't
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and if they if they know some practice is wrong you know i'm not talking about your isolated occurrences i'm talking more about the
 		you know the thing that they know maybe they're willfully manufacturing something that they know is hurting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there and they continue to do it even after they become aware of that
 	
 	
 		sure
 		okay
 	
 	
 		then i think they ought to have to pay something out of their own pocket
 		
 		
 	