



Legends 
See Leyendas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Leyenda Negra</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Black Legend</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Leyenda Negra</ENAMEX> is the term used for a myth that describes a very negative attitude many believe pervades the historical perspective regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Legend</ENAMEX> embodies a belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spaniards</ENAMEX> are basically a cruel, evil, lazy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy</ENAMEX>, treacherous, and fanatical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It originated in the era of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Inquisitorial Spain</ENAMEX> and has misrepresented the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1500s</TIMEX>. The printed history of the conquest of the New World depicts a violent and corrupt invasion, but there is a belief that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Legend</ENAMEX> has influenced the way this history has been written.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Legend</ENAMEX> originated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixteenth century</TIMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant Reformation</ENAMEX>, with the beginnings of a rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholicism</ENAMEX> and abhorrence of the political and military power of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> remained loyal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catholicism</ENAMEX>, and expanded their empires by settling in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>, and parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> looked on very disapprovingly. This viewpoint has continued to color everything about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> since then, including the grim legacy left by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX>. It has justified the dictatorial treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early nineteenth century</TIMEX>. Biased attitudes toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Spain</ENAMEX> were inherited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo Americans</ENAMEX> and brought to the New World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>.
The term <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leyenda Negra</ENAMEX> was assigned to this belief by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Juderias</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>. He stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Spanish</ENAMEX> propaganda and misconceptions had continued to develop since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixteenth century</TIMEX>, and historical distortions in both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> constituted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leyenda Negra</ENAMEX>. It is thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Legend</ENAMEX> is actually the basis for the discriminatory treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo Americans</ENAMEX> during the conquest of the frontier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1800s</TIMEX>, and even for the current treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicanos</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twentieth century</TIMEX>. The cause for derogatory stereotyping of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin Americans</ENAMEX>, is difficult to understand, and the negative stereotype seems to have no historical basis, until <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> understands the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Legend</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publications</ENAMEX> by early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> depict the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish Mexicans</ENAMEX> in not only horrendous terms, but with extreme passion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson Farnham</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1840s</TIMEX>, ‚ÄúIn a word, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> are an imbecile, pusillanimous, race of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and unfit to control the destinies of that beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">country‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weber</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">295</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Austin</ENAMEX>, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1822‚Äì1823</NUMEX>, after a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> wrote, ‚ÄúTo be candid the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as far as I have seen them want nothing but tails to be more brutes than the apes‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weber</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">298</NUMEX>).
During the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> war of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1846‚Äì1848</NUMEX> the uncivil treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Californios</ENAMEX> and the public conviction in the righteousness of the war are cited as examples of how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> was disrespected by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Historically powerful stereotypes of inferior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican Americans</ENAMEX>, perpetuated by arrogant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, led to the accep-tance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manifest Destiny</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America‚</ENAMEX>Äôs right. ‚ÄúThe result of such efforts to discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and justify war was a widespread belief that the God--forsaken <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> were unworthy to keep the valuable resources and land they had inherited from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spain‚Äù</ENAMEX> (Sanchez <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>).
The popular image of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> with a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sombrero</ENAMEX> sleeping under a cactus very likely originated from these early writings of traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, with the result that the icon has become imprinted forever upon the collective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicanos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX>. The common reference to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúfinally the sleeping giant awakens‚Äù when conferring on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican American</ENAMEX> social-political issues is made often by educated and acculturated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chicanos</ENAMEX>, manifesting an internalization of an image imposed from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> culture. Although no one actually mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Legend</ENAMEX> belief, its legacy permeates a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicano</ENAMEX> oral folklore.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Powell</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>; Sanchez <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weber</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leyendas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legends</ENAMEX>)
A leyenda, a legend, is an oral narrative different from a folktale in that it is narrated as if the event described occurred in the recent past and the story is believed by the narrator to be true. There is often a supernatural element to the narrative, such as a person‚Äôs disappearance into thin air, yet it will be recited as having occurred in a specified locale. Often the narrator <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where the story originated and explains that the events were observed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. The names of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> and places in the narrative will be familiar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicano</ENAMEX> oral tradition, stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Llorona, the Blue Lady, or Joaqu√≠n Murrieta</ENAMEX> can properly be called legends and almost always tell a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> wants to believe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicano</ENAMEX> community‚Äôs cultural belief system is inherent in the narrative, otherwise the legend would not be recited and retold, again and again. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of variants of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Llorona legend</ENAMEX>, all narrated about known encounters with her, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 200 years</TIMEX>. Her tragic story is believable, and one can say she is probably the quintessential legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicano</ENAMEX> folk belief system.
The urban belief tale, sometimes just called an urban legend, is a subtype of the legend and is called such because it circulates among all classes and ages and reflects modern stresses and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX>. It is not only found in urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> but in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> as well. In addition to the legend of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Llorona</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weeping Woman</ENAMEX>), another widespread legend in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicano</ENAMEX> folklore is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanishing Hitchhiker</ENAMEX>, although not always known by this name. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> folklore journal <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> carried an article about it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicano</ENAMEX> version appears in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miller‚</ENAMEX>Äôs narrative collection from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> with a date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>. The story usually involves a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> who picks up a hitchhiker, often <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX> and often a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, and he drops her off at or near her home. She leaves something in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, or he lends her a jacket or sweater, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> he returns to retrieve it and learns that she was a ghost, and has been dead for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. Sometimes she is met at a dance, and asks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to drive her home, or she might be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>, but the ghost is rarely a male. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brunvand</ENAMEX> calls it a classic automobile legend, and its prevalence has increased since <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> became affordable to all social classes. Interestingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vanishing Hitchhiker</ENAMEX> legend is one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narratives</ENAMEX> shared by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicano</ENAMEX> folklore. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Glazer</ENAMEX> discusses a collection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">152</NUMEX> variants from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio Grande Folklore Archive</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan American University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and states that the legend is ‚Äúpart of a culture which believes in miracles, mystery, and romance‚Äù (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>).
See also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agreda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar√≠a de Jesus Coronel de; La Llorona; Murrieta, Joaqu√</ENAMEX>≠n
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Brunvand</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glazer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987b</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1973; Robe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limpia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleansing</ENAMEX>)
A folk medicine ritual also called a barrida, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> verb barrer, meaning a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúsweeping</ENAMEX>,‚Äù as in housecleaning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limpiar</ENAMEX> means to clean and a limpia is similar to a barrida. Both words mean a cleansing, in a medical and in a spiritual sense. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use the word limpieza instead of limpia, but the significance is the same. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> may seek a limpia from a healer if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is not feeling well with no specific cause or feels that bad luck or misfortune is prevalent in his or her life. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">limpieza</ENAMEX> can expel the hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and also provide spiritual strength so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can effectively fight off negative energy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Spiritual healers</ENAMEX> who are not curanderos perform limpias, although mostly it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curanderos</ENAMEX> who perform this ritual. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> may be standing, sitting in a chair, or lying down while the ritual is performed. The healer will sweep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with a little broom made of herbs, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX>, rosemary, and rue, believed to be effective in eliminating evil influences. Herbal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, holy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is sprinkled over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the form of a cross, and the healer‚Äôs hands are used to sweep along the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, pushing away the evil spirits. While this is being done prayers are recited. The prayers may be the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Lord‚Äôs Prayer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las Doce Verdades del Mundo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Twelve Truths of the World</ENAMEX>). Instead of herbs some curanderos use an object for the sweeping, such as an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> or a lemon, believing that it will absorb the harm or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> affecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> are burned after the ritual, ensuring the recovery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is swept on all sides, front and back, and if there is pain in a particular spot, special attention will be given to that area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotter</ENAMEX> states that ‚Äúthe presence of the curandero, the soothing effect of the sweepings (touching), and the low-key monotone chant of the prayers produces in the patient a light trance state that is comforting and reassuring‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chavira 1997</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82</NUMEX>).
See also Curanderismo; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Las Doce</ENAMEX> Verdades
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Roeder</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chavira</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Llorona</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Weeping Woman</ENAMEX>)
This is the name of probably the most famous legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Mexico</ENAMEX>. The ancient legend of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Llorona</ENAMEX> has been traced to pre-Columbian times in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, and there is continuing discussion whether it may also have medieval <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> origins. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicanos</ENAMEX> heard of her as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, read about her in literature, or learned of her from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Llorona</ENAMEX>, meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúthe weeping woman‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúthe howling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>,‚Äù may be represented as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, an ugly old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch</ENAMEX>, or a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in white with long flowing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>. She always appears <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX>, and her crying and weeping can be vividly heard as she shrieks, ‚ÄúAyyy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mis hijos!‚Äù</ENAMEX> (Oh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>!).
According to the tragic legend, there once was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was abandoned by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, and left with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Angry and seeking revenge, she kills her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by throwing them into a river, or sometimes by other means. When she realizes what she‚Äôs done, she goes insane. She is condemned to spend eternity searching for her lost and dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Consequently she is often heard in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> calling her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. She frequents rivers and other bodies of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and is sometimes seen floating above the water looking, searching for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Her legend has been recited for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 300 years</TIMEX>, and in contemporary times she is still believed to be wandering the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, as well as in the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> where numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> report encounters with her. At times she is seen as a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, wearing a white dress, roaming back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, crying and weeping. Sometimes she becomes visible to the wayward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> who is out late, drinking, and when he approaches her, she turns into an ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-faced hag, scaring him into swearing abstinence forever. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> use her name to scare little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">obedience: ‚ÄúHay viene La Llorona</ENAMEX> .<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">¬†.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">¬†.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portat√© bien‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Llorona</ENAMEX> is coming, behave yourself). Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who‚Äôve heard the story many times and do not want to admit belief still fear a late-night encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Llorona</ENAMEX>.
There are ancient texts of indigenous mythology narrated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aztecs</ENAMEX> and recorded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spaniards</ENAMEX> that very closely resemble the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Llorona</ENAMEX> legend. In some tales she is believed to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cihuacoatl</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron goddess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who die in childbirth. It is said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cihuacoatl</ENAMEX> carried a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> cradle on her back, or a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in her arms, as she roamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> crying through the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>. Those who saw her considered it an ill omen. Sahag√∫n mentions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">The Conquest of Mexico</ENAMEX> that ‚Äúa <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was often heard [as] she went weeping and crying out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loudly</ENAMEX> did she call out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. She walked about saying: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄòO my beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, now we are about to go!‚Äô‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horcasitas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butterworth</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">208</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horcasitas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butterworth</ENAMEX> reprint several texts of these early chronicles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego Mu√±oz Camargo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ca. 1529‚Äì1599</ENAMEX>) also reported that before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spaniards</ENAMEX> arrived, ‚Äúmany times and many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> was heard the voice of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who cried out in a loud voice, drowning herself with her tears, and with great sobs and sighs, wailing‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horcasitas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butterworth</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX>).
Contemporary texts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Llorona</ENAMEX> collected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> assert that the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Llorona</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Malinche</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cort√©s.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cort√©s</ENAMEX> abandoned her to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, and according to the legend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malinche</ENAMEX> killed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> with a knife. This could be the source of another characteristic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Llorona</ENAMEX> legend. In many variants the reason for her abandonment by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> is their class differences. He leaves her for someone of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, or she is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> or a mestiza (mixed-race <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>) and he is of pure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. In other variants, she is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, who doesn‚Äôt want her illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, so she throws them into the river. She is always described as having long hair, down below her waist, and is seen wearing a white gown. Sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> see her as a temptress and a siren; she entices them to follow her, and then she frightens them with her horrible looks. They are usually found dead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>. What appears to be an unjust punishment is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Llorona</ENAMEX> is condemned to wander for eternity, crying and repenting, searching for her lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who have lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> identify with her, and feel her pain.
The prodigious amount of published literature about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Llorona</ENAMEX>, by folklorists, literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, anthropologists, and feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, attests to the complexity of the legend. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Children‚Äôs</ENAMEX> books, short stories, novels, and films have been created based on this basic story of infanticide and repentance. We find narratives in rural and urban areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>, on college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>, in juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, in large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, and among the native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicanos</ENAMEX> see themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orphans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Llorona</ENAMEX>, as the lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the marriage between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aztecs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Conquerors</ENAMEX>. She is a beloved female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">archetype</ENAMEX> among contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chicanas</ENAMEX>, who write poems, short stories, and academic research articles about her. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> put it, ‚ÄúIt is finally time to let go of a single, narrow understanding of the tale and to see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Llorona</ENAMEX> instead as an always evolving emblem of gender, sexuality, and power‚Äîand, too, as another female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of history‚Äôs tender mercies‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candelaria</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX>).
See also Leyendas; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Malinche</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Muerte</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Anaya</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984, 1995</TIMEX>; Arora <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barakat</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>; Candelaria <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>; Garc√≠a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> Obregon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horcasitas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Butterworth</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lim√≥n</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1988b</ENAMEX>; Paz <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebolledo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivero</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simmons</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vigil 1994</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zinam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molina</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Lobos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wolves</ENAMEX>)
The name of a musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> formed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, with the full name of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Lobos del Este de Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> has been together ever since, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>, all raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Starting out playing Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> band music, they eventually decided to play traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> folk music, using traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> instruments. They‚Äôve incorporated into their music the instruments, such the bajo sexto (a twelve-string guitar), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el</ENAMEX> guitarr√≥n (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass guitar</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el</ENAMEX> quinto (a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-string guitar).
Their repertoire reflects the variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicano</ENAMEX> music, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tex-Mex, M√∫sica Norte√±a</ENAMEX>, rock and roll, blues, salsa, rhythm and blues, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> styles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> plays norte√±o music interspersed with rock and roll. They played and recorded the music for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Bamba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoot Suit</ENAMEX>, and other films and have toured worldwide. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone Magazine</ENAMEX> named the group <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band of the Year</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. They received a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grammy Award for ‚ÄúAnselma‚Äù</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> song.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> they produced an album, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Pistola y el Corazon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Pistol and the Heart</ENAMEX>), of acoustic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> songs, which is considered a great collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> folk music.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Freedman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guevara</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>; Loza <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>; Monsalvo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>
Low Rider
The expression ‚Äúlow rider‚Äù is used to describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, the subculture, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who drives a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> that has been lowered, rides very low, and has been customized. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> that has been lowered‚Äîand this can be achieved by various methods‚Äîmeans that it sits very close to the ground and has a sleek streamlined appearance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is called a low rider and the act of low riding refers to all the activities associated with driving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>: cruising, caravanning, and hopping. Low <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> have commonly been associated with cholos (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1990s</NUMEX> urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>, but traditionally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicanos</ENAMEX> seriously involved in low riding and customizing low-rider <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are not involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>, and low-rider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> actually present an alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> involvement. Low-rider car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> communicate a message of cultural pride and unity. Although different, the cholo subculture can be closely linked to the low-rider subculture.
It is not clear when low riding started, but it was already a custom by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>, although the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúlow rider‚Äù</ENAMEX> did not come into usage until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, because of the growth in the economy, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicanos</ENAMEX> could afford to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, old and new, and the practice of customizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and cruising became very popular throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>. The most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to lower are long ones, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fords, Buicks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hydraulic</ENAMEX> lifts are used to lower and raise both the front and rear ends of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. Before it was discovered that a hydraulic lift could be used with the batteries stored in the trunk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, different methods were used to lower the chassis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. Early crude methods were to place heavy bricks and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cement</ENAMEX> bags in the trunk, or to cut the spring‚Äôs coils, or lower the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">car‚Äôs blocks</ENAMEX>. To give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that lowered look the top might be cut back to lower the roof. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent times</TIMEX>, once a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is ‚Äúlifted‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúall juiced up,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> controls the lift with a hand control.
The painting and decorating of the exterior and interior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> are very important for appearances, personal identity, and also for belonging to a car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and participating in car shows. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior</ENAMEX> may be upholstered in crushed velvet, red or black, have wall-to-wall carpeting, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, a chandelier, a TV, and a stereo tape deck. The exterior may be painted in two tones, a lacquer mixed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">iridescent flakes</ENAMEX>, or have a pearl finish. Sometimes the undercarriage is chromed and gold-plated. Painting low-rider <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> is a specialty only available at certain paint and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body shops</ENAMEX>, so low <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> must be aware of such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. Besides the painting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, other decorative designs or motifs may also be applied, such as pinstriping, fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lace</ENAMEX> (a fire design), and murals. Murals of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aztec or Mayan</ENAMEX> scene or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Virgen de Guadalupe</ENAMEX> are popular icons painted on the trunk, hood, or roof of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. Even though there is similarity in the styles, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is very different in the final production. There are many techniques employed to arrive at a unique personal style. For instance accessories from different<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are interchanged, such as side panels from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX> model may be cut and welded to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äú‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äô57</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> tail lamps on a ‚<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Äô62</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Impala‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">196</NUMEX>).
Low <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> are usually young urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chicanos</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of eighteen</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>, and there can be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of low riders in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The cost of fixing and maintaining a low-rider <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is fairly high, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> typically is a working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Since finding older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, say from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, is becoming difficult, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">low riders</ENAMEX> now customize small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> as well. The movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mi Vida Loca</ENAMEX> (My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy Life</ENAMEX>) depicts the work that goes into customizing a pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>.
Cruising involves driving very slowly up and down city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mission Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Whittier Boulevard</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Story Roads</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The objective of cruising is to socialize, to see and be seen, to give others the opportunity to admire one‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and to admire the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>; consequently the driving must be very slow, muy despacito. Driving a great customized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, beautifully painted, is a unique experience for the low rider. Cruising slowly and smoothly, sitting low in the driver‚Äôs seat, glancing out at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, nodding the head slightly when being recognized, all these make up an experience only a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicano</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">low rider</ENAMEX> who has invested lots of time and money in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> can appreciate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruising</ENAMEX> is often compared to the custom of promenading around a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX>, referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">el</ENAMEX> paseo in many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. In this sense, the low-rider car becomes a cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>, as represented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert Lujan</ENAMEX> in his series titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúCultural Vehicles</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
A low-rider <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford LTD</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚ÄúDave‚Äôs Dream‚</ENAMEX>Äù is on display at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian National Museum of American History</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and only low-rider <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chimayo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Martinez</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Jaramillo</ENAMEX> worked on customizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>. It has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hydraulic pumps, with the batteries stored in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, that lift and lower the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and can make it rock from side to side and give it an appearance of dancing. Actually ‚Äúcar dancing‚Äù is an event held at low-rider car shows.
Within the low-rider subculture there exist several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> of traditions. For instance, car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> are an important aspect of the culture and a way to showcase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in competitions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the oldest ongoing car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> is named the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dukes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> are referred to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as ‚</NUMEX>Äúclubbers,‚Äù and they compete for trophies, ride in car caravans, and often participate in fund-raising events. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúCholos‚Äù</ENAMEX> are considered another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, less financially stable with more modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, less ornate, and likely more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mexicano</ENAMEX> in orientation. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the ‚Äúcha chas,‚Äù are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, who drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyotas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volkswagens</ENAMEX>, and are a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Low Rider Magazine</ENAMEX> was founded during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> to provide a forum for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">low riders</ENAMEX> and the culture that surrounds low riding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Low Rider</ENAMEX> has been very instrumental in the widespread growth of low-rider car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúLow Rider Happenings,‚Äù</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>. Low riding is looked upon as a very Chicano cultural phenomenon, yet it has spread to other ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. There are many non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicano</ENAMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> have also adopted it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Low Rider</ENAMEX> has been publishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> edition for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past four years</TIMEX> and has organized low-rider car shows in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osaka</ENAMEX>. As a form of artistic expression and folk art, the customizing of low-rider <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicanos</ENAMEX> is an expression of tradition and cultural pride.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Bright</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994, 1995</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chabran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chabran</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; Gradante <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marks</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parsons</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; Plascencia <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas 1994; Vigil</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luminarias</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonfires</ENAMEX>)
Not to be confused with farolitos, luminarias are small bonfires, and the custom of lighting them dates back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. These small fires are built in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> to celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Noche Buena</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX>, and to light the way for the announcement of the birth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> may light <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> luminarias in front of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> each for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>, while another may light twelve, one for each of the twelve apostles. It is believed luminarias originate from the huge bonfires built in pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> times to celebrate rituals to the gods and goddesses. Also in ancient times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shepherds</ENAMEX> built fires to keep themselves warm and to scare off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wolves</ENAMEX>. This tradition continued in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> with the shepherds‚Äô fires to illuminate the way for the coming of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>. They are not as well known as farolitos in contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> popular culture, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> often finds farolitos mistakenly called luminarias, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> articles describe how to make them, especially during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas holidays</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Anaya</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995a</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown 1978</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortega</ENAMEX> 1973




