



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofrenda</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Offering</ENAMEX>)
Sometimes used interchangeably with altar, ofrenda means “an offering” and is set up as a component of an altar. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Día de los Muertos, the Day of the Dead or All Souls’ Day</ENAMEX>, an offering is made for a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> who has died, or for several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who have died, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>. An ofrenda may be set up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and personalized for a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. In some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> an altar is permanently set up for general and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> prayer, but an ofrenda is specifically for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Día de los Muertos</ENAMEX>. An ofrenda will have lit votive candles that are meant to help guide the soul to the ofrenda. It will also have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, because these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> are considered to be the main supports of life. In addition the personal favorite items of the deceased will be placed out for him or her, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sweets</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>, photographs, and even an especially liked shirt or dress. During <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Día de los Muertos</ENAMEX>, altars are set up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> and exhibit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> as artistic and cultural expressions, with ofrendas created for particularly known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
See also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altars; Día de los</ENAMEX> Muertos
References Cash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>; Portillo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>; Sommers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Mother Game</ENAMEX> 
See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Vieja Inés y los</ENAMEX> Listones
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Onda Chicana</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicano Wave of Music</ENAMEX>)
A phrase used to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicano</ENAMEX> music, especially that of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1960s</TIMEX>, which is a combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> music styles. In musical terms, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Onda Chicana</ENAMEX> was created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orquesta</ENAMEX>, which synthesized the elements from different music styles, such as ranchera and big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> swing, to create a blend of music that characterized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicano</ENAMEX> music of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s and 1970s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Onda Chicana</ENAMEX> also reflected a cultural and political sentiment, an ethnic pride in being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chicano</ENAMEX> and working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, and it also embodied a recognition of being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> popular culture. The lyrics of the songs may be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>, and sometimes both languages are used in the same song. Although the conjuntos of norteño music and the orquestas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> were all accepted as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mexicano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chicano</ENAMEX>, the music of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Onda Chicana</ENAMEX> was purely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicano</ENAMEX> music.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> that typified this sound was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Joe y La Familia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Joe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Joe Hernandez</ENAMEX> was born into a migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmworker family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and started his musical career as a teenager. He sang with his cousin’s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Corona y Los Latinaires</ENAMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> before taking it over and calling it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Joe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinaires</ENAMEX>. When that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> split up he reorganized it as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Joe y La Familia</ENAMEX>. He recorded many successful albums in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, and has been called the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">“King of Brown Sound</ENAMEX>.”
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peña</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Onda Chicana well: “It</ENAMEX> synthesized all the musical elements.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"> .</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"> .</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"> .</ENAMEX> to achieve a highly innovative bimusical sound that combined a ranchera (country music) and jaitón (high class music) within the same piece.” Other bands that fit into this genre were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunny Ozuna</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunliners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Lobos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alacranes Mojados</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Camacho</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tear Drops, and La Rondalla Amerindia</ENAMEX>.
See also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conjunto Music</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Lobos</ENAMEX>; Ranchera
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Loza</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>; Peña <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>; Villarino <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oremos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmas House</ENAMEX> Visits)
A custom from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, at least <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>, where on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> go from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to house asking for treats, much like on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>. This custom was sometimes just called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oremos</ENAMEX> (literally, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">“we pray”</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> would knock on the doors of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and chant:
Oremos, Oremos
Angelitos somos
D’el cielo venimos
A pedir Oremos
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si no nos dan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Puertas y ventanas quebrarémos</ENAMEX>.
(We pray, we pray
Little angels we are
From heaven we come
To ask we pray
If we don’t receive
Doors and windows we will break.)
The chant states that they’re angels from heaven and are asking for gifts, although if they receive none, they may break doors and windows. The origin of this custom is not known, but some believe it is to remind society that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> at the door should not be forgotten. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorin Brown</ENAMEX> reports that in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> went out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX>, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canutillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, it was the custom for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to go door to door on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day</TIMEX>, although they didn’t recite the above chant. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> expected them and were ready with gifts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candies</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lottie C. Devine</ENAMEX> makes reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papago Indians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, saying that on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">“Christmas Day</ENAMEX> most of them came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, all dressed in party clothes, and went from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to house ‘calling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>.’ Everyone gave them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> and many of them in turn gave baskets or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pottery”</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">29</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabeza de Baca</ENAMEX> refers to this custom as aguinaldos, and the chant she records is similar to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> above, except that the last line is “A pedir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aguinaldos y Oremos</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">” Aguinaldos</ENAMEX> are gifts given during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas season</TIMEX>.
See also Aguinaldos
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Brown</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cabeza de Baca</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>; Devine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>
Oso, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juan</ENAMEX>
The name of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk character</ENAMEX> found in tales collected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aurelio Espinosa</ENAMEX> and his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Manuel Espinosa</ENAMEX>. In some tales <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Oso</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Bear</ENAMEX>) is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> and a bear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> is kidnapped by a bear when she is out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> and is taken to a cave where she eventually has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> bear and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> human. Finally she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Osito</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, are able to run away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX> and go live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juan</ENAMEX> grows up he leaves his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to wander the land, and from this point on, various tales describe the different adventures of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juan Oso</ENAMEX>. In a variant of the tale, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby son</ENAMEX> are captured by a bear and taken to live in a cave where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> grows up learning the ways of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX>. They also escape and return to live with the woman’s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Oso</ENAMEX> wanders off to explore the world. Even though he is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> wild, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Oso</ENAMEX> develops into a strong, smart, and sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who will not be outwitted. In variants collected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Miller</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, where he is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan del Oso</ENAMEX>, he has magical abilities. After he saves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> princesses he is usually allowed to marry one of them.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Espinosa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. M.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Espinosa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. M.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> 1973

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otero-Warren</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adelina</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1881–1965</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Otero-Warren</ENAMEX> is known primarily as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of the book Old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> in Our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>), a memoir of life in early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. It is more than an autobiography, since it is interspersed with folklore narratives, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hispano</ENAMEX> traditions, and early southwest history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Otero</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Lunas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> named after her grandfather’s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, a descendent of an early influential <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. They were fairly wealthy and the marriage of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX> was lavish and elaborate. The details of the wedding are well described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlotte Whaley</ENAMEX> in her biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, was killed in a shoot-out when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina</ENAMEX> was still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> later married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. M. Bergere</ENAMEX>. They had a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> together, all of whom are well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina</ENAMEX> attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>, married and divorced, and eventually settled into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Mexican</ENAMEX> politics. She was appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> area and was active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Union</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> and lobbied for the vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX> she ran for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. House of Representatives</ENAMEX> but was defeated. She continued working for government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> as an educator and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> education. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX> she worked as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>, which had a training program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Mexico</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX>. Like her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleofas Jaramillo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aurora Lucero</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>, she had an interest in folklore, and her book Old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> in Our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> was one of the first private ethnographies to be published by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of her era. In it she describes the early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>, life on the hacienda, the religious fiestas, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">santos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> songs, folktales, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX> of the region. In her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>, up until her death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businesswoman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Otero-Warren</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ponce</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>; Rebolledo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>; Whaley <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outcast</ENAMEX> 
See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Tiradito</ENAMEX>




