



Zoot Suit
A style of suit worn by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Americans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Filipino Americans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican Americans</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s and 1940s</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicano</ENAMEX> culture this style of dress is primarily associated with the pachucos of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>. The fashion at that time was to wear very baggy pants with pegged legs, long jackets with high and sharp shoulder pads, thick-soled shoes, and long watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> dangling from the belt. An addition to the whole style common to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chicanos</ENAMEX> was a particular haircut, long with a ducktail and a wide-brimmed hat.
The word zoot was known within the urban jazz culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>, and it meant something either exaggerated in performance or in style. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Americans</ENAMEX> wore an extravagant style of clothing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baggy</ENAMEX> pegged pants and jackets with padded shoulders, that later became known as the zoot suit. In the novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Invisible Man</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison</ENAMEX>, he describes the zoot--suiters‚Äô style, ‚Äúwalking slowly, their shoulders swaying, their legs swinging from their hips in trousers that ballooned upward from cuffs fitting snug about their ankles; their coats long and hip-tight with shoulders far too broad to be those of natural western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">380</NUMEX>). In the late-night jazz scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> this style was ‚<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Äúa killer</ENAMEX>-diller coat with a drape-shape, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reat-pleats</ENAMEX> and shoulders padded like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lunatic‚Äôs cell‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">380</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> makes the point that the zoot suit was an extremely symbolic costume, which gave the wearer the look of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in adult clothing. The broad square shoulders gave a macho look to the youth, and the finger-tipped coat was made for fun and leisure. The long baggy pants were made for dancing, especially the jitterbug, and the wide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> hats were another sign of adulthood. ‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of fun, dancing and dating were the key characteristics displayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoot-Suiters</ENAMEX>. It was an escape from drudgery and futile labor to the bliss of free-wheeling movement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> in the new youth culture‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>). Prominent black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entertainers</ENAMEX> wore the zoot suit, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cab Calloway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Davis Jr.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke Ellington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellington</ENAMEX> performed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orpheum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941 and 1942</TIMEX> with a musical called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jump for Joy</ENAMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> wore zoot suits, also known as Gone with the Wind suits, after the style worn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Gable</ENAMEX> in the movie by the same name.
Even though the zoot suit was worn by the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of several different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> and ethnicities, it is primarily identified with the pachucos of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Pachucos were mostly second-generation <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> and working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pachucos</ENAMEX> created their own subculture, an arrogant style of dressing, a bilingual secret argot, and for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> membership in petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal gangs</ENAMEX>. The zoot suit became a symbolic disguise that identified the zoot-suiter as neither a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> nor an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>. It was not a bicultural or binational position, but rather a position between cultures, a ‚Äúhanging in space‚Äù position. The overly confident, slow swagger of the pachuco, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> exemplified by the cholo, made it appear in fact as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zoot-suiter</ENAMEX> were walking on air.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1943</TIMEX> the attention of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> and zoot-suiters battled with each other in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. It is unclear if this was a race riot or a riot of patriotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> who attacked, beat, and stripped young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican Americans</ENAMEX> whom they perceived to be unpatriotic zoot-suiters. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between the third and thirteenth of June</TIMEX> zoot-suiters were open targets. Much has been written about these riots from both literary and historical perspectives.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> the zoot suit received wide recognition and popularity with the production of a successful play by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Valdez</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> a film by the same name, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoot Suit</ENAMEX>, was produced and directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Valdez</ENAMEX>, with performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Valdez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward James Olmos</ENAMEX>.
See also Cholos; Pachucos
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Barker</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>; Cosgrove <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>; Mazon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>; Orona-Cordova <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>; Sanchez <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Valdez</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>; Zoot Suit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>
Zozobra
A giant, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">effigy</ENAMEX> in the form of a puppet, which is burned during the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe Fiesta</ENAMEX> held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. The word <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zozobra translates to ‚Äúgloom‚Äù or ‚Äúworry‚Äù or ‚Äúanguished</ENAMEX>.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zozobra</ENAMEX> is ritualistically burned at the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">fiesta</ENAMEX>, which symbolizes the end of destructiveness, gloom, and worry, setting the tone for a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">fiesta</ENAMEX>. The creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zozobra</ENAMEX> was introduced into the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">fiesta</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Shuster</ENAMEX>, who felt that the fiesta had become ‚Äúdull and commercialized.‚Äù Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zozobra</ENAMEX> changed from a simple <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twenty-foot</NUMEX> puppet to the elaborate <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty-foot</NUMEX> figure with animated eyes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, and mouth that he is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuster</ENAMEX> turned over the responsibility and copyright of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zozobra</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>. He is hung on a tall pole on a hill, outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, where the burning can be seen by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who come to watch. The death of gloom is supposed to resurrect happiness.
In response to the tradition of the burning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zozobra</ENAMEX>, a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico Chicanos</ENAMEX> started a tradition of burning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Kooko√≥ee</ENAMEX>, a figure known by many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chicanos</ENAMEX> as the bogeyman, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival de Oto√±o</ENAMEX>.
See also <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Kooko√≥ee</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe Fiesta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">References Cohen</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grimes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weigle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>




