



Discussion of
Draft Recommendations

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Hungerford</ENAMEX> opened <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the final</TIMEX> session of the conference by
outlining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s ultimate task-to create research
recommendations from conference deliberations. Before the
conference, he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Pollock</ENAMEX> drafted recommendations for the
steering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to consider. During the conference, the steering
committee modified those recommendations, and they were distributed
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> for general discussion.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford</ENAMEX> stated that the goal of the conference was not to
achieve unanimity regarding the recommendations, but to have
significant and general agreement. He indicated the process would
be to discuss the recommendations <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, identifying any gaps
or omissions and offering general comments. He emphasized that the
sequence of the recommendations did not imply a priority order.
Because the published recommendations will include supporting text,
he encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to consider any points of clarification
that would be instructive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford</ENAMEX> then opened the floor for
discussion.
Recommendation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1</NUMEX> Research on screening and intervention should
address the full spectrum of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Brown</ENAMEX> remarked that in many circles, "intervention" does
not necessarily include referral, so he suggested that the first
recommendation include "referral." Also, he said the phrase
"alcohol problems" does not always include risky drinking and
problem drinking, so he suggested adding "risky and problem
drinking" to the recommendation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Hungerford</ENAMEX> noted that the supporting text could provide
detail on the spectrum of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems. He suggested the main
point of the first recommendation was that research efforts should
include the whole continuum of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems, not just a portion
of the continuum such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol-dependent drinkers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Shope</ENAMEX> advocated that the definition of "the full spectrum
of alcohol problems" include primary prevention. She recommended
this under-standing be made explicit in the final document.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Smith</ENAMEX> suggested that the recommendations should address
the problems of poly-substance abuse.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Soderstrom</ENAMEX> wondered whether "alcohol problems" referred to
the spectrum of drinking problems or the medical problems
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with drinking.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Diesenhaus</ENAMEX> pointed out that hazardous drinking causes a
complex set of problems that include personal, social, and legal
problems in addition to medical problems. The phrase "alcohol
problems" includes all those problems as well as the hazardous
drinking. He noted that different pieces of the solution will lie
in the medical realm and in the social welfare realm. He expressed
concern about how to reflect this complexity in the
recommendations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guohua Li</ENAMEX> suggested changing the phrase "among <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>" to
"in the emergency setting" because alcohol problems are not limited
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the recommendations should address alcohol
problems among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hargarten</ENAMEX> thought that the term "alcohol-related
problems" would appeal to clinicians more than "alcohol problems"
because they see those problems in their practices. He said that
including "related" in terms gives the sense of broadening
them.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ries</ENAMEX> said he did not believe that screening for alcohol
neuropathy was intended to be part of the recommendation. He
suggested that the recommendation be clear that it is addressing
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use disorders or problems, not for medical care
consequences.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hungerford</ENAMEX> replied that screening for specific medical care
consequences was not part of the recommendation, but that
consequence items may be used in the screening. He added that broad
screening would identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with medical conditions as well. He
found that
screening with a low cut point on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX> identified more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with severe alcohol problems and alcohol dependence than did
not using a uniform screening method. He agreed that this issue
needs clarification in this recommendation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Longabaugh</ENAMEX> said that the term "alcohol problems" implies
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s problem is consumption. He favored
"alcohol-related problems" because consumption is not the problem.
The problem is the consequences resulting from excessive
drinking.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elinor Walker</ENAMEX> endorsed the notion of using "the emergency care
setting" rather than "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>" particularly to include focus on the
pre-hospital care setting.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford</ENAMEX> added that the trauma care setting should be included
as well.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li</ENAMEX> added his support to "alcohol-related problems," but
suggested another alternative, "problem drinking," which is
commonly used.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Bernstein</ENAMEX> pointed out that the recommendations would
likely stand alone for readings and come without context. With that
in mind, he suggested listing the full spectrum of alcohol
problems, from risky drinking to alcohol abuse to alcohol
dependency. He felt that it would be a mistake to open this set of
research recommendations with a recommendation that included
screening for withdrawal or other conditions. Another possibility
would be to say, "the full spectrum of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> misuse."
Recommendation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX> Screening instruments under consideration for
use in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX> should be evaluated as a component of protocols that
provide interventions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Woolard</ENAMEX> supported the recommendation and noted that most
research on screening has involved an evaluation of screening, but
not an intervention. Trying to apply those findings to a
clinical
setting, where there is the question of training and the link
between the screening instruments and the intervention, becomes
problematic. Enough research has been conducted on instruments
alone, he said, and new research should link screens with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Degutis</ENAMEX> recommended amending the recommendation to read,
"screening, interventions, and methods under consideration." Then
in the supporting text, she suggested addressing the different
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might be doing the screening and the need to tie it to
intervention.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Longabaugh</ENAMEX> wondered whether the intended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> of the
document would include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>, and academicians.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford</ENAMEX> answered that the summary of the conference would be
published in an emergency medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> would
include these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Pollock</ENAMEX> added that the message of the recommendations
could also be conveyed at professional meetings. The goal was to
influence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are in a position to make changes in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> believed the recommendation was worded too strongly. To
him, it was saying that work should not include screening research
in isolation. He noted that little is known about effective
screening for certain sub-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, so screening research still
has its place. Although he agreed that a total research portfolio
should have a strong emphasis on intervention and not just
screening.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diesenhaus</ENAMEX> described his use of a slogan and abbreviation for a
treatment strategy, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Screening, Brief Intervention</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Referral-SBIR</ENAMEX>." Research on the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> is important,
but the strategy for the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> setting is as follows:
screen, decide if a brief intervention is called for, and if not,
give a referral. Emergency setting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> need to understand all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> components and how they are linked. He was not sure if
"referral" could be included every time, but acknowledged that it
is a vital part of the work.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford</ENAMEX> emphasized that research on screening is needed.
However, he believed research on screening instruments that is not
linked with an intervention leads to the easy assumption that
results will be generalizable to using that screening instrument in
a full protocol. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> recommendation, therefore, is intended
to point out that results from the screening literature are not
necessarily generalizable to real-world settings in which screening
would be paired with interventions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ries</ENAMEX> suggested that defining "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SBIR</ENAMEX>" upfront might help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clinicians</ENAMEX> understand the recommendations better. If we do not, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clinician</ENAMEX> who is interested in seizures or pancreatitis could
easily misread the wording of this recommendation. To avoid that,
for this recommendation we would have to say something like,
"Problematic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-use screening instruments under consideration
for use in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> should be evaluated as a component of protocols
that provide alcohol-use interventions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to decrease
problems or use."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford</ENAMEX> said he understood. If we do not pre-define "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBIR</ENAMEX>,"
we have to define what we are talking about with each
recommendation. If we do define "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SBIR</ENAMEX>" upfront, we make the reading
more understandable and more efficient.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail D'Onofrio</ENAMEX> noted that in this context, we use "referral" to
mean sending a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> to a specialized treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>.
However, in emergency medicine, everyone gets a referral-to primary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> follow-up, or another health or social service. The
"referral" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBIR</ENAMEX> could include both meanings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hargarten</ENAMEX>'s initial understanding of this recommendation was
that screening activities for alcohol problems should be integrated
with the screening and interventions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> does for a whole range
of problems. He suggested that the recommendation be worded in such
a manner that this effort does not seem to be a parallel
activity.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford</ENAMEX> proposed that just as screening research should be
carried out in the context of protocols that include interventions,
those protocols should be integrated with the whole system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
operations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Dunn</ENAMEX> thought the word "evaluate" made this
recommendation vague. What would be evaluated-the usefulness of a
screen or the psychometric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">properties</ENAMEX> of a screen? He believed that
the screen can have an interventive effect, so he wanted research
on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> fare as well with a screen as they do with
brief advice or more sophisticated techniques.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Fiellin</ENAMEX> advocated eliminating the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> recommendation.
To him the statement implied that screening instruments should be
evaluated only as a component of protocols that provide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>. He believed that the statement was dangerous because
there are research methodologies that are related to evaluating
screening and separate ones related to evaluating interventions,
and we may not want to obligate tying the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> together.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Babor</ENAMEX> supported technical research on screening and the
wording of this recommendation. However, he raised a larger
issue-the moral imperative of screening. He said that screening
sets up the expectation that something has to follow. Without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screening</ENAMEX>, there cannot be much intervention. He noted that the
recommendation could be seen as a way of driving widespread
applications of interventions. If that is the goal, he thought we
should be examining how to accomplish screening. There are large
obstacles to screening, and practical research on screening
implementation, incentives, efficiency, and its ability to reach
large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at low cost is necessary. He believed in a
public health approach to screening which means we would not do it
if the yield is low. He suggested that the technical aspects of
screening were not as fruitful topics for research as how to screen
the greatest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at the lowest cost.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> suggested that the recommendation not be eliminated,
but rewritten to reflect the discussion.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford</ENAMEX> concurred. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford</ENAMEX> added that the
intent of the recommendation was not so much that integrating the
screen with the intervention gave better estimates of the
performance characteristics of the screen, but that it would
redress the imbalance between
research emphasizing the performance characteristics and
research on operational and practical characteristics.
Recommendation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Interventions</ENAMEX> that have shown promise in other
clinical settings should be adapted to and evaluated in emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bombardier</ENAMEX> wondered whether the recommendation should
limit evaluation only to interventions shown to be effective in
other settings. There might be interventions developed specifically
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> that would be worthwhile to test.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> thought the goal of this recommendation was to
de-emphasize fine-grained, developmental work and to emphasize
pursuing work using available interventions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolard</ENAMEX> noted that the effectiveness of screening, brief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>, and referrals has been proven outside the emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, but not yet in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. Therefore, he hoped that the
supporting text for this recommendation would include statements
about the need for a large, multi-center trial in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longabaugh</ENAMEX> noted that new and creative interventions may be
developed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> that the rest of the field will want to adapt
and explore.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> made a plea not to adopt the abbreviation "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SBIR</ENAMEX>" because
it is already used to designate small business innovation research
grants by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. It could be very confusing. She
suggested "SIR" instead.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> returned to the idea of linking alcohol interventions with
the other interventions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. If there were a package of
interventions that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> could document and be reimbursed for,
that would ease acceptance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> and help
institutionalize these new practices. Documentation would also help
ensure interventions would not be repeated unnecessarily.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> pointed out that proving the cost-effectiveness of a
specified, well-described service in a clinical setting is a
critical consideration in moving a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> from a research
endeavor to a reimbursable service. Whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> emerges as
an adaptation from primary care or as an innovation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> is
less important than whether it can be evaluated to the satisfaction
of those who make key decisions about whether it becomes part of
standard practice.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Gentilello</ENAMEX> asserted that effective treatments already
exist, not just treatments that "hold promise." The "promise" has
to do with the intervention's likelihood of success in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>, not
with its success in other settings. He suggested that the wording
be made less tentative: for example, "treatments that work should
be made to work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Gordon</ENAMEX> proposed that the recommendations address the
issue of financing and suggested the following phrase, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX>
should also identify the most effective and cost-effective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX> and delivery mechanisms (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">provider types</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>)." She said this type of information is absolutely
critical for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> whether research on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> interventions
had to be done in a specific clinical setting in order for
interventions provided in that setting to qualify for
reimbursement. He also asked how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> distinguishes between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prevention</ENAMEX> and treatment for the purposes of authorizing
reimbursement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> explained that because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> is prohibited by statute
from covering preventive services, it must draw a distinction
between treatment and prevention. The kind of information insurers
require to cover these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> includes necessary frequency of
treatment, types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> best suited to provide treatment, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ironclad</ENAMEX> case that the intervention is effective, a consensus in
the professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> around the intervention, and an ability
to guard against the potential for fraud and abuse.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> added the notion that demonstrations of effectiveness in
primary care settings, in the eyes of policymakers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX>, are
not tantamount to demonstrating cost-effectiveness in emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>, underscoring the importance of research in that
setting.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> agreed.
Recommendation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX> is needed to evaluate the effects of
legal, privacy, confidentiality, regulatory, and human subjects
issues on screening and interventions for alcohol problems among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> praised the recommendation for addressing a very important
issue. However, he thought the human subjects aspect might not
belong, because human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> issues will not affect screening and
intervention on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis in the clinical setting. They only
affect research studies.
Bombardier suggested that in addition to evaluation, this
research should develop ways to mitigate legal, privacy, and
confidentiality problems associated with screening and
treatment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Mahoney</ENAMEX> said the recommendation should be worded to focus on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. For example, she indicated that the
concerns institutional and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> have about
reimbursement or legal, privacy, and confidentiality issues
influence whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> receive screening and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hargarten</ENAMEX> commented that this area has the potential to cause
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consternation</ENAMEX> and divisiveness, so it will require a great deal of
textual commentary to tease out the important issues that it
addresses. He noted that alcohol screening in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> is currently
being discussed on the "ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circuit</ENAMEX>." He suggested that perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethics</ENAMEX> should be added to the recommendation.
Recommendation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX> is needed on how demographic and
cultural attributes of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>, and
interventionists influence the success of screening and
interventions for alcohol problems.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hargarten</ENAMEX> said there should be some reference in the
recommendations to the high-risk environment in which these people
live and work and visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. He wondered if this recommendation
was the appropriate place.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Sommers</ENAMEX> noted that different clinical settings can
profoundly influence how screening and intervention is delivered.
She cited differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Level</ENAMEX> I trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and community
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. She suggested that the influence of setting be made
explicit somewhere in the recommendations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Moore</ENAMEX> indicated that these differences can also influence
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and clinicians tailor interventions to apply to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with different cultural attributes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li</ENAMEX> suggested that co-<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characteristics</ENAMEX> could also have a large impact on the success of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>.
Recommendation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX> is needed to identify the factors
that foster the organizational and practitioner behavior changes
needed to institutionalize screening and intervention for alcohol
problems among <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> urged that this research not be confined to academic
medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, but be designed and carried out in partnerships
with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, particularly community-level <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>.
She believed that this should be in the recommendation, not just
supporting text, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> would want to know how screening
and intervention can be implemented into clinical practice when
considering grant applications.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Lowe</ENAMEX> suggested a range of research topics could come
under this recommendation. Who should do interventions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>?
How should ED interventions be linked to the primary care and
public health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>? Which services should be provided in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
and which should be provided elsewhere? How can referrals be
effectively accomplished? How can interventions be paid for? He
suggested wording for the supporting text for this recommendation.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX> in this category may address a broad range of
organizational issues-from the structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and screening
treatment services within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> to the relationship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of primary care and the organizational and fiscal
factors affecting that relationship. This research is crucial as
the field progresses from evaluating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">efficacy</ENAMEX> in research settings
to examining effectiveness in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the current</TIMEX>, complex health care
delivery system."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babor</ENAMEX> supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowe</ENAMEX>'s revision and suggested adding the word
"implementation" to the recommendation. Research is needed on how
to implement and institutionalize these programs. Factors to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">explored</ENAMEX> range from practitioner behavior and practice guidelines
to policy changes that are needed to facilitate implementation of
screening and intervention in these settings. If this
recommendation is too narrowly defined, we will encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
look at small things like training programs. However, no matter how
strong a training program is, if there are no incentives for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> to use the training or the legal restrictions are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insurmountable</ENAMEX> or the health care system is in total chaos and you
cannot find who is in charge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> because somebody has
bought out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, you will have difficulty implementing an
intervention.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rostenberg</ENAMEX> noted that most trauma care is delivered in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> in that setting often do not
relate to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Level</ENAMEX> I trauma care research. Therefore, he supported
including community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> in research efforts. He thought the
biggest barrier was how to change the culture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> so that
staff would ask screening questions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ries</ENAMEX> thought that the recommendations should encourage studying
outcomes that are important to medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, such as health
care outcomes and recidivism, rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use outcomes.
Hargarten related that a recent survey found that almost
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> in community settings. He
thought that encouraging this linkage in research proposals could
help increase this proportion. He also suggested that involving
opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the field of emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> could help
reduce the lag time between academic research showing the
effectiveness of an intervention and broad implementation in
non-academic, clinical settings.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Perry</ENAMEX> believed that the recommendation was not yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>. Hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> merit mention because they
are key to wide implementation. She thought state and federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">policymakers</ENAMEX> should also be included in the statement. She observed
that institutionalizing new practices was just the beginning of the
task. Once they are in place, the program needs to be maintained.
She wondered what factors influenced maintenance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Lenaghan</ENAMEX> suggested that clinicians need recommendations
about what could be accomplished now. They need to know that
screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> and that the sooner screening is implemented the
sooner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with alcohol problems can receive help. She noted
that collaboration with community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and public health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
is appropriate for alcohol problems because they are not just
present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. She said that such collaboration has contributed
to the success of domestic violence screening across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bombardier</ENAMEX> noted that barriers exist among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> within
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> as well as among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. He advocated developing
information systems that follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> so that data collected in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> can be used later.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Maio</ENAMEX> suggested defining the unique role of the emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> in the overall picture of treating alcohol problems.
What can the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> do that cannot be done in other
settings?
Soderstrom suggested that the term "practitioner" in this
recommendation needs to be clarified because it can mean anyone who
takes care of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX>, and
others.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> clearly need
specialized treatment and that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with hazardous
drinking need out-patient counseling. He said if access to that
counseling is not available, screening and interventions are less
likely to happen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. He called for research on barriers
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> face in getting further care for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
with alcohol problems.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hargarten</ENAMEX> wondered about supporting text that calls for
policy-relevant research to institutionalize and to promote
organizational changes. He suggested that research on ways of
paying for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> could be an important factor in promoting
and institutionalizing changes.
Recommendation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX> is needed to explore and define the
role of information technology in facilitating screening and
intervention for alcohol problems among <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> asked whether other forms of technology should be
included, such as audio tape headsets.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Williams</ENAMEX> suggested the phrase "information and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> technology." She said that these technologies can
assist in follow-up and continuity of care.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ries</ENAMEX> commented that educational videos in waiting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> can be
helpful.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hargarten</ENAMEX> added that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tele-medicine</ENAMEX> has a role in making the
booster intervention a reality.
Recommendation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> should support research on
screening and interventions for alcohol problems among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> patients
and make the mechanisms of research supportknown to potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> in emergency medicine.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Longabaugh</ENAMEX> wanted the recommendation to include research
training as an explicit component. He said that it has been
difficult to get good, physician <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s
post-doctoral program in intervention and treatment research.
However, the program has produced a great deal of research.
Mechanisms to facilitate the training of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>,
particularly ones from emergency medicine, are needed and should be
encouraged.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hargarten</ENAMEX> added that training mechanisms should not be limited
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>. He suggested including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhDs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diesenhaus</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are required to fund different
types of research. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAMHSA</ENAMEX> funds applied research, and their
application pro-<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX> is oversubscribed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> felt that the recommendation placed too much
responsibility on funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. He suggested the recommendation
encourage the emergency medicine academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to help its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> find other funding opportunities. He thought there were
many opportunities through other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that should be
tapped.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello</ENAMEX> said he has long supported placing a priority on
research in this area. However, funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> cannot be forced
to accept this. He agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> that professional societies
should be clear about funding opportunities. At the same time, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> indicate many missed opportunities for treatment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>.
For some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> visit is the only contact with the
medical care system. It can be their only opportunity for
intervention, and injuries are the most common events that bring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into contact with the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. We can present a
strong case that work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> should be a high priority.
Pollock suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> visits are crucial opportunities, and
the supporting text for this recommendation can make that clear. It
is possible to emphasize this topic without stating that it should
take precedence over other issues or have a certain amount of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> devoted to it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hungerford</ENAMEX> thought that work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> needed a higher priority
and more resources if the field is to move forward.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> asked for a more specific definition of
"prioritization." It is unfortunate, but in the eyes of funders, it
is perceived as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> sum game.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> suggested that the supporting text for this
recommendation would have to explain the need for political
commitment to changing the health and social outcomes resulting
from alcohol problems.
Hargarten suggested that we do not have to ask federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
to make research on alcohol problems in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> a high priority.
Instead, we could recommend that, compared with other settings, the
prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems among <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> makes it worthy of
careful consideration. We can also recommend that research efforts
should include an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> focus and that emergency medicine experts
should be included in the grant review process. This strategy would
attempt to broaden the focus of current research activities to
include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Longabaugh</ENAMEX> commented that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIAAA</ENAMEX> effort to conduct research on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spirituality</ENAMEX> and addiction came about by setting aside funds
specifically for this topic. He said the way to accomplish this is
to find and work with agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> interested in the topic. He
believed that data on the prevalence and severity of alcohol
problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX> can have a major impact.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ries</ENAMEX> agreed and suggested that this recommendation should
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">promote ED</ENAMEX>-based research by emphasizing the large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> affected by alcohol problems and the significant health
care impact of those problems.
Fiellin suggested the recommendation should ask for a level of
support that is commensurate with the burden of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello</ENAMEX> pointed out that the literature includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">randomized</ENAMEX> trials on brief interventions in family and general
practice settings. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in press) are in emergency medicine.
The emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harborview</ENAMEX> probably sees <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> times as
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with alcohol problems as the psychiatry or family
medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>. If we were to choose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place to set up a
screening system to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need interventions, it should
be the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. He said there needs to be a shift in
priorities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Dufour</ENAMEX> described how NIAAA sets research priorities. To
secure some funding for this conference, she had to "compete" with
other conferences, which indicates that this issue is high on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIAAA</ENAMEX> list of priorities. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIAAA</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Advisory Council</ENAMEX>
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> that helps to set research priorities.
Interacting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is an important way to influence
research priorities, she said. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every three to five years</TIMEX>, NIAAA
reviews its whole research portfolio; it identifies gaps, which
become research priorities. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> and injury, as well as brief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>, are on the list. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIAAA</ENAMEX> is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> with
more priorities than money.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> suggested that the recommendation remain as is, but that
the supporting text list ways that priorities could be changed.
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use is also an important issue among <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, he
thought combining <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and drug research in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX> could lead to
more research dollars. He noted a growing understanding of the
importance of screening for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> together. To
appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIDA</ENAMEX>, he said, the referral aspect of the research should
be strong because of their focus on treatment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diesenhaus</ENAMEX> agreed that both support from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and
the "burden of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>" argument could be influential. He said that
demand for research in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX> from outside an agency would also be
important. He suggested that conference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> needed to
interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that influence policy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gentilello</ENAMEX> acknowledged that there is a demand problem. The goal
is to help trauma surgeons and emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> realize that
dealing with alcohol problems is an integral part of their job.
Research on alcohol problems is as important as research on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPR</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> web site, he found no information on
alcohol-related research in the surgery section. It was all in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> section, which surgeons do not explore. If we want surgeons
to become interested, it should be repeated in the surgery
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Longabaugh</ENAMEX> remarked that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> is increasingly trying to
individualize the routing of grant applications so that study
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are a matter of public record. If a study section
does not include a relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>, then a cover letter with the
grant application can request such an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li</ENAMEX> suggested that adding a reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Healthy People</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>
objective to reduce alcohol-related injury and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> visits by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX>
might enhance the rationale for more research.
General comments about the recommendations
After <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> had given extensive feedback on specific
proposed recommendations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hungerford</ENAMEX> asked if they had general
comments about the recommendations overall.
Fiellin reflected on increasing information about the biological
basis for addictive disorders, the increasing effectiveness of
pharmacotherapy, and the fact that we are trying look at these
disorders the same way we look at chronic medical conditions like
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. He asked whether we might initiate
pharmocotherapy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with alcohol-related problems in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ED</ENAMEX>, much like we initiate use of oral hypoglycemics and
anti-hypertensives with some type of follow-up.




