



Session 3.
Intervening with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcohol Problems</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergency Settings</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlo C. DiClemente</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PhD* Carl Soderstrom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>
Excessive alcohol consumption plays an important role in many of
the medical conditions, accidents, and injuries that cause visits
to emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. Many studies have
documented the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> admitted to
emergency depart<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-ment1-5</ENAMEX> and trauma center6,7 settings. Other
studies have demonstrated that even blood alcohol concentration
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX>) determinations under-estimate the extent of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems
among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who are triaged and treated in emergency
settings<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4,7</NUMEX> The prevalence of this co-factor to the emergency
admission, and the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is a risk factor both for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> visit and for a return visit to the emergency setting, have
occasioned a call for an effective method of intervening with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems in these settings<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> Although there are problems
with and barriers to intervening in these settings, a number of
studies and a few controlled trials indicate that interventions
focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' drinking can reduce the amount of drinking as
well as injury episodes, including repeat re-admission for injury
and other negative consequences of drinking. This review will
examine the rationale for intervening, types of interventions and
interveners, and barriers and concerns that need to be addressed.
Then we will offer suggestions for research and practice related to
intervening effectively with alcohol problems in emergency
settings.
Motivational considerations
The rationale for interventions in the emergency setting is that
the medical condition or injury prompting admission provides a
"window of opportunity" when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> may be more vulnerable
and more open to seeing the connection between current consequences
and his or her drinking or drug abuse and may be more motivated to
change<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
* <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presenter</ENAMEX>
The presence of an adverse consequence that can be linked to
drinking-such as gastrointestinal, vascular, renal, or other
medical problem; an automobile crash; unintentional injury; or
involvement in a violent incident-facilitates intervention among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with alcohol problems encountered in the emergency
setting. In an emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>) study of injured crash
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> who had been drinking, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherpitel</ENAMEX> found that more than
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> linked their drinking to being injured and thus were
deemed good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for "brief intervention."16 In another study
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sommers</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">colleagues15</TIMEX> involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trauma centers</ENAMEX>, patients
who were injured in vehicular crashes and had a positive BAC were
asked, "To what extent do you believe your alcohol consumption was
responsible for this injury<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" Overall, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62%</NUMEX> attributed being injured
either "somewhat" (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24%</NUMEX>) or "mostly" or "totally" (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38%</NUMEX>) to be the
result of drinking. This attribution may be less endorsed with
medical conditions such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">liver disease</ENAMEX> or pancreatitis.
Whether this awareness is viewed as a "hitting bottom"
phenomenon or in more traditional motivational terms, there does
seem to be a connection between readiness to change and recognition
that negative consequences can be directly linked to a behavior<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX>
Reports from emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and anecdotal descriptions of some
interventions support the results of the above studies, indicating
heightened motivation in the initial period of time in the
emergency setting. However, it is not clear how long this initial
openness to change lasts. There are also reports that after a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of days</TIMEX>, spurred by concerns about legal responsibility,
family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> advice, or rationalizations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> openness to
discuss drinking and other problem behaviors decreases
dramatically.
We do know that alcohol consumption changes for many problem
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drinkers</ENAMEX> after their visit to an emergency setting. Several studies
have documented consumption changes not only in the intervention
condition but also in the minimal intervention control groups<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.18,19</NUMEX>
However, changes in alcohol consumption are often not sustained
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in control conditions. After the emergency
visit, there seems to be a reduction in drinking that gradually
returns to baseline problematic levels for many untreated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
Changes in drinking that are produced simply by the visit to the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> seem to dissipate without an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-specific
intervention<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.18</NUMEX> Although there may be some
natural or unaided salutary effect on drinking resulting from
the medical emergency or injury and the ensuing visit to the
emergency setting<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,20</NUMEX> that effect appears to be short-lived for many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>-injury and readmission to an emergency or other medical
setting is much greater for problem drinkers than for other
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.12 It is clear from the literature that without
some intervention that can facilitate enduring reductions in
drinking, simply giving medical treatment alone to the problem
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drinker</ENAMEX> admitted to the emergency setting will not reduce the rates
of re-admission or prevent re-injury related to alcohol
consumption. Although it is still not clear what the nature and
extent of the intervention must be, some type of intervention
specifically for drinking needs to be given.
Interventions in the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>: a review
Various types of interventions have been proposed and examined
for the emergency medical setting (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). These range from
brief interventions delivered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> to more extensive
counseling during the admission that includes referral to intensive
treatment after discharge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> conducted a
pilot intervention at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> that consisted
of a substance abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> mobilizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and at times
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, to intervene with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s drinking and to
arrange for immediate entry to a residential substance abuse
treatment program after discharge. This program appeared to be
successful in getting problem-drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to treatment, but
only with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who could be engaged and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> or insurance.21 This and other seminal studies encouraged
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> to call for some type of consultation service or
brief intervention to be employed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in emergency rooms
or trauma settings<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13,22</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
Many of the early studies that documented the efficacy of
interventions with problem drinkers in emergency settings were
evaluations and not controlled studies. Nevertheless, the
documented outcomes have been impressive. Several studies have
examined the outcomes achieved by substance abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> intervening with problem drinkers. A brief
intervention in an emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> by alcohol health workers
demonstrated a mean reduction in drinking of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43%</NUMEX> for a subset of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were enrolled in the study.26 The pilot
program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> described above demonstrated a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> successful
referral to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> treatment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who
agreed to be in the program<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.21</NUMEX> A substance abuse consultation team
in a trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> reported acceptance of referral for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> treatment in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62%</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> consecutive cases
retrospectively evaluated<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemphill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watkins</ENAMEX>
reported successful referral of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to treatment with nearly
half of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> referred for treatment remaining for the
duration of the treatment program<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">.28 Early</TIMEX> reports of screening and
referral of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have been promising in terms of reduction in
drinking or in successful connection with appropriate alcohol
treatment programs<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29,30</NUMEX> For the most part, these interventions
have used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood alcohol</ENAMEX> concentration as one of the critical
defining features in screening for the intervention.
Interventions for drinking problems have also been successful in
reducing re-injury. In a recent review of intervention trials for
problem drinking that measured injury outcomes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dinh-Zarr</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> studies that measured injury outcomes
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in a variety of settings. They reported that
reductions in a variety of injuries, injury hospitalizations, and
deaths ranged from a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX> reduction in "drinking-related injuries
and accidents" to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX> reduction in "accidental and violent
deaths."31 However, in this review there was no clear evidence that
the mechanism of action of these interventions was reduced alcohol
consumption. These interventions appeared to affect risk taking in
addition to or instead of reductions in drinking and included
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who had legal charges pending. Most of the studies
reviewed were not well controlled and the numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
and effect sizes reported in these studies were modest.
Until recently, no well-controlled intervention studies have
addressed whether interventions in emergency settings would reduce
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> consumption and consequences. Several current publications
have begun to remedy this lack of prospective, randomized trials.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harborview Medical Center</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, conducted a randomized controlled trial in a
Level I trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> who screened positive on a
combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood alcohol</ENAMEX> concentration (BAC), serum <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma</ENAMEX>
glutamyl transpeptidase (GGT), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMAST</ENAMEX> scores, and who agreed to
a follow-up study, were randomized into an intervention or control
procedure. The intervention was a single motivational interview
that lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 30 minutes</TIMEX> with
a doctoral-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> trained and certified in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motivational</ENAMEX> interviewing techniques. A letter was sent summarizing
this session <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month later</TIMEX>. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">366</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were randomly
assigned to the intervention condition, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 15%</NUMEX> of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were discharged before the intervention could be given,
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 2%</NUMEX> refused the intervention. At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-month</TIMEX> follow-up,
the intervention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> demonstrated an average reduction in
drinking of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> compared with a reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> per week for the control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Most of the drinking
reduction occurred among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with mild to moderate alcohol
problems and not in the heaviest drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">subgroup</ENAMEX>. There were also
significant reductions in new injuries of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50%</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> and
a reduction in inpatient hospital re-admissions for injury
treatment of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> follow-up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> suggest
that this type of intervention alone is insufficient for patients
with more chronic and severe alcohol dependence. Another limitation
of this seminal study is that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were lost to
follow-up at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX>. However, this trial demonstrates that a
rather brief intervention delivered by a trained professional in
the emergency setting can produce significant reductions in
drinking and repeat injury episodes.
A controlled trial of a similar motivational intervention with
older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 18 to 19 years</TIMEX> treated in an emergency room
following an alcohol-related event randomly assigned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">184</NUMEX>
eligible patients<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> were assigned to a motivational
intervention or a standard control of a handout about drinking and
driving and a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The intervention,
which lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 to 40 minutes</TIMEX>, was delivered in the emergency
department either immediately or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a couple of days</TIMEX> of the
visit. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 25%</NUMEX> of the eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were discharged before
the intervention and another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> refused to participate.
Nevertheless, drinking and driving, moving violations,
alcohol-related injuries, and alcohol-related problems were
significantly reduced at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six-month</TIMEX> follow up, with the
intervention group experiencing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third to one-half</NUMEX> fewer events
than the control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Although drinking decreased over time for
both intervention and control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, their drinking levels were
not significantly different. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bachelor</ENAMEX>'s or master's level staff
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>' of experience and extensive motivational
interview training delivered this intervention.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Follow-up</ENAMEX> was limited to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>, so this study would have
missed any rebound back to baseline at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later time</TIMEX> points, and the
refusal rate was rather high in this study. However, the evidence
was strong for a harm reduction effect across various indicators of
risk and re-injury.
Who delivers what type of intervention
Most of the interventions described previously were conducted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> trained in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or substance abuse counseling or in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motivational</ENAMEX> interviewing techniques. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interventionists</ENAMEX> met
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, discussed drinking and substance use openly and
directly, and offered some advice and assistance. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Substance</ENAMEX> abuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> typically offered advice and referrals to treatment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> or self-help programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motivational</ENAMEX> interview counselors
typically discussed the perceived consequences, readiness to
change, pros and cons of change, and plans to reduce drinking and
avoid alcohol-related injuries in the future. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Substance</ENAMEX> abuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type or another typically delivered drinking
interventions in emergency settings with a few exceptions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29,30</NUMEX> No
studies have compared different types of intervention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> in
these settings.
In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> in a variety of primary care
settings have delivered brief alcohol-focused interventions. These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX> also appear to be effective in reducing drinking and
risky behaviors<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20,32,33 One</NUMEX> recent study demonstrated that a
brief, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>-centered alcohol counseling intervention delivered
in the context of a regularly scheduled internal medicine visit
produced significant reductions in alcohol consumption among both
male and female high-risk drinkers<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.34</NUMEX> Based on these interventions
in other medical settings, a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have recommended
the involvement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> in the emergency setting in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> intervention<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9,26,35,36</NUMEX> However, few studies of
physician-delivered interventions in an emergency setting exist.
Clearly, none of the extant studies could be done without the
support and involvement of emergency medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> and trauma
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surgeons</ENAMEX>. However, it may be difficult to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> to deliver
these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-focused interventions for a variety of practical,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philosophical</ENAMEX>, orientation, and training reasons.
To some degree, all interventions described in the emergency
setting are motivational. Each intervention attempts to highlight
problematic alcohol consumption, the connection between injury and
drinking,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> plans to address excessive drinking. Prototypic
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> abuse interventions focus on motivation to enter
treatment because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are severely dependent, heavy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drinkers</ENAMEX>. Referral to "appropriate" treatment is the critical end
point of this type of intervention and compliance with the referral
the important outcome. Change of drinking and risky behaviors is
left to the treatment program, and almost always, abstinence from
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is the goal of these treatment programs.37 On the other
hand, motivational interviewing approaches view change as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> and responsibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and work with the
individual at whatever level of motivation or stage of change is
appropriate to promote consideration of change and an
individualized plan of action that does not necessarily include
additional treatment or self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alcoholics Anonymous</ENAMEX>.
Brief motivational interventions have been used with a wide range
of problem drinkers and have been found to be effective in reducing
drinking and its consequences<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.38</NUMEX> Goals for this treatment are
articulated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and can include reduction as well as
abstinence from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>.
Nearly all interventions delivered in emergency settings consist
of a single intervention visit. It is difficult to prescribe
multiple visits unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> is admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> from
the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> or has an extended stay in a trauma
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have suggested that the follow-up visit to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> for extended treatment would be the best place for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> interventions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.25</NUMEX> However, postponing intervention to the
follow-up visit poses great logistical problems. Scheduling of
follow-up visits depends on type of medical problem or injury.
Moreover, these visits are not consistently attended by the patient
or delivered by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> who saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in the
initial visit to the emergency setting. Although many single-visit
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol interventions</ENAMEX> in medical settings have been effective<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,32</NUMEX>
the context of the emergency setting does increase the importance
of considering follow through after the initial contact. Gentilello
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> sent a letter home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> after discharge as a
reminder of the intervention conversation<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.18</NUMEX> A currently funded
trial at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland Shock Trauma Center</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> is using a feedback letter and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more follow-up
phone calls to extend the intervention beyond the emergency setting
interview. This extension into the post-discharge period is most
relevant for interventions that do not rely completely
on referral to treatment. However, post-discharge follow-up
could also be used to solve problems related to treatment
recommendations and enhance compliance with the
recommendations.
Issues and challenges for interventions in emergency
settings
Substantial evidence indicates that interventions with problem
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drinkers</ENAMEX> in emergency settings can produce significant change in
drinking behavior and/or reduce risk of re-injury. The number of
studies that have demonstrated effects either with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer</ENAMEX> or
randomized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> is modest but increasing, and the effects
range from minimal to very sizeable reduction in risks that have
significant public health importance. Evaluation and referral
interventions have been able to get a number of emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and trauma center <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> into alcoholism
treatment<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29,30</NUMEX> It is not always clear whether there were long-term
positive outcomes from these trials since referral has been the
outcome variable most often studied. However, one can assume that
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> referred to treatment had very positive outcomes in
terms of reductions in drinking and of risk profiles. Motivational
interventions in emergency settings have more recently demonstrated
important clinical outcomes in terms of risk-taking, negative
consequences of drinking, and, at times, reductions in
drink-ing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.18,19</NUMEX> The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> who were not screened,
who refused, who were discharged early, or who were ineligible was
large in some studies. However, when the intervention was delivered
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in emergency settings and compared with standard or
minimal interventions, intervention <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had significantly
better outcomes on relevant measures. It is important to note that
minimal interventions are not insignificant since they include, of
necessity, an assessment of drinking behavior and a follow-up
contact, and they are often much more than ordinarily occurs in the
emergency setting. Screening or assessment alone, however, does not
appear to be as effective as some type of specific
intervention.
Bringing research to practice
This review of interventions, focused on addressing alcohol
problems among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in various medical settings, highlights
several important issues and offers a perspective on the challenges
to creating sustained, effective intervention programs in the
emergency setting. Strategies and
insights from clinical trials should be gathered and made
available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> to help every emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and
trauma center implement a coordinated, effective, and feasible
program of screening and intervention for problem drinkers.
However, several conceptual and practical issues need to be
clarified so they can be resolved in a future research and
implementation agenda.
Although an opportunity exists to intervene with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who
have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use problems, and there are published guidelines for
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> concerning intervention,
that opportunity has not been seized<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8,9,35,39</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> noted that although "trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are uniquely
positioned to implement pro-<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">grams</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> screening,
intervention, and referral," and "despite emphasis on injury
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and prevention, little has been done to incorporate alcohol
intervention programs into care of the injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>."10 This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation</ENAMEX> was based in part on the results of a national survey
of trauma centers which revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood alcohol</ENAMEX> testing, which
is often a precursor for any intervention, was routinely conducted
at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 64%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> despite a published guideline by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Trauma of the American College of Surgeons</ENAMEX> indicating
that testing was an "essential" characteristic for those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>.40
The survey also found that although <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5%</NUMEX> used screening questionnaires
to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use problems.
Although we know of no studies assessing clinical practices
regarding alcohol problems in emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, a survey of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,055</NUMEX> emergency medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> found
that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> favored testing and reporting injured,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-impaired drivers<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.41</NUMEX> However, ambivalent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> were
revealed concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. On a scale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>
(strongly disagree) to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7</NUMEX> (strongly agree) the statement "alcoholics
are difficult to treat" received a mean score of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.25</NUMEX>, and the
statement "<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> is a treat-able disease" received a mean
score of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.27</NUMEX>. In an earlier report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astrachan</ENAMEX> documented
low BAC testing rates for intoxicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> by emergency
department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>.42 One of the reasons they cited was
"defeatism about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>." In a recent survey of
emergency medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> agreed that alcohol
abuse/dependence is a "treatable <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>," but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 90%</NUMEX>
indicated that there was a lack of time to perform interventions,
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 51%</NUMEX> supported
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> interventions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.43</NUMEX> These attitudes and
practices are similar to those found in a national survey of
physicians practicing internal medicine, family medicine,
obstetrics-gynecology, and psychia-try<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.44</NUMEX> Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> reported
asking about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use but few used recommended screening
protocols or offered formal treatment.
The first challenge for implementing recommended screening and
interventions for problem drinking in emergency settings involves
convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of the importance and efficacy of such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>. Although the research to date supports the efficacy
of these interventions, clinical trials are needed to confirm these
findings and to set the stage for the next logical step of
effectiveness studies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feasibility</ENAMEX> and successful dissemination
must be demonstrated. Prototype interventions that can reach the
majority of problem drinkers, motivate them to change drinking
patterns or enter appropriate treatment, and produce positive
long-term outcomes should be introduced into several emergency
settings of differing size and staff composition. These multi-site
effectiveness studies can then be used to promote change in
standard practice in all emergency settings.
What we have learned from the research to date gives us some
direction as to how to implement interventions in emergency
settings to reduce drinking and alcohol related risks. The first
step to developing an effective and efficient intervention program
would be to create a screening procedure integrated into the
admission and triage system of the emergency settings. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX>
problems can be identified along a range of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use and
consequences. However, it is important to clarify what type of
problem interveners are attempting to address. The screening
procedure can have a net with larger or smaller mesh that can be
set for more or less severe alcohol problems. However, whatever the
titration of the screen, the procedure must be clearly delineated
and uniformly applied to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> admitted to the emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> or trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. The primary screen must be integrated
into the standard intake procedure of the emergency setting and
must be the responsibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to administer to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
This preliminary screen should trigger a more in-depth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX> and a brief intervention that can be delivered either
separately or as a package (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The assessment is critical
for evaluating motivation
and decisional considerations and for determining the need for
and appropriateness of referrals to treatment. The success of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motivational</ENAMEX> and patient-centered approaches seems to indicate that
it is critical to take into account the motivation of the patient
and his or her readiness to change<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.24,25</NUMEX> Once motivated, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> may need a variety of options depending on the nature of
the alcohol problem and the needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. Many treatment
providers believe that intensity of treatment should be determined
by level of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problem, although controlled trials do not
always support the assumption. Greater dependence and,
particularly, greater support for drinking in the environment, may
indicate a need for more intensive treatment, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detoxification</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inpatient</ENAMEX> or residential treatment, or intensive
day treatment. Self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alcoholics Anonymous</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sobriety</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rational Recovery</ENAMEX>; outpatient treatments; and
guided self-change45 may also be appropriate for a wide range of
drinking problems. In any case, the broader the net cast by the
screening instrument that identifies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with alcohol
problems, the more flexible and wide-ranging should be the referral
and post-discharge options.
The assessment and intervention could be delivered by a variety
of trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> who have some expertise in motivational
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>, understand alcohol problems, and are armed with a
series of viable options to assist the patient<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.35</NUMEX> The intervention,
by necessity, needs to be brief and limited in contact consisting
of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 to 40 minutes</TIMEX> of interaction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interventions</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> who
conducts them need to be flexible and creative in adapting to
situations created by the injuries and the noisy and often chaotic
nature of emergency settings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communication</ENAMEX> rather than
confrontation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> rather than condemnation, and facilitation
rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> or law enforcement should mark the interventions.
If there is a legal aspect to the case, it should be separated from
the clinical intervention as much as possible. Multiple, feasible
referral options that vary in intensity and scope should be
available as part of the intervention. Since data from other
studies indicate that facilitating the referral and making the
connections increase compliance, the intervention ideally should
have a component of compliance enhancement if it includes referral
to community treatment programs.
Next steps
Research is needed to confirm and extend the findings to date
about interventions in emergency settings. Unresolved questions
about the nature and format of the intervention that could use
input from research are enumerated below.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Should there be several types of interventions for differing
levels of severity? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> with less severe alcohol problems
may benefit from a brief intervention with little or no follow-up
or referral<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> Are there subpopulations that benefit more from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motivational</ENAMEX> or brief interventions?46,47 Should we triage the most
severe problem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> into a more intensive intervention in the
emergency setting? What are the long-term outcomes (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> or
more) of various interventions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> of differing levels of
severity?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Who can best deliver the intervention? How involved should
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s attending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> in the medical treatment be in
the intervention for alcohol problems? Most emergency department
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> do not believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> would be the
best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> to provide effective treatment<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.42</NUMEX> There are a variety
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> that could be trained to deliver the intervention
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>, social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX>. However, it may be more a matter of
skill and ability to work in this setting and deliver the needed
type of intervention rather than of profession that should
determine who should deliver the intervention.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Should the intervention include the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>? Are family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> a help or hindrance in the intervention? Family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> can be of significant assistance in the intervention<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.48</NUMEX>
However, they can also interfere with the interview by suggesting
non-cooperation, interfering with the candidness of the
self-report, and trying to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> from the
intervention in some misguided attempt to help. Including family
should be done carefully and thoughtfully, if at all.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. What are the constraints regarding the timing of the
intervention? Must the intervention occur in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 24 hours</TIMEX> or
can it be included in discharge planning and delivered after
discharge? We need to know more about the closing of this "window
of opportunity" and whether delay interferes with motivation.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. How can emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> be trained to facilitate the
screening and intervention? Would particular approaches to training
be more effective in reaching emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. How does extent of injury or severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> affect the
intervention? It is clear that some injuries create barriers to
intervention in the emergency setting. Is a separate protocol
needed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who are admitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for surgery
or other medical treatments that necessitate a hospital stay?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Should all interventions triage and intervene based on
patient readiness to change? The perspective of the stages of
change <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> appears to be an appealing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
interventionist under-stand the process of change for addictive and
health behavior<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.49,50</NUMEX> Incorporating this perspective into
interventions in the emergency setting has been suggested by
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>.24,25
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Are there significant policy issues that must be resolved to
make interventions for alcohol problems more feasible? For example,
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> do not routinely obtain a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BAC</ENAMEX> test because of a
fear of denial of payment for medical care by third-party payors
for injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who test positive. This fear is well grounded.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rivara</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in a survey of insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> found
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> indicated that intoxication at the time
of injury allowed for exclusion of coverage<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.51</NUMEX> A review of state
statutes, including those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>, revealed
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have a provision that allows third-party payors to
issue policies that deny payment for injuries sustained while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intoxicated</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rivara</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> note, "this option seems
to be enforced rarely by most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>," we are aware of anecdotal
reports of emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that have
ceased testing because of the fears of non-payment. However, our
inquiry to billing department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Shock Trauma</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, which admits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 6,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, revealed not a
single case of denial of payment.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. There is also a need for health services research to examine
technology transfer and explore ways to disseminate research
findings to emergency settings of differing size and complexity.
Implementation is as important as the intervention in these
settings. Unless screening and
intervention becomes an integral part of the emergency triage
and treatment system, it will be an appendage that will be
inconsistently applied or tried and discarded. An intervention
template with options incorporating the alcohol problem
intervention into the various settings should be developed and
evaluated.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. As we have indicated, guidelines and best practices have
been published that deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> dependence and abuse and
emergency medicine. The challenge now is to discover how government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> can promote adoption and
implementation of intervention guidelines.
The opportunity
A combination of basic research, program implementation and
evaluation studies, and policy and procedure evaluations are needed
to resolve the issues outlined previously. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
Zuska, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> with an interest in alcohol problems among injured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> noted: "The crisis that brings the alcoholic to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surgeon</ENAMEX> is an opportunity for intervention in a progressive, often
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fatal disease</ENAMEX>."<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52 More</NUMEX> recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Substance Abuse Task Force</ENAMEX>
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Academic Emergency Medicine</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>'Onofrio
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> emphasized that in the emergency department setting,
"Early intervention and appropriate referral of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems have the potential to reduce alcohol-related
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and mortality."<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> An accumulating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of evidence
supports these calls for intervention. However, systemic and
practical barriers must be overcome and additional research
conducted to take full advantage of this opportunity.
References
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherpitel CJ</ENAMEX>. Screening for alcohol problems in the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">158-66</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Degutis LC</ENAMEX>. Screening for alcohol problems in emergency
department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with minor injury: results and recommendations
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> and policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Drug Problems</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">463-75</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing JA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Detecting alcoholism</ENAMEX>: the CAGE questionnaire. JAMA
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">252:1905-7</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maio RF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waller PF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blow FC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill EM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer KM</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX>
abuse/dependence in motor vehicle crash <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> presenting to the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acad Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:256-62</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whiteman PJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman RS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldfrank LR</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alcoholism</ENAMEX> in the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>: an epidemiologic study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acad Emerg Med</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:14-20</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rivara FP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkovich GJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gurney JG</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seguin</ENAMEX> D, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fligner CL</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ries R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raisys VA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copass M.</ENAMEX> The magnitude of acute and chronic
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> abuse in trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch Surg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">128:907-13</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soderstrom CA, Smith GS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dischinger</ENAMEX> PC, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDuff DR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hebel JR</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorelick DA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al. Psychoactive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> use disorders among
seriously injured trauma center <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. JAMA
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">277</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1769-74</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. D'Onofrio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolard RH, Brewer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Craig SA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zink BJ</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with alcohol problems in the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, part <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: improving detection. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAEM Substance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abuse Task Force</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society for Academic Emergency Medicine</ENAMEX>. Acad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;5(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX>):<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1200-9</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. D'Onofrio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolard RH, Brewer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Craig SA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zink BJ</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with alcohol problems in the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, part <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX> intervention and referral. SAEM
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Substance Abuse Task Force</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society for Academic Emergency</ENAMEX>
Medicine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acad Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;5(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX>):<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1210-7</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello LM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donovan DM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn CW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rivara FP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX>
interventions in trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>: current practice and future
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">274:1043-8</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowenstein SR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Weissberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry D. Alcohol intoxication</ENAMEX>,
injuries, and dangerous behaviors-and the revolving emergency
department door. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Trauma 1990</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1252-8</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. Soderstrom CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole FJ, Porter</ENAMEX> JM. Injury in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>: the
role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>-an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">EAST</ENAMEX> position paper prepared by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Injury Control</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Violence Prevention Committee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Trauma</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>):<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1-12</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dyehouse JM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sommers MS.</ENAMEX> Brief intervention after
alcohol-related injuries. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Substance</ENAMEX> abuse interventions in general
nursing practice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nurs Clin North Am</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>):<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>-104
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longabaugh R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minugh A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nirenberg</ENAMEX> TD, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clifford PR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becker</ENAMEX>
B, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolard R. Injury</ENAMEX> as a motivator to reduce drinking. Acad Emerg
Med <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:817-25</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sommers MS, Dyehouse JM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe SR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lemmink J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis K</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy M</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russlee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AC</ENAMEX>. Attribution of injury to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> involvement in
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
seriously injured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">alcohol-related</TIMEX> motor vehicle crashes.
Am <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Crit Care 2000</ENAMEX>;
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:28-35</TIMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherpitel CJ</ENAMEX>. Drinking patterns and problems and drinking
in the event: an
analysis of injury by cause among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualty</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> Clin Exp
Res <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2:1130-7</ENAMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiClemente</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX>. Motivation for change: implications for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> abuse.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychological Science</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>):<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209-13</NUMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello LM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rivara FP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donovan DM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al. Alcohol</ENAMEX>
interventions in a
trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> as a means of reducing the risk of injury
recurrence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Surg</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">230:473-83</TIMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monti PM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colby SM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnett NP, et</ENAMEX> al. Brief intervention
for harm
reduction with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-positive older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> in a
hospital emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Consult Clin Psychol</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">67</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>):<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">989-94</NUMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lloyd G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crombie E. Counseling</ENAMEX> problem drinkers in
medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wards</ENAMEX>:
a controlled study. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Br</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Med J</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">290:965-7</ENAMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello LM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duggan P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drummond</ENAMEX> D, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> al. Major injury as
a unique
opportunity to initiate treatment in the alcoholic. Am <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX> Surg
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">156:558-61</TIMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El-Guebaly N</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armstrong SJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hodgkins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Substance</ENAMEX> abuse
and the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>: programmatic implications. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Addict Dis</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>):<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21-40</NUMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Madden C</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cole TB</ENAMEX>. Emergency intervention to break the
cycle of drunken
driving and recurrent injury. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>):<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">177-9</ENAMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soderstrom CA, Dischinger</ENAMEX> PC, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerns TJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kufera JA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalea TM</ENAMEX>.
Epidemic increases in concaine and opiate use by trauma
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center patients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Trauma 2001</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">557-64</NUMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith AJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shepherd JP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodgson RJ</ENAMEX>. Brief interventions for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
alcohol-related trauma. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Br</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Oral Maxillofac</ENAMEX> Surg
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">408-15</NUMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright S</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran L</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meyrick M, O'Connor R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Touquet R.</ENAMEX>
Intervention by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in an accident and emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol Alcohol</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>):<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">651-6</ENAMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuller MG</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond DL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan ML</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walters MC</ENAMEX>. The role of a
substance
abuse consultation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in a trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Stud Alcohol</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">267-71</NUMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>. Hemphill C, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett BE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BL</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alcoholism</ENAMEX>: the
response of a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Health</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>):<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-6.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levenson S. Project ASSERT</ENAMEX>: an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ED</ENAMEX>-based intervention to increase access to primary care,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preventive</ENAMEX> services, and the substance abuse treatment system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>):<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">181-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungerford DW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock DA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd KH</ENAMEX>. Acceptability of
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>-based screening and brief interventions for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acad Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1383-92</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dinh-Zarr T</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Diguiseppi C</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heitman E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts I. Preventing</ENAMEX>
injuries through interventions for problem drinking: a systematic
review of randomized controlled trials. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol Alcohol</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">609-21</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleming MF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry KL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manwell LB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson K</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">London R.</ENAMEX>
Brief physician advice for problem <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol drinkers</ENAMEX>: a randomized
controlled trial in community-based primary care practices. JAMA
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">277</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1039-45</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Walsh DC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hingson RW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrigan DM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levenson SM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coffman GA</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heeren T</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cupples LA.</ENAMEX> The impact of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>'s warning on
recovery after <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> treatment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>;267(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>):<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">663-7</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ockene JK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> A, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurley TG</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wheeler EV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hebert JR. Brief</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> practitioner-delivered counseling for high risk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drinkers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch Intern Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">159:2198-2205</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn CW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donovan DM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello LM</ENAMEX>. Practical guidelines
for performing alcohol interventions in trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Trauma</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">299-304</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reyna TM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollis MW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hulsebus RC</ENAMEX>. Alcohol-related trauma:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>'s responsibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Surg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">201:194-7</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller WR</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alcoholism</ENAMEX>: toward a better disease model.
Psychology of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Addiction Behaviors 1993</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:129-35</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bien TH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller WR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonigan JS</ENAMEX>. Brief interventions for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems: a review. Addiction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">88</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">315-36</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Substance Abuse Treatment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Substance Abuse</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental Health Services Administration</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> and Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Screening of Hospitalized Trauma Patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treatment Improvement</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protocol</ENAMEX> (TIP), No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHHS Publication No.</ENAMEX> (SMA) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95-3014</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soderstrom CA, Dailey JT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerns TJ</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>: an assessment of testing and clinical practices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Trauma 1994</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">36:68-73</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astrachan BM, Weil U</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryant K. Reporting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-impaired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>: results from a national survey of
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">284-90</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astrachan BM</ENAMEX>. The emergency department
surveillance of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> intoxication after motor vehicular
accidents. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">260:2533-6</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham DM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maio RF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blow FC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill EM</ENAMEX>. Emergency physician
attitudes concerning intervention for alcohol abuse/dependence in
the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Addict Dis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:45-53</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman PD, McCullough D</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chin MH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saitz R. Screening</ENAMEX> and
interventions for alcohol problems: a national survey of primary
care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Gen Intern Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>;
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15:84-91</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sobel MB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sobel LC</ENAMEX>. Problem <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drinkers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guided Self</ENAMEX>-change
Treatment. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guilford Press</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather N. Interpreting</ENAMEX> the evidence on brief interventions
for excessive drinkers: the need for caution. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol Alcohol</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>):<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">287-96</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poikilainen K. Effectiveness</ENAMEX> of brief interventions to
reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol intake</ENAMEX> in primary health care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>: a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meta</ENAMEX>-analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prev Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">28</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">503-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCrady BS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epstein EE</ENAMEX>. Marital therapy in the treatment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. In: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gurman AS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobson N</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clinical Handbook</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Marital Therapy 1995</ENAMEX>. 2nd <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guilford Press</ENAMEX>;
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 369-93</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiClemente</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prochaska JO</ENAMEX>. Toward a comprehensive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transtheoretical</ENAMEX> model of change: stages of change and addictive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">behaviors</ENAMEX>. In: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller WR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heather N</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Treating Addictive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behaviors</ENAMEX>. 2nd <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plenum</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.3-24</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimmerman GL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olsen CG</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosworth MF</ENAMEX>. A "stages of change"
approach to helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> change behavior. Am <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fam Physician</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">61</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>):<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1409-16</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rivara FP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tollefson S, Tesh E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello LM</ENAMEX>. Screening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trauma patients</ENAMEX> for alcohol problems: are insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
barriers? <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Trauma 2000</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">115-8</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zuska JJ</ENAMEX>. Wounds without cause. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull Am Coll</ENAMEX> Surg
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5-10</NUMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Types</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergency Setting Interventions</ENAMEX>
Brief Advice (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Referral</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Substance Abuse Evaluation and Referral</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motivational Enhancement</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Referral</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Personalized Feedback</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Discharge Contact</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>)

Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
Points of Intervention


Screening
Evaluation

Referral Counseling







Follow-up



Response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlo DiClemente</ENAMEX>'s Presentation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail D'Onofrio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>
I am honored to be a discussant following <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiClemete</ENAMEX>'s
comments about interventions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> presenting to the
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>) with alcohol problems. We have just heard
compelling evidence regarding the efficacy of brief intervention in
a variety of settings including primary care, inpatient trauma
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>, and emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, and for multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>,
ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.
We now know several truths. First, screening and brief
intervention (SBI) does work. A recent evidence-based review of the
literature on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBI</ENAMEX>, conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Degutis</ENAMEX> and me, revealed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> studies (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> randomized controlled and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> cohort) with a positive
effect demonstrated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> of these studies.1 We also know that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> visit offers a potential "teachable moment" due to the possible
negative consequences surrounding it and that in essence we, as
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, have a captive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. In addition, we know
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> presenting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> are likely to need our help more
than those who present to primary care. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherpitel</ENAMEX> recently compared
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> presenting to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> with those presenting to primary care
in the same metropolitan area. She found that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were one
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-half</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times more likely than primary care patients
to report heavy drinking, consequences of drinking, alcohol
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dependence</ENAMEX>, or history of treatment for an alcohol problem<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>
It is now time for us to adapt the information we have learned
from these efficacy trials to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> setting and move on to
effectiveness trials. In doing so, we face unique challenges. These
include time pressures, competing priorities, few formal follow-up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protocols</ENAMEX>, negative attitudes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and a multitude of
systems problems in an environment that at best can be described as
controlled chaos. Perhaps the largest hurdle is the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> have not yet bought into the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBI</ENAMEX> is part of
their role or responsibility.
To be effective, our research strategies must be brief and
clear. In real life, there is not a cadre of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to screen
and administer lengthy interventions. Therefore, protocols must be
capable of being integrated into existing systems with available
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>.
I am going to show you a clip from a video entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The</ENAMEX>
Emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Physician and the Problem Drinker: Motivating Patients</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Change.3 Actual ED</ENAMEX> scenarios are used to demonstrate common
problems or traps that arise when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> attempt to counsel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> about their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use. The intervention featured, the
brief negotiation interview, includes establishing rapport, raising
the subject of problem drinking, providing feedback, and assessing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s readiness to change. Specific strategies to
intervene, based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s readiness to change, are
demonstrated to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> start the process of finding his
or her own solutions to change. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> versions of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>/patient
interaction are depicted: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that is likely to be unsuccessful,
and one that is likely to be successful.
To be successful in developing effectiveness trials in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
setting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> must be very clear about a number of issues
when developing their proposals. These issues include:
Who should be screened?
Should we target certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>-the injured or non-injured;
the at-risk, harmful, or hazardous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drinker</ENAMEX>; or the dependent
drinker? Should we concentrate on the life cycle, from adolescence
to older age, or should we concentrate first on more defined
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>? It is unrealistic to assume that one intervention will
work for everyone.
What should the intervention include?
The message of the intervention is vital. It should be brief,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scripted</ENAMEX>, and reproducible. Exactly what constitutes brief? The
exact time of the intervention should be recorded. What is included
in the intervention should be clearly stated. Should we be sure to
include the acceptable components of brief intervention as outlined
in the acronym FRAMES: feedback, responsibility, advice, menu of
strategies, empathy, and self-efficacy?<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Is making a connection
between drinking and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> visit important? Is there a
prescription or recommendation given to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>? Does the
message include advice or add a component of motivational
enhancement therapy? Does the research protocol monitor adherence
to the message, and how?
Who should provide the screening and intervention?
Which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> actually screens for problems and provides the
intervention? Different sites can be creative about who conducts
the interventions. Is it best done by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, or health
promotion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>?<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Is it possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> can be screened
by completing computer programs while waiting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>, with
results then relayed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>?<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
How can we motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> to change?
What can be done to motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> and other health care
providers to change their behaviors and incorporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBI</ENAMEX> into their
practices? What are the motivators? Are they patient driven so that
documentation of a decrease in recidivism and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and
mortality must be proven to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>? Or are they
tied to reimbursement? Are emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> more likely to
include counseling in their practice if it is a billable service?
What other barriers must be removed or systems changes made before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBI</ENAMEX> is successful in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>? Available resources are essential, as
well as perceived support and role models<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> A great deal of time is
spent developing continuous quality improvement projects in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX> for
problems with far less prevalence. Return visits and deaths are
often tracked. Why not include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with alcohol problems in
this process?
What exactly is included in educational programs for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>?
Standard didactic educational programs have not been shown to
change
physician behavior and subsequently improve patient care<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>
However,
evidence indicates that skills-based interactive sessions can
change practice<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9,10</NUMEX>
How do we measure success?
What outcomes are we measuring? Do they include a decrease in
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> consumption or decreases in negative consequences, such as
drinking and driving violations or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and work problems? A
decrease in morbidity and mortality may be more difficult to
measure and require a lengthy follow-up period, but it provides
much more meaningful data to the practicing emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>. It
is also possible that tracking
referrals to primary care or specialized treatment programs may
be an important outcome. Rates of enrollment in treatment programs
and compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointments</ENAMEX> may be meaningful outcomes.
How long one brief intervention may affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' behavior is
unclear. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> have no formal relationships with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> beyond the index visit, and it is entirely plausible that
the effect of the brief intervention may be short lived. Therefore,
certain outcomes may need to be measured early at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or three</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. However, one may also argue that it is possible that there
may be a "sleeper effect," or delayed emergence of treatment
efficacy, as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O'Malley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carroll</ENAMEX>,11,12 making it
imperative that assessments be continued for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> or more.
All of these questions need to be answered in future studies if
we are to prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBI</ENAMEX> is effective in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> setting. It is
crucial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are clear on all aspects of their research
protocols so that future projects can either replicate or build on
past experiences. These aspects include exclusion and inclusion
criteria, the specifics of the intervention (i.e., what, how, and
by whom), and the specific outcomes to be measured. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adherence</ENAMEX> to
the protocol should also be assured.
In conclusion, there is no "silver bullet," or one exact
intervention that will work for everybody. We must focus on small,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incremental</ENAMEX> steps and realize that the entire process will be a
long one. Fortunately, the number of ideas and research questions
are endless, allowing for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple</ENAMEX> studies and a great deal of
creativity on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>.
References
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. D'Onofrio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Degutis LC</ENAMEX>. Preventative care in the emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>: screening and brief intervention for alcohol problems
in the eergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>: a systematic review. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acad Emerg Med</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>;9(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>):<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">627-38</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherpitel CJ</ENAMEX>. Drinking patterns and problems: a comparison
of primary care with the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Subst Abuse</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20:85-95</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. D'Onofrio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein J. The Emergency</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Physician</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Problem Drinker: Motivating Patients for Change</ENAMEX>.
[videocassette] <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Natick</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marino & Company Production</ENAMEX>;
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller WR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanchez VC</ENAMEX>. Motivating young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> for treatment
and lifestyle change. In: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. Issues in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcohol Use</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Misuse in Young Adults</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX> (IN): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Notre</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dame Press</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55-82</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levenson S. Project ASSERT</ENAMEX>: an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
based intervention to increase access to primary care, preventive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, and the substance abuse treatment system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Emerg Med</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">181-9</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes KV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lauderdale DS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stocking CB, Howes DS, Roizen MF</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinson W. Better</ENAMEX> health while you wait: a controlled trial of a
computer-based intervention for screening and health promotion in
the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">284-91</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartwright AKJ</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> of helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> towards the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alcoholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>: The influence of experience, support, training,
and self-esteem. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Br</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Addict 1980</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">413-31</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis DA, Thamson MA, Oxman AD, Haynes RB</ENAMEX>. Changing
physician performance: a systematic review of the effect of
continuing medical education strategies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">274:700-5</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis D, Obrien MAT, Freemantle N</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> FM, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazmanian P</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor-Vaisy A. Impact</ENAMEX> of formal continuing medical education: do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conferences</ENAMEX>, workshops, rounds, and other traditional continuing
education activities change physician behavior or health care
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">282:867-74</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saitz R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan LM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Samet JH</ENAMEX>. Training community-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinicians</ENAMEX> in screening and brief intervention for substance abuse
problems: translating evidence into practice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Subst Abuse</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:21-31</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O'Malley SS, Jaffe AJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rode S, Schottenfeld R</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meyer RE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rounsaville B.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six-month</TIMEX> follow-up of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naltrexone</ENAMEX> and
psychotherapy for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> dependence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arch Gen Psychiatry</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217-24</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carroll K, Rounsaville BJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nich C</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordon LT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wirtz PW</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gawin F. One-year</ENAMEX> follow-up of psychotherapy and pharmacotherapy
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> dependence: delayed emergency of psychotherapy effects.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arch Gen Psychiatry</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">989-97</NUMEX>.


Intervening with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcohol Problems</ENAMEX> in
Emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine</ENAMEX>:
Discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">DiClementi and Soderstrom Article</ENAMEX>
