



Session 2.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Identifying ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcohol Problems</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Woolard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>) have alcohol
problems, and they can be identified<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX> on techniques used
to identify these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> has been conducted, but several areas of
interest should be addressed by further research. We need to
further examine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">refine alcohol</ENAMEX>-screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">questionnaires</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. We need to determine the sequence and combination of questions
and tests that constitute the best screening process. We need to
study barriers to screening, identify factors that promote
screening implementation, and demonstrate the impact of a screening
program in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. The final aim of screening must be improved
outcomes through referral and counseling. Identification is only
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in a process of care.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> problems defined
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> problems designate a spectrum from risk behavior to
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, and from problematic consumption to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use disorder.
We must be careful when interpreting the results of studies, and in
our own design of screening procedures, that we are clear about the
endpoints we are measuring. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinicians</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> are interested in
screening for several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol endpoints</ENAMEX>. Acute intoxication is of
concern to emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>. Intoxication in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> would
certainly be considered an "alcohol problem." The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or breath
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol concentration</ENAMEX> (BAC), coupled with our clinical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observations</ENAMEX>, may help us identify intoxication. Most alcohol
screening tests identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use disorders or
problematic consumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psychiatric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM III</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV2</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX>
(WHO) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9th</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">10th International Classification of Diseases</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ICD-9, -10</ENAMEX>) have rigorously defined alcohol abuse and alcohol
dependence<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> These definitions largely agree for dependence, but
not for abuse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> includes social and legal consequences of abuse
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ICD-10</ENAMEX> has only medical and psychological consequences. Fewer
cases of alcohol abuse meet the ICD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> definition. In general, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use disorder is present when an aspect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s
function has been compromised
by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. Before function is compromised, problematic
consumption occurs. Much of the emphasis of screening has shifted
toward identifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with high alcohol consumption before
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> develops. WHO defines hazardous drinking as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> or more
drinks/day for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>/day for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute on Alcohol Abuse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alcoholism</ENAMEX> (NIAAA) defines at-risk
drinking as consumption of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week or more than 4</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">drinks/</ENAMEX>occasion for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> ages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 to 65</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of all ages and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> older than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 65</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week or more than 3</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">drinks/</ENAMEX>occasion is considered at risk. Binge drinking alone is also
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> and has been variably defined as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 3, 4, 5</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> on an occasion<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
Characteristics of an ideal ED screening test or sequence of
tests
An ideal screening test would be accurate, practical, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motivational</ENAMEX>. The accuracy of a test can be measured in several
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. For a screening test, high sensitivity is the most desirable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parameter</ENAMEX>. High sensitivity ensures that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
problems will be detected. High specificity is also desirable to
help ensure that positive tests represent real problems. There is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> off between sensitivity and specificity defined by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receiver operator</ENAMEX> curve. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> curve best
reflects the performance of a test; the larger the area the better
the test. Each point on the curve represents a potential "cut
point." A cut point with a high sensitivity and specificity should
be manifest in an ideal test.
Theoretically, an ideal test should remain accurate throughout
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use spectrum. However, real tests don't perform
uniformly across a spectrum. For example, if we're interested in
identifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with binge drinking, we can define binge
drinking as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3, 4, 5</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> on an occasion. Screening tests
designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with more severe problems (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>) will be
less sensitive at identifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with less severe problems (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>).
An ideal test would perform uniformly in all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> and
sub-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. However, when we screen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> with high case
rates (trauma admissions, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">,5</NUMEX> a highly sensitive test with
moderate specificity performs well. The same test used to screen a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> with low case rates (pregnant clinic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> does
not perform as well. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, a test with higher
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specificity</ENAMEX> may be needed to avoid
too many false positives. A test that is used to screen a
diverse population (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>) will perform better in
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX> than others based of the different case rates among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX>.
An ideal test should remain accurate in the presence of common
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> problems, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>, injury, acute <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, intoxication,
other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety disorders</ENAMEX>. Many of the
screening tests were developed outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. Fortunately, many
have been applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. Hence, their performance has
been demonstrated in the presence of some of these distracting
factors. An ideal test should also remain accurate with differences
in gender, age, race, ethnicity, or language. Some variation in
test performance among demographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> has been demonstrated in
studies of screening tests in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7,8</NUMEX> An ideal test in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
would address both current and lifetime alcohol problems. Current
use would more likely prompt referral or counseling, but past use
predicts poor outcome from medical problems such as injury<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>
In research trials, the impracticality of a screening test may
not be evident. Research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> do not have to contend with adding a
screening test to an already lengthy list of clinical care duties.
In clinical practice, several practical issues will make all the
difference to successful implementation. The ease of use of a
screening test will determine its success. Staff with any level of
prior health training and little additional training should be able
to administer an ideal test. Results should be immediately
available and easy to interpret. The test should be acceptable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
Several factors may interfere with implementation. For example,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> may find certain questions offensive, or they may not be
willing to have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> drawn or submit to breathalyzers. Clinical
staff may be uncomfortable asking some types of questions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Regulators</ENAMEX> may restrict access to records based on answers to
certain questions and add burdens to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> record-keepers.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Payers</ENAMEX> may pay for some tests and not others. These and other
factors may reduce the effectiveness of a screening procedure that
has been proven effective in research trials.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> agree that an ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ED</ENAMEX> test is brief (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 to 2</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>). Most of the quest to develop efficient ED screening has
emphasized brevity. However, a longer test could be
self-administered. An ideal screening test should not interfere
with the routine sequence of medical history, physical examination,
and laboratory testing. The test should be
confidential since there may be legal, financial, or social
consequences to screening positive. Finally, the ideal test should
actually motivate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> to further assessment, counseling, or
referral as needed.
Currently available screening tests
Based on current evidence, screening should be undertaken using
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or a combination of structured questionnaires<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> Screening
undertaken using clinical impression or biochemical tests is not as
accurate or as sensitive as structured questionnaires for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">identifying alcohol</ENAMEX> use disorders or problematic consumption<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Of</ENAMEX>
course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> can help identify acute intoxication. The alcohol
concentration can be determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX> testing, breath analysis,
or blood test<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11,12</NUMEX>
Clinical impression
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Clinicians</ENAMEX> often use their general impression to help with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagnosis</ENAMEX>, but clinical impressions concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems can
be inaccurate. Trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> counseling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX> could
identify <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 50%</NUMEX> of acutely intoxicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.13 Primary care
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicians</ENAMEX> and emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> identified <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 50%</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with alcohol problems. Unfortunately, the majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicians</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54%</NUMEX>) screen only those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> they suspect based on
their clinical impressions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stereotypic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">profiling</ENAMEX> may be the
consequence of screening only suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Gentilello
reported that in a trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ED</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-ism in
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who screened negative on structured questionnaires.
These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were more likely to be young, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>, disheveled,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uninsured</ENAMEX>, and low income<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.17</NUMEX> Of course, some <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> may
spontaneously volunteer information about drinking. Cherpitel
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> self-report of drinking prior to arrival had
a sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX> for alcohol problems in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>
Structured questionnaires
Self-report may be enhanced when specific alcohol questions are
asked. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyr</ENAMEX> reported that a single question in a primary care
setting-"Have you ever had a drinking problem?"-had a high
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensitivity</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40% to 70%</NUMEX>)<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">.18 Subsequent</TIMEX> reports from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> did not replicate the high sensitivity of this single
question<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> Cherpitel evaluated single question screens in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> and found them to be less sensitive than structured
questionnaires<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>
Most existing screens were developed for primary care settings
to detect <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use disorders. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAGE</ENAMEX> was developed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> as
a brief screening tool for primary care providers to detect alcohol
abuse and dependence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAGE</ENAMEX> is a mnemonic from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> questions, Cut
down, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annoyed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guilty</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eye</ENAMEX> opener. The questions address
problems over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s lifetime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAGE</ENAMEX> takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 to 2 minutes</TIMEX> to
administer<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.24,25</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAST</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Michigan Alcohol-Screening Test</ENAMEX>), developed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> as
a screen for alcohol abuse and dependence, has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> yes/no questions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAST</ENAMEX> has been self-administered and used in a computer format. It
addresses problems over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s lifetime. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAST</ENAMEX> requires <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to administer. A shortened version of the MAST exists, a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-question Brief (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAST</ENAMEX>. BMAST takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 to 12 minutes</TIMEX> to
administer and performs nearly as well as the longer
version<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.26</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAAST</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Self-Administered Alcoholism Screening Test</ENAMEX>) was
developed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> to screen for alcohol abuse and dependence. It
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> yes/no questions. While lengthy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAAST</ENAMEX> has the advantage
of being self-administered, and it has also been administered in a
computerized format. It addresses problems over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s
lifetime. A shortened, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-item version, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brief SAAST</ENAMEX>, takes the
patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> to complete<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29,30</NUMEX>
More recently, screens have been developed to detect at-risk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drinkers</ENAMEX>. WHO developed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcohol Use Disorder</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Identification Test</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> as a brief screening tool to detect
at-risk drinking in addition to alcohol abuse and dependence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX>
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> questions. It assesses problems experienced within the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> and over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s lifetime. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX> takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 to 8</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to administer<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.31,32</NUMEX>
Several screens have been developed for pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Concern
about even lower levels of alcohol consumption in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> has
prompted development of the screens <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWEAK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-ACE</ENAMEX>, and NET. TWEAK
screens for alcohol abuse and dependence. It has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> questions,
addresses problems over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX>, and takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 to 5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to administer<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-ACE</ENAMEX> also screens for alcohol abuse and
dependence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-ACE</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> CAGE questions and replaces
the guilt question with tolerance question. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-ACE</ENAMEX> addresses
problems over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> and takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 to 2 minutes</TIMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">administer.34 NET</ENAMEX> was developed to screen pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for
at-risk drinking, alcohol abuse, and dependence. It is a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-question screen that takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 1 minute.33</TIMEX>
One screen has been developed for emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> use, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapid Alcohol Assessment Screen</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RAPS4</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherpitel</ENAMEX> screened an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> with questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAGE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMAST</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWEAK</ENAMEX>. She
created RAPS4 by combining the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> highest-yield questions from
those screens, which covered feeling guilty after drinking,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blackouts</ENAMEX>, failing to do what is normally expected after drinking,
and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> drinking. However, this new instrument has not been
studied when administered as a stand-alone test<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.35</NUMEX>
In addition to these questionnaires, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIAAA</ENAMEX> suggests that all
primary care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> ask an opening question-"Do you drink
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>?"- followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> questions about alcohol consumption
and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAGE</ENAMEX>. This sequence was not explicitly designed or
studied as a "screening test." D'Onofrio and others have
recommended using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIAAA</ENAMEX> approach in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX>
Studies of screening tests
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherpitel</ENAMEX> conducted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> studies comparing multiple screening
tests in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWEAK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX> were most
sensitive, identifying <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84% and 81%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, respectively, with
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ICD-10</ENAMEX> diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> dependence<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> study,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX> were more sensitive than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWEAK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAGE</ENAMEX>, identifying
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">79% and 78%</NUMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72% and 71%</NUMEX>, respectively, of patients
with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ICD-10</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX> diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> dependence, harmful
drinking, or abuse<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5,36</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soderstrom</ENAMEX> has compared multiple screening tests in a trauma
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>. He reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAGE</ENAMEX> performed best, with a sensitivity of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84%</NUMEX>, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX> diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> dependence<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.37</NUMEX> Fiellin
reviewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> studies of screening for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use disorder in the
primary care setting. For at-risk, hazardous, or harmful drinking,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX> was found most effective with sensitivities of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51% to 97%</NUMEX>.
For alcohol abuse or dependence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAGE</ENAMEX> was found most effective with
sensitivities of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43% to 94%</NUMEX>. As expected, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAGE and AUDIT</ENAMEX> performed
best within the spectrum of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use they were developed to
explore<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.38</NUMEX>
Screening biases
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherpitel</ENAMEX> analyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">variability</ENAMEX> of test performance in subgroups
of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.39 In her first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAGE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMAST</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWEAK</ENAMEX> were less sensitive among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, and non-injured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. In
her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> study with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAGE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMAST</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWEAK</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPS</ENAMEX> were less sensitive in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with less
acculturation, and non-dependent drinkers<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.36</NUMEX> Lowering the cut point
on these screening instruments improved sensitivity without loss of
specificity among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>. Using lower cut points for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> may
maximize screening test performance<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.40</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> reviewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> studies with data on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s responses to
screening mainly in primary care settings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAGE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX>, and TWEAK
were the best tests for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> dependence among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Their
reported sensitivities were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66% to 92%</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> screens performed
better among black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> than among white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TWEAK</ENAMEX> per-formed
better than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAGE</ENAMEX> or AUDIT among white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAGE and AUDIT</ENAMEX> had low
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensitivities</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59% and 48%</NUMEX> respectively) for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> dependence
among white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. We must be careful not to employ screening
techniques that do not address important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX>.41
Evidence of such low sensitivity in an important subgroup may
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">necessitate</ENAMEX> use of multiple screens tailored to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX>. In
addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX>, older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>
may need screening with modified or unique tests. Standard screens
may not perform as well in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient subgroups</ENAMEX> that may
represent a considerable part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Adjustment of
cut points or use of alternative screening tests may be necessary
for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> concentration
Many injured <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are screened with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX>, which can help
identify intoxication. The presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> may not always
indicate an alcohol problem. While a very high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> in an unimpaired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> can be a specific screen for dependence<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> is an
insensitive screen for an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use disorder. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> study found
that only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of intoxicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> had an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use
disorder<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.43</NUMEX> In an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> was a poor screen for alcohol abuse
or dependence with a sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>, less sensitive than
self-reported drinking<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> In another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> study, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva alcohol</ENAMEX>
level equivalent to a BAC greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g/dl</ENAMEX> in an injured
patient identified harmful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinkers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX> > 
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) with a sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX>.44 In one trauma
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> had a sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX> for an alcohol disorder<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>
Other biochemical markers such as mean corpuscular volume, platelet
count, liver enzymes, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma-glutamyltransferase</ENAMEX> (GGT),
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALT</ENAMEX>), and carbohydrate deficient transferrin (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">CDT</TIMEX>) perform poorly
with sensitivities of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13% to 67%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use disorders or
problematic con-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sumption.45</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biochemical</ENAMEX> tests other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> may
have use in settings other than an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>, but they offer little as
screening tests for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
Research questions: improving existing screening
questionnaires
We still need to find the most accurate test for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> use. This
may be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RAPS4</TIMEX>, which is designed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>, but it needs further
direct testing. Many tests would be improved by wording questions
to address current problems (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year or three months</TIMEX>) rather
than lifetime problems. Screening with embedded questions and
indirect questions may also improve self-report among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX>
and other groups<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20,51</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> These approaches need further testing in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>.
The most practical test may be the shortest, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-question
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NET</ENAMEX>. Further sequencing of questions within questionnaires may also
improve efficiency<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.35</NUMEX> If one question answered "yes" yields a
positive test score, asking that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and stopping as soon as
the score is positive would be the most efficient approach.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherpitel</ENAMEX> has analyzed the sensitivity of each of the RAPS4
questions and sequenced them from most to least sensitive for most
efficient use<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.35</NUMEX>
Minimizing question sets for interviews will result in obtaining
less information. Computer-administered or self-administered
screens may address this issue by allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to spend more
time completing in-depth questioning with no additional staff
time<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.54,55</NUMEX> This approach promises practical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> for obtaining
more information. A trial of screening tests in various formats
(e.g., interview, self-administered forms, and computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX>) should be undertaken to compare their cost and value
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>.
The most motivational screening test is unknown. Drawing blood
and confronting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood alcohol</ENAMEX> levels may
actually push them away from counseling. Screening questions that
reveal the negative consequences or link <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> to current
problems may motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to seek counseling. Providing
immediate feedback may help make the transition from screening to
counseling with little additional intervention. The motivational
aspects of a variety of screens, with and without verbal or
computer feedback, need to be explored.
Research questions: finding the best approach to screening
To determine the best of the available screens, a multi-center
trial with a broad demographic mix and a large number of patients
subjected to different screens is needed. Further evaluation should
be performed of lower cut points for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWEAK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAGE</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX>. The
advantage of tailored screens or specific questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX>
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,41 adolescents<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,54</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,60</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX> needs to be
determined. RAPS4 must be further tested as a stand-alone screen in
isolation and against other tests. A longer, self-administered
screen-including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> administered by computer-should also be tested
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>.
To determine the best sequence for screening, the approach
recommended by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIAAA</ENAMEX> for primary care should be compared with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX>. Several trials of variations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIAAA</ENAMEX> approach are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warranted</ENAMEX>. Trials should be conducted starting with other or no
opening questions, using other consumption questions such as those
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX>, using other screens such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWEAK</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAGE</ENAMEX>,
changing the sequence to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CAGE</ENAMEX> or TWEAK followed by consumption
questions, and checking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> at the beginning or end of the
protocol.
The best screen should be determined in the context of a
screening and intervention program. Some questions or screens may
lead naturally to referral and treatment. Others may not promote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">referral</ENAMEX> and treatment. Much of the screening literature is
isolated from intervention. Future studies need to incorporate
evaluation of screening linked to intervention protocols.
Barriers to implementing screening
In a research protocol in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> were trained to screen
all emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAGE</ENAMEX> and then provide feedback. Only
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were screened. Of them, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX> had positive CAGE
scores; of those, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 41%</NUMEX> were provided feedback. Even with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feedback</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 12%</NUMEX> accepted follow-up. Of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,663</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 13</NUMEX>
were entered into the trial and the trial was abandoned<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.65,66</NUMEX>
There are multiple barriers to screening. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nurses</ENAMEX> identified lack
of resources, inadequate training, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>, poor morale, and no
perceived value to the intervention. In a survey sponsored by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College of Emergency</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians</ENAMEX>, a minority of emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> reported routine
screening and counseling of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.67 The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> reported
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">provider attitudes</ENAMEX> of disinterest,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">avoidance</ENAMEX>, disdain, and pessimism as well as inadequate time,
insufficient education, and lack of resources as barriers. Surveys
and interventions should be undertaken to define and reduce
barriers to implementing screening in clinical practice.
Currently, screening is a research tool, not a clinical tool. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
staff does not use structured questionnaires for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> screening.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> has no systematic approach to alcohol screening. Staff
chooses to screen some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and not others based on clinical
suspicions or partially implemented protocols. In general, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> staff
screens less often than addiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> recommend.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> screening is appropriate in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> with high case
rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX> have reported high case rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems,
especially acute intoxication, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9% to 31%</NUMEX>.17<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,28,46,68</NUMEX>-71 Within
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>, there are even higher case rates in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX>. Major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trauma</ENAMEX>, injuries, assaults<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,72</NUMEX> depression, and alcohol-related
medical problems like gastrointestinal bleeding or seizures define
even higher risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> advocate focusing
screening on some of the highest-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> or screening with
greater intensity and different tools in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
Implementing screening in clinical practice
Any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> could be assigned the screening task.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Physician</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>, clerical, social work, or volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> can
conduct screening. We do not know which staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> will be most
effective. Self-administered questionnaires, computer screen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interactions</ENAMEX>, or interview techniques may be easier to implement.
Screening questions can be stand-alone or embedded into general
health questionnaires or existing registration, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>, and
nurse documentation. Screening protocols can be mandatory or
voluntary. The approaches that will be most effective in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>
practice should be determined by studying the implementation of
these strategies in actual ED clinical practices. Studies of the
translation of efficacious research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> into clinical practice
is needed most since screening instruments have been used by
research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and not clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.
Impact of screening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> patient care should be improved by implementing alcohol
screening programs. A major limit to realizing this improvement is
the lack of counseling available to address <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' alcohol
problems in most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX>.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDs</ENAMEX> provide very limited alcohol services. When care is
unavailable, screening makes little sense to clinicians. Realizing
a gain from screening in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> is entirely dependent upon linking
the screening program to some form of counseling, onsite or through
referral services. The impact of screening should be demonstrated
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> environments that have treatment available, an adequate
volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and the capacity to undertake
clinical trials. Studies in these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> should demonstrate the
benefits of screening: increased referrals, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> receiving
counseling, and better outcomes such as reduction of risk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">behaviors</ENAMEX>.
Summary: research areas of interest concerning screening
The ideal screen that is accurate, practical, and motivational
has not been developed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> must continue to analyze the
performance of structured questionnaires and try computer-based
screening tools in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. The sequence of screening tests needs to
be evaluated by studying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIAAA</ENAMEX> approach and several
alternatives. Screening must move from research to clinical
practice. Barriers to screening in clinical practice must be
identified and removed. Studies of implementation of screening
programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> clinical practice should be undertaken. The impact
of screening on referral and intervention, as well as outcomes such
as reduced risk behaviors, must be demonstrated.
References
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowenstein S</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Koziol-McLain J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al. Behavioral</ENAMEX>
risk factors in emergency department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>: a multisite survey.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acad Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5:781-7</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psychiatric Association</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostic and Statistical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manual of Mental Disorders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psychiatric</ENAMEX>
Press; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spitzer R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibbon M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">et al. User's Guide</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Structured Clinical Interview</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III-R. Washington</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>):
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psychiatric Press</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Physician's Guide to Helping Patients with Alcohol Problems</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</ENAMEX>;
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> Publication No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3769</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Soderstrom C, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith GS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kufera JA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> al. The accuracy of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAGE</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brief Michigan Alcoholism Screening Test</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> Use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Disorders Identification Test</ENAMEX> in screening trauma
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center patients</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Trauma 1997</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">962-9</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gale T</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ja W</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welty T. Differences</ENAMEX> in detection of alcohol
use in a prenatal population (on a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Plains Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reservation</ENAMEX>) using various methods of ascertainment. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Medicine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">235-40</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherpitel C. Screening</ENAMEX> for alcohol problems in the emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">158-66</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherpitel C. Comparison</ENAMEX> of screening instruments for alcohol
problems between black and white emergency room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> from two
regions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clin Exp Res</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1391-7</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkovich G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rivara</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gurney J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> al. The effects of acute
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol intoxication</ENAMEX> and chronic alcohol abuse on outcome from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trauma</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">270:51-6</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. D'Onofrio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">al. Patients</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> problems in the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, part <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: improving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">detection</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acad Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5:1200-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibb K, Yee A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin S, et al. Accuracy</ENAMEX> and usefulness of
the breath <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol analyzer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">516-20</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibb K. Serum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> levels, toxicology screens, and use
of the breath <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol analyzer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">349-53</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sobel M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sobel L</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanderSpeck R. Relationships</ENAMEX> among
clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">judgement</ENAMEX>, self-report and breath analysis measures of
intoxication in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Consult Clin Psychol</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">205-6</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becker B</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolard RH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nirenberg</ENAMEX> TD, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minugh A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longabaugh R</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford P. Alcohol</ENAMEX> use among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subcritically</ENAMEX> injured emergency
department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acad Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:784-90</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rydon P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redman S, Sanson-Fisher R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reid A. Detection</ENAMEX> of
alcohol-related problems in general practice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Stud Alcohol</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">197-202</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaacson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zacharek M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tzelepis A.</ENAMEX> A screening
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX>) in an
inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Gen Intern Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9:550-3</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentilello L</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villaveces A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ries RR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al. Detection of</ENAMEX>
acute alcohol intoxication and chronic alcohol dependence by trauma
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Trauma 1999</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1131-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cyr M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wartman S.</ENAMEX> The effectiveness of routine screening
questions in the detection of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">259:51-4</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleming M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry K.</ENAMEX> The effectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>
screening in an ambulatory care setting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Stud Alcohol</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>-6.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleming M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry K.</ENAMEX> A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-sample test of a masked alcohol
screening questionnaire. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:81-91</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naughton</ENAMEX> B, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughes S. Screening</ENAMEX> elderly veterans
for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Gen Intern Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5:361-4</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schorling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Willems J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klas P. Identifying</ENAMEX> problem
drinkers: lack of sensitivity of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-question drinking test. Am
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">98</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">232-6</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taj N</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devera-Sales A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vinson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>. Screening for problem
drinking: does a single question work? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Fam Pract</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">328-35</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing J. Detecting alcoholism</ENAMEX>: the CAGE questionnaire.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">252: 1905-7</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mayfield</TIMEX> D, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLeod G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> P. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The CAGE questionnaire:</ENAMEX>
validation of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> screening instrument. Am <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Psychiatry</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">131:1121-3</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Pokorny A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller B</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan H. The Brief</ENAMEX> MAST: a shortened
version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Michigan Alcoholism Screening Test</ENAMEX>. Am <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Psychiatry</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">129:342-8</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selzer M.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Michigan Alcoholism Screening Test</ENAMEX>: the quest
for a new diagnostic instrument. Am <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Psychiatry</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">127:1653-8</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selzer M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vinokur A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Rooijen M. A</ENAMEX> self-administered
Short <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Michigan Alcoholism Screening Test</ENAMEX> (SMAST). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Stud Alcohol</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117-26</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis L</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurt R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morse R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien P. Discriminant</ENAMEX>
analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Self-Administered Alcoholism Screening Test</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clin Exp Res</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269-73</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis L</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morse R. Self-Administered Alcoholism</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Screening Test</ENAMEX>: a comparison of conventional versus
computer-administered formats. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> Clin Exp Res
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">155-7</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aasland O</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amundsen A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant M. Alcohol</ENAMEX>
consumption and related problems among primary health care
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WHO Collaborative Project on Early Detection of Persons</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmful Alcohol Consumption</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I. Addiction 1993</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">88</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">349-62</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aasland O</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babor T</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">De La Fuente J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant M.</ENAMEX>
Development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIT</ENAMEX>). Addiction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">88</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">791-804</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martier S, Sokol R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al. Screening</ENAMEX> for
pregnancy risk-drinking. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clin Exp Res</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1156-61</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sokol R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martier S, Ager J.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The T-ACE</ENAMEX> questions: practical
prenatal detection of risk-drinking. Am <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Obstet</ENAMEX> Gynecol
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">160:863-70</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherpitel C.</ENAMEX> A brief screening instrument for problem
drinking in the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the RAPS4</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapid Alcohol Problems</ENAMEX>
Screen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Stud Alcohol 2000</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">447-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherpitel C. Differences</ENAMEX> in performance of screening
instruments for problem drinking among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>
in an emergency room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Stud Alcohol 1998</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">420-6</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soderstrom CA, Smith GH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kufera JA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> al. The accuracy of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAGE</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brief Michigan Alcohol Screening Test</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> Use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Disorders Identification Test</ENAMEX> in screening trauma
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center patients</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Trauma 1997</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">962-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiellin DA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reid MC, O'Connor</ENAMEX> PG. Screening for alcohol
problems in primary care: a systematic review. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch Intern Med</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977-89</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>. Cherpitel C, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark W. Ethnic</ENAMEX> differences in performance of
screening instruments for identifying harmful drinking and alcohol
dependence in the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> Clin Exp Res
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">628-34</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherpitel C. Analysis</ENAMEX> of cut points for screening
instruments for alcohol problems in the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Stud</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">695-700</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley KA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd-Wickizer J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell SH, Burman ML</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX>
screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">questionnaires</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">280:166-71</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Criteria Committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Council on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alcoholism</ENAMEX>. Criteria for the diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. Am <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>
Psychiatry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">129:127-35</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Gijbers A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whelan G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX> Does a blood alcohol
level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.15</NUMEX> or more identify accurately problem drinkers in a
drunk-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver population</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Med</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Aust</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">154:448-52</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sparadeo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minugh P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al. Identification of</ENAMEX>
hazardous/harmful drinking among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subcritically</ENAMEX> injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acad Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:239-45</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleary P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> B, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warburg M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delbanco T</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aronson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Prevalence</ENAMEX> and recognition of alcohol abuse in a primary care
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Am <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">466-71</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Escobar F</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canteras M. Diagnostic</ENAMEX> tests for
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> in primary health care: compared efficacy of different
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instruments</ENAMEX>. Drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alcohol Depend 1995</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">151-8</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reynaud M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schellenberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loisequx-Meunier M-N</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> al.
Objective diagnosis of alcohol abuse: compared values of
carbohydrate-deficient transferrin (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">CDT</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma</ENAMEX>-glutamyl
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transferase</ENAMEX> (GGT), and mean corpuscular volume (MCV). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> Clin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exp Res</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1414-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aithal G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thornes H, Dwarakanath A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner A. Measurement</ENAMEX>
of carbohydrate-deficient transferrin (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">CDT</TIMEX>) in a general medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinic</ENAMEX>: is this test useful in assessing alcohol consumption?
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">304-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sillanaukee P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aalto M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seppa K. Carbohydrate</ENAMEX>-deficient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transferrin</ENAMEX> and conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> markers as indicators for
brief intervention among heavy drinkers in primary health care.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clin Exp Res</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">892-6</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yersin</ENAMEX> B, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nicolet J-F</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decrey H</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burner M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melle G</ENAMEX>, Pecoud
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Screening</ENAMEX> for excessive alcohol drinking: comparative value of
carbohydrate-deficient transferrin, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma-glutamyltransferase</ENAMEX>, and
mean corpuscular volume. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch Intern Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907-11</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadhead W</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weissman M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al. Development</ENAMEX> and
validation of the SDDS-PC screen for multiple mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> in
primary care. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch Fam Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4:211-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olfson M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weissman M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> al. Brief screens for
mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> in primary care. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Gen Intern Med</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">426-30</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hore</ENAMEX> B, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alsafar J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins R. An</ENAMEX> attempt at
criterion-oriented validation of an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism questionnaire</ENAMEX> in
general practice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Br</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Addict 1977</ENAMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72:19-22</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> D, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kreisberg J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Volpicelli J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alterman A.</ENAMEX>
Screening for problem drinking in college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Am</ENAMEX> Coll
Health <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">36:89-94</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55</TIMEX>. Heck <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Developing</ENAMEX> a screening questionnaire for problem
drinking in college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Am Coll Health</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227-31</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kokotailo P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adger H, Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duggan A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Repke J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joffe A.</ENAMEX>
Cigarette, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use by school-age pregnant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adolescents</ENAMEX>: prevalence, detection, and associated risk factors.
Pediatrics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">328-34</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werner M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walker L</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene J. Screening</ENAMEX> for problem
drinking among college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Adolesc Health</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303-10</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werner M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walker L, Greene J. Longitudinal</ENAMEX> evaluation of a
screening measure for problem drinking among female college
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">148:1331-7</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werner M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adger H, Jr.</ENAMEX> Early identification, screening, and
brief intervention for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adolescent alcohol</ENAMEX> use. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch Pediatr Adolesc</ENAMEX>
Med <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">149:1241-8</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dawson</TIMEX> D, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer L. Relative</ENAMEX> frequency of heavy drinking
and the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> dependence. Addiction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">88</TIMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1209-18</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willenbring M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christensen K</ENAMEX>, Spring W, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rasmussen R.</ENAMEX>
Alcoholism screening in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Am Geriatr</ENAMEX> Soc
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">864-9</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bercsi S, Brickner P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saha D. Alcohol</ENAMEX> use and abuse in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frail</ENAMEX>, homebound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>: a clinical analysis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. Drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol Depend</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">139-49</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fulop G</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Reinhardt J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Strain J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> B, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller M</ENAMEX>, Fillit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Identification</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> and depression in a geriatric
medicine outpatient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J Am Geriatr Soc</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">737-41</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">64</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fink A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hays RD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> AA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck JC</ENAMEX>. Alcohol-related
problems in older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>: determinants, consequences, and
screening. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch Intern Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">156:1150-6</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX>. Brooker C, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCabe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short N. The</ENAMEX> views of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>
to the conduct of a randomised controlled trial of problem drinkers
in an accident and emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Int J Nurs Stud</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>-9.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooker C, McCabe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short N. Problems</ENAMEX>
encountered with opportunistic screening for alcohol-related
problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> attending an accident and emergency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. Addiction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">93</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">589-94</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinnis A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gutman D. Health</ENAMEX> promotion practices
of emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>. Am <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J Emerg Med</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:17-21</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke T.</ENAMEX> The economic impact of alcohol abuse a



