
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well uh i don't know i think the budget is really out of hand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this election year</TIMEX> i think that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there ought to be some at least some conversation about what we are supposed to do about this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah see it like seems to me you know that everyone's offering you know their token little tax cut program you know when it's when it's just such a bad time for it you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and uh well as you said mostly they are token cuts uh especially what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">for instance George Bush</ENAMEX> is offering
 	
 	
 		no
 		it the ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven cents</NUMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		yeah ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven cents</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> now what that's really not gonna do a lot of good it doesn't seem to me to your average middle income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you know another ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven cents</NUMEX> hell you can buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> or something for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hell i mean mostly you know it's it's not actually a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a cut it's just a cut in the with hold in the amount with held you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um yeah i don't just don't see it changing my life style a whole lot
 	
 	
 		nah that ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven cents</NUMEX> really isn't gonna do it for me either uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i i haven't really heard much of what the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have said that has made a lot of sense to me either especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> uh don't seem to be coming up with much that really sparks my interest as far as yeah maybe that could
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do something to affect our budget at this point
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i mean you know in in retrospect um was it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Mondale or Dukakis</ENAMEX> that said you know i'll i'll tell you right now i'm gonna raise taxes
 	
 	
 		i believe it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> but i i can't
 	
 	
 		it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> yeah i have a lot of respect for him
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean that's better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> who came out and said no i will not read my lips or whatever and then you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten months later</TIMEX> he said well sorry you know i i can't follow through on this but it seems to me that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that the budget is so out of hand and especially now that they say okay the cold war is over and we're supposed to be getting a peace dividend of you know of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> number of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion trillion dollars</NUMEX> a year well i'd really like to know where where that money is actually gonna go because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in my opinion i don't think i'm ever gonna see any of this peace so called peace dividend
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  i know it it's
 	
 	
 		i mean if they could actually put put something together and make i'm not really in favor of large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> social programs either because i feel that they waste money also but with this peace dividend it seems like you could set up some kind of like public works
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> like they had in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i i i i think that would be a great idea you know like the conservation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> you know where it would it would it would help unemployment greatly
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 		exactly and in that way we could really focus on building the infrastructure structure of the country
 	
 	
 		and it
 		
 
 		yeah our infrastructure is in is in i mean we we've we've hurt ourselves incredibly over the last fifty fifty years of the cold war yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and and there's no way that we can ever really recover from from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that we're in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> unless at least i feel unless we focus on the infrastructure and i surely don't hear anybody saying that right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um yeah i i agree totally  um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean we this this it just seems so you know so ridiculous that it was allowed to happen um i i'm in college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and oh really where do you go
 	
 	
 		so am i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh IU</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> um and in my i had political you know the required political science class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things we discussed was you know were where the budget situation how how the budget situation just got so out of hand and essentially what happened was and i think it was like in eighty in the um tax year of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty one</NUMEX> um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> basically said you know
 		i'm gonna give this much of a tax cut to the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX> and and created this this ludicrous budget that he knew that that um
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would not in the right mind pass and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Congress</ENAMEX> realizing that they were gonna lose a the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> realizing that they were gonna lose a propaganda war you know by by you know slicing by by removing the tax cut
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		further cut the taxes and created you know that that that you know what created the the huge deficit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> which moved us into the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion dollar</NUMEX> deficit
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you just  i mean it's just
 	
 	
 		you you just have to wonder what they're thinking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it's just like you know playing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> with a loaded gun
 	
 	
 		yeah uh well it's it's more than a loaded it's a loaded cannon i mean they've got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillions of dollars</NUMEX> to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and they in my opinion don't do a very responsible job of spending that money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum well yeah and what really bothers me is it just seems like if if anyone were to say you know well i'm gonna raise taxes
 		and cut the budget and we're gonna have you know we're we're gonna we're gonna have to do some unpopular things i mean he wouldn't have a chance of getting elected
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		i mean it's kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and circuses thing you know where where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just want want to have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know what ever will make them feel good right now you know and
 	
 	
 		for the for the moment and that's what really is getting me about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s stand on the budget is right now is that he is saying i am gonna give you this ludicrous little tax cut so that you'll be happy come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> and you'll elect me again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i'm gonna go on and just forget everything that i said or you know it doesn't seem that it's gonna make much of a difference
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah that i mean i don't know i i
 		i don't i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> will make the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> happy with ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven cents</NUMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		no no not at all
 	
 	
 		well i just don't think it was a well thought out incentive
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 		
 	