
 
     		
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		
 
 		just just as i answered the phone there was there was a voice that came on the line and said
 		you were suppose to you talk about capital punishment how does the law what how do the laws in the different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> compare and to be restricted to certain crimes or certain circumstances or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i honestly don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>' position on capital punishment is do you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i know we're kind of beefing it up now uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> or so
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are on death row and have been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they're beginning to go on and executed them now We have the uh lethal injections lethal injection
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		it's going to take at least all ready <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> have been put to death
 		and i think at this point i am for that as long as you know they've had all the chances they need to have on appeals and
 		this i don't see why they should have to and why we should have to support them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty or thirty years</TIMEX> on death row
 		that once they have been sentenced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> found guilty and then gone through the appeal
 		bit then
 		why continue
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i strongly i strongly agree i think uh well in general i think we have we have a fairly lax legal system as far as protecting the criminal
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh and i can see the the necessity of it
 		but uh
 		i don't know if someone's guilty and there's there's no question if if if there's is no question about it a lot of times you sentence someone to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and there and there the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> finds them guilt then not in everyone's mind it's not actually settled
 	
 	
 		right i can agree with that That it's
 	
 	
 		so i can i can see letting uh letting for example the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> make the call or or maybe an appeals court make the call and on this it was this not just beyond a reasonable doubt but beyond any doubt
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so under circumstances where it's you know where there is no question about it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> actually did kill somebody and in particularly particularly in some of the more brutal cases or prevalent where they've killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		yeah i i totally agree i i think it's kind of appalling that some one can commit murder and they know that they probably won't die for it
 	
 	
 		yes Well i know of uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that have been put to death have uh i mean they have already they had admitted to it They i mean there was no question and yes they had been going on fifteen to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> there on death row
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		uh i think probably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is the most lax <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> there is on this That it just
 		oh wow We do everything else fast
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>
 		that's that's probably why this was picked as one of the topics because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's in the news it's not really in the news much up here i guess it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahlmer</ENAMEX> case
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that was in the news everywhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now where was that at
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i think that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that's what i thought
 	
 	
 		i believe so and uh
 		i know we're going through a case right now that uh where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s starved a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to death
 		and uh
 		i've heard you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wondering whether you know should these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get the death penalty or not
 		uh i i guess i would feel strongly about that when it involves a child especially they they tied this child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> found the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> tied and starved and uh there's no doubt a case like that there's no doubt in my mind
 		that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ought to get the death penalty
 		that uh
 		they did it they did it knowingly
 	
 	
 		i guess that would be that would be the issue and they just tie the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and
 		and were they were they punishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and they don't realize that he was going to die or oh they did
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 		oh they the were just punishing They didn't think far enough ahead i don't guess that you know that he would actually die or that they would get caught They had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		well see that's i think i would think that differently they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> did not die
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> didn't
 		huh
 		yeah in that case he i think he could argue that i don't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were really intending to kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well could be
 	
 	
 		that would that would seem that would seem like that would that would i would have a harder time saying the death penalty was in order for that
 	
 	
 		well i don't think i would  but uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		no i i certainly think punishment is in order but the death penalty because that's i am not sure that is homicide because they didn't i i it it certainly wasn't intentional homicide
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		Well you may have a point there i
 		it's just that i guess they have gotten so much publicity here but and i have read so much about it and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		just
 	
 	
 		that is
 		that is a tough one
 	
 	
 		but other than that uh you know i just
 		
 		
 	