
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Greg</ENAMEX> uh i'm i'm not familiar i think uh you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> don't you have the the death penalty
 	
 	
 		yeah we do have the death penalty here it's not exercised very often  but we do have it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i believe it i can't even remember the last execution we had here actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> personally i'm in favor of capital punishment i know there's a lot of lot of problems with it but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		seems to me that some crimes are just so heinous that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> just uh i feel doesn't deserve to live doesn't deserve for the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX> to spend however many <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> it costs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to keep them in in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i know there's a lot of problems with that like well they say okay if you declare someone put them on death row and execute them well then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten late years later</TIMEX> you find out that he really didn't do it then that life was wasted but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just seems like in some cases that it's a it's a good policy
 	
 	
 		um-hum uh i i tend to agree with you uh  i've changed my views over uh even even within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> uh to be honest  uh
 		
 
 		uh when i was in college when i was an undergraduate i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh of course at that time you know i thought uh how it's it was stupid to kill anybody for uh you know that the eye for an eye was a stupid argument
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but  the uh
 		the more now i live in  downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and i uh  you know i've seen uh i've seen cases on in the news and all where where you know uh a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who had murdered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and then commits another murder
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think that  maybe a
 		a good solution to capital punishment might be uh reserve it solely for uh repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> of a crime like uh murder
 	
 	
 		that's a that's a thought that i had never really had on that which which seems pretty sensible
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i
 		yeah it seems sensible and and fail-safe i uh i i don't you know not completely fail-safe but if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s convicted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> murders uh you know there's a pretty good chance that something's wrong
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 		i also  uh to tell you how liberal i have turned uh toward this or or or whatever side that is i've kind of chosen uh i believe that that uh
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		big time drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importers</ENAMEX> like uh say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> for example these these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to be uh eliminated uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from society and i think i think the death penalty is the best choice for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because uh really any kind of uh
 		uh jail sentence for them is just another chance to uh
 		create another power structure
 	
 	
 		yeah you're you're right there uh
 	
 	
 		you know the
 	
 	
 		i just basically my views i guess they tend to be more economically oriented in that i just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you know they come out with these figures that it costs fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> taxpayer dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to keep someone alive in jail when they're going to be there for life they're never going to be rehabilitated
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean i don't believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> system that we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> does much towards rehabilitation to begin with so to me i'm paying taxes you know twenty percent of my check or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to keep somebody alive who i in my mind shouldn't be there in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place and is never going to be a valuable or worthwhile part of society so i i'm all in favor of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		uh
 		
 
 		do you uh are there cases where you think that that uh the capital  capital punishment shouldn't be uh uh sentenced
 	
 	
 		well i i really don't know on that question it just seems like for instance the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahlmer</ENAMEX> case i mean i i don't really think that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is going to ever be a worthwhile part of society i hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> never gets back out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in that case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> doesn't have a death penalty so he's going to be sentenced to life imprisonment
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think that that he should not be allowed to live but you know then you're kind of playing God  which is never never a good thing to do but cases where i think the death penalty should be withheld
 	
 	
 		that's true yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh not really that i can think of i i would i would be in favor of the death penalty in things like you know murders and like you said repeat murders or serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't really agree with the uh death penalty for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> and such as that i think that they're
 		they're operating on a more i mean i know that they're causing massive problems in society up here but i don't really think that that it's
 		it's in our power to take these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from a sovereign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and say you don't deserve to live because they're feeding our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX> needs
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure yeah i understand i understand your point
 		yeah uh of course you know with uh with with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dahlmer</ENAMEX> now uh you you realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> uh gets to try him next and they do have the death penalty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		so uh that was a curious case i
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that is very curious
 	
 	
 		uh uh that was something is sort of nightmarish to say the least
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's that's right
 	
 	
 		uh well here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we uh i think even even this last week
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> they had another they uh you know they use their capital punishment by lethal injection uh uh
 		
 		
 	