
 
     		
 	
 		so uh
 		do do you know what the laws of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are in regard to capital punishment
 	
 	
 		um i have to plead ignorant i really don't know i i think that that uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is for it i don't think we've had any instances of it
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry would you repeat that please
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry you you're just a little  just a little quiet i just couldn't quite hear what you said
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		sorry i said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is is for capital punishment um-hum i don't think we've had a case uh recently but but it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and he i i'm uh
 		i believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> it is permitted but for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> they were
 		not doing it i don't think i don't think there's been an execution for a while uh but i'm a little ignorant of it myself i know that there was a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was a state supreme court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> who was uh being pounded on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> because she was overturning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh convictions or she was somehow keeping death penalties from being carried out and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		giving her a very hard time on that although i always suspected it was something else and that was just something to bang on her about
 	
 	
 		yeah could be could be how do you feel about about the capital punishment
 	
 	
 		well i
 		i don't to me it seems unnecessary
 		um
 		i think that the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who
 		would be deterred
 		by capital punishment would also be deterred by life in prison
 		um
 		and uh
 		
 
 		it seems just with the possibility of
 		making mistakes that uh
 		i would rather opt for life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> where at least there's a chance the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could uh either change or perhaps even
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know contribute to society from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in some way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well what do you feeling
 	
 	
 		well uh i probably tend to fall come down on the side of of being for it but i i think it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it shouldn't be um there should be more safe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> to be sure that that you're you know no mistakes have been made
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but then i i tend to i tend to come down on the side that if if the laws were were enforced that were on the books you probably wouldn't need it
 	
 	
 		right it's uh
 		do you think it would be a deterrent
 	
 	
 		well obviously that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> wouldn't do it again
 	
 	
 		well that is true that is true um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and it but but i think that like i said if if the laws that are already on on the books that exist were enforced to the letter of the law
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then i think that in itself would cut down on all kinds of crime
 	
 	
 		oh i see you're thinking that if the laws were enforced in general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be
 		maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be stopped at doing something before they got to the point of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of killing somebody
 	
 	
 		right because i i think too many too many of them walk you know
 	
 	
 		um
 		well you know i mean i think i think i'm in agreement with you on this point that hey there's a problem and
 		the solution to the problem isn't whether you kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or not at the end it's what happens before that uh and i would say that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know putting more
 		giving more attention to uh child rearing
 		you know as early as that is is it the terms of giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a good education and uh
 		sort of a good uh
 		i don't know moral or self esteem sort of backing that would keep them from getting into that sort of life in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
 		could make it less necessary also
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's true you've got to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's i it seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh
 		focus more on the one end of the system where you're executing someone or not rather than the other end of the system where you're turning out a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's likely to do something like that or not
 		uh
 		so i think that sort of goes along with what you're saying
 		uh
 		are there certain you know i mean are there certain crimes or do you think there are or should be certain crimes that are liable for it and others not i mean clearly there are but which ones do you think should be liable
 	
 	
 		um well i think murder is number one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i i i i
 		tend to believe in an eye for an eye if you if you take a life then you need to lose yours you know not not that you can bring the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> back and and obviously can't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i see no reason
 		to
 		for you to continue you know and and possibly get out and do it again you know there's too much of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you could put them away and be assured that they would stay there you know where they couldn't hurt anybody else that'd be one thing but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		most of of the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> that go to jail get
 		
 		
 	