
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well hello <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frances</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  yeah i guess when i uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> i guess i have mixed feelings about this uh
 		subject when i first heard about it um i thought it was kind of a neat way of uh
 		
 
 		screening uh
 		uh screening for potential problems
 		good way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to weed out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with drug problems but since then i've been hearing uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i read an article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that talked about um the different results that they get from uh different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> and that uh many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> will give uh false positives especially some of the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		the less expensive ones and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been denied employment on this basis
 	
 	
 		well the reliability seems to
 		
 
 		not be too great um
 		i don't know
 		
 
 		i'm kind of like you i have mixed feelings but all in all i think i'm for it  uh  i really do um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because we lose so much
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and what have you with the the drug problem
 		and it's just so prevalent nowadays that uh
 		i think it's only fair for the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to uh
 		have some kind of guidelines to go by
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but like anything else this can be misused
 	
 	
 		yeah there's a i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> have had have been able to uh reduce some tremendous problems they've had with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> turnover health problems and accidents and theft and i understand that certain jobs like if you're driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> or something of course there'd be increased need for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		one thing that always kind of bugged me about it was uh
 		there's they most of them don't test for
 		actually the number one drug problem which of course is uh alcohol abuse
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and of course that you know everybody talks about all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but uh
 		i i understand <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is really still the number one health problem and the number one abused <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> in in our country
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it seems kind of too bad that that one's tolerated while other ones are are you know are the ones that they focus on
 	
 	
 		well it is in every situation that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is
 		more acceptable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it seems than the other quote <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but uh it can do more
 		harm with the uh i don't know we just seem to have a rash of drunk driving and killings around here lately and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well see now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh didn't they only recently ban open containers in in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes yes but we aren't very uh we aren't very hard even on the you know when they're picked up for drunk driving time after time again
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		this is a real problem here that they get a little slap on their wrists and there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> here that had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWI</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh man
 	
 	
 		and the only reason they finally came down on him he finally did kill someone
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystander</ENAMEX> and when looking back he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty two</NUMEX> convictions and yet he was still walking loose so we've got problem here with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> especially that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 		yeah i expect possibly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's uh
 		you know a an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> knows they get in front of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> will be thinking well i've done that before or he's just a good old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		the good old
 		yeah good old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> stuff  you know well this is yeah this is natural this is tell me what do you expect
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right what else how else do you drive in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup</ENAMEX> down the highway
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i'm afraid you know it may come out with some of these other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> too that uh i know i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of uh you know it's they use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's acceptable it's becoming acceptable to them that well you know they're not
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		they're not hurting anyone else and i thought where have i heard this before  and i'm afraid that's what we may be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		facing in the very near future
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		other than that i don't know because i don't  drink and i don't do <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and it's uh so neither is really acceptable to me
 	
 	
 		well same here
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh then the work place it's just i don't know what is well we really infringing on other rights or their
 		
 		
 	