
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'll talk about my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> a little bit
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i've noticed that there's actually being uh quite there's been a quite a bit done uh i noticed that uh the uh several of my uh
 		uh grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> have been putting up signs that plastic bags and uh trying to recycle the uh gallon uh containers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i i'm beginning to see some uh real positive effects i mean huh although i won't claim that that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that</TIMEX> that we're doing everything and it's uh you know i i try to recycle uh papers and cans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum what about glass they have glass
 	
 	
 		uh i have not seen a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> but the same time in this area
 		at least when it comes to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Coke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> uh they don't really hardly use any glass
 	
 	
 		huh so they know um here they have um they have trash sorting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i mean not not right here where i am but in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> next door they have um
 		they have trash sorting and you know they put out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in separate bins
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh  i guess there's a lot of raiding by homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing because they go out and it's like
 		they they pay for this by the by the by the aluminum they collect
 	
 	
 		right right well i i know that uh uh that's that one thing that uh they're not real good about yet is
 		it seems like the paper sorting you still we still are forced pretty much to take everything in you know we don't really have any help from the sanitation department
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so the life is not easy in that way we still have to kind of take care of our own aluminum uh so it's still up to the individual it's it's not really part of any uh a government sponsored programs or anything
 	
 	
 		i see so so um do you actually live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah uh pretty much i i really don't live in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> as what you'd call <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> central but there's several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> that count as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are um i think Dekalb
 	
 	
 		you well that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dekalb</ENAMEX> actually it's you're right it's spelled that way D D <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E C A L B</ENAMEX> but that that's Dekalb
 	
 	
 		Dekalb yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dekalb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fulton</ENAMEX>
 		i thought it was i thought it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> i always thought it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> but um never mind um
 		and uh isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fulton</ENAMEX> what another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> that's uh
 	
 	
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fulton</ENAMEX> and actually also contained in that is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cobb</ENAMEX> and also contained in that uh to to some extent is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clayton</ENAMEX> county although it's pretty much uh still in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> proper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		uh but there's no concentrated concept
 		uh on that sense uh we have uh
 	
 	
 		now where's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> the city limits it's kind of odd that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> would actually spread over uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> the city limits would actually fall into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the the the central uh part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> the downtown area is in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fulton</ENAMEX> almost exclusively
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but yeah i mean i i most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> tend to stay mostly mostly in in in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> so you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> is entirely within the the the limits of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco County</ENAMEX> in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco County</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> have the same city limits
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so that's kind of a weird thing but um
 	
 	
 		right
 		anyways i guess i'm trying to figure out what else there is out here i mean oh we do get papers uh we get we get some help with the papers uh our our our uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> trash <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> does do a a uh uh if if you sort the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and and put them in a bag they will put them in a separate area into into the uh uh
 		uh garbage garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> i guess i don't know exactly how they do it but they do that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's an interesting term because i mean if you if you think about it's the garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> well is it really garbage if they're taking it off to be recycled and somebody's willing to pay for it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it pretty well the the i guess it is in in in that sense uh it still is uh i don't i uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> themselves i mean they some how put them off to the side and i don't know exactly how they do it
 		uh but they but they they do indicate that service
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i think that we you know i think they ought to really start pushing it more you know the idea that you were talking about where they they separate each each container
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that should be more available we should have more containers in all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> uh uh and all the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh to help on on that sort of thing that would that would make it a lot easier
 		i know in uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that they actually distribute out they as part of the the service they give you extra containers that you can that you can put things into so you you know you don't have to go out and buy your own garbage cans and things like that
 	
 	
 		huh
 		huh
 		you have a you have a very uh distinctive accent um where're you from originally
 	
 	
 		well i'm actually originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton Ohio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		but that's
 		
 		
 	