
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um what do you think
 	
 	
 		well it depends on whether i have to buy my next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> before or after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are out of the house
 	
 	
 		well that makes a big difference doesn't it
 	
 	
 		we've we've gone from small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagons</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini van</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's kind of like well if
 		right a little more domestic there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i i guess the biggest factor for me lately is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> versus non <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and while i'd really like to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know it just it really depends on reliability for me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> right now and it's been a pretty good truck
 		but some of the things are not that good about it and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> sales have been really bad in terms of customer uh customer service at least for me
 		so it's i don't know it's it's kind of disappointing
 	
 	
 		well well when we  i guess this is talking about previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> opposed to to next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but when we went to look for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini van</ENAMEX> i wanted to get you know i thought it'd be nice to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and i went and looked at all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ones
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the doors didn't close right and the i mean and this is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> and you're thinking to yourself if it's not right now what is it gonna be like after i've had it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well one of the good i guess one of the good things that i have to work on is my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> he's a pharmaceutical rep and he he gets a new car about once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he's been driving a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini vans</ENAMEX> in the last like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh he generally goes with i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astro Van</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um it's the only one that has a standard <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> cylinder which is real important to him but
 		i don't know i guess i guess for my next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i'd probably have to probably have to scale down to an actual car instead of a pick up starting to get into that i'm a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> right now i'm a doctoral student
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i anticipate getting a full time job soon so  you know probably one of those things where i really don't need the the hauling capacity much i'll be a little more stable but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i guess i don't know i'm i i think i'll probably buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> but i'm just not real sure you know
 	
 	
 		you have to go out of here go talk to dad
 		yeah
 		well um
 		i know i've i've always looked for mileage
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know cause i figure the the better miles it gets the better but the less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> it's putting out cause the better job it's doing burning stuff up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> and i
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and that opens up a whole another can of worms i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> is suppose to start out with they're gonna actually put out a line of electric <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah doesn't that sound neat if you were gonna if you if you could afford <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and you were going to do a lot of city driving
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah
 		um-hum oh that'd be a definite yeah that'd be the way to go for sure i think there's no questions in in in terms of whether i would have that or not i
 	
 	
 		go away from here
 	
 	
 		sounds like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> want to get on the conversation
 	
 	
 		just a minute
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX> from my presence i'm on the telephone
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i bet they'd have something to say about buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		well my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> think it's great we've  unfortunately our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convertibles</ENAMEX> have been retired for lack lack of time on our part to um
 		to work on them but we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX> an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX> and an old MGB
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		sitting in behind our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are convinced the older <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are convinced that that's going to be their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX> hasn't figured out yet just you know it's like who want oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> you know and the but the other ones aren't very old either
 	
 	
 		how old are they
 		oh i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's like who's going to inherit you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>'s like well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini van</ENAMEX> you know you got to go get another old convertible my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> would love to buy next is a Miata
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> Miata
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard some good things about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		it's suppposed to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		really solid car we have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		yeah a big factor for me is is ergonomics and and in terms of control and display design that's that's what i'm going into for my degree
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		and so that's that's something i really try to consider a little more heavily heavily than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably do but
 	
 	
 		well it they have something that
 		you know i there's some things i like better about my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX> and some things i like better about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> and uh you know and i'm always looking at that kind of thing at other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it it
 	
 	
 		it's amazing how much spot light it's gotten lately you know it seems like everyone that's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> now you know it's
 	
 	
 		well it's not just you know but like i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that tells me which door is open and the other one only tells me that a door is open
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so when it only tells me that a door is open i have to get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and go around slamming doors until i mean that's a nuisance that's a real pain
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah um and one of them only has the standard full to empty gauge and the other
 		
 		
 	