
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay um Chuck</ENAMEX> do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> there at your home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i do
 	
 	
 		and what kind do you have
 	
 	
 		i've got a male Siamese <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year old</TIMEX> here i live alone in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>  how about you
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  well we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat um</ENAMEX> he's probably
 		oh a good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years old</TIMEX> big old fat and sassy tabby
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh how's the disposition of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Siamese cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's uh you know they're just uh aggressive by nature
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he's been neutered and declawed so and he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">indoor cat</ENAMEX> so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that kind of calms him down for the most part and uh
 	
 	
 		well yeah he's uh he has been really aggressive at especially towards my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> for some reason he's uh
 	
 	
 		how about yours
 		huh
 	
 	
 		been so mean to her  and
 	
 	
 		and and you say you had him how long
 	
 	
 		we've had him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> and and he was so mean to her
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um right after we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got him so we had him neutered and
 		and declawed and now he bites her he can't scratch her anymore he bites her
 	
 	
 		huh
 		does he bite her enough to draw blood
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah he has a couple of times so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he's a very
 		possessive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> he he loves my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> it's his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and he's the only one that allows him to touch him or pet him or love him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and he's so funny he just follows my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> around just like a dog
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		he won't even let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> shower he meows and wants to get in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and while he showers it's so hilarious
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so he's quite a animal
 	
 	
 		yeah boy i guess well as long as he doesn't get too aggressive i guess  with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> he's all right you wouldn't want him to carry her off or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well we we did uh actually take him to the pound a couple of times you know because we just couldn't have him being so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		aggressive towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> but
 		uh he seems to have mellowed out a little bit and we do keep our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> away from him so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		were it not for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> would not be in this house
 	
 	
 		is that the only pet that you have
 	
 	
 		it is uh-huh we've we tried a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years ago</TIMEX> and we ended up with a
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malamute</ENAMEX> and
 		some other kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mix</ENAMEX> anyway it was it ended up being just a huge huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that ate us out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and home so
 		we gave him up
 		and tried
 	
 	
 		well do you live you you in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or a place where you uh
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh we're in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but we're in a subdivision where we really can't allow the dog we couldn't allow him to run free so he was just chained up all the time and it was it was unfortunate
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i see
 		sure
 	
 	
 		so have you tried any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no i i live alone in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and uh it's it's not that big that uh although i've heard rabbits are pretty good
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know i i saw something on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> or on cable here uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a while ago that showed some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that had rabbits in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my word
 	
 	
 		and in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and they apparently uh especially when they're young when they bring them in uh
 	
 	
 		oh my word
 		and do they they just paper train it or something
 	
 	
 		i guess i guess yeah and i would imagine that they don't have many more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to start with either because uh
 	
 	
 		yeah  well rabbits are darling that would be fun if you could get them trained otherwise they're pretty smelly  um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yep that's right
 		did you see the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> the the dog show uh
 	
 	
 		huh-uh we don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> we don't have cable
 	
 	
 		they
 		i see well they have uh
 		uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster</ENAMEX> they call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Westminster Dog Show</ENAMEX> uh uh i think it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> at the at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gardens</ENAMEX> there once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> live
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and they had that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and that's really kind of something to watch uh it's on i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three nights</TIMEX> for maybe <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		oh
 		is that right oh
 	
 	
 		and uh some of the weirdest <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> you ever wanna see on there some of them are really beautiful too  yeah so
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh-huh  well that would be interesting to watch
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		so you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> do you
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton</ENAMEX> we live  out here by it's by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ogden</ENAMEX> it's north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		goodness
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we really love it out here it's uh
 		kind of country we're we're <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about ten minutes</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but not too
 	
 	
 		well
 		do you all work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> or or
 	
 	
 		not
 		no huh-uh do you
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh well see i'm getting so many calls to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this is the very <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one i've i've talked to you know
 	
 	
 		oh well great yeah i've been doing it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks</TIMEX> and uh no my
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	