
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		topic is recycling today
 		and actually i'm pretty hot about the topic right now yes i am
 	
 	
 		oh you are
 		you're you're into uh recycling
 	
 	
 		i'm into recycling i've got several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who use me as their recycling drop off matter of fact
 	
 	
 		um-hum what materials do you recycle
 	
 	
 		i recycle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass plastic</ENAMEX> and aluminum
 		also paper and plastic bags
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> we recently had a report on the news in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
 		about what's being done with the recycled the recycling materials
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and several other items but green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> in particular is being tossed into the landfills
 		and i got really hot about that because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> drinks a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ginger ale</ENAMEX> and it's packed in green glass
 	
 	
 		so
 		so you're trying to take action to have that changed
 	
 	
 		well yeah i'm i'm racking my brain thinking okay where can i what can i do to take action on this the only recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> i think in the south is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're paying i think
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen</NUMEX> cents
 		for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> pounds of green glass
 	
 	
 		right so economically it's not a situation where you're going be able to attract a lot of attention
 	
 	
 		no i'm not but i've got
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		good gosh i've got probably
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty or thirty</TIMEX> pounds of it in my yard right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		waiting for a recycling place to take it to and
 		i would really be disturbed if i found out that the place i took it to
 		was going to just put it in the landfill i mean i could have done that
 	
 	
 		well i think um that is kind of becoming one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> now the fact that with all the recycling that took place the price per pound has declined i know aluminum in our area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year ago</TIMEX> aluminum was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five cents</NUMEX> a pound and now it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty last time</TIMEX> i went it was twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two cents</NUMEX> a pound
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it uh  there's not a lot of money to be made but it's just a question of trying to help the environment
 	
 	
 		no
 		well that's the that's the thing is  i uh i would rather help my environment and uh when i turn in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and aluminum i turn it in to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> which has a community center
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community center</ENAMEX> uses the money to help with an after school program to help keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and to to give them a fighting chance in the world
 		in regards to education and i think that's a real worthwhile project and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's really what got me started recycling was this uh community center
 	
 	
 		hm yeah where  where i work we recycle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that's about it
 	
 	
 		so
 		do you which kind of paper computer paper
 	
 	
 		yeah any any um noncolored noncolored or nonfilm type paper just white paper and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		oh any
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh-huh but do they recycle computer paper
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i mean like the the green and white barred
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh we don't use that kind of paper any more no we have perforated
 	
 	
 		oh you don't use that paper okay
 	
 	
 		for personal printers and then like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaserJet</ENAMEX> type paper
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		we don't use the green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> type paper any more
 	
 	
 		the old the old green bars um-hum
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah because our our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> also recycles computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and
 		i don't know why i was thinking it was just the old green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> style as opposed to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even the personal
 		uh letter sized
 	
 	
 		well i would guess that your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is probably at a point where they're not really breaking even on their recycling
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		uh well
 	
 	
 		unless they get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have trucks and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> and there's not that it's
 		not that wide of a participation participation just yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so although with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> helping we we contribute quite a bit of glass we all have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 		quite a few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are in baby food
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> food jars believe it or not really add up fast
 	
 	
 		right well there are neighborhoods in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> area where uh you have specific trash bins to put recyclables in and then they're collected on a regular basis
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh yeah curbside recycling
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah they have that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		and i saw another report where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> they take the bins
 		and they load them up into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> in the separate areas in the truck
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the truck goes and dumps all of it into one landfill
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that got me heated up too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that got me real heated up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s told her about that and she was telling me about it and then i saw a report on TV too
 		and i thought why are we going through this trouble
 		and i had a report tell me why we are we go through the trouble because everybody's worried about the environment
 		and now that we have uh the the smaller the lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> worried about the environment
 		now we have to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> worried about using the recycled product
 		that not that many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	