
 
     		
 	
 		okay so you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um what type of things do you do as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to spend time together
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh we spend a lot of time out doors jogging bicycling uh going to the park
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um  some time watching VCR movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um generally cheap things
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  yeah we know how that goes uh
 		with lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you don't have lots of money for recreation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> that's fun so um
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		let's see uh some of the things we do together as a family we like to play games a lot and
 		uh you may think this is funny but one of our funnest games we like to play together is hide and seek and  we just have a hoot playing hide and seek when it's dark in our house
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that is so fun the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just get a crack out of that
 		um we like we do like to go to the park too you like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> um
 		we don't do a lot of vacationing have you taken a lot of vacations together or
 	
 	
 		most of our vacations are to go and see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grandpa</ENAMEX> we get an occasional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two day</TIMEX> thing but most of them are going and seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandma</ENAMEX> and Grandpa
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and where
 		oh
 		oh now where do they live
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so that's a bit of a drive for you then oh so you like to go there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh we don't go very often for holidays generally we try to get all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> back home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Grandpa</ENAMEX> come and visit us
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh uh-huh uh what are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		they range from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four to five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah so you have some in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX> and some out huh  we have ours start at twelve and then they go down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		i think the hardest thing for us has been is to find activities you know leisure time activities that all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can enjoy together
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 
 		i bet yeah
 	
 	
 		with the age span that we have you know like the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love playing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> games and that kind of thing but the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't understand it
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and so they get real frustrated when we try to do that and
 	
 	
 		yes and then if you want to play something on the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' level then the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get real bored and and they want to and do something else so yeah i can i can relate to that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um do you feel that the current trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> spending time together is a positive one or a negative one
 	
 	
 		i think it's improving actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we had an interesting experience <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> we we have a pretty much a a routine that we spend we don't have our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and we just kind of keep them at home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and our next door neighbor uh we were at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and our next door <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> was there
 		somebody came up and asked if if their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> could spend  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and she said no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays our</TIMEX> family day  and we keep our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at home so we can spend time with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		and i think those kinds of things are happening a lot where we are right now i think it's gone to one extreme where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> were just all running every different direction
 	
 	
 		oh good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are interested in spending time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		i think so and i feel like you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Bush</ENAMEX> has mentioned quite often that we are trying to become a kinder and gentler <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and it does begin with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so i i'm a firm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in that too
 	
 	
 		i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are panicked how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are turning out and how things are going for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and realizing they've got to start doing something so
 	
 	
 		um yes that's that's true well we see that a lot out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um so hopefully hopefully it's going to spread huh that's a good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s a lot better than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh um do you have a lot of large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> out there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 		very few
 	
 	
 		very few you feel like you're in the minority
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh definitely when we tell people how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we have they look at us like we didn't have good sense but uh
 	
 	
 		oh dear  oh well out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five</TIMEX> is about the the average yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		average yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> until i guess we were about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we've never been back since then but we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> up there now so we get up occasionally
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		oh i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> out there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s out there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> right now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> with her cousins on their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		where where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well uh no i'm trying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aberdeen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		it is that close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> oh don't you it's i guess guess it's out there clear out they have a ranch it has like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hundred acres</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i don't have any idea i've never heard of it must be a little town
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	