
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh i myself am not in favor of drug testing in the work place except in in specific uh
 		very specific in this uh very specific examples such as uh transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> as in uh air traffic controllers <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't really  think that it's uh
 		too many i think it's a severe invasion of somebody's privacy to say well we're going to look at your urine and then decide whether you're uh you know worthy of working for us i really don't see that that's a very very valid uh
 		thing for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to say and i personally i don't think i would work for somebody if they were going to reject me on the basis of what's inside my body
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i guess i basically agree that uh do you think it's okay for a company
 		to reject somebody just knowing that they have take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i mean suppose they found out some other way
 	
 	
 		well i think i think what you i think the problem here is is that a a drug test does not necessarily imply that someone is taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or not taking drugs
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		there's too many cases where it can you know there can be false positive results and that that sort of thing i don't think there's any definitive you know okay this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> so we don't want him here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		like i said some industries though i think it'd be very necessary i wouldn't want any air traffic controllers high or anything like that when i'm flying in an airplane
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i mean i just i find it to be pretty offensive that that it's such a a big deal i mean if your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s not going to trust you or you know it i just i think it's a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> issue i just can't see it
 	
 	
 		have you ever been in a situation where you you were drug tested or
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i have been
 	
 	
 		yeah i have once too so
 	
 	
 		i
 		i mean i was very offended by by the whole process i mean it's uh very humiliating and i mean i'm not speaking in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but i uh i am totally against that sort of a uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it's it's a pretty personal thing when somebody says i want to look at your urine before i'm going to talk to you
 	
 	
 		yeah i had it during a job interview and
 		i just thought it was dumb of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> at a point where they were trying to convince me to to want to work for them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to do this and i'm just like well uh i'm not even going to think much about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you're gonna treat me with this much respect even before
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you've gotten to know me
 	
 	
 		right that that's basically my opinion on it right there is that it's just
 		you know i did i it was in the same sort of situation as it was a job interview and then you had a physical where you were drug tested and it's i just i mean i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been drug tested and who have not you know
 		been hired by a corporation
 		which uh you know i really The other side of it is is besides its being an invasion of personal privacy as in my it's my bodily fluid and i don't really want you to look at it or or something pretty basic like that just to the fact that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know that it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s business to regulate what it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are doing when they're not at work
 		i mean the during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the eight hours</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when they're supposed to be there i think they have every right to say this is these behaviors are acceptable and these are not but when it enters into what they're doing when they're not at work i find that to be fairly offensive also
 	
 	
 		yeah well like you say i mean if it's not a critical kind of job where someone could get hurt then really what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ought to be doing
 		i mean the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> ought to be judging you on how well you do your work rather than on these other factors
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i mean if you are doing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and it's causing a problem then they'll notice it for other reasons
 	
 	
 		that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and also i just think it it gets a lot i'm a big uh supporter of personal freedoms and personal privacies and i think that it just moves down along a line that
 		that i really would find bad if if most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> went down that line into regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' lives outside of work when you know there's already talk of people well we're not going to hire you if you smoke
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well you know i i can see how they can say in the work place we you don't want them to smoke but when somebody leaves work i don't think that it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s right to regulate their lifestyle at all
 	
 	
 		well do you think it's should be illegal for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> to do this or
 	
 	
 		uh i really think it should be except as i've mentioned twice now in the specified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> or or jobs because there are certain things where it's just vital that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is clear minded at all times
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and other than that i think i do not think it should be allowable i think it should be illegal for them to to want to do that
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		it should it's kind of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> syndrome  i mean i just anything like that just kind of scares me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i tend to to view it
 		even though i don't think i'd work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that did that i sort of want to defend
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s rights as opposed to an individual's uh in addition to an individual's rights but an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> really i think has the right to hire someone on any basis they want to
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and if they say they don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> i sort of feel like an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> should have the right to decide whether they want to allow that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and  i don't really
 		
 		
 	