
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i think
 	
 	
 		yes yes i'm sure that it
 	
 	
 		let's see i didn't i didn't hear the message that it says you make the uh maybe i didn't press it hard enough let's try again
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hum
 	
 	
 		well it it just that that uh recording would begin when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who called presses
 	
 	
 		right okay so so i will just assume that we are being recorded now i thought that they had a confirmation message when that occurred but perhaps not anyway i did press let me press <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> once again
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i'll i'll take it that that did it okay so um the answer to that well maybe i should answer the question <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> since i have had so long to think about it um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i uh use uh a program on my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> which is called <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Dollars and Cents</NUMEX> actually it hails from the bay area where you're from and uh
 	
 	
 		oh i'm not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frisco Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frisco Texas</ENAMEX> uh gee i don't even know
 	
 	
 		where are you
 	
 	
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh North Carolina</ENAMEX> i thought you said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowlett</ENAMEX>  we have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> out here yes okay you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i see okay well anyway it doesn't hail from the area where you are
 		but uh uh anyway uh so so anyway i use this a personal personal accounting program on my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> to keep track of expenses but it also has a budget feature but i don't find it very useful because it makes all kinds of assumptions that aren't
 		the case in my situation so i use the the little spread sheets for that i i i don't know actually i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are in the series are a little bit familiar with computers but if you're not let me know and i will give more explanation
 	
 	
 		oh okay i am familiar i am familiar with computers
 	
 	
 		okay so have you do you do you use a computer to do your budgeting
 	
 	
 		no we don't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh takes care of our finances and he just uh just does it all all manually he keeps uh a book sort of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he uh doesn't keep it on the computer i work with computers and we have one at home but he doesn't use it for that
 	
 	
 		i found that it was uh you well you have a lot more information if you use a computer because you just can't keep track of everything manually you'll never go back through the old slips and see what your electric bill was and so forth but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if if you can just print it out it gives you a lot better feel for how you stand compared to last year
 		um
 	
 	
 		and that is a software program that was written for your uh i mean that you
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		just for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dollars and Cents</ENAMEX> and actually the leading program is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing</ENAMEX> Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monies</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Tobias</ENAMEX> but i used that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> and it was so awful that i just gave up
 	
 	
 		too much detail
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		was it too much detail to it
 	
 	
 		it was well it would bring up a new screen for everything you know you you um
 		you would make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> entry like for example if you were reconciling your check account and you wanted to
 		change a transaction let's say you wanted to add in interest or put in a fee or something it took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> screens to do that and you could only see the one transaction you were working on all the earlier transactions were hidden it was just it it you just
 	
 	
 		primitive
 	
 	
 		yeah it had tunnel vision i mean it had a lot of features but they were all so hard to use that i never never really used any of them so
 		uh i i i read since then though that they've redesigned redesigned uh redesigned the interface so probably it's a little better uh than it was before um
 		so um do you do you do a uh a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> budget or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> budget or
 	
 	
 		uh i am not sure right now i think he is keeping he has it uh kind of a forecast out for oh about the next uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> or so he keeps track of all of um
 		you know the the payments that are due when and uh what what pays off when and uh of course he knows ahead of time about when the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s is due and when the car insurance is due and such like that and he just
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		sort of keeps uh i guess you would say a running record of it so that he he knows at what point uh we are going to be able to to have uh some extra money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh yeah i try and uh i think that one of the things i've i've worked on is cutting down on the number of transactions
 		uh so so i i instead of paying bills <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> if they are not very much uh i just pay enough for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> when i pay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX>'s bill and that way i have to send you know substantially
 		fewer number of things out in the mail which saves a lot of time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> gee i pretty my pay my cable TV annually
 		you get a discount for doing that they give you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the thirteenth month of month</TIMEX> of service free if they remember
 	
 	
 		well that's nice
 	
 	
 		but they say  uh they always forget you  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they mess it up and forget to give me credit or or or shall i say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> out of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last six years</TIMEX>
 		so i called in and uh at first i got kind of upset  but now
 	
 	
 		now you expect it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah now i know they are going to do that um
 		
 		
 	