
 
     		
 	
 		okay um i guess we're going to talk describe uh job benefits and so what do you think next to salary do you rank is the most important job benefits
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i would say the medical uh group insurance uh area as far as uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		covering medical costs for yourself or family members
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well um does your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> have good benefits in that  in that regard
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i work for a a public school system district and uh  so it's different than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> fund almost the entire thing where the school district does um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> must pick up
 		a greater figure in the way of uh costs but overall um i've been pleased with it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> i think the biggest frustration
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is because of the cost of insurance
 		going up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> has had to alter uh you know change <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or now we're on a managed care thing which has stressed a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out although
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		it has not disturbed me any how about yourself
 	
 	
 		i see
 		uh well i'm my medical coverage is with an HMO um so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's in my opinion that's getting that's bordering on a health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> but it seems to be a good way to maintain costs and still provide a good amount of coverage um
 	
 	
 		right yeah our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district</ENAMEX> did that
 		for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school year or calendar years</TIMEX> and i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> and um
 		i i was because my my same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> you know agreed to be in it for uh they usually sign a contract or something and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i did have surgery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> and i paid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars when i went to see him that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first day</TIMEX> and i've never seen another bill so i i have to say it really works but again
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i was fortunate because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> agreed to be in it uh if you've been going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> for you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> or something and he elects not to join
 		it can be very stressful for you know those people
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's right yeah i'm i'm fairly young myself i've only been
 		when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started working which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> is when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got into full time employment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh at that time i immediately joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> and i never really
 		so the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> i i've kind of consistently had has been through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> and uh you know for me it's worked out real good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right but if you you know have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and um
 		everybody's gone to different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> uh it is hard to give up somebody who you feel
 		knows you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and your just has you know all the medical history and you feel comfortable with it i i'm sure it would be very stressful and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i have just elected that if that happens i will go and just pay you can continue to go to your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> but your benefits are not as
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know good so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um like you you mentioned you work for a school system i work for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> in the research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> and i guess
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh all right
 	
 	
 		another one that that that i rank up there high is the uh kind of job flexibility and time off um i enjoy as a as a benefit
 	
 	
 		i do too are you talking about like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> break and right
 	
 	
 		right yeah getting a lot of a lot of breaks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between quarters</TIMEX> and that and having a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		it it really um
 		i don't think
 		most of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> now i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i am the a secretarial executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> but
 		i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> could stand the stress all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> long frankly it is just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has really um
 		
 
 		you know they want everybody educated no matter what it's costs uh and it it would be just
 		we all look forward to like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> break and i don't know who looks forward to it more the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> or the or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> what do you do there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		well um i'm not actually on the teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> but we have a large research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and that's who i work with
 	
 	
 		okay i like
 	
 	
 		um
 		and we're given you know a good bit of flexibility in what we do we can kind of pursue our own interests in terms of the research areas that we study
 	
 	
 		well that's good yeah i would think that that type of
 		employment you're you're
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one day</TIMEX> you might be really tuned in and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> oh a little lukewarm or something and and um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it's good that they allow you that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it um as i say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> now we do have to work you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> but we do get
 		many days off and um
 		we all look forward to it that's only reason i work there is that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now have graduated and graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> but at the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i worked there because my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> were the same as theirs and uh i've just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		continued to uh stay there
 	
 	
 		okay are there
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		are there any things that that you'd like to see changed in terms of the the benefits
 		
 		
 	