
 
     		
 	
 		okay i guess we're on uh capital punishment uh
 		my my feeling by the way is that i think there is a need for capital punishment i don't think it ought to be applied to every crime obviously but there is a need how do you feel about it
 	
 	
 		oh i believe there is you know there is a need for it like you said it shouldn't be applied to every every crime you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i feel like you know they need to
 		instead of giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on on uh
 		you know like death row and stuff just leaving them there and sit there and make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> pay for it i think they ought to do something about it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it does does get uh strung out too long that they uh they keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten twelve years</TIMEX> uh uh that seems to be the norm
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		i i don't know how effective a deterrent it is when when that happens uh but
 		more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are being executed for crimes i think down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> didn't you have one an execution down there
 	
 	
 		yeah we had uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> just yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple days</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		yeah well they haven't executed anybody in uh in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> since i think nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty four</NUMEX> or somewhere around that time frame it's it's been a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we do have the death penalty but uh they don't use it very much instead they sentence them to life and uh we end up as you say uh fitting the footing the bill <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next forty</TIMEX> or fifty years
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's what i think that they need to do something to change that because
 		i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> should have to pay for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to stay in the stay in there for life you know
 	
 	
 		i think one interesting question would be uh
 		uh you know as far as circumstances uh i think we agree if somebody you know is involved with a premeditated murder or you know a cold blooded first degree murder they deserve the death penalty that's in my opinion i don't know how do you feel about that
 		if they take another human life you know and they've they've planned to do this
 		or they're doing it for pay don't you think that deserves the the death penalty
 	
 	
 		it sure does
 	
 	
 		now how about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> where they don't directly take a life you know it's not like they're pulling the the the trigger on a gun or or something like that what do you think about uh major drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> getting the death penalty
 	
 	
 		well that not they're partly you know they're a lot responsible for it because they're the ones selling the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to the to the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> out on the street you know and i think they they need to get capital the capital punishment
 	
 	
 		i think capital punishment in those instances is probably even more effective than for uh the just the common street criminal that kills somebody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> probably isn't thinking too much about it but these major drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> uh you know they got some brains they wouldn't be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> if they didn't have and if they're threatened with the death penalty i think it might make a difference on them
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i think it would too you know sometimes i think they ought to just  take them out and shoot them and just you know but uh
 		that's my opinion on some of the cases
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i think <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is a bad deal and stuff
 	
 	
 		that's right it certainly ruins a lot of lives uh whereas a you know somebody that uh
 		is holding up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and shoots somebody effects a fairly small circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that was killed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but but a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> a major <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> is effecting what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of lives
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and in effect causing some of them to die
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and you know it's
 		especially i just saw something on TV <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> on the news about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> so it's
 		effecting it's way down there in the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and stuff and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> need to be sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life imprisonment and stuff you know or given the death penalty
 	
 	
 		yeah and and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX> even gets into the grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> when they sell these uh stickers they look like uh i guess they're dots on a piece of paper or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know that's really that's really a crime to give it to the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i guess we've talked about all we can on this topic what do you think
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 	
 	
 		okay well it's been nice talking with you hope you have a nice day good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> talk to you later bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay you too
 		all right bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	