
 
     		
 	
 		oops hello i pressed the button one so we're recording right now i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 		that's okay i'm Bill from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrisville Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so another one from
 		a different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> besides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  um okay Bill we're talking about family reunions
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		okay um have you ever had to plan a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yes and no it wasn't really a family a planning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but it was kind of uh it was a birthday and i brought a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> together then
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and how did you feel it went
 	
 	
 		it went pretty good i'm i've worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> so i i kind of know how to do these things i used to you know
 	
 	
 		oh
 		all of this planning and and getting together and such
 		um
 		oh let's see what else
 	
 	
 		usually when we have kind of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s birthday and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's all of like she she comes from a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> she has like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		and they show up and all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and then all she has uh i have
 		like uh let's see she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they show up and all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so it's a pretty big reunion it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> maybe
 	
 	
 		oh my word  oh well what did you find was most helpful in planning the birthday get together
 	
 	
 		um the probably the biggest challenge was uh getting a place where everyone
 		you know could eat comfortably and and everything uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess probably the most helpful thing was that uh
 		for the rent uh we rented like a a rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> building or something like that and uh
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the everybody that showed up donated donated some money for the rent and for
 		for like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soft drinks</ENAMEX> and and so nobody like really got stuck with the bill  each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the family you know brought a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> or some
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh that's good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and then did you have a main <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> or did everyone just bring it was just potluck uh-huh
 	
 	
 		it was kind of potluck you know everybody brought their specialties i guess you would say
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah show off a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and of course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was as always gone first because she's such a great cook
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh now how old is she
 	
 	
 		uh she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh goodness is she pretty spry is she you know pretty
 	
 	
 		now she does she looks probably like she's in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early sixties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and if she didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> she'd get around better than me as a matter of fact
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh  oh well that's neat that she's in good health and that at that age
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh my nickname for her is honey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that's what i call her
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really  well that sounds fun well i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i had a real challenge of planning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and there were we sent out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> uh announcements
 		because our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is quite large like your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there and
 		so that was a real challenge and i was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and
 		i wasn't sure i appreciated that duty for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>  but i found that advance planning was the key to success
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> also one thing that's helpful and i don't know if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s spread out or whatever but most of all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lives like in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>  so it's just kind of like get on the telephone and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well that was wonderful though
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's so and such <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> from such and such date and everybody just shows up
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh well that is that is helpful yeah our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> ranges from oh goodness
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boise Idaho</ENAMEX> and
 		and uh all kinds of places
 	
 	
 		i would say you're spread out then
 	
 	
 		we are
 	
 	
 		uh my my immediate family you know my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> i guess we're the ones that have the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gypsy blood</ENAMEX> or whatever because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and we were
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we were pretty strung out all over but since they've moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>'s uh we still are the only ones do not live in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anson County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> and then my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> and i have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> and um another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that lives in outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayetteville</ENAMEX> so i mean we're we're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're spread out but everybody else is centralized in in my home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> Waynesboro so
 	
 	
 		boy
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		nobody moves away except us  yeah i got out as soon as i graduated
 	
 	
 		they must really like it there
 		yeah  oh
 	
 	
 		just like this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is too small for me good-bye
 	
 	
 		oh  you're ready to move on to big
 		
 		
 	