
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um have you had any experience in trying to find child care
 	
 	
 		um yes some what um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sitting here like
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> and i share <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sitting and um then i ran a preschool so i know you know from the other end you know trying to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		really
 	
 	
 		find day care so yeah
 	
 	
 		okay well i've done more or less the same we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		so what about you
 		goodness
 	
 	
 		uh yeah  i just haven't found it equitable to work outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and so i have done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care inside my home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		how has that worked out
 	
 	
 		well i've done it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and uh it's pretty well driven me crazy
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		yeah i can imagine i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i think i mean
 		it's sometimes it's easier like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was gone and i had  my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> nieces and nephews over and it was really much more calm than than than having just my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh was it oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's true sometimes sometimes they do offer a just a play time for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yeah
 		yeah it it depends though it depends on how well behaved the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are yeah we have some times its like oh if i can only get these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		hum
 	
 	
 		um  hang hang on just a second  um
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay just a second i'm on the phone  yeah i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> preschoolers um but uh
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i i think it's we've wanted to do i've wanted to join a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sitting co-op
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and um that's we there're several of them around here um
 		the one my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in law is in you have to be recommended in to
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> you know that way some one knows you and you and you just aren't giving your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and i just haven't found one that's close enough to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that i feel comfortable with at this point um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but because i mean you don't wanna you don't wanna leave with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with anybody and um
 	
 	
 		no no you don't
 	
 	
 		the day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> around here i i really my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to preschool and i have found some really good ones um
 	
 	
 		oh good
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them goes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days a week</TIMEX> and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> goes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day a week</TIMEX> and that's a nice break and  it's this is a
 	
 	
 		oh how fun
 	
 	
 		i really like the one that that they're in um they've got some really qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> there they've been there for a long long time they've got um a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		certified kindergarten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> doing the curriculum for the older you know the fours and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year olds</TIMEX> and stuff so that's that is really good i really like that
 	
 	
 		oh good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that would be fun yeah that's good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and then it's fun for you too to have that little break during the week
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i like that i i like that little break oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh now on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op um</ENAMEX> do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> just trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sitting or
 	
 	
 		you you you start out with like coupons and um i don't  i think i think you start out like with say <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> and and you have to um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when when you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sit somebody they pay you in coupons and then um
 		they uh then you pay the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in coupons and i think some of them is in like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX> time slots or in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> time slots and you have to do it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		um-hum oh gosh
 	
 	
 		you know per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child um</ENAMEX> at least the the ones that i've seen that have worked and then they normally get together like once a month and um
 		to you know decide you know how many do you have and and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they say okay you need to you know if if you're taking in a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sitting
 		and you're not you know doling it out also then um
 		a lot of times they'll say okay you need to you know you need to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sit for you um that way it'll even out you some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't getting you know without they don't have any more coupons left
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh what my goodness
 	
 	
 		and um their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> meetings the one i went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and they a lot of times they'll have um special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come and talk about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh say safety or you know different things with about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and some times they'll just have get togethers you know even even with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it gets them helps them to know one another and then you know its can be pretty informative also
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well that sounds like a terrific idea my goodness i haven't heard of anything like that out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and it sounds like that'd be something good to start huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah i that's i don't know all the um i don't know all the details uh um i i i don't know if
 		it seems like it seems like her the my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in law's um uh they are in
 		
 		
 	