
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh well we have a budget we go by every pay check  since i have been in the service we get paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice a month</TIMEX> so that's what i go by
 	
 	
 		well we
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		we try
 		it's it's not as easy as i had thought it would be but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i started keeping a total of our expenses and and where they were all going and i have uh a budget book that i use
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have personal computers it would be much easier
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um and then at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> i i totaled up what we were spending say for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> or or entertainment or things like that and then this year i tried to keep it within
 		you know a bounds there and then if there's if we are over budget in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> item if we want to apply that to another one i try to do that but it's not always
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		easy when you have extra expenses say the car repairs came up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> things like that that you're not expecting
 		i don't really know how some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stay within a budget
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i can i can understand that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you have kids
 	
 	
 		got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		one we don't have any because i thought if well if we had a child i don't know what we'd do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> gets paid once a week and i get paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every three months</TIMEX> i have a bonus check and but then that's when we we try to put some a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">side</ENAMEX> at that time
 		as far as savings uh i take out of each pay check i put so much into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K pan</ENAMEX> in a profit sharing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then he does the same thing he puts one into uh a stock plan at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and also into a retirement plan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because to me that's the only way we're ever going save to be able to save
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i
 	
 	
 		because if the money comes in it's spent if it's not taken out before i get it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i understand that right right now that's just the problem i have and we don't ain't been able to save any because i am putting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> through school right now
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		through nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so it's kind of
 		got to
 	
 	
 		that's very hard
 	
 	
 		maxed out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we try to put a little away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every every month</TIMEX> you know and plus we've got child care which we got to put in there and everything and
 		we try to put a little away for his you know school education and stuff for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> on
 	
 	
 		yeah they say how old is he
 	
 	
 		he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> they say by the time
 		kids his age are ready to go to college it's gonna be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about seventy thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year for college
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and it's just unbelievable
 	
 	
 		well that's
 	
 	
 		you know i i'm just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty nine</TIMEX> and when i went it was probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> for the tuition books and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah if you yeah it's kind of expensive for her you know going to nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is one of the more expensive ones
 	
 	
 		um-hum where is she going
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh U T</ENAMEX> A
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i'm sure it is
 	
 	
 		and you know
 		the the uh budget part kind of falls in there you know you get unexpected expenses and stuff
 		for that because she has to drive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty thirty minutes</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> to school and that
 		that adds more to the gas budget
 	
 	
 		oh yeah is she started having do the uh working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do what ma'am
 	
 	
 		has she started doing any of work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no she goes they have a class there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Tuesday</TIMEX> and that's what they do and then she'll start during her senior year
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> going to the hospital <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times a week so
 	
 	
 		yeah because i i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that just graduated and took her test to to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R N</ENAMEX> and i i think towards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> they were working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and then they all had to buy all the uniforms and
 		and all the things which was an added expense
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but it is hard i don't know in in compared to say my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and father
 		living in a budget was no problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was just this is what we have and this is what we spend but that's in this time and you know i don't know what it is it's well it's
 		you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> let's go play some golf you know something like that or let let's run to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> with me and and before you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		parent's didn't do that if they didn't have the money they didn't get it and we're not that way
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah i understand
 		that's the same problem we fall into you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know when we do have a little extra we try to go out and do a little something you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		be with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a little bit during that time and
 	
 	
 		and it's hard
 	
 	
 		kind of a family deal
 	
 	
 		and as far as like the you know with interest rates now as low as they are
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card rates are still
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sixteen seventeen eighteen nineteen</ENAMEX> percent
 		
 		
 	