
 
     		
 	
 		what do you do there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> as far as uh recycling is concerned
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you know they actually started and i assumed it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> wide um uh they they've started putting out at least recycling bins for the paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i've you know either computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or different types of paper i've had some ideas on how i think they could probably do it a little um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		less expensively and accomplish the same purpose but i i guess i need to put it on paper and turn it in
 	
 	
 		oh yeah what what would be more efficient about it what what
 	
 	
 		um
 		well the way they have you know they have boxes located at certain areas throughout a module or down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> or  a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't going to get up walk out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and go there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know where i used to work we had what we called <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> boxes that's just what we called them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were recycled cardboard they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight and a half</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and you set it by your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> and you know as you got rid of a piece of paper you stuck it in there
 		and when it filled up you called you know facilities whoever to come pick it up and they brought you another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> so not only is it you know i think more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would take advantage of it and use it
 		uh i think you save a lot of the cleaning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>'s time and effort and money that we're paying for them to to empty the trash cans and combine it and bundle it and things like that now when it could all be done in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		kind of type thing so
 	
 	
 		i see yeah i i i i uh i was gonna say because i know i have right here a trash can for trash and a trash can for it says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> on it you know and uh if
 	
 	
 		right
 		but
 	
 	
 		if i have a if i i printed up something that i don't need it just chunk it in the in the paper
 	
 	
 		right but somebody still has to collect all that and bundle it together and whereas if you had a box that was preset and it got full you closed the box it's already bundled it's already done for you
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		hm
 		certainly that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		so you're saving a lot of time and effort i just need to put it on paper and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess recommended it to somebody and see if they think it's feasible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um what else do they do in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		well um as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s concerned i'm not sure um and
 		uh i've heard uh you know uh in residential situations i live in a dorm and i've heard in residential situations uh like in Plano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um that they are doing uh stuff like having recycle picked up
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		where uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> uh i guess the sanitation department uh as part of their responsibility picks up
 		uh the recycled items as well you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> and the paper  uh and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and um
 		the only responsibility of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> is to separate them and then the the uh i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> takes them and and does what they do with them and it doesn't cost the patron anything doesn't really cost the uh department
 	
 	
 		anything extra
 	
 	
 		right they don't pay they don't pay for the recycled items
 	
 	
 		that sounds good there's i i've been wanting to put like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of three bins like right out my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> door where you know from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> where
 		you know you can throw cans in one or the glass in the other or the uh even uh
 		there are areas that can recycle the the tin cans like your you know vegetable things come in and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i i've not done that but that's kind of what i wanna set up so because we do go through aluminum cans you know that's probably the one we use most
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but
 	
 	
 		well what what what kind of uh services do you have there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> as far as uh where can you take your recycle items i i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX> for a uh i went to school there at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abilene Christian</ENAMEX> and i it was so hard to uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		find a place
 	
 	
 		you know if you if you wanted to recycle your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> it was impossible
 	
 	
 		well um
 		uh
 		they they do have facilities for recycling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> aluminum cans
 		those are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major items now we can take oil like car <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> recycled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> to they have uh dump areas like at the fire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> throughout town
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't know that they yet have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> here to do the tin cans uh i think they can do the plastics like the liter bottles things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i i don't know i know for sure though they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> can and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> at the fire departments
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		i do that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are becoming more aware
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know of of the waste and you know i i like to see you know you you drive through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX> now and the bags are recycled paper and you know so you know i feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more aware of it or becoming more aware of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know like maybe it's making an impact
 	
 	
 		do you tend to buy more recycled items that if if something uh in the pack says recycled and something else doesn't do would you tend to chose the one that does or
 	
 	
 		i'm not as good about searching something out like that but if i'm there and the choice is there i would probably take the recycled product
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you know that's just where i probably need to be a little more responsible as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> wise you know looking or searching those out because you figure if we as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> do that then the manufactures and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> will start
 		packaging it that way
 	
 	
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		so um
 		you know they're getting away from the styrofoam
 		
 		
 	