
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hi Ed</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello Carolyn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you uh work for a large organization
 	
 	
 		yes i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina State University</ENAMEX> which has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six or seven thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow what do you do
 		are you
 	
 	
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and you do
 	
 	
 		i'm a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and always concerned about benefits
 	
 	
 		right well i i'm on the benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> here one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> so that's why i checked that topic
 	
 	
 		oh you are
 		i see uh
 		what do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is about benefits is it mostly in the area of health care
 	
 	
 		i swear that's what i was going to say we seem to get more more uh complaints about that than about anything else although you get a good deal of complaints over other kinds of insurance too um
 		
 
 		yeah health care we have we are on the state health system which is my understanding is that it is a lot worse than the system we had when we had our own just for the university
 		and i wouldn't be real surprised if that's the case um
 		
 
 		uh yeah they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are uh complaining because the rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> uh what you know the the uh
 		
 
 		uh the additional amount you have to pay to cover a family has gone up quite rapidly
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		well we've our benefits have changed recently to where we have network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and network <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> kind of uh a preferred provider
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the  you wouldn't believe the complaints
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		because  you know you're family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> may not happen to be in the network
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh so there uh you your benefits are reduced if you don't go to a network doctor
 	
 	
 		well
 		do you yeah but i mean do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get to choose whether to take the the preferred preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right you get to choose whether or not you want to change doctors
 	
 	
 		huh
 		right but so so so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would stay in an existing plan that that didn't require you to go to a preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> in that case right
 	
 	
 		no no the the plan allows you to do either one the benefits that are paid are considerably better
 		when uh
 	
 	
 		with the preferred provider
 	
 	
 		we are with the preferred provider yes
 	
 	
 		huh
 		wonder about the economics of that uh the uh you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>'s just got started uh when they started enrolling a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh it was felt that this would be the way to control health care costs
 		and it worked to some degree but it didn't work that much and the reason was adverse selection the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that go into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>'s are are those that have uh
 		you know that that have generally lesser health needs and i mean it's obvious why that is because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that that are already sick are going to see a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and they don't want to switch just to come in the HMO
 		so you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H O</ENAMEX> they they don't uh you know require that much uh care at all and then some how you got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> paying premiums into the into the uh insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> than you have uh uh
 		you you have almost as many claims so uh that's that's caused a problem uh
 	
 	
 		have you heard about uh cafeteria the cafeteria plan of benefits
 	
 	
 		yes uh i don't think we have a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> being a university industry tends to have a lot better programs
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't know i i would i'd be interested in seeing in learning more about that because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so i am not interested really in child care benefits except i suppose as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the world or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		well i i don't know i mean the questions is should should it be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> that pays for child care uh
 		if if there were a tax credit then everybody would get it regardless who they worked for and you you would also be better in the sense that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had only one income in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would get as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and you would sort of think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have one income kind of need it more
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i just i i like the concept of being able to choose which benefits are more important to you
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh yes no that that that it's true that's that's important i agree uh yeah that's true and child care is one of the big ones that that gets thrown in um
 	
 	
 		well you know if you were married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> then you might not need so much
 	
 	
 		medical care
 	
 	
 		medical insurance or something i don't know
 	
 	
 		i don't know about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you'd have you'd you'd have your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> visits covered but that's only a small part of the total
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh on the other hand you know maybe maybe if you had false teeth you wouldn't care about dental insurance
 	
 	
 		uh well i think you probably would need more denture work wouldn't you now i don't care too much about dental work because of of their dental the dental insurance because i rarely well almost never for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last eight years</TIMEX> have i used up enough to
 	
 	
 		would you
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh you know paid enough in in dental bills to uh come up to even the smallest amount you can set aside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>
 		uh but not everybody is like that and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that need uh you know an orthodontist services certainly would not be in that situation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 		but that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like
 		
 		
 	