
 
     		
 	
 		uh do you have any recycling going on in your community
 	
 	
 		uh yes we do we've started out with uh um
 		all the waste <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">haulers</ENAMEX> have uh been authorized or commanded i'll put it that way to pick up uh lots of
 		different kinds of waste
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they uh
 		uh the result has been that they have increased their rates by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> times
 		uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh so
 		now you have all kinds of of uh things they didn't use to pick up like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and uh
 		various forms of of uh
 		glass tin and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		so they used to pick this stuff up but just throw it away but
 	
 	
 		well no in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX> you didn't uh they didn't pick up any of that and then uh they started to pick up a few things but lately they've gone in to it in a big way and they've said the uh they have to pick up
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i think it's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and glass well plastic and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> which uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> nobody picked up
 	
 	
 		it's my impression that uh it's rare to find someone who will
 		recycle magazines
 		the glossy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and then they charge you for the service
 	
 	
 		yes well now these so they're
 		we're being charged because the rates have the trash uh pickup rates have gone up uh like i say almost by a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> for some people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		was this something that was voted on or uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> did it they decided that there was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> is kind of a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ecology</ENAMEX> minded area and so they uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh although there're some complaints because the
 		there were volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that would do it uh at a minimal charge and a lot of the
 		the articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> or the letters in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> have suggested that the waste <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">haulers</ENAMEX> now that they have a monopoly uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		they'd charge for it
 	
 	
 		they charge
 	
 	
 		whether
 		you take advantage of it or not
 	
 	
 		much more exorbitant rates than the uh than the volunteer you know you pay to have your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> recycled that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the past they said well we we were paying far less to have our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> recycled than we do now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because the waste hauling uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have a monopoly now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they can you know it's the old thing about uh now that i have to do it uh they can
 		they don't have to work very hard at at keeping costs down
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so how about your area
 	
 	
 		well we have uh
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer</ENAMEX> run recycling in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> near here uh in our own neighborhood there's a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that comes around once a week and uh picks up recyclables they do not pick up magazines
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i believe they don't pick up the plastic i think it's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories you talked about it's just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> bottles cans
 		and uh cardboard
 		and it used to be free
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> then they
 		sent out little flyers saying hey we still want to do this for free but we're not quite making ends meet and we'll take donations
 		and i
 		i'm i don't not sure if anybody really sent the donations in to this private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> just to be nice and i believe they're going to start charging now
 		uh
 		and i
 		i'm not sure what we're going to do i mean it definitely diminishes the amount of trash we have to put out
 		so it may work out monetarily
 		okay for us to be charged for it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and since they are private if they charge too much they'll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will just start throwing it in the trash
 	
 	
 		of course around here we we have to pay for our trash pick up
 	
 	
 		right we pay for our trash pickup but this isn't the trash people
 	
 	
 		oh i see what you're saying
 	
 	
 		this is another this is uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Carl Carl</ENAMEX>'s recycling
 		and uh he comes around with a truck of his own so it's completely uh
 		private and nonmandatory
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just put things out on the curb
 		um he's competing with some uh
 		very small scale <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who go around with shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> before his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> comes and try to get the most valuable recyclables
 		so it's uh
 	
 	
 		the thing that that has uh another thing that's been in the press here has been
 		that uh with the volume of recyclables coming in the the prices have dropped so that they can't even pay for the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how should i say it the market can't absorb
 		all of the uh
 	
 	
 		yes yes i've heard that that yeah it's uh
 		they have all this used newsprint that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want
 		right
 	
 	
 		right and certain kinds of glass uh the green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> has no market it's piling up
 		i don't know where they get green glass i guess they get it from
 		
 		
 	