
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh uh uh capital punishment i understand means if somebody commits a serious enough crime we kill them
 	
 	
 		that's correct
 	
 	
 		is that your understanding of it
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		well let me put it bluntly  there's not too many things that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> do right but one of the things they do is have a low crime rates they don't have too many repeat offenders
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they have uh very serious capital punishment over there
 	
 	
 		yes i i really think that um
 		there is room for that
 		i feel like if anybody has committed murder and they and they convict them that they definitely and they're sentenced to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> then it's not fair to have us to pay for them to stay there for life and then get paroled and go back out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i believe that if they're convicted and it's um
 		you know the only scary part i see in that is a crooked law system that would put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to death without enough evidence
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to close the case do you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah that shouldn't shouldn't happen but unfortunately it it can
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i i'm in i think we're pretty much in agreement uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> this
 		death by injection seems about as civilized a way as you can do it i guess
 	
 	
 		well i don't think it's too uh productive to put someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for a life time or like they say sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> life sentences on top of each other
 	
 	
 		yeah and then get out in what
 	
 	
 		right and um then they're repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> um i went to school with one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Bundy</ENAMEX>'s attacked girls
 	
 	
 		um
 		hm
 	
 	
 		she was um older than me she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> older but she went to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> as i did and we all knew when she was taken and he had been under suspicion and everything at that point
 	
 	
 		he killed her
 	
 	
 		and i think he killed her definitely uh-hum
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		well i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and hid the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> in the field
 		and every now that was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties every now</TIMEX> and then he comes up for parole it just scary that he could actually get back out
 	
 	
 		right um i think that in my belief i believe we uh i believe that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has killed
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		then there really isn't much point to them going on anyway because they pretty much ruined what they came to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> to do you know what they're here to do to try to make life um the best that they can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what would you think about public executions
 	
 	
 		i definitely no i don't think so i don't think that that's something that we should try to get excited about watching like boxing or some sport i don't agree with that and i don't even think that they need to
 	
 	
 		televised
 	
 	
 		have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than just a couple</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there to make sure that it's done and it should be i think it should be done as painlessly and just done as nicely as it can be
 		but i don't believe in keeping all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> what do you think
 	
 	
 		hm
 		uh
 		if if it's death let's get it over and done with uh the appeal process should be speeded up quite quickly quite quickly they had this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the  news that's been around since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy six</TIMEX> and he's cost us over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four million dollars</NUMEX> so far
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh let's speed it up be sure it's as close to being accurate as possible and get it over and done with on the other hand it may not be capital punishment if you committed armed robbery and get caught you shouldn't be out you shouldn't serve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and get credit for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or or ten days</TIMEX>
 		uh that maybe off the subject but uh
 	
 	
 		oh i think that there should be capital punishment even for other things i think somebody that's caught selling drugs
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		if that shouldn't be capital punishment but if they're the high ones that are making these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and importing them i think that you could consider that because in essence they're taking lives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i'd i
 		i'd go with the ones on the street corner
 	
 	
 		because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are thinking you know what am i going to get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> if i'm caught so what's the big deal
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no yeah start at the bottom start pushing the ones on the street corner they'll run out of supplies
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm cruel on that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> have no place at all
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and um
 		so i i i think that it could go even farther than
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that i don't know it's hard you don't want to be so mean that you're you're doing away with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have a chance to change
 		but then i you look at the reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and they act like they're reformed and then they get out and they repeat repeat these offenses
 	
 	
 		right
 		fairly quickly
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		fairly quickly i don't have uh you know  we're in so much agreement i guess i'm try to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s advocate
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> i can't even be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s advocate i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and i still think there's an appropriate place for it
 	
 	
 		that's
 		yeah i'm i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> also and that's why you get in the situation where um it says how i believe but if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s committed murder that's an unpardonable sin
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and so why should we pardon something that we don't believe our our Lord uh God is pardoning do you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i can go along with that i just wish we could get  get uh debate going here to get some verbal usage for the computer uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i have a brother-in-law that is strictly opposed to it and uh he is a uh very liberal uh
 		believer in uh probation uh and convicts not being sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> but being sent to uh halfway houses
 		
 		
 	