
 
     		
 	
 		okay um well why don't you go ahead and start because you have more experience it sounds like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> one of them 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year old</TIMEX> and one of them 's going on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> anyways where i'm located my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> it's really hard to find child care around here because most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are around here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're either <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Filipino</ENAMEX> and they don't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 		so it's like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> pick up really funny words
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they come home and say something to me and i don't understand what they're saying
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it's like i mean day care is really expensive it costs like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		for day care for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> and when they come home i don't even understand half the stuff they're saying
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh goodness
 		so do they know what they're saying though do they seem to know the words that they're saying
 	
 	
 		um
 		sometimes
 	
 	
 		because they're they're real young
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah because that could be a blessing further down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> but it can also be a problem now
 	
 	
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> he came home and said something and i asked him what he was saying i told him to point to it so i could understand what he was saying and he was talking about the cartoon you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he said it you know in i i don't even remember i don't i don't even know which one it was it was either <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Filipino</ENAMEX> i'm not even sure which language it was
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		but he knew it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pan</ENAMEX> it's just he didn't say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter Pan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and so it's kind of hard to understand what they're saying
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't wanna tell him not to say it because there's nothing wrong with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just  makes it hard to understand
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they'll be because at this age they're real real young and they could pick up any kind of language it it's amazing how easy they can learn
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i've uh i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as well my oldest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and my youngest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and i used to teach and when my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one was born i was lucky enough to be able to choose whether i wanted to work or not and
 		even though i had just gotten my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s degree i chose to stay home just because i worried a lot about child care and really wanted to be able to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that raised my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i like you're feeling the frustration of what they're picking up on that's exactly the worries that i had is that i worried about what kind of things they might be exposed to or pick up on and i was just really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paranoid</ENAMEX> and i guess just decided to be my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s caregiver and at times i've regretted it just because i miss working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know speaking regular language more than the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s you know kind of language
 	
 	
 		yeah and actually having conversations instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> line sentences
 	
 	
 		right right and as a cartoon once said i would like to have dinner with someone who can cut their own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing um
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		but now i'm getting up at the at the stage where i will need to go back to work and so i'm looking at this issue and my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> is just at the point where she'll be starting kindergarten <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> which is still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> so we'll still have to look at that kind of
 		of set up for her so
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i made a deal when our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was born because we had i had to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was after our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was born there wasn't any choice i had to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we made a deal he's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> he's gone on a ship
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so for those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> i don't work i stay home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but while he's in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> and he's you know on shore duty for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> then i work in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we have child care for them it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only six months</TIMEX> out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> but still it
 		it's just it's kind of weird because the quality of day care is different than what i'm used to because i'm i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> yeah really
 	
 	
 		oh are you so am i yeah what part oh okay i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mesa</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayer</ENAMEX>
 		yeah a little tiny dinky <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> up by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prescott</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but um it's really strange because
 		i'm used to just going to my next door <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> and she babysat me and you know when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> had when we first had our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> she babysat him until we moved and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's really different here
 	
 	
 		oh yeah because now you're depending on other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah moneywise and you don't know them and you're worried you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well it never happens to you it just happens to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> disappear but it's still scary when you have to look for day care
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you always have that fear
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i got to find somebody really you know really that i can depend on
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah
 		and even if you have someone there right at your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> doing that kind of day care you still always have that little worry i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		that's that is a problem what kind of criteria do you look for when you are shopping around
 	
 	
 		well i have a notebook and in it i have the top <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> questions  and that may sound kind of strange but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's i'm just kind of paranoid as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> it's like  i want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> safe
 		
 		
 	