
 
		
 			
 				well what kind of music do you like to listen to
 			
 			
 				
 				i'm pretty diverse actually um i consider myself both a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> and also an enjoyer so i kind of get into all all types i run the gamut from uh
 			
 			
 				are you
 			
 			
 				alternative to uh to rock and roll to heavy metal to you name it so i'm pretty open on that
 			
 			
 				oh you like country western
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s not bad i can i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> so it was like um yeah i i listen to it once in a while but it's it's probably not my my top mode i guess that's pretty pretty popular down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> though uh
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				um yeah we've i mean it you know there's you have all sorts here too um
 				i went to a pretty uh
 				well the school i went to was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M</ENAMEX> an and uh  either you either you went country western dancing or uh
 			
 			
 				oh yeah
 				so you didn't do anything at all right
 			
 			
 				yeah  pretty much pretty much so so i have i really liked i liked it there but i also also like some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> um contemporary music that they have play
 			
 			
 				huh
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 				are you into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> thing at all or is that popular down there right now i know that he's kind of a big name right now
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				yeah yeah it's popular here and  uh there's all
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				and you're also into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> contemporary stuff
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				yeah i had a i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> that was really into that he was into all the um
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like uh i'm trying to remember DMZ
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Resurrection Band</ENAMEX> uh what else
 				there are a couple of other ones he was into he was into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petra</ENAMEX> as well
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				in fact it's interesting he he's actually an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> i don't i i'm going to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 				and he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> that does sound mixing mixing right now for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> bands
 			
 			
 				oh really
 			
 			
 				so yeah he's pretty into it
 			
 			
 				that's fun
 			
 			
 				it's been it's been lucratim for him
 			
 			
 				well what you you mentioned alternative music
 			
 			
 				well yeah um kind of like
 			
 			
 				what is that
 			
 			
 				i don't know in the early seventies i think it was called punk rock
 			
 			
 				oh okay
 			
 			
 				but then now it's it's kind of taken a different slant and i think it's it's gone more diverse toward
 				um not so much the head banging on the wall stuff as much as just runs
 				really a wider more eclectic uh
 				tone flow and things like that so it's i don't know i like i said i consider myself fairly diverse so um
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 				you said you're also a performer
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah i well i play the trumpet um and also keyboards i played keyboards for about uh oh i don't know twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years</TIMEX> and played trumpet for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about ten so</TIMEX>
 			
 			
 				what do you perform
 				do you
 				oh wow
 			
 			
 				it it's good for a side diversion and a little bit of side income you know whenever i can do you do you play anything at all
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				um not on a consistent basis at this point  i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they're preschoolers so i do good to  get a book book read or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> read or anything so
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				oh wow
 				sure sure free time is not much of a luxury uh
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah
 			
 			
 				i know that feeling
 			
 			
 				in fact i do good to  listen to anything but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' tapes at this point because i know all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' tapes it's like yeah
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				
 				yeah well maybe hey that may be more quality you know after all
 			
 			
 				they do have they do have some good tapes out there for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we  i don't know um
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Scruggs</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that is out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> here that has some wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> tapes it's really i mean they are really fun and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Scruggs</ENAMEX> he's with he's an educational
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Scruggs</ENAMEX> huh
 			
 			
 				um it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shadow Play</ENAMEX> and if you ever see any of his stuff he is just he's really good and  and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um kids</ENAMEX> really like it
 			
 			
 				interesting uh
 				when you said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scruggs i</ENAMEX> was thinking because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Scruggs</ENAMEX> is a real famous <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">banjo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> a real famous blue grass player
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				and uh in fact if you remember the the theme from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beverly Hillbillies</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				he actually played part of that
 			
 			
 				oh
 			
 			
 				uh he and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lester Flats</ENAMEX> so uh i was thinking wow wonder if this is a relative
 			
 			
 				i don't know i don't know  well um  have you  um  they're not they're more uh oh have you ever heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Riders In The Sky</ENAMEX> i don't know if they're
 			
 			
 				but
 				anyway
 			
 			
 				if they're big up there in fact i think they may have even had a television show on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				oh
 				yeah i haven't heard much about that no
 			
 			
 				um
 				they're pretty neat they're kind of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a blue grass <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh they're real fun i mean they're
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that i mean they can yodel and they can they play the fiddles and the and the saws and stuff and they're real fun they're a real fun group
 			
 			
 				all right yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> probably get into that quite a bit
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				i'm uh i'm not quite at that point in my life yet so
 			
 			
 				yeah well yeah
 			
 			
 				it'll probably be a while before i uh before i get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' music in at all so
 			
 			
 				
 				well we saw them originally at a at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> down here um probably about oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX> and um
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				then just in the last i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> we saw them on a TV show  and i think they were i think they were doing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' music but
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				what we saw in the you know was adult in the but i don't know i don't know where they run the gamut and i don't know um
 			
 			
 				right
 			
 			
 				you know i don't know if the south is more towards the you know has more of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> or not i don't know i don't know do you
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 				well it's yeah it's hard to tell i know you know like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Appalachian Mountain</ENAMEX> area there that thing's real popular yeah i i've had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> that's you know that it's real popular around there
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 				well
 			
 			
 				and
 			
 		
 	