
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so what do you think about uh
 		uh health care for the elderly
 	
 	
 		well i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> who is uh eighty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years old this year</TIMEX>
 		and uh
 		she she
 		uh sometimes well she lived with us for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> and then she moved
 		uh to live with my bother because she got tired of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> but uh in my house
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i think health care for the elderly is uh
 		is uh its kind of a difficult
 		i say difficult i mean there's as your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is running downhill they can spend an infinite amount to keep you alive
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and on the other hand it's kind of nice uh
 		if you're taking care of an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to have somebody come along and pick up the the uh
 		the tab the the one thing that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> got into was that was pretty nice was an HMO they took all the money from from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how should i say it uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> thing said uh had an agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> that said uh on the average you're gonna spend <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> per year
 		so if you'll give us that money we promise to take care of of uh all the bills
 	
 	
 		all the bills
 		does that include um
 		nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> type care
 	
 	
 		no this is just you know standard
 	
 	
 		just strictly health care
 	
 	
 		health care like you'd get from your employer
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point uh and and that was pretty good for her because uh
 		there was a set of things that she knew she was covered for and uh and
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent coverage so it's that's good
 	
 	
 		well it was close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent there were things that they wouldn't cover but they like they bought her a uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		a uh
 		let's see they bought her a wheelchair and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> thing that was good about it was that it uh
 		uh before that time she was always subject she she'd have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX> that would call and say hey if you'll just buy this handy dandy motorized uh easy chair for
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the the real price uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> will pay for it and so she was always buying stuff that she didn't need
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and then finding out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> was either going to pay just a small fraction or no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> wouldn't pay for it
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so it kind of put the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX> at bay put it that way
 	
 	
 		right
 		so where does does she well um
 	
 	
 		so how about you
 	
 	
 		i guess in terms of where do you is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> now in a a nursing home is
 	
 	
 		no she's still she's staying with my uh actually she's staying with my
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who's doesn't have teenagers
 	
 	
 		right i guess
 		that's the big question is um what what happens when they begin to get older i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and it she's not really
 		uh you know she's getting to the point where she almost can't be in a nursing home she spent some time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> some time now she's with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> of mine living with them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but she requires a lot of attention and she can't really exist on her own any longer
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that's that's kind of a difficult situation that that she has to live with one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it was difficult for us to because uh
 		
 
 		well actually it it was all right as long as she could
 		could get back and forth to the uh you know to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and
 		things like that but when she got when she got really sick and she couldn't move very much then it was exhausting absolutely exhausting
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so
 	
 	
 		yeah my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> is hers is physically she's in not too bad of shape she's in her upper eighties i guess forgetting in my order but uh she's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and so her memory is very poor  and so she can't really be on her own but she can still do things by herself but you just have to uh kind of direct her
 	
 	
 		yeah uh and that  to that extent i think like i say this health care for the elderly is
 		is uh i i think they do a lot there was one thing that that uh that helped pull my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> out of uh this
 		oh i don't wanna know fog so to speak uh we had uh a a baby fairly late in life and uh as soon as that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> came along uh
 		uh she paid a lot of attention to you know something to take care of i'll put it that way and something to pay attention to and and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the other thing i've noticed is that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh pets</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		if they have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> to take care of uh like she got yeah she got uh
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		
 		
 	