
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Liz</ENAMEX> do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i do but they're but they're both out of college so i have one who's uh living in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in another city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i have one who's actually living with me because um because of the economy and the job that she's got but she's about
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		she's on the verge of moving to her own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> so what about you
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh well we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and  uh their ages range from range from twelve to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh little ones then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yep</ENAMEX>  and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh some things we like to do together with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are um in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> time we like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> we
 		that's our thing we pack up a picnic and and go to every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Utah</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow oh you mean like state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> that kind of
 	
 	
 		well mostly mostly just play parks yeah so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um with the with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and such we don't get a lot of vacationing in so we just like to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">little weekend</TIMEX> trips and go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and such
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		you probably have pretty ones there when you were saying parks i was just uh we have a different terrain here so
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> when i was a teenager i spent some time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i i remember it's pretty  it is flat oh
 	
 	
 		it's flat
 		yes so the mountains would take a while to get around to to find any there are some as a matter of fact but um what other things do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well we like to
 	
 	
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> or during during during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> do they ski or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">weekends um</ENAMEX>
 		no we're not into skiing it's just too expensive we
 	
 	
 		it is expensive yeah
 	
 	
 		we can't do that so  um we like to uh rent videos and sit down and have a video bash pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">popcorn</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		yeah that's fun
 	
 	
 		and do that so we've done that quite a bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX> and um we like to play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> games together sometimes it's a little difficult with the younger <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yes that's
 	
 	
 		but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> we have some fun times with those after the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> go to bed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and let's see uh we like to get real wild and crazy and play hide and go seek and  oh yeah things like that
 	
 	
 		all of those things yeah
 		well the twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> probably feels he or she's much older than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> so there should be different activities in in their minds at at any rate yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		yeah yeah he's really patient though he with us he's he's a real fun twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		but he's rapidly approaching teenagehood so we'll see what happens
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		your first experience with it well it um it's interesting  there's a dramatic change at thirteen and it doesn't end until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty five</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		oh
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		it's part of what's supposed to happen or they can't fly the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX> so um that's that's one way of looking at it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway i was trying to think what what what we spent a lot of time well reading i loved to read to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when they were when they were younger uh obviously not any more but
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we still we
 		like um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> movies we really got into them when they were young there were a number of movies that we liked and we just simply liked the experience of the movies and um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ironically uh my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven my twenty four and my twenty two year old last year</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> we rented <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Jungle Book</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh how fun
 	
 	
 		and uh i gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jungle Book</ENAMEX> and one of them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fantasia</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas this year</TIMEX> and it was one of their favorite gifts so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i think that's fun
 	
 	
 		so that's something and besides the  another thing we used to do is watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> together which there were a lot of um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> loves science programs and um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we would all just stop and watch whatever the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> were doing or whatever was going on
 	
 	
 		yes i think that is good that sounds
 	
 	
 		yeah which was which was fun yeah and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		now were you able to get away on some vacations and
 	
 	
 		yeah we did and um and we enjoyed that um my now we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> back when they were younger younger got did we would go from here to like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and ski
 	
 	
 		oh oh how fun
 	
 	
 		and they did both uh learn to be scuba divers
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh we went once on a vacation with my parents
 		to an island and they snorkeled and that that really got them you know fascinated with the deep and so they actually went through all the course and all the trouble in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> as we were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		oh how fun
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and uh went and i don't can't remember what it's called uh but it's
 		
 		
 	