
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um  so what do you think of um the way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has has moved towards you know getting involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s individual  uh lives
 	
 	
 		well uh i did did have you ever heard of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Friedman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um yeah he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> isn't he
 	
 	
 		yeah well no no he actually wasn't he he's an he was uh
 		he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> type uh fellow he's not really a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> i don't i don't believe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but he wrote several books <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and and he put out like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> different movies on government and and uh
 		and i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milton</ENAMEX> kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Friedman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and he's anti big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and that's that's my feeling about it i think our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is way too big um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that there's just a tremendous amount of waste i'm i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> and i can i see the way they uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butcher people</ENAMEX> as far as i'm concerned and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in in the in the tax end of it as as far as how they they
 	
 	
 		and so do you sort of lean towards like the libertarian view
 	
 	
 		take money from them
 		you bet i do yep
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something interesting to me right now too is this presidential campaign uh i i can't believe how
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		tax you you know  our money our life really <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> around money the whole thing and you can see uh how
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		tax laws uh in new legislation right now are really a critical big issue
 	
 	
 		yeah and it means a horrible time to have tax cuts at this point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think you know as far at least as far as our deficit's concerned
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and everyone and every all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> just seem to be you now have this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and circuses policy of
 		you know we'll give you a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> a day if you vote for us you know
 	
 	
 		that's that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah i mean your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> won't be happy but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you'll be able to buy that that extra <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of the week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		the deficit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> is just incredible i heard a statistic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i don't know if this is wrong or right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man woman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> they're in debt uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about forty thousand dollars</NUMEX> a piece
 		i have a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> if i had if i had to pay that much responsible for that much debt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'd be done i'd be sunk
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i just i there's no way i can generate the income to service that kind of debt
 		i don't know what the heck our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s going to do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time um i i really personally think we're going to have to collapse just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> did
 		or uh i i don't know how how how can we
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it really wouldn't surprise me if that happens in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah right i don't see it in the near future but uh
 	
 	
 		um
 		and we we are still considered the best credit risk in the world
 	
 	
 		yeah because we write off debts we loaned the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred million dollars</NUMEX> or whatever and forgave them
 	
 	
 		supposedly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's the same thing with what happened over there um in i and i believe it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> We wanted to use their air strips during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we just went over there and said gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you owe us all this money well i tell you let us land our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> here and we'll just forgive it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's ridiculous
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and i don't know if that's really the case you know i'm talking all out of hearsay and conversation from what i've heard uh from other from from other some of my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> but that wouldn't surprise
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe i would
 		we we've been known to spend a lot of money for expediency in things
 		i uh um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what do you think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and the comments they've made recently about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'm not sure that's uh actually a political issue but uh
 	
 	
 		well it in it um
 		i think if anyone but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> had made it if if if an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> had said the same thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably would have agreed with them
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i'm not so sure they're all that wrong
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah yeah
 		um
 		you know we we we our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are have definitely become top heavy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um in management um
 		you know our
 		we you know we we you know
 		you know the trend of over consumption since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> Two um
 		you know theory being that that's what what what would be required to make our economy to thrive the best you know that that we you know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> just been given that just moved for better and better standards of living
 		and where a bunch of other factors i think you know is just
 		you know it's it's uh we're we're unable to keep on increasing that
 		you know when when you know when you combine with the mismanagement that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have had
 		and yeah i think that you know that's really when he says that they were lazy i think lazy probably wasn't the best term to use
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i think you know you know unwilling unwilling you know unwilling the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> probably are not willing to do as much work for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as little as</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	