
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> uh on taxes i i'd guess i'd have to say that i my opinion is that i'd do think that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are paying too much in taxes uh what's your feeling about that
 	
 	
 		i agree i think taxes are high
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh
 		where you live do you you have a state income tax and a sales tax both
 	
 	
 		um yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> we have uh uh no no what we call broad base taxes no income tax and no sales tax
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh we tax business uh <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> businesses are taxed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX>
 		and we have uh what we call the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>'s uh  for our taxes
 		booze uh butts cigarettes beds uh hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> tax bellies a meal tax and bets uh gambling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so uh we do have a very low tax rate but you know combined with the federal income tax i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> uh generally do pay in too too much in taxes
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i agree i agree  i think this is about time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> where you you just start getting
 		um well if you do get money back from  like jobs like i'm still a student so um i only work part time so i i get a check back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's nice
 	
 	
 		from from taxes but
 	
 	
 		nice to nice to get a refund
 	
 	
 		yeah it is but  it's not much
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you think that uh for whatever taxes we do pay that uh we're getting value for it
 	
 	
 		so
 		no
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh my my opinion of taxes is that when you send money to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> or to the state and they say they're going to send some back it's like giving yourself a transfusion it's like one arm giving the other a transfusion
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it it really uh i should say one arm giving another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> a transfusion through a leaky tube because
 	
 	
 		yeah there you go
 	
 	
 		right because uh yeah there's an old saying in in amongst taxes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> that uh there's a fly paper effect and that is that money tends to stick where it lands first
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and when you send it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> or send it to your state capitol uh a lot of it stays there and uh not that much comes back to you
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i don't know i don't doesn't seem like they're doing much with it neither i mean there's plans there and now with the voting and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know getting into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> and government and stuff i mean they have nice plans and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but  they don't always work and then you know they try to raise taxes more and i don't what happens with all the money because if their plans don't work you know and the taxes get raised
 		i don't know i'm not you know really into politics i don't really understand it but
 	
 	
 		that's it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well it does it it it it does seem that uh the more taxes that are raised the more the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> spend
 		uh it's almost like they'll spend as much as the they were were they're allowed to collect you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um  i there's an interesting proposal that's been uh going around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> of having a flat tax
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent or thirteen percent there would be no figuring i mean you would take your income tax you'd have a certain amount i mean you you take your total salary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh those who made under a certain amount wouldn't have owe any taxes and then there'd be a set amount for however many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> you had
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and you would just pay a flat tax no exemptions no deductions or anything else after you you know after you uh figure out  you know who's in your family
 	
 	
 		right huh
 	
 	
 		and that would eliminate a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> and it would eliminate all these loop holes that the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> get away with you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that could be nice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i i'd like to see something like that yeah i think it would be fairer and uh it would put a lot you know a lot of the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> out of business and i'm sure they'll fight it tooth and nail but
 		i really think a flat tax would be a lot fairer for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean it doesn't seem right that somebody that makes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five or thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four five thousand dollars</NUMEX> in taxes while somebody that makes uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> might pay nothing in taxes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		hm
 	
 	
 		doesn't seem fair to me
 	
 	
 		yeah it isn't there's not much out there that's fair that's for sure
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		huh i'll agree to that
 	
 	
 		right i think your taxes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> are pretty high i i if i'm not mistaken aren't they
 		i mean for your state what is do you know what your state income tax rate is
 	
 	
 		um
 		um no i i have no idea i just
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> does it all for me
 	
 	
 		just
 		you just pay it huh
 	
 	
 		i use
 	
 	
 		you're like you're like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's in in college down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and uh she works as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> and she's attending college full time also and she sends her taxes to me and i figure them out she really has no idea she gets a refund check and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	