
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh no i don't i don't
 	
 	
 		are you are you married
 	
 	
 		no no i'm in i'm in college i'm just a sophomore in college
 	
 	
 		are you
 		well um do you know what we're um suppose to talk about is is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and stuff like that and um how how you
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		how you spend time with you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and stuff uh i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		have you
 	
 	
 		yeah so and i stay home with them so it's um
 		i spend a lot of time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i really enjoy it i uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		i've uh i i was in college for you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and and worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> and and now we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> preschoolers so i spend a lot of time with them and yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's great how old are they
 	
 	
 		um i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six month</TIMEX> old a uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half almost three year old</TIMEX> going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> and then a uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and a half year old almost five year old</TIMEX> so i've got a couple a couple of little ones but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i spend a lot of time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> um yeah it's
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		uh i i really am glad that that i'm able to stay home with them and stuff so it's real fun but well um do you uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that must nice
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hum oh okay well how would you spend time with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> if you were if you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or or uh do you do you do any babysitting do you did you use to when you were in uh high school or anything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yes i <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sat all the time for uh for my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in high school my full time job was going over to a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and babysitting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> until they got home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		so what'd you do with them did you i mean of course you were paid to uh to spend time with them and stuff but what did you do to uh entertain them and keep them entertained were they older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or school age
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		they were
 		they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven and nine years old</TIMEX> both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> so we played we we did stuff like play softball and frisbee and that kind of thing and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		sort i sort of watched them you know ride their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> and
 		that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		they were outdoorsy types
 	
 	
 		yeah we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are
 		of course now that it's getting warmer much more outdoors than than indoors but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		shoot they can sit and work puzzles and read books for a long time so that's kind of and they did they pretty much they entertain themselves when i need them to but
 	
 	
 		right right
 		well that's nice
 	
 	
 		i spend a lot of time i spend a lot of time with them reading and we play games and stuff but
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah but it's it's it's neat cause they're really they're they're well behaved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they're and they
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they interact pretty well with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> they're shy at times but they interact pretty well with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		none of them have started school yet
 	
 	
 		uh i have my oldest goes to preschool <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days a week</TIMEX> and my my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> goes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day one of the same days</TIMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and then my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> will start kindergarten <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> so we went and checked out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last last week</TIMEX> in fact they had an open house and stuff so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah that's an adventure i think it's gonna be harder on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> than it's  than it is on him but you know  it's like oh i can't send my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> to school  it's just yeah it's like i can't believe i you know he's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he's he'll be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five in</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and it's just hard to believe that you know time has has flown by so quick so yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know it's it's
 		they're pretty fun they're they're good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so yeah well uh what are you majoring in in college
 	
 	
 		well that's
 		that's great
 		i'm i'm in physics
 	
 	
 		in physics
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well you won't you won't deal much with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in that area
 	
 	
 		oh no  i don't think i'll be out of school for a long long time
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 
 		oh i know it seems like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX> and i think uh i i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> you know wants to go back for um some uh master degree and stuff and i just think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i just not into that right now maybe in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> i you know i might want to do that but it's i don't know i i was glad to have gotten out so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah i will be too
 	
 	
 		yeah that was uh i enjoyed my time but you know met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and met him there so it was uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		a a nice nice sideline of it so that was good but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well what else about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> how do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spend time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do you have any idea
 	
 	
 		um not really my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are divorced and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> uh is dating a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		kind of different huh
 	
 	
 		yeah it is real different but they go they just went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> so they just went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> and they they do some fun stuff together go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		we go we went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> as a matter of fact yeah it's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i mean it's it's fun but you i mean with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		really
 		i bet
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two</TIMEX>'s pretty easy
 		
 		
 	