
 
     		
 	
 		how do you feel about gun control
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh
 		i mean i don't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> should be outlawed
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but it's going to a lot of the stuff that i mean all you do is to get guns
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then like with the stuff of that massacre in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Killeen Texas</ENAMEX> not too long ago
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't really know i mean unless they do uh just outlaw them how you can uh i mean prevent that
 	
 	
 		well don't you think that you know just having you know some
 		you know almost like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license be required you know with stiff penalties if you are found with with you know
 		you know a gun that is not registered or you know that you are not licensed to carry
 	
 	
 		yeah that well do you even know what the procedures are now
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		it varies from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		there is no national
 	
 	
 		but it's kind of like if you want a gun you can get a gun especially if you have the money to pay for it
 	
 	
 		uh in most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> as long as you aren't a convicted felon
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know or on probation or  you know
 		other obvious things like that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i know i know that like in a lot of states you could you could be just like released from a mental hospital <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before
 		you know be be obviously insane and then you you know but have your legal right to get a gun
 	
 	
 		huh i didn't know that well that's pretty scary
 		so does now do they want us to say where we feel about it like in rating it one to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh yes i'd probably i'd probably say about a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's where i would probably be
 	
 	
 		
 
 		seems like it's a good safe number to pick you know
 	
 	
 		well i mean i mean i don't really know what they can how they can really enforce the laws any better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i mean i do think that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need them and like for protection and stuff and i can understand them wanting to have them but then again it's just like all those nuts out there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh  well you know uh uh other than that if you are looking at like
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that you know uh where they do have a lot more gun control like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and places like that you know the amount of violent crime has decreased by so much
 	
 	
 		it has
 		because
 	
 	
 		well i mean yeah the uh the in comparing per capita murders are incredibly lower than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you know i mean the problem though is you know they if the since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had this you know pretty much unrestricted flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> going for so long
 		that i think you know if you were introduced
 		you know any controls
 		it would probably take a long while for them to take effect just because there is a glut of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> out there already
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so it's so it's really into a kind of a complex problem
 	
 	
 		well is the crime that bad there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i'm not really sure how bad it is i've i've not really had that many problems with it but i mean apparently we we were ranked pretty high up
 	
 	
 		yeah i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i mean i think you know in the  i mean i i think we have been like ranked in one of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> for murders in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> but oh do you own a gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no i've i've thought about getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> if i get one i think i will probably you know get something
 		i probably wouldn't get a hand gun i would probably get like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> just for protecting myself
 		you know from you know burglar type thing i do kind of live in the downtown area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and shotguns are really good because you know they're
 		i mean somebody is not going to break in steal it and you know use it to mug someone you know
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you know you
 		yeah i just don't i just don't understand these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know that like when they they decide they're going to buy a gun to protect themselves they go out and buy a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> magnum which is going to shoot through you know
 		they are probably going to miss the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and they're going shoot and they're going to shoot through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> and hit someone you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> just just struck me as being you know a real good defensive weapon you can sort of point it somewhere in the direction of you know whoever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you pretty much you pretty much stop them and you don't then the actual shot doesn't go that far you know a wall will stop it pretty much
 	
 	
 		well
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i moved up here by myself and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> gave me a gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i never did go out and practice with it enough to feel comfortable with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i finally ended up giving it back to him i said i don't want it i don't want to be responsible for it because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if you're not going to teach me how to do it and if i am not going to you know be responsible enough to go out and learn i don't need it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that that really does scare me <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> because you know
 		if you ever get in the situation where you know you are not prepared to shoot but you pick up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and point it at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> rushes you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and they get it from you uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and you know you're pretty much dead you know because you you've just told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that you you're about to kill them then
 	
 	
 		set them off
 	
 	
 		you know and and well i mean
 		you you you you basically made it clear to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that you know unless he unless you know that  you are a real danger to them and then you know if you if they manage to get the gun from you you know their first reaction is going to be you know
 		stop you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's why i ended up giving it back to him i thought well you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't want it if i don't know how to operate you know if i don't really know how to use it and i just didn't want the responsibility
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		so
 		well well uh
 		did you hear about that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Killeen</ENAMEX> massacre or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah the did it happen at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		that kind of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it just makes you wonder how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get guns
 		i would be scared selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to people
 		
 		
 	