
 
     		
 	
 		okay well uh i guess since i called i'll start out with my feelings about it uh i think that it's absolutely essential that some some at least some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> be tested especially when it effects public safety i mean the military obviously uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that run <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> and and the like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh for others i don't know i don't feel as strong about it uh i don't really don't have any objection to it but i can't really say i'm for it either what's your feeling
 	
 	
 		well uh it it it it becomes sort of a a topic where i sit there and and i have a knee jerk reaction and then i have a a reaction after i think about it a little longer uh
 		for me i i guess i feel like uh we have we we that we when we give in on these things we tend to move towards a
 		a uh society where uh everything is a is uh regulated
 		uh i think you're right about uh certain jobs and uh certainly something like uh a bus train pilots
 		uh it's obviously something that's a necessity it because it because the function of the job is is within all everyone pretty much everyone in the world
 		uh would admit to the fact that that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> might impair their abilities
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and like so i guess in some ways i'm agreeing with you
 		uh that those would be something that should continue to have uh drug testing of course it is certainly not acceptable for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> to
 		uh have just had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> martinis before he went off to fly
 	
 	
 		right  or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> has had a lot of problems with that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i uh i've been in uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> situations where i've had to under go grug testing drug testing i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> for a number of years
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> uh as a as a an electrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> uh
 		in a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that was under construction and in both cases uh you know we were subject to uh to random testing for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 		and i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> refused to a lot especially at the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> or would uh you know strongly object to it but uh you know i could see the need for it so i i went along with it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i think if i were a clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> for instance though uh and really couldn't have effected anybody else i'm not sure that i'd
 	
 	
 		i think it might be inappropriate for us to say for me to say that in any in any industry
 		uh something where where see you're talking about a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> where okay if you're a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or where you're a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who works on safety features for nuclear inspection well that makes sense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh we're talking about you you know you're saying well uh and i think you uh that you just stated the same thing that if you were a clerical you you you know a clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> there or you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> there now where's the justification
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		what what what okay you know  let's say that we can you you you you had had a uh uh you went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and
 		uh not not that anyone ever does it but you were smoking pot uh now how is that going to make any difference
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know unless you very unless you uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCP</ENAMEX> does exist apparently in the blood stream
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for a long period of time but the ability for you to function seems to be
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh very it it's very questionable as to whether it has any real effect upon you
 	
 	
 		right probably <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> has more of an effect for for a shorter period of time
 	
 	
 		right
 		so but i I just went through one recently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the place i just transferred jobs not too long ago and so i went through the whole process and the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's really no justification what so ever for why i had to do it i mean uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
 		it's basically a oh
 		management engineering company
 	
 	
 		um-hum so they were doing it just to they wanted to make sure that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were productive probably that's why
 	
 	
 		now
 		what wait but then but then uh but then if the if you're saying that
 	
 	
 		that's probably why they justified it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no i'm just trying to imagine why they would wanna test you
 	
 	
 		they should also regulate right what they should also regulate how many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of sleep i must have they should also regulate how much what kind of nutrition i have they should also regulate see it's a it's a it's a disturbing trend
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		yeah i i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do something that could hurt somebody else
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> should be subject to the testing i guess that's probably the the way i'd term it and i'm talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> as you mentioned and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and what have you
 		uh others that really can only hurt themselves shall we say uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	