
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well how do you feel about trial by jury
 	
 	
 		i feel very uncomfortable with trials by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> recently uh
 	
 	
 		in what way
 	
 	
 		in that it seems to me they're swayed more by emotion than uh by evidence that's presented
 		i have uh very little regard for the law
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's presently practiced
 	
 	
 		i mean do you do you feel they're they're swayed more toward are you talking about with criminal or civil suits
 	
 	
 		i was thinking primarily criminal cases
 	
 	
 		um-hum so you think that i mean that the stereotypical bleeding heart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> where they feel sorry
 	
 	
 		yes
 		um-hum that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of mine uh
 		i would feel more comfortable in many cases i think with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> uh you know doing the sentencing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		the other thing the other thing that really bothers me about that is i think you know that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> can be
 		uh i like the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers um</ENAMEX> in that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you you you you get more <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> making the decision making a decision and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of all you get a wide variety of background so that
 	
 	
 		yeah my question i guess is are they really your peers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i'd agree that that's that's definitely a problem
 	
 	
 		uh too often i think they're not and uh when you you when you are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		selecting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and you're doing it partially if if not entirely on the basis of which color representation you have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that's a matter of concern to me too uh i think that uh in such cases uh
 		they're not really looking for unbiased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but rather for biased
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> now i happen to know several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and there's one that i'd feel uncomfortable but has  doing sentencing without the jury
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'd feel a little bit uneasy about but the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i feel uh would give either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the full</TIMEX> benefit of the law
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i guess that's what i am concerned with
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		i guess i i definitely agree with you but sentencing the well what i don't like about uh sentencing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> doing the sentencing in that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it becomes a lot less the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the the same</TIMEX> crime gets unequal sentences
 	
 	
 		this is very true
 	
 	
 		i uh i i think there is more of an ability of you know you know selecting selecting selecting a jury <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> that would
 		most of the time come up with the same idea  the same idea versus you know whether he is guilty or innocent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		i think i think that there'd that there'd be a large variation in
 		in trying to
 		gauge the the severity of the crime and an appropriate punishment and and have that
 		that measure stick across the board
 	
 	
 		yeah and you do see such uneven uneven sentencing uh you know evidence of it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and such i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where uh it would appear that the crimes were very similar but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> and the other one was sentenced to life for something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		of course a lot of that's also the the ability of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> to uh get a good lawyer
 	
 	
 		isn't that the truth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there are times when is it uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh goodness my mind's gone blank it uh Othello
 		you know where he says kill all the lawyers  every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then one is tempted to feel that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		but i it's taken me a long time to understand that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are concerned with the law and not with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> as we think of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know amateur as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novices</ENAMEX> tend to think that uh attorneys care about justice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah i i agree with it yeah they and they'll admit to you that they cannot don't have the benefit of being able to you know of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of letting allowing themselves to believe their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client client</ENAMEX> innocent or guilty it's more of the game plan of how do they convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> or jury
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		through argument that the
 	
 	
 		and they're very effective too uh even i've been involved  slightly slightly in a case where i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is guilty but uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> gotten him off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has dropped their charges against him because their the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> has presented enough evidence of doubt to convince the judge
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh
 		yeah this is a little bit of the subject but one one thing that i that i really dislike uh also that's that's new is the uh is that i have heard that there are federal sentences
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	