
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh no this elderly care of the elderly i am looking at this right now with my father
 		and it is a tough decision to make
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh
 	
 	
 		does he he live at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yes he's and he's living at home  more or less alone my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> spends an awful low of time with with him which is a burden on her
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and his health is so bad that we don't feel right about you know just letting him do what he wants to do
 		and of course he feels like he is capable of taking care of himself and we know better
 	
 	
 		no i know my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> is still alive and uh feisty old old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> she's uh she's really pretty good but she really just can't get around any more and she does have significant significant health problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is looking after after her and it it's a big drain on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> i can tell when i get calls from her she she sounds worn out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and uh it's tough on on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> because she's use to just
 		going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and getting what she wants and baking up things for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> but now she's no longer where she grew up her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have all passed on or in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> she can't just run right out and get things so a lot of these thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		fall on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> get me this i want to go do that uh i've changed my mind phone calls in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> because she's lonesome yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah Yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh you know i i can see from a distance i'm not right there on top of it maybe i am a little more objective but
 		i would think that they would try like to try and find her some place that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all she could be happy
 	
 	
 		well that's that will be a problem because i have looked  and they all really amount to the same thing uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i have looked for all both ends of the scale really from your kind of State run things to the very private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> type and really it
 		boil down to i think to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing you're putting somebody in there and more or less waiting for them to die
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and it's uh it's sad but that's the way we've been brought up to look at it
 		and i hate it but there comes a time when when this is what what happens
 		especially with the way <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> It's keeping us alive longer and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we're living longer so therefore you know
 	
 	
 		you almost like to have some place that's almost hospice care but a little bit more independent than that almost almost like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that has partly something like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominiums</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah it's kind of our
 	
 	
 		where those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are mobile can still retain their their independence
 		but maybe have somebody come by and check on them once or twice a day bring them the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> or come by and chat or whatever and then a hospice for those who no longer quite so mobile
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the problem with everything else in health care is is the cost
 	
 	
 		the cost is just unreal
 	
 	
 		uh i mean that's that's almost why some of the you know the the experimental cooperatives you hear about where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sort of throw in all their money together and and do that sort of thing but it's it's
 		you you start getting commercialization of it and the cost just skyrockets
 	
 	
 		right well that's
 	
 	
 		so they want to really make a a method of it i wish that we could find some place for for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> she would be happier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> wouldn't have to drop everything and and really she's lost a great deal of control of her life to the point where her own health is deteriorating
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> is just enormous i i feel for you you're you're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step closer than i am to it and it must be it must be really draining on you
 	
 	
 		well it is especially since he lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>  This this you know it makes in fact i just got back from having to go stay with him because she needed to get away
 	
 	
 		oh
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's uh
 		but uh i don't know what other solution there is eventually we're going to have to put him in a home some place
 	
 	
 		oh it it right now though he's independent enough to to take care of day to day or or have
 	
 	
 		well more or less but he is almost to the point that he's legally blind so that is really what bothers us uh he could start a fire uh just about anything  could happen
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah
 		oh
 		yeah yeah i can i can appreciate that and there's  there use to be programs in some of the more progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of of house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		somebody that comes and lives there and for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> takes care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you need you need a contact service in the community i'd i'd even be happy just
 		uh trying to find a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> program that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> would be willing to accept that she could go and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> meeting some right now she tries to hold up in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> she
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	