
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Karen</ENAMEX> you're  you're first
 	
 	
 		okay i was just going to say i think one of the biggest thing for me is like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for advancement
 		you know not to get in like in a dead end job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and plus
 		for me it's uh i mean like medical and you know uh benefits and dental
 		they're also important
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah i guess one of the differences i see is uh working for a university uh
 		there is room for advancement but not so much so our in uh
 		quite a highly unionized environment and then also in an in administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> so there is a
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		progressive path but
 		not being in the
 		say the commercial sector the motivation isn't there for a lot of people
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh like
 	
 	
 		are they like well pretty much trained for a specific job and that what's their hired for and then uh
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		just just very little variation from there
 	
 	
 		yeah somewhat that but then also there just isn't the ability to in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense have uh
 		a broader scope for rewarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for
 		uh their performances
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so that's
 		in in our situation where we're dealing with an institution
 		uh it's a little more difficult to recognize an individual's performance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i suppose that's maybe a disadvantage of being in a larger institution
 		perhaps somewhat even with the business
 		uh but i agree you know the uh medical benefits and those kinds of things are
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
 		big pluses for working for a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and also the uh
 		security aspect for long term employment uh
 	
 	
 		well you know that's kind of interesting though because i don't know if that's necessarily the case anymore i use to think that you know after you worth
 		you mean security job security
 	
 	
 		job security yes
 	
 	
 		um
 		that use to be i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> but i don't know
 		if it is so much anymore in fact they we just had a lay off in what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um it wasn't necessarily i mean you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had been there a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah uh we're seeing that here as well like in some of the large oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> there has been massive layoffs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so i i think there it's probably a major distinction between
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and the corporate world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> are slower to
 		react both on the growth side and then also on the reduction side where the businesses
 		we need to cut back that's what we do
 	
 	
 		um-hum and there's no doubt yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah and institutionally like here at the university
 		oh if there is a cut back well gee it's not  where it necessarily is needed it's where it's most expedient which
 	
 	
 		expedient yeah that's exactly it yeah where the most dollar what it where it you know cuts back the most
 	
 	
 		well in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense sense for us it's where it makes the least noise which means it's often the lowest support type roles
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh see yeah
 	
 	
 		so we end
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's one of the things too you get too many management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		it's very easy
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's very easy for them to say oh this is the best way when they really aren't aware of what all it took to get the work done you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then they wonder why it doesn't get done in the same amount of time when those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't there anymore
 	
 	
 		right because it's the support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are providing the speed for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah but so what else do you think is important
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 
 		the uh
 		uh that's that's maybe the majority of the importance i guess
 		uh yeah because my perspective is from an institution
 		uh the there is not much incentive for
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">innovativeness</ENAMEX> because the the the limitation for reward is is very severe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if you're in the corporate world i think there is considerable motivation for
 		uh i guess in innovation although
 		he the you know the more complex your structure
 		the uh less difficult it is to kind of carry some things through
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i think there is uh
 		it's a long term type of process where in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> it's uh
 		things can happen much more quickly and so you can see the reward of your efforts
 	
 	
 		i think probably in a smaller yeah i was going to say more it's more personal for one thing you probably have a better team
 		uh cooperation or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> playing atmosphere
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		probably where as in a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> sometimes i think you think you're just a number you know
 	
 	
 		yeah you end up being your own person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh if you do your job fine and if
 		somebody else is messing it up well then that's their problem and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you really
 	
 	
 		whereas yeah in a smaller i think you'd be more willing to either help that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or help it
 		get accomplished you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it becomes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> instead of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> being uh you know a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> themselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	