
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hi
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nice to meet you
 	
 	
 		pleased to meet you
 	
 	
 		where are you
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are you so am i where are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		okay are you ready for me to push one
 	
 	
 		sure anytime
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		so what do you think about capital punishment
 	
 	
 		well i think it's a necessary uh
 		a necessary tool that uh needs to be used uh to establish justice in some cases and to that that it if used properly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think it can be uh it would it would be a useful deterrent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what do you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX>
 		like not getting since they don't have it in
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think that
 		i think there are certain
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in society that have no redeeming
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh worth to them and that it's it it's a waste for society to continue to support those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be
 		you know disposed of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know because it's like it's kind of like a tough call because all they do is sit in jail and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are overcrowded you know it's like problem upon problem upon problem
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		it's like you could put them in jail for the rest of his life well all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are already overcrowded
 		you know and they add more problems
 		you know since <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are overcrowded they have to reduce you know
 		time to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like one third</NUMEX> of what you're supposed to do it you know it gets kind of ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right i mean they probably you know we
 		the you know our our justice system is not designed to be either efficient or effective or just you know it it's designed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as a set of artificial rules that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> play with each other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know i i guess i could be for it and against it in some ways i mean
 		i think i'm definitely for it and stuff when i think of someone like like him that killed all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and has
 		no remorse or anything you know i feel like that's the right thing to do and i guess i would have to say it would be for more circumstances you know
 	
 	
 		well it it it uh yeah but it you know the the problem is
 		it when when we administer it
 		by you know i i mean like like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we have the death penalty right and they killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> a while back and you know he'd been in jail for twelve or fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> or something like that waiting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know waiting waiting waiting waiting his sentence
 	
 	
 		yeah see i think that   what is the point of that
 	
 	
 		what what
 		there there's no point in it i mean
 	
 	
 		where did that come from
 	
 	
 		well it it's because it's because
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't wanna recognize
 		how to make you know how to how to make a punishment effective
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it
 		punishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> by killing them doesn't do anybody any good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the only reason the only way it does some good is if it convinces convinces somebody else that they shouldn't do something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true definitely true
 	
 	
 		and you know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> waits around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> or whatever it is you know how is that a deterrent to anybody
 	
 	
 		see why do you have any clue why that they sit on like death row that long
 	
 	
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> require it
 		i mean they they they have said that well everybody has to have certain you know has to have the the the right to appeal well
 	
 	
 		see
 		yeah i understand that
 	
 	
 		but not only do they have the right to appeal they must appeal and you know they the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> go in there and they generate
 	
 	
 		it takes prolong it forever
 	
 	
 		well they generate all kinds of possible reasons that they might be able to appeal uh you know they they're they're trying to generate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		technicalities you know things which aren't really related to whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> did it or not but as to whether something in the process was right or wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah the the
 		yeah
 		see
 	
 	
 		and you know it it it doesn't work you know our whole justice system doesn't work like that
 	
 	
 		yeah it'd be easier if at least if someone was
 		you know sentenced to death then if they were to have to have an appeal it should be taken care of as quickly as possible you know
 	
 	
 		yes that's right
 	
 	
 		and i understand appeals take a long time and everything else but you know
 		i mean they should have like
 		God there's something so it'd be done faster you know because then they complain about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> and the
 		this and that and this and that and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sitting on death row for like fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> well that's dumb
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it is it's terrible
 	
 	
 		mean mean at least if you're going to do it do it like because i mean that's like even torture kind of you know
 	
 	
 		oh i again i i don't feel sorry for the for the for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> that that's on you know for the for the criminal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	