
 
     		
 	
 		well i definitely think taxes are too high
 		uh taxes at all levels uh state local and federal are over fifty percent of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s uh income now
 		and uh the amazing thing is to think that one of the primary reasons for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Tea Party</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Revolution</ENAMEX> was exorbitant taxes
 		but for them exorbitant taxes were under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent it was ridiculous you know uh that that uh we we took such drastic action over taxes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it's so much worse now but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just apathetic about it and sit back and do nothing
 	
 	
 		well let's see uh yeah i think taxes are high but uh
 		yeah maybe in some cases they're not high enough for instance uh
 		here in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		you have a real high sales tax there if i recall
 	
 	
 		yeah we do yeah but the but the reason the sales tax is high is because we don't have an income tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know we don't have an income tax because uh basically nobody nobody wants any new taxes but the upshot is that we can't properly fund uh education here
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah so like the amount that we spend on education here in uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> per uh per student
 	
 	
 		get out of my room
 	
 	
 		is is actually in the in the lower percentile uh i mean is is is low it we're we're ranked fairly low
 	
 	
 		interesting
 	
 	
 		uh per fifty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> yet uh you know yet we expect a lot out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know we've got here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> area we've got a lot of uh
 		uh high technology industries we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> here well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> expects well educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is only paying property taxes towards uh
 		towards uh towards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> so and there are those that argue well they waste too much money in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or those or there there's
 		you know more money doesn't solve the problem but i feel like in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that they uh
 		uh that they really don't fund it they they don't basically fund it very well
 	
 	
 		my my feeling about at least i I don't know if we want to get off the subject of taxes and on to the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but around here
 		uh some of the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> get more funds than
 		the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh in terms of you know the per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> expenditure at say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carver High School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> is over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> per student
 		but the best private school
 		is uh has a tuition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only seven thousand</NUMEX> and all of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of course rank consistently in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> etcetera and the the public school that gets uh quite a bit more money
 		just doesn't uh doesn't turn out that quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well it's cheaper to to educate uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent than it is to have to educate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped</ENAMEX> and the developmentally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> and all that stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah but i think a lot of it is just that uh the money is wasted on bureaucracy and it's not very efficient um
 		uh we we have you know a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of education and things which
 		all all they do is do statistics and push paper around and none of the uh one of the things that's happened here is that uh the percentage of the money going to instruction
 		meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s salaries and books and materials has been falling even though that the uh total funding has been going up
 		uh so that uh you know whereas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> seventy percent of the money going to schools
 		went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s salaries and books and materials now it's only forty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> and that's really scary to think that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's i've i've been hearing that that's uh that that's been going down and uh i don't know what uh what all the reasons are for that
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that uh one of the reasons our taxes are so high is just that uh
 		on on top of the inefficiencies like what i just described is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> tries to do too many things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has no business doing you know we're spending
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred billion dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to maintain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> uh we have no business spending that money
 		and uh we're spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over two hundred billion dollars</NUMEX> a year on interest on the debt uh there was a Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate forum</ENAMEX> here
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX> and just we just had our primary in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and uh
 		uh you know i I one of the questions i asked the representative of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Carey</ENAMEX> who was there was uh
 		and we have a projected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred billion dollar</NUMEX> budget deficit this year
 		what are you gonna do to to correct that and all he talked and and all they could say all the is the only thing he would do is consolidate some cabinet
 		
 		
 	