
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> how do you feel about crime in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> uh you said you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right i i i actually i live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and uh i guess it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of mine uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know for my own safety
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i mean do you find do you find crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> really bad i mean i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		oh that's right um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think it is bad in certain areas however i think uh the area that i live in it's not
 		uh the the crime level is not as high as it is in other areas of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i think it seems that there's certain certain areas where uh the crime is focused um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well what do you think can be done about the crime in the city
 	
 	
 		well i think it's what's been happening over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX> it seems they've been beefing up the police patrols trying to put put more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> more cops higher visibility
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it had some impact but not a tremendous amount
 		and probably um
 		they need to try to increase community involvement that sort of thing i think's the best way there is
 	
 	
 		i'd probably agree with that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you know uh particularly in some of the housing projects
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh you know that's that tends to be where a lot of that crime is focused and they've got to do more than just having having cops there they've got to kind of change the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's probably true um
 		so do um well do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> is as bad as most other cities
 	
 	
 		um well i've been to i'd say it's it's probably in the top
 		top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> in terms of crime
 		um
 		it's nowhere near as bad as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> for example probably not not as bad as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i don't think it's as bad as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		we i don't think we don't we have as much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> problem as a lot of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have
 	
 	
 		yeah that seems to be true um yeah if you've ever been to like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can just you can just as you walk through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> you can see crimes being committed it's that obvious
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i know i've i've come to the conclusion also that you know just if you are walking in a downtown area you know where where there's a lot of crime a lot of that's gonna just just keeping your senses about you and you know trying not to look like a victim
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		you know walk with you know walk with you know with
 	
 	
 		with a big stick or
 	
 	
 		well  not silly just walk you know confidently and you know don't don't be looking around like you've never been there before and you have no idea where you are
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		sure  right don't don't walk down a an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> or don't get just try to keep yourself out of a bad situation but yeah there are times when you can't avoid all that um and and then you're kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on your own
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and if you have you ever have you ever been mugged in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no the only thing i've ever had is i've had my wallet lifted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that was in a more of a
 		a a setting where there was a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around and i kind of got  i was much younger at the time and kind of a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they just took it from me without me knowing really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and kind of passed it off so i didn't know who had it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've had that happen but that's that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah i've been pretty lucky about getting mugged i don't
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i've only actually seen like one you know one actual robbery with a gun
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and that's been about the only you know real violent crime where you know potentially violent crime that i've seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and that and that was just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> running out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> that he just robbed
 	
 	
 		really well i've had my
 		um-hum i've had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> stolen so maybe that counts
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		wow where was where where was that was that downtown or
 	
 	
 		oh no that was in the northern part um up near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cumberland Mall</ENAMEX> area it's actually <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cobb County</ENAMEX> but it is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 		um-hum metropolitan yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> thefts in that area
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've actually i've known known some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have had their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> stolen
 		um
 		and uh and uh you know but half the time they seem to
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APD</ENAMEX> seems to recover them you know in in various states of disrepair  up on blocks you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who had a um
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW Rabbit</ENAMEX> and when he when he got it back his um dashboard was sitting in in his front seat
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah mine was just it had been wrecked and some superficial type damage but they didn't they didn't strip it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i got it back
 	
 	
 		well you're probably luckier than
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		than most
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		so does like insurance pay for the body damage or was that was that all it was body
 	
 	
 		right it it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand</ENAMEX> to put everything together they cracked the steering column of course to steal the car
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah you've got to you crack the steering column then you pull the there's a pin in there that you can pull on these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and you can start start it up basically pretty easily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so how do you know this much about um stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well after i found mine i had to i had this
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	