
 
     		
 	
 		how do you feel about capital punishment
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um i'm i'm definitely against it definitely against it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		for what reasons
 	
 	
 		uh i think that they make a lot the system makes a lot of mistakes and a lot of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are probably convicted of crimes and it's bad enough when um
 		you know when it's not capital punishment but when it's capital punishment when you find out later it's too late
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah definitely yeah i i  i agree that you know capital punishment is bad but just more for the economic for economic reasons because i i don't think it acts as a deterrent
 		and i don't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">um  and and</ENAMEX> and for what i've what i've read it costs a lot more to actually you know go through the process of condemning someone and killing them than it does to actually just feed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> end you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it dose because because of uh  the the legal system that we have now and i'm sure you can make it cheaper if you wanted i don't think you should
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you can make it cheaper to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by not allowing all the appeals and as a matter of fact i think they are starting to cut back on some of them at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i forgot what area it is but regarding uh capital punishment there are some cases that won't automatically get reviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> when they used to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so what happens is you have to pay all these high powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to keep on arguing the case over and over again uh while they're waiting for capital punishment which is what happened uh which happens a lot a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine uh does that type of work down in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> he's he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> he represents <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on death row
 	
 	
 		is he prosecution
 		he's he's he's for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and i did criminal defense work for a while so i kind of have a a um  let's say um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		cynical about the system and the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are convicted of crimes not that i think i do believe that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are charged with crimes and convicted certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are convicted of crimes most of them are probably guilty anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i'm not denying that but there are a few that probably aren't
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh i mean i've you know i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know definitely got screwed by the system
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		before yeah um is do they have the death penalty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no huh um they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> right yeah they
 	
 	
 		yeah they do um  yeah i'm not sure how often we how often this actually it seems like about once a year they execute someone i don't really keep you know i only keep up after when the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was
 	
 	
 		right well that's the thing i mean i happened to have been talking to somebody at at uh work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just happened to come up in conversation and so i was surprised when i got this topic come up and uh the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the bottom line was that uh  what was i saying uh nobody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> has been convicted has been executed since nineteen executed since nineteen
 		uh seventy uh what seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or whenever it was that they ruled that the death penalty was cruel and unconstitutional
 	
 	
 		constitutional
 	
 	
 		yeah and whether it was unconstitutional and then like i said they came back and um like the nineteen eighties and and determined that if they have like a separate trial to determine the death penalty they call them bifricated trials
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they have a separate trial just to determine whether they're going to give the death penalty or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um then then that's okay they can it becomes constitutional i guess it's like a procedural protection that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but nobody's been nobody's been executed since they've brought that back and
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> so it puts a lot of pressure on them
 	
 	
 		you know one thing that i've always that i've one idea that i've heard that that that i've you know kind of had some sympathy for is though that you know when you have someone that's
 		you know that that that's you know that that you are going to be stuck is going to be stuck with life imprisonment you know or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred and fifty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you know none of it served you know at the same time that you know to give them the choice of having the death penalty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it seems you know if you lock him away for the rest of his life you know
 	
 	
 		yeah but it's kind of like under under duress anyway but you know kind of saying to someone all right now that we've got you by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chops</ENAMEX> because you decide whether you're going to die or not but but yeah that's what that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Gilmore</ENAMEX> did right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh yeah he he told us his yeah he said that he wanted to die at that point
 	
 	
 		that guy
 		right and they you know kind of chose his way to death which is is kind of interesting but um
 		yeah i i personally think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have the right to die if they want so yeah if you're in jail if you're in jail for life then you should be able to commit suicide if that's what you want
 	
 	
 		um-hum  it
 	
 	
 		which is basically what that is but
 	
 	
 		you know it really bothers me that in historical cases where you know someone tries to kill themselves in prison you know on death row and you know where they've actually you know spent you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> reviving them you know just to kill them
 	
 	
 		yeah sure
 	
 	
 		and it always so it seemed to be some sort of
 	
 	
 		i did some i did some environmental environmental law as well and and one of the i remember in studying something about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> D A they was it what the hell were they trying to do they were trying to get a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a drug
 		it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that they were using for the death penalty and they right they tried to get it proved safe before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> D A would approve it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	