
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what's your view
 	
 	
 		all right
 		huh
 	
 	
 		what's your view
 	
 	
 		well
 		i have a hard time thinking that they can control <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		personally
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		you know even if they give it a shot it's still going to be black market all over the place you know
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		i don't know coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you're probably
 		i don't know i i shouldn't make stereo types but gun control is probably frowned on quite a bit down there i would think
 	
 	
 		yeah it is but i'm not really from
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm not really from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i just live down here now i've i've lived down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you're just living down there
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm originally originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		yeah there uh there uh there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well
 		i know how you feel i'm uh i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> and and we always use to go out and hunt all the time you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> there's no way  there's no way i would ever go for a total ban on all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that's just i don't know
 	
 	
 		i just think i think it's ridiculous i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah it doesn't sit with me very well
 		i don't know i anymore i keep a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty eight</TIMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah i just about all well i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> and
 		i well actually i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> but i am staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> for a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know both areas are pretty crime ridden right now
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it's just you you never know who is out there you know it's just for self protection purposes and then
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		of course there's the hunting issue so
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good that do you do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i
 		i'm in uh program control for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> up here
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		we do schedules
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		programs programs schedule programs what do you do
 	
 	
 		i'm uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX> up here
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> uh do you get much of a chance to hunt or anything or
 	
 	
 		uh i haven't had a chance to do any hunting since i've been down here i don't own a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> but i'd like to go <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> hunting
 	
 	
 		yeah you know that's something i miss quite a bit
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah uh when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> we went
 		dear and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elk</ENAMEX> hunting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you you know quite a bit but
 	
 	
 		all right yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was uh a guide for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX> and elk hunts out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> for a while
 		and uh really enjoyed it quite a bit but
 		i don't know i guess that what the scale now is it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> for uh
 		for a complete
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for a total ban and uh
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		i guess i am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or nine</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i agree with you there
 	
 	
 		yeah no doubt about it but uh
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		if they can anyway get it keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> from having <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> which they can't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i you know i'm not for it
 	
 	
 		yeah if there is if there's a way you know to limit it
 		to to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i don't know that
 		they they i guess they passed a couple of uh of laws a here while back in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in terms of a waiting period
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where they you know you go to buy a hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and then they actually
 		uh i know it's this way in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> they have a waiting period where you buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and that's a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then they check you out and make sure you don't have a record you know and things like that i think that's a pretty good idea
 		uh
 		and that's i don't know
 		that's not a bad idea but then again you can always get around that you could go through the black market like you say you know you always be able to get around
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		yeah it's one of those things
 		but uh
 		i don't know i guess
 		i guess some forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> should probably be controlled just like
 		i'm not real sure why anybody would need
 		a fully automatic weapon
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't either
 	
 	
 		you know i'm just not i think those have been pretty much you know banned altogether anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i fully auto but even well
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i mean a semiautomatic
 		i guess that's
 	
 	
 		it kind of takes the sport out of hunting
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know it's like
 		what can you do with that that you can't do
 		in a self protection situation with like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or a or a or a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> shot twelve
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you know you might do the same thing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so it's like i don't know it it it does it takes the sport out of it
 		for me i would much rather have a bow any time
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i i like bows you know i have done some bow hunting and i uh i get into it and i think it's more of a challenge you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know i guess it keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> in business
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know
 		anyway that's about where i stand
 		
 
 	
 	
 		me too yeah i am about the same way
 	
 	
 		you uh
 		have you uh eaten yet or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock</TIMEX> there
 	
 	
 		uh yeah it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX> fifteen
 	
 	
 		you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> central
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		how is the weather up there
 	
 	
 		oh it's it's not too good it's kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rainy</ENAMEX> actually you know it's
 	
 	
 		is it
 	
 	
 		around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of year</TIMEX> you expect it up here to get down to about uh i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> degrees and it's been up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around forty</NUMEX> so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are whining about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and stuff but not not too bad about the temperature <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> is starting to melt and stuff like that so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i am just up here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year or so</TIMEX> and it's kind of shock to
 		
 		
 	