
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay how do you keep up with current events
 	
 	
 		um well actually usually um  in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> i am getting ready to either go to work um usually catch the news in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah what what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> do you watch or what station
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh NBC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's the one i watch i usually keep up with TV
 		i don't i am a student so i really don't have much time to like read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i get a lot of stuff through the grapevine which is really isn't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		too great sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah i usually tend to just you know rely on you know TV um again you know just through the grapevine just just to know like
 		yeah  what  what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s stories are and i usually like go out an buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> if you know i'm interested in any particular one
 	
 	
 		yeah the radio doesn't really have much
 		news sometimes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> i listen to are just mainly music
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you you pretty much have to listen to all news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> to get any news at all
 	
 	
 		yeah do you think that TV is um pretty accurate i mean sometimes do you think it gets pretty commercialized or
 	
 	
 		well what i really don't like about TV especially local news as compared to like national news is just
 		um it seems it seems like everything is very spoon feed
 		and you know it's
 		it's more like the news shows is now is is now you know an entertainment show like a sitcom
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or like the news because they would always have like the wonderful investigative reports you know is is you're kids <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> smoking crack on the way to school you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's they mainly go with like popular topics just not like basic news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah also also i have the observation with um
 		with the press is that like any any stories that
 		i had any first hand knowledge of that i see in the press you know which only happened like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times in my life
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you know first thing you know for anything of you know or anything that actually had had
 		more than just a blurb about it that the press has managed to just mess up some aspect of the story
 		it's something wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		going they're looks like they're going more for ratings than for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know actual news
 		i think you know the
 		probably the best source of just plain journalism would be newspapers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they
 		typically have a better i am from a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> too here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so that then like local news is really who grew the biggest tomato and
 	
 	
 		yeah the farm report
 	
 	
 		yeah farm report and oil reports
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's pretty pretty sad or who killed who
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah also i have um founded like in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> probably aren't as bad as television but i just you know
 		read the story and just found it so incredibly watered down and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well in um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um i don't know if you heard about the killing where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> drove into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luby</ENAMEX>'s
 		and the story was uh
 	
 	
 		was that like  he started shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah and the news covered it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> after it happened and they were taping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were crying who
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		had everything and then like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days later this</TIMEX>
 		local news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> was using as a as their promo
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to promote themselves i just thought that was really
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i have seen that happen lots of times you know
 	
 	
 		that's kind of cold
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Channel X</ENAMEX> gives you the best coverage  you know we were on the scene with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team players</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah and it was just they were showing like these dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they were showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> crying i mean just taking advantage of you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it real personal moment
 	
 	
 		they are trying to get the you know most emotional response for
 	
 	
 		yeah it didn't seem like there was much coverage of the story but just the play on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s emotions
 		it's just gotten so i mean
 		somewhere there's it's lost a lot of the quality that they use to have like in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Cronkite</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah i have
 		you know i've pretty much stopped watching local news totally you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um  you know even the national news i just find it to be you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		very watered down very
 	
 	
 		yeah what did you think of the coverage of the war
 	
 	
 		um
 		i found i found it very one sided
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		um
 		you know i mean it just it just seemed to lack any sort of debate
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know you know not saying that we should that we that we definitely should have been there or shouldn't have been there but it just seemed like you know
 	
 	
 		they kept just showing you know how great we were doing and it never really showed what actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the damage that really happened that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of times like the news coverage showed all the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who didn't get hurt coming home and all the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and they kind of you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they were going to show that why didn't they show the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		got really hurt and everything and
 	
 	
 		yeah and i really think that you know in the in the involvement that
 		the press states you know that the the military basically sets the press
 		
 		
 	