
 
     		
 	
 		what do you think about drug testing
 	
 	
 		i think it's pretty good i think they should do it especially in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> where
 		uh you deal with uh either with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or with uh stuff that uh
 		i want to say uh
 		deals directly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX> everywhere uh you know when uh when i was in college
 		when uh everywhere i i applied a job for uh pretty much did a drug test because most of them were like defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		except uh the the last job the job i actually took
 		they didn't care
 	
 	
 		oh is that right was it a large or a small company
 	
 	
 		so
 		it's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> telecommunications and i think uh they may require it for like the field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that actually go out you know and drive their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> around and stuff like that uh or run the heavy machinery but they don't require it for you know the engineering positions
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah i was kind of surprised but
 		defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> only want you doing it because uh they don't want you to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for you know for secrets or something you know
 	
 	
 		well sure i there's that part of it i think and
 		and i think most defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> also have other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> of the company
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that can also be affected by that and i think what they have to do in the interest of fairness or to keep from getting sued or something is test everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> at least on a random basis in other words no matter whether you work in uh defense or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 		right
 	
 	
 		consumer products or whatever you'd you'd have an equal chance of being tested
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know i just think it's a sick thing that we've come to that i don't like the way the world's going
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean
 		yeah i mean i have i have no problem i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> complain so much you know about random drug testing and infringing their rights and all this stuff
 		and you know i i don't know i guess it's bad you know to to go inside somebody you know hand them a urine sample bottle you know but uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		does it i've heard a lot of discussions about this and i guess the scariest part of it is the chance of a false positive
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and and that's what
 		what really upsets a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are you know very straight and probably wouldn't ever think of using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but the idea that they could lose their jobs
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or in our case be forced to go to all this counseling and that sort of stuff you know just in the case of a false positive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i mean now even if you had a false positive i mean they're they're better you can have retests or what do they do test on your hair
 	
 	
 		uh no urine
 	
 	
 		they can uh
 		well can't they also test your hair
 	
 	
 		yes they can and i think that's probably be more acceptable i believe it's more accurate
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but that's not what they're doing at my company
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		no it's urine samples i haven't been tapped yet  to do this
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well you know
 	
 	
 		but they certainly started out i believe with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well they uh i mean all the places i went to you know they gave us you know small tests and stuff like that i guess if uh
 		you could always get a second opinion i mean if your company
 		tests positive
 		i mean i i i would just think there was a way there'd be a way around it if i mean even if you did test positive you could probably get tested again
 		and uh
 		test negative
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		and any way have time for that
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		wouldn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah i i suppose i suppose it's
 		it's just you know the whole idea of all the hassles you'd have to go through and certainly the records that would be left behind
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know everybody has databases these days
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they know a lot more about me than i'll ever remember i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah and a matter of fact i think there are too many of these dull databases going around
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm i'm certainly certainly sure that uh any drug test results would become a part of that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true i guess they put it in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> file
 	
 	
 		probably so
 	
 	
 		yeah because i i'm i'm you know
 		i'm surprised they don't do it you know in uh in my organization
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well i certainly believe in it for uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like airline pilots
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or uh what seems to be more of a problem train drivers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">train</ENAMEX>  and also uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> captains i mean not necessarily big boat captains
 		but small the uh small personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they had trouble with uh not just substance abuse but uh alcohol abuse and stuff
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		and they had these boat crashes and you know all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were getting arrested and
 		and they finally said no more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> out there
 		you know in uh like where i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they had a lot of problems with uh with boat wrecks and involving you know alcohol related incidents and uh drug related incidents
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so they finally just said uh if we catch you we're going to take away your license and take away your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> if we have to
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so
 		straightened a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		well i guess it would i guess so
 		well i don't know i
 		i i really haven't sorted out all my feelings on the drug testing uh i'm totally straight would never consider using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 		um-hum well you know i'm the same way
 	
 	
 		but uh it it sort of goes back to it's a presumption of guilt and you have to prove that you're innocent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on the other hand uh
 		
 		
 	