
 
     		
 	
 		so um do you have a PC
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> thirty
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintoshes i</ENAMEX> have a um PC my a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PC myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eighty six</NUMEX> but i'm probably eventually gonna get a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three eighty six</NUMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		what do you use yours for mostly
 	
 	
 		um mostly um word processing applications and uh just as a dumb terminal uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i'm um i think eventually i'll start using it for spread sheets and things like that um what do you find that you use yours mostly for
 	
 	
 		well i do a lot of word processing and spread sheets and data base and uh about the only thing i am uh i'm just starting to get in into uh a little bit more communications now i've just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ordered a fax modem so i'll be able to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		send and receive faxes right over there without using you know you don't have to make a hard copy that way
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are you using windows
 	
 	
 		no i i think i i'm planning on like moving up getting a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three eighty six</NUMEX> before i move up to Windows although you know i do like the the graphical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> environment yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well it's getting to be more and more like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's just
 		um i want it i want it you know well  i just i just want it more for multitasking which i suppose is also like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		um-hum well the one thing i used to use a i've never used an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> actually i used to use a just an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> two E which of course is looks pretty primitive now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i used that's what i learned a lot of languages on was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX> in my high school
 	
 	
 		but i don't have any uh any real programming capabilities on my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> right now i don't have uh any compilers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm uh  wanting
 	
 	
 		well do you use your computer for uh
 		just things around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or in the in the
 	
 	
 		i use it in my business
 	
 	
 		i see what do you do
 	
 	
 		i uh do uh consultation and and testing of various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinds</ENAMEX> for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> programs
 	
 	
 		oh wow um and uh are these like uh do these programs um
 		are they are they based on on a on a um
 		other language or are they based are are they based like a lot of the um i know a lot of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> classes will have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all sorts of you know parts of the world
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> just tries to tries to teach English you know through natural understanding
 	
 	
 		that's uh exactly what yeah that's the kind of thing i'm working with exactly you seem to be uh better informed than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it was just uh when i was high school i worked for the community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> class and it always seemed strange to me that you know all these all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know
 		spoke English not too well and spoke you know a variety of different languages were all being taught at the same time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		imagine it's a lot harder on a computer because you have to you know you don't have as many cues you can't don't have hand gestures and things like that
 	
 	
 		right well now we uh what i use a computer for is to write materials that are later printed though most of the stuff that i do is not uh interactive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i use it for testing uh data analysis on testing so
 	
 	
 		oh to see how well they retain the vocabulary and things like that
 	
 	
 		well just actually just uh item analysis statistical analysis of the tests uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know when you when you write a test you have to look at some data from it and see how the different questions are performing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and find out which ones are discriminating well and which ones aren't find out how reliable the test is you try correlate it with other tests and things of that sort so it's involves a lot of spread sheet use
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i'd imagine so um
 		so um what were you doing when you were using an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> two E
 	
 	
 		well i was doing some of the same stuff but doing it more slowly  and with smaller files  i can't believe you know i've got uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">megabytes</NUMEX> on this one now and on my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX> i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred twenty eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum it it's amazing
 		yes it it's amazing you know how how like in the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user community</ENAMEX> the expectations have just grown so much i remember my first computer was a TRS eighty with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know and then then i moved and then i started playing with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Apples</ENAMEX> you know and and those had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty eight</NUMEX> or you know if if they were really great they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh the old
 		the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> uh the the the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> had what yeah <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty eight</NUMEX> i guess didn't it
 	
 	
 		uh all i know i know that in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they had a bunch that had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> on them
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is all and there's i remember that there was one game that i played that required forty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> and there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> computer that had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> on it at the time
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know it's just so amazing that generally you know if you if you i'm not sure about about um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macintoshes</ENAMEX> but i know in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s you you you generally you know you buy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a megabyte</NUMEX> at a time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that's that's your low that's the low end
 		um
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> goes up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i haven't upgraded it quite that far yet i think probably when i get system seven i may have to do that and and get another possibly another hard disk i don't know they say that system <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> uses a lot of memory
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah imagine just to support
 		
 		
 	