
 
     		
 	
 		how's the quality of air in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		very good
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh well let me put it this way it's it's relatively uh it's very good if if you are a little bit away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and it's and it's wonderful on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> that it rains
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh downtown they have a few problems but it's
 	
 	
 		um-hum probably a lot of ozone lot of smog
 	
 	
 		but it's fairly localized it's not like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> where i used to live
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 		oh yeah i've heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> is horrible and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> is i hear is really bad
 	
 	
 		yes yes uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s moderately bad um you know we have we have a big problem with ozone um
 		and you know it's generally you know it's it it's quite often you know be a very hazy sort of day you know because there'll just be this pollution hanging in the air
 		um
 		i think a lot i think well i think most of our problems caused by automobile emissions
 		because you know it's a very you know mobile city
 	
 	
 		it i guess that's the the major problem with most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> except except places like uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> or some place like that well i guess it's it's a problem there too but but they do have some places where that's caused by power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		of heavy industry yeah i think i think the  has been you know relatively good about
 		um you know having regulations at least in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years or so</TIMEX> about
 		industry industry pollution but it just seems that i think i think i think we really suffer because you know we don't have any sort of an organized mass transit system any sort of you know like high speed rail or even you know even even you know decent regular passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rail</ENAMEX> across the country
 		um it seems it seems like like there's a lot you know there's a lot there's a lot more federal subsidies for automobile you know for through through the construction through the construction of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> for automobiles
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		although  there is one thing that i uh i learned in in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chemistry</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> and that's uh i don't know are are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		i know a little bit of chemistry
 	
 	
 		okay anyway this is principle called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Chatelier</ENAMEX>'s principal as i remember and it's
 		basically uh
 		uh when you have uh
 		a reaction and it it uh  the reaction will go until it until until it kind of comes to a balance but if you take away some of the products of that reaction then the reaction will go farther
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so uh the illustration that the chemistry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> pointed out was he said he said in a in a desirable area
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will move in until until bad things happen that cause the uh desirabilities to go to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know to uh balance kind of balance out he says if it's not air pollution it'll be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it will be uh congestion or price of land or something like that so what i'm looking at here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> area is is a temporary situation it's a very desirable area as far as i'm concerned and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the wonderful air the lack of of uh congestion the low low cost of of uh property uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> something's going to cause i mean there's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just going to continue to move in until we either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		until just gets the air it can't just it can't support them and the quality of life they want
 	
 	
 		and and
 		and as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move in as move out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it'll come to a balance and then if they come along and they add new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeways</ENAMEX> so let's say they reduce traffic congestion then air pollution will get bad or something else and that's happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> that's for sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as far as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> do they have a uh do they have uh regulations on on uh like inspection
 	
 	
 		um they they do have automobile automobile <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> tests but um
 		it's there there's some sort of rule i don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so i don't know the actual specifics but it's like if your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is if the make if the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model model year</TIMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than twenty years old</TIMEX> you don't have to have it inspected any more
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> type thing
 	
 	
 		you know which is which is just kind of ludicrous you know because those are the ones that you'd expect to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know be the hardest be the most biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">polluters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although i think that's partly because it's harder to get parts and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's true
 	
 	
 		so let's see what was my other question uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> thinks this is uh a uh sales call so she's telling me to talk to you about
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the problems with uh she thinks it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">from</NUMEX> from uh our cable company
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh let's see what else we have uh
 		uh let's see do you live
 		you don't live too close do you live close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or far away from it
 	
 	
 		i basically live downtown
 	
 	
 		okay downtown
 	
 	
 		and i go to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> which is pretty much located in the heart of downtown or within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> from the heart of downtown
 	
 	
 		do they have smog days there
 		uh
 	
 	
 		it's i don't think it's really announced you know in the sense that the way it the way it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> but um
 		i have heard on the news in the you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of months</TIMEX> or so that you know that apparently there's some federal guidelines for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um smog</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s like it
 		
 		
 	