
 
     		
 	
 		i haven't had to put anyone in a nursing home but we came close have you had that experience yet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i haven't either but a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> had to put his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in a nursing home and i know just going through it with him i mean it's a real traumatic experience
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's for sure yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> just even deciding to do it and then i think feeling guilty after you know that it needs to be done you know
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum uh yeah i had a a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who just did it and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh and uh well both his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were sick not doing well went to take care of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and then one of them died and then it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you do with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> it's particularly hard if they live away
 	
 	
 		okay that's what i was just going to say if they're out of state you know it's different if they're in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> i think you have a little more chance to look out for them but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then too if you work you know you get there has to be somebody there
 	
 	
 		well that's a problem and i  uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was ninety
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two ninety three</NUMEX> when she died and she was able to stay in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> but the but the cost of that was unbelievable to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> now i don't know that it would have been any better in a nursing home but at that point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was you know uh she was old enough that it was like that's where she she wanted to die was where she was not to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh you mean not staying at home you mean and not yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		staying at home yeah not going somewhere else i think it's harder if they if they're younger but need a lot of care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> that's one thing at at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> or seventy it's something else and yet
 	
 	
 		no yeah well that's just it because i mean jeez they've got probably probably good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> to live you know some some cases if they're healthy you know
 	
 	
 		right right
 		right exactly and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">and</ENAMEX> and yet if the care is just is just so hard then that's
 		you know that's really hard and i don't know what you know what the different things that you would look for i mean obviously uh you want it to be clean you know
 	
 	
 		it would be clean yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> and that that it's got a good reputation as far as health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">et cetera</ENAMEX> but then atmosphere seems like would make so much difference
 	
 	
 		i know and to make sure that there's enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there to keep everybody like that can you know to be involved instead of just leaving them sit in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yes that that's the picture you always see of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		in fact i used to date a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that reminds me when i was back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> but his mother i mean he had she ended up i guess getting it <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> what they now call <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		Alzheimer yeah
 	
 	
 		but to begin with you know when they first i mean she would know us you know and we'd go to visit her but then
 		it would get you know like she didn't really know she didn't know me and then she thought he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> you know and it just got steadily worse you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well i that's the thing i mean when it's something like that i i think it particularly if it's something like that and they really don't know where they are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it doesn't feel i would think that would be easier than someone who really does know and is saying i don't
 	
 	
 		and has been independent all their lives and then all of a sudden you know
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		and i you know i don't i don't want to go kind of thing but the other side of it is that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>
 		moved out of her home and into an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> but it is was not a nursing home and that's where she died but she lived there for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve years
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		and she did she really went through uh like a depression for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> moving out of her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but then she said
 	
 	
 		just getting used to it
 		oh
 	
 	
 		well she says course this is so wonderful because all i have to do is open my door you know go out the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> and down stairs to the place to eat or down stairs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> and there're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which in her home you know there weren't i mean the logistics of it become so difficult that she said i've i've really made some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and that feels good so that's the other side of it is
 	
 	
 		well that yeah would definitely be a positive part because they'd be around more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and would be easier for them to get out and to see those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah but but it's just that
 		you know how do you i guess unless you visit a lot and unexpectedly and assuming that you can visit unexpectedly
 	
 	
 		well i would think that you ought to be in fact i was going to say that i would go at different times of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> not only when they're expecting you to come
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just to see how you know at different times of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> what they do and how they treat them you know
 	
 	
 		exactly and how everything looks and and then and then the other thing is really listen to what they say because and that's another hard thing
 		uh you know if the as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get older we we all seem to uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		fuss just a little bit more about everything so then the question is is the fussing legitimate or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		or is it just because yeah they're having such a hard time adjusting you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so they'll tell you well she says she doesn't like the food but you should see her plate you know or some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so then you i guess you'd have to be there to be sure that that's
 		
 		
 	