
 
     		
 	
 		so do you do a lot of camping
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh well yeah a fair amount mostly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> scouts
 	
 	
 		oh is that right uh-huh um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scouts</ENAMEX> also uh so i know they go a lot of camping but i don't go with them
 		but uh we used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and we did a little bit of camping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> not all that much but um enough to get a little flavor for it uh where mostly do you go with your camping
 	
 	
 		well mostly uh well boy scout <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> near uh near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh
 		in in fact i i think i know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean right Jan Novak</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh who am i talking to
 		oh i can't believe that  well we can talk about anything  well
 	
 	
 		but we can talk about camping none the less
 		they didn't
 	
 	
 		you know this is really funny because i i've tried to make these phone calls um whenever it pops in my head and sometimes they say oh we can't find another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and after they
 		they say that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times i can't keep hanging on the phone and i just saw that card down there and now i'm really supposed to be baking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cistercian  i</ENAMEX> said oh i'll make another phone call i guess another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> helps  so anyway
 	
 	
 		but we we should talk about camping because they're recording this
 	
 	
 		oh we have to talk about oh that's right we're on this recording thing well anyway um we used to go camping out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> up by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mendocino</ENAMEX> and um  to um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">uh Lasson Park</ENAMEX> which is a volcanic a volcanic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and uh that was absolutely extraordinary and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rangers</ENAMEX> there that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do the tours and the little classes and the lectures and everything were quite extraordinary so that was uh one of our uh major camping times that we enjoyed very very much
 		uh do you ever go camping outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> scouts
 	
 	
 		well we used to do a lot of camping uh in fact before we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie</ENAMEX> and i would go
 		we did a lot of canoe camping uh either in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> where there are a lot of lakes up near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Placid</ENAMEX> and in that area and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ontario</ENAMEX> which is also full of lakes
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and some of our longest trips went for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six days</TIMEX> and covered <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seventy miles</NUMEX> where you you canoe
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> from lake to lake sometimes by rivers where they connect or else you have to portage your canoe and all your equipment to the next lake
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so that that was a i i think it's a lot in a way easier to go canoe camping because you you don't have to watch the weight so much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's also cleaner because you can go swimming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and it's very easy to keep keep cool and keep clean
 	
 	
 		oh that's true too
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and that's
 	
 	
 		we took <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one canoe</NUMEX> trip in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> now but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> were very very small when we were out there and um it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webbie's</ENAMEX> that got this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> together
 		and uh there had been some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> and therefore the river was a little more swift than what might normally be expected and um
 		i i i found it exciting but i really thought that it was a trifle dangerous maybe because the currents were kind of bad and we just went ahead anyway but it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian River</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		what what river was that yeah i've seen i've seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian River</ENAMEX> we never went canoeing on it that that can get pretty fast
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah it can and it did and um it was my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webbie</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time doing this also and we just trusted uh trusted in the uh knowledge of
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that got this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> together that it would not be over dangerous and we had our
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		life belts on and everything else like that but we did dump over once and uh you know with small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> like that just made me very nervous we didn't go again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> we just uh kind of uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp site</ENAMEX> and uh cooked  but it it was it was very exciting and
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		really very nice and um i wouldn't mind doing something like that again
 		and i guess the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time you do a major endeavor like that you really are a neophyte you don't know exactly what to expect or even sometimes what to do  but um
 		it it was quite an experience uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well you you have to be careful
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum yeah yeah so
 	
 	
 		you have to be careful
 		your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philmont</ENAMEX> are they
 	
 	
 		oh yes well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		again
 		right so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny</ENAMEX>'s not going again
 	
 	
 		no no no he's not gonna go again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time</TIMEX> but uh you're gonna inherit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean</ENAMEX> on this trip and uh um-hum
 	
 	
 		okay well i'll i'm going with them so
 	
 	
 		i know uh-huh have you been out there before oh you haven't well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> says it's i think it's really quite challenging
 	
 	
 		no
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh absolutely uh i kind of got the information by drips and drabs from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> as different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> would talk to him and apparently whoever has to carry that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or part
 		
 		
 	