
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right uh
 	
 	
 		did you uh did you have to wait very long
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		did you have to wait very long
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh i forgot my i i had to dig through my suitcase and find my personal identification number
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right so uh
 	
 	
 		they had
 		
 
 		are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> still paying too much too many taxes
 		that's a that's an easy one are we supposed to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> on this
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well no  i mean yes
 	
 	
 		oh you think you that we are paying too much
 		in taxes
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i don't think we're paying a lot too much i uh
 		i think we're paying i i i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> and uh i know that they pay a lot more than we do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's even higher uh tax rate over there on income
 	
 	
 		yeah so i guess we should be grateful that it's as low as it is
 	
 	
 		right are are you you're a native you're from uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		but you worked over there for a couple of year
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i was so when i was living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> i got uh an impression kind of an impression of their system which is socialistic
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and so they everything is subsidized by their government their their taxes are higher than ours so i guess i shouldn't be i shouldn't complain so much
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i uh i do get concerned that there's that there's a lot of uh government spending on things like um
 		things that that don't really benefit anyone outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">district</ENAMEX> who proposes the measure like restoring some old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		right you talking about special projects in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> you mean now
 	
 	
 		it
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		okay yeah it's true i feel that um you know i don't feel that uh we're paying too much taxes provided we get the right services for what we pay for but i think we've kind of gotten away from that
 		um for what we get we're paying too much i would say
 	
 	
 		you wouldn't mind paying that much if you were getting that equivalent value for it
 	
 	
 		right or if if things i didn't feel that things were wasted
 	
 	
 		i can go
 	
 	
 		for uh you know through uh red tape through waste you know uh money a lot of money is lost and how much effect are you getting out of your dollar and how much goes to just waste
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i have to agree although i pay an awful lot of taxes because i'm single i'm in a reasonably high tax bracket
 		so
 		um it seems very expensive to me for what i get
 	
 	
 		right right typically um
 		you don't get a whole lot
 	
 	
 		no although i get some things that i very much appreciate i mean i don't i don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> i don't i'm not reporting for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> i live in a free economy and so i mean in a sense i don't mind spending money on
 		and uh welfare on
 		reasonable amounts of welfare i don't mind spending money on
 		and things like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> and stuff i don't mind spending on
 	
 	
 		well right a lot of federal money goes for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> but speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> who are on welfare i know one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Buchanan</ENAMEX> has a idea that says that
 		if he's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> if you don't get a job within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> then you're taken off welfare
 		so to eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who continuously uh kind of leech off the system
 		you know you you have you get to spend your time but then you're off
 	
 	
 		huh
 		don't know if i agree with that or not
 		i mean because there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that just plain i don't know what the percentage is but there is some percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that just cannot get a job for whatever reason
 		although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> that does sound like quite a while
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i don't know what do you think of that one
 	
 	
 		well i i i guess i'm not i don't like to make hard and fast rules that you have to live by because there's always exceptions but i think something has to be done some type of reform measure
 	
 	
 		he certainly seems to be looking at the right issue
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um one thing that i've kind of been following that i i'd really i'm kind of waiting for it and i maybe after the presidential elections we'll see it and that is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to uh see if he can
 		see if he can uh give the line item veto a try
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh apparently he's been waiting for a test case he's been waiting for quite a while
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but i think it'd be fascinating to see him try vetoing some of the one of these rider bills that's that's clearly a waste of money and to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> reacts to that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that'd be quite an exciting battle
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i don't know what's your situation i live uh i'm a property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> in the city limits of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we get taxed tremendously tremendously on our property taxes and a lot of that money doesn't go for what the original intent of property taxes was
 		um i pay for a a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grady Hospital</ENAMEX> where a lot of
 		indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are go and get free care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> which you know maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> should pay for that but i i and a lot of other things
 		
 		
 	