
 
     		
 	
 		well what do you think about how we've changed in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think it's pretty amazing i think um that my grandparents especially have seen a whole lot of change in their lives but um
 	
 	
 		in in like in what ways particularly are you thinking
 	
 	
 		well technology but also morals morals and things like that i think even even in the last like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> you can still see things falling so fast and that can be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for me that's the biggest change it's so frustrating um to see everything
 		
 
 	
 	
 		disintegrating
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disintegrating</ENAMEX> and losing control your your losing control it seems like of the moral fiber of our society
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems that well it its a seems like it's definitely a transitional time i'm not sure
 		exactly what's happening there're good things that have happened but but at the moment we're suffering from
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think information overload for one thing um just just the technology like you mentioned
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faxes</ENAMEX> and car phones and VCRs and all of that that make us so immediate there there's no time for
 		relationships talking sitting being with each other all of that
 	
 	
 		i think you're really right i think like well even with computers um
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		you can there i mean there's so much that's happening in in that field and it
 		it just has forced us to go so fast and
 		um even the way we write it used to be if you read a book like you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hardy</ENAMEX> takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> to establish the mood and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just describes the scenery and what's been going on and stuff and now we just chopped all that out and say well let's get to the point and
 	
 	
 		exactly no patience
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no attention span
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		these sound bites you're exactly right i mean all there's all that and then we've got the rich getting richer and everyone else getting poorer
 		with with you know with with little hope of of having any impact i think impotence is a
 		is a a word that that suits most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> now we don't feel like we can influence you know influence anything
 	
 	
 		yeah you feel out of control
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> like just a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have it all wrapped up and they're not going to let you through um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it's a bad feeling
 	
 	
 		yeah it is it's really frustrating and the way our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> you know our nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disintegrating</ENAMEX> and stuff it's just a real
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't have the the social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> we used to have to
 	
 	
 		yeah go ahead
 	
 	
 		to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and things like that with everyone moving
 		you know every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> you lose your contacts you lose trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that you know they'll do things you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> it seems now it's independence is the thing and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know heaven forbid if you ask anyone for anything
 	
 	
 		yeah then that's
 	
 	
 		whereas we used to be able to depend on each other and trust each other and
 		you'll help me and i'll help you not and not in this corrupted sense but in the sense of
 		you know when you're in trouble and you need someone you know someone to babysit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> sure
 	
 	
 		um-hum the interdependence interdependence in a nice way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh i i don't know there was a lot there was good and bad in the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we've certainly found out a lot about the bad about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but but but the community
 		however the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> looked and it didn't always look like a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> even then you know you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> living together or you know whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has just definitely been lost and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trying to reestablish it in all sorts of different ways um you know well okay so we don't have a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and okay so we move but
 		you know maybe there's some way that we can have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that works together you know everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do live in communal you know almost commune areas that they've started up again you know
 		um special <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> or little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> that do that to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do it through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> or through a book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> or something i mean something you know  even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> have started sort of becoming the community
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think i think because it's a necessity
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as as as human beings we need a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> around us of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we can rely on i guess that's uh thing is that right now it's such a um
 	
 	
 		um-hum and yeah
 	
 	
 		temporary thing that how far does it go how far can you depend on them and they're so much more fragile at the touch you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and that's a good point and and we don't have the intergenerational generational
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> either which means that do you do you have to be between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> to be accepted and if
 		
 		
 	