
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> what kind of a personal computer do you have
 	
 	
 		uh we still have an old uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Computer</ENAMEX>
 		back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> was making uh computers that were similar to in terms of power to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> i don't remember what those were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ATs</ENAMEX> or something like that or
 	
 	
 		something like that yeah i have one of those too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> back when i don't know where to get any new software for it unfortunately so we just sort of stumble on using
 		the same stuff that we always have
 	
 	
 		yeah do you use computers at work or
 	
 	
 		um well i used to i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s degree in computer science but i haven't i i took a time out on careers about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so do i
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX> when my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year old</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so nowadays i'm teaching him at home and we're using the computer to drill him on math and to let him do some
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		creative writing without having to have uh
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of
 		handwriting get in the way of his words this way he can
 		he this way he just has to hunt and peck on the keyboard i have to admit i'd like a
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a more logical
 		arrangement of the letters and uh
 		what do they call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cortiope</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		something like that
 	
 	
 		arrangement
 	
 	
 		oh
 		do you use your computer for other things balancing checkbooks do you keep budgets and that sort of thing in it or
 	
 	
 		um
 		we haven't for
 		we ended up uh
 		actually just sort of keeping it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> isn't that a terrible statement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we're pretty involved with computers in all sorts of other aspects but um
 		i guess i wanted something that was easier to use than this and that was more intuitive and so we just
 		it just ended up not not getting used i should use it to balance my checkbook
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but then you have to remember to write it down
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 		well mine mine kind of died so it's being worked on right now
 	
 	
 		or enter it
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where do you find a place to work on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i found a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> who works at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and does things like that in his spare time
 	
 	
 		well that's nice to know that there are still such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		but i most of the stuff i've used that computer for were work related just bringing work home
 	
 	
 		yeah well i used to do that i'd used it um until
 		as i say until i took a hiatus hiatus from working i used to
 		to uh
 		trying to think of what you call it i i used it essentially as a terminal then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 		and
 	
 	
 		yeah i've done a lot of that
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		and i suspect most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do uh use them as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX> or
 		have a spreadsheet and a word processor and that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what else do you need right
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> think i should have games
 	
 	
 		well that's probably true
 	
 	
 		on top of games on top of games
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and of course we don't have any i keep telling them well you know just learn how to program
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah write your own games right
 	
 	
 		write your own games yeah i just
 	
 	
 		the computer i work have at work came with uh Windows software and it has a couple of games on it one of which is a solitaire just
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		just standard card solitaire
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but the graphics are so incredible and you can choose what you want the deck of cards to look like you know you can have <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> on the back of them or fishes or oh yes or a robot who has a little gauge that moves in his tummy and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i just i just happened to stumble across that of course i don't play games at work right
 	
 	
 		no who would do something like that
 		but uh
 		yeah we have basically we use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordStar</ENAMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know for a bunch of
 		i'm taking a class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and
 		um i'm actually getting a degree in nursing at this point and i asked the
 		and the class i'm taking now all of a sudden they want everything typed till now everything's been handwritten so it was a good thing that the computer was back up and running hooked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX> up to it
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		i was going to say you must have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		right  right well i couldn't figure out how to it's been a while since i've gotten it going all right so i tried to hook the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX> up and i was sure i put all the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">connectors</ENAMEX> in right and everything and had checked to make sure the pins were all facing the right way and i couldn't get the computer to recognize that there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX> there to save my life and so i was like oh this thing doesn't work and we've lost the
 		you know we've lost the install software documentation what am i supposed to do so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> took it in to work
 		
 		
 	