
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay now it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		all right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX> um what kind of music do you like to listen to
 	
 	
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Country</ENAMEX> and it's really hard to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that enjoy country music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		in my age
 		because i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two</TIMEX> and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> my age like hard rock and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not me  i think it was the stupidest thing ever invented
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i still like country music and
 	
 	
 		do you oh
 	
 	
 		so it's kind of hard for me to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i agree with on music
 	
 	
 		oh um now have you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> all your life
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		no you just moved there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i i have to be here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but i'm going home <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> opportunity i get
 	
 	
 		now where's home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay so country music is prevalent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i was born in a little tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that that's all they have
 	
 	
 		is it oh
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and all they know is country music
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean they still have barn dances and stuff
 	
 	
 		oh how fun oh
 	
 	
 		yeah it is pretty fun
 	
 	
 		oh gosh i don't blame you uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> Reserves and so he's going out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three weeks</TIMEX> for his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> week
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> stint so
 		i'll be missing him then but
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s leaving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> twelfth he has to go out to sea again
 	
 	
 		oh and how long does he stay out
 	
 	
 		so
 		well usually they stay out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six to nine months</TIMEX> but this time they're only going out for i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks this time</TIMEX> because they're just they're just doing their sea trials making sure they're ready to go out to sea again
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh well thank goodness
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i think that's terrible oh
 	
 	
 		yeah it gets kind of monotonous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i incorporated him into country music because he didn't he didn't like it when we got married but since he married me and i was the country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that's all i have going on at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so now he's gotten where he really likes country music and for my birthday he went out and he got me a brand new pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Llama</ENAMEX> boots and he bought himself a pair too and took me out country dancing
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>  so he is real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah and all his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> tease him on the ship
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		are you sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> know how to swim
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		he he gets upset about it but it's funny
 	
 	
 		that is that is well out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and we live kind of in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> it's by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden Utah</ENAMEX> i don't know if you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well it's it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a hour</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> so we're out here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and we hear a lot of the country music
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in fact i work in a bakery and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> comes to work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> and i come to work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock in the morning</TIMEX>
 		and he just has the country music just a blasting and he just rocks and rolls in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX>  to country music
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah i know how that goes i think country music's the only thing keeping me sane with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i i bet that's really hard being their alone with all those with the two little ones
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it is but
 		i don't know it's worth it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> it's a way of life for a while huh
 	
 	
 		it's worth it to me
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good
 		well um my favorite kind of music is New Age and it's that sounds like it's hard rock and roll but it's not it's the
 		oh the synthesizers synsi synthesizers and all of that
 	
 	
 		yeah and it kind of has a bluesy mix to it yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and it's just beautiful i love it i
 		i find it so relaxing and i do i'm getting beginning to like country music more and more since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> has it on all the time but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but my very favorite is that New Age i like my favorite recording <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yanni</ENAMEX> and he's not he doesn't make you yawn  he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		do you know who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariah Carey</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		um i have yeah i've heard of her in fact i was watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammy's</ENAMEX> and i i saw her on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammy</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		i don't particularly like her kind of music but she's got a couple songs that i i i can listen to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know without going totally bonkers
 	
 	
 		yeah she's not too wild
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah but
 		i don't know i just i guess i'm kind of the only country one that got left
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and everything are either hard rock or disco or um just a blues bar we've got several blues <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood neighborhood
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> what happened to juke boxes and sawdust on the floor you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i i asked that of a i went into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> on our anniversary and i asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i said have you ever heard of a a juke box and he goes yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i said why don't you install one he goes what music do you want on it and i said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and he goes no way i'd lose all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and i'm like thanks
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		oh
 		oh oh
 		
 
 		
 		
 	