
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		oh we have one rotten <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		one rotten <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i heard a laugh in the background
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> they they know i don't like it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh you don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats this cat</ENAMEX> is a uh more like a dog
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah he's uh a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a one</NUMEX> owner
 		he likes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and that's about it
 	
 	
 		that said what does how does he treat the other people
 	
 	
 		just uh stays away or runs
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		usually but he follows he'll follow my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> around
 		you know when he's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> he'll come up and he'll jump on his lap
 		but if anybody reaches over to pet him or whatever he'll just kind of look at them like what are you doing
 	
 	
 		did he raise him or something
 	
 	
 		and
 		he he's yeah we bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> for him and so he's he's been the one that you know spent the most time with him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i i've never owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> like that i've had cats growing up all the time and you know they're usually either that way with everybody or friendly to everybody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		so it's a weird <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh we have a a mutt well we we named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Hooper</ENAMEX> because that's where we got it from  uh some lady
 	
 	
 		a mutt
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh uh drop off abandoned abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> at her house
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and she used to work for a veterinarian veterinarian so she would spay uh neuter them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		give them all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX> and we saw an ad saying it was free so we went down there and picked it up and it's been an excellent dog but this is my first <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> i've i've had
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we got it because well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> stays here at home alone while i go to work so that's mostly why we got it to keep her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> while i'm away at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so that is that kind of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		um yeah right now it it is it's kind of good training i mean we've been trying for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but right now we haven't had any but
 	
 	
 		you feel like
 		
 
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		it's pretty good training i think i mean it it keeps us on our toes
 	
 	
 		have have you had dogs before
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> has um we didn't do a lot with them um i never felt it like it was mine or anything you couldn't do anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i mean it's a bit more responsibility
 		when it's yours and not your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well i just um  we've you know when i was growing up i had we always had a dog
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		and we had mostly well not not mutts but mixes you know like one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or two mix
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and those dogs always seem to be the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's what we found ours is uh like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockapoo i</ENAMEX> think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cocker Spaniel</ENAMEX> and half <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poodle</ENAMEX> but it's a really good dog
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know they seem to be i mean listen better or something is your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> a purebred
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no no it's just uh
 		an accident  from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> down the street their their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and just end up with some kittens and
 	
 	
 		would you ever want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in the family
 	
 	
 		um we i would we um
 		we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that was a um
 		mix between a an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> Malamute and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Labrador</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  i should say a pup and he was just too big for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when we got him and we
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		when we moved into our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that was the first thing we wanted to get was uh you know was a pet and and it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that we gotten
 		he was just he was just too big um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> couldn't handle him and i was still going to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was working and i was working and so we just didn't have time to really train him so he was kind of just there you know he's too big for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to handle so he was just tied up to a post
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so we gave him to uh i don't know if you've there's a place out here on it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shorties Lane</ENAMEX> out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harrisville</ENAMEX> and they have um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess it's kind of an animal shelter but he just takes a few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in and some he destroys and some he keeps
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we took him up there and he ended up keeping him
 		um
 		because he's had him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven years</TIMEX> we we've
 		saw him just a oh i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> and uh i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that sure looks like that pup we gave away and so we asked him about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and he said yeah he's been the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> i've ever had in my life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		just goes everywhere with him i he would've been a great great dog
 	
 	
 		they just need a lot of time
 		
 		
 	