
 
     		
 	
 		okay i guess it took so i guess recording has started now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		so have you ever served on a jury
 	
 	
 		i served i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and served on a court martial uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> a couple of times which is very similar to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> a lot of the same rules apply have you ever served on one
 	
 	
 		yeah i finally served on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one last year</TIMEX> i've um been voting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and i couldn't figure out why i hadn't been called yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i finally was so  it was an interesting experience i was kind of boring
 	
 	
 		was it civil or criminal
 	
 	
 		uh it was uh
 	
 	
 		a grand jury or something
 	
 	
 		uh it was uh
 		well let's see it was municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> so it was a combination of uh and i was in the pool for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so it was a combination of criminal and civil and they had uh well most of the time we we spent sitting around in the jury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and getting to know the other potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was always we was exciting when we got called to to to go because then we thought we might be able to do something else besides uh just sit in the jury room
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX> did did the judge uh hand down sentences or did you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> do that
 	
 	
 		uh yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> did uh i uh i had a hard time getting seated on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i kept getting uh
 		i'd be questioned uh for impaneling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and they kept uh dismissing me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		course they don't have to give a reason but it's just whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> or the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> feels like you know they want to get the best uh mix for their case so they ask all kinds of wild questions
 	
 	
 		no
 		that
 		that's a science in itself
 	
 	
 		yeah well i kept getting called up for drunk driving uh
 		questions and i think part of it was they didn't uh
 		they didn't like the fact that i don't drink any more
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i see because you'd probably be uh too puritanical and to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that was probably it although in my case i might have been more uh sympathetic with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who got caught i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh were were the uh sentences that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> handed out what you thought to be fair or would if you were deciding do you think that they would have been different
 	
 	
 		well i was never there never there for any sentencing uh i finally got impaneled on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case uh on my next to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> and uh we got into the uh jury room to uh
 		decide the case and there was one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> who announced to everybody that he didn't need to deliberate because he'd already decided that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was uh not guilty and he would never vote for guilty
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so uh they appointed me jury jury <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreman</ENAMEX> and i uh didn't think that uh going in without deliberating
 		allowed us to reach a verdict so i told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> that we weren't were unable unable to reach a verdict because we couldn't get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to deliberate so the whole thing had to be tried over again
 	
 	
 		um
 		wow i bet that made him happy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it was uh it was funny
 		the uh i just i i don't know i uh
 		i didn't uh
 		uh i didn't like not being able to deliberate i uh i i wanted to vote guilty for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were kind of mixed
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had to go through the whole thing all over again cost him a lot of money i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> was it a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> or twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> jury
 	
 	
 		uh it must have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's kind of curious to me i didn't realize until the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX> trial uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> that they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> i thought that they you know it was always twelve twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> tried and true so to speak
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but uh apparently for some some crimes it's permissible to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sit in judgment
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i know on a getting to this unanimous thing whether you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> should be unanimous or not or not in a court martial case it doesn't require the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to be unanimous it's simple a simple majority you know rules
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well let's see is it on uh capital crimes that they have to be unanimous and
 	
 	
 		a probably on capital i don't know we weren't we  the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that i were on had to do with drugs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we were uh unanimous in acquitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> even though we in our in our uh gut felt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were both guilty just because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> because of various things
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> really failed to prove its case and you know being fair to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't prove its case no matter how you feel you have to go by what's offered as proof and we had to acquit him in both cases
 	
 	
 		uh too it was too circumstantial
 	
 	
 		uh yeah it was yeah in some of the critical things like the off special investigations at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time in one of the cases had videotaped this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but something happened to the camera and the tape and
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		all they could do was testify about
 		
 		
 	