
 
     		
 	
 		well do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their twenties now</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		child care is something that i i no longer fortunately have to take care of but it is something that was hard
 		at the time just finding finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitters</ENAMEX> i
 		did not work though so i didn't have to uh
 		have to worry about you know
 		all day during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> which i think is a real problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah i agree uh
 		cause  i suppose when when i do start having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh
 		i'd like to stay home for a while but uh
 		you know eventually i'd i might have to put them in day care to work
 		i and i think it's hard to find um good day care because just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night um</TIMEX> on the news in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> um
 		they're closing down a day care because um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who owns um slapped a child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um she had a lot of um
 		like um
 		um what did she have um like
 		tickets against her um saying that the she didn't have proper food um prepared for them
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		and that it was just dirty and
 		and she didn't take very good care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you know you don't want to send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to place like that
 	
 	
 		no it's really scary and there does seem to be more and more of that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing it
 		instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> and aunts and you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that kind of thing where where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing it for money
 		and trying to make ends meet then it's it it becomes an entirely different thing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we keep reading about all these different things that go on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with criminal records etcetera i think it would be very frightening
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> but not many of them do
 	
 	
 		right or you have to um
 		it's pretty expensive  i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the college i go to they have uh child care
 		um there but you still have to pay
 		you know it doesn't come with them
 	
 	
 		do you know how much it is
 	
 	
 		no i don't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but that's what i've heard is that that you've got to earn an awful lot i mean you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a lot of times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s money basically covers what you have to pay out so that doesn't help
 	
 	
 		right it's like uh uh if you do work  most of the money goes back into taking care of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you might as well stay home if you're married
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's right well i i and and uh and then there's the question of you know if
 		what what to look for what's what's going to be uh what's going to be
 		a good place and uh do they
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		do they turn out as well as the ones where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> stays <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that's that's a really difficult issue i know
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've heard a lot of things about that too um
 		with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say  it's not healthy for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to be in day care
 		and you know other's say it is so i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you you haven't decided yet huh
 	
 	
 		uh no
 	
 	
 		no i think it's going to be hard i feel like i was i was lucky to get to be at home and
 		there were a lot of times that it was boring and it and it certainly isn't true is true that didn't
 		didn't set me up for a career but at the same time uh
 		it felt good to be there when they got home from school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		those were the stories that
 		that that i got to hear it was even hard to get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> to
 		get to hear them you know they would come home and they'd say all this and then
 		later on you say well tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> about you know and they go oh i already told you you know it all gone kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh and that parts good and you get to see them as they progress etcetera
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but at the same time if you don't have enough money or if you are trying to build a career
 		you know then you have to give everything up just to stay home and i think that's a real question
 	
 	
 		yeah that is it's a tough decision
 	
 	
 		and uh do you know uh
 		you say they have it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is it for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> or for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or for both
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um  i think it's
 		for for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know if it would it's it makes sense to have it for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		i'm not really sure  i haven't looked into  it i don't need it
 	
 	
 		well what about you and your own background did did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> stay home or did did they work or
 	
 	
 		um yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> stayed home um she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 		she stayed home with all of us until i got into about kindergarten and then she went um back to work after
 	
 	
 		and so you so you were in school
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and when you came home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was there some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">there or</ENAMEX> was uh what happened
 		i mean did she get off when you got home or was there some one taking care of you like an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		do you remember
 	
 	
 		for a while she was there
 		um when i got home but then um and she started working later until like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and i would come home <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and i and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> were all older than me so
 	
 	
 		so you had there was some one there to take care of you yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum yeah there was already somebody home
 	
 	
 		yeah cause i think that's another
 		
 		
 	