
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i don't know how you feel about drug testing but i'm dead set against it
 	
 	
 		well so we can have a conversation on on agreeing with one another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> right because we keep working to see if we can find any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who will help us
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		change the the trend that we have seem to have of interfering with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s personal life
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah um i think about the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> that are out there that are you know anti antiwar on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or VIV war on rights is uh pretty much your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> which
 		um i personally have some doubts as to whether any of them can get elected elected
 	
 	
 		well that's always a problem i have to admit that that back when uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> governorship
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		race was going on that was the one thing that made me really pleased with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX> is that she refused to get involved in discussing that whole issue
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well it just i mean really seems the ridiculous because um
 		the um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S Department of Labor</ENAMEX> whatever i'm not sure might be a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> requires um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to post this poster that has like minimum wage laws and a bunch of other laws and one of things it posts is
 		um on the illegality illegality of um lie detector tests and um you know i feel that lie detector tests are
 	
 	
 		for self decrimi self incrimination kind of thing yeah
 	
 	
 		well it means that that that there are limits there are there are definite government limits to you know how an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> can use lie detectors on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and i think that
 		oh i mean i don't i i agree that the lie detectors are inappropriate but i think you know that it's hard to justify being i don't understand how our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can can encourage drug testing and discourage lie detector tests because they seem like they're testing the same sort of nebulous
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah because the the tests are equally unreliable and
 	
 	
 		character
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		personally i don't even think it's a question of whether they're reliable or not i mean it doesn't matter how reliable they are then i think that it's inappropriate you know actually i can almost understand it more for somebody who's
 		getting ready to hire someone than i can allowing them to spot test or random test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		currently employed because i think that current employment you know continuation of employment should be based on performance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and and you know i i agree with with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know claim instead of having random drug tests for continuing employment have um motor impairment tests um because you know the they they would not be any more priced they would they would
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		be similarly priced um and you know if some if some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> goes to work and he had a had a fight with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before
 		and you know he has that on his mind and isn't gonna be able to function properly you know i i just as you know i'd i'd almost as much you know have as much uh fear of him driving the bus i'm riding than
 	
 	
 		or maybe more well you know if you stop and think about it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah or maybe more yeah  i'll show her
 	
 	
 		stop and think about it you can get awfully hostile and decide to to take care of the whole world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> or something yeah well you're absolutely right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum and also and also on the question of you know just getting employment i'm you know i'm i'm a senior in college and i'm applying for jobs and i know i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are doing it also and i know some of some of which that do indulge in certain um
 	
 	
 		you're absolutely right uh
 	
 	
 		non uh sanctioned um hobbies and their basic attitude toward drug testing is is just um moving away moving away from
 		you know the relatively harmless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> like marijuana which uh you know lingers for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about thirty five days</TIMEX> to things like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX> which you know one they don't test for well LSD they don't test for and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> which only stays in your system for about a week
 		and i used to snort i just you know wonder what effect this is having you know
 	
 	
 		uh it certainly sounds that if if that's what college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are doing that that's anti productive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i and i mean that's you know that's entirely anecdotal evidence i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple people</ENAMEX> you know that have moved in the direction but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just you know wonder you know overall what the trend is
 	
 	
 		well that of course there's really there's really no way to know uh it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just you know unfortunately i've i've talked with a um
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> recently about that because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s in a job situation that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		makes him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		subject to this sort of thing and it makes him extremely unhappy with his work place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know not that he does it not that he's ever done it you know i mean he's he's one of the straightest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know which is it and it has nothing to do with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know with any of the rest of it he doesn't like the feeling of loss of control so he doesn't
 	
 	
 		yeah and just the feeling that you know you the there there's
 	
 	
 		so he yeah so he wouldn't do it but on the other hand he also doesn't like the sense of loss of control of his personal life
 		
 		
 	