
 
     		
 	
 		uh well it's nice to talk with you um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh i guess i'll go ahead and start off with uh i think that there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things that could be done that are procedural to  uh
 		to help the budget the first i believe in would be to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a line item veto um
 	
 	
 		i agree with that
 	
 	
 		uh i think that a lot of times the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of congress
 		uh when they're faced with uh the possibility of having to to cut jobs in their district by because of shutting down a federal project or something just don't have the
 		the willpower on their own to uh
 		to make the tough decisions and sometimes it would be best to give that over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who who has overall responsibility for the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and can uh
 		i guess be a little bit more insulated from from uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> district
 	
 	
 		local politics yeah
 		well also too often too the uh individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> has the uh especially if they are on on uh some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> that put these budgets together
 		uh have the opportunity to slide things in that normally should not have gone in at all and the line yeah and the line item uh veto would be ideal for that i mean to
 	
 	
 		yeah that's exactly right
 		
 
 		yeah one of the the uh there's a bill pending before congress which i'm trying to remember what it's called it's something like the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buster</ENAMEX> bill that um if approved would make it uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh uh you wouldn't be able to um
 		put in uh new projects and things in a conference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> or at anytime where they weren't reviewed by the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that has responsibility for that
 		and that's like what you were talking about where they slip things in at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the conference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> is really the worst place for that to happen
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because no one
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> has uh it doesn't go back into the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> for review after the conference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> it just goes back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">senate</ENAMEX> for a final up or down vote on the whole thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		there's another idea uh uh another uh way where the budget could uh probably benefit and this has to do of course uh it has to do with federal projects
 		too often uh those are uh not there's no uh accountability once the uh projects are awarded to make sure that the quality is done and they end up getting stuck with
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> of overlay
 		or if contracts are put out uh no one uh is responsible or it does does not seem to be
 		for following up that if it goes over budget it it well you know it's set up laissez faire attitude well that's to be expected we just sort of built it in well that shouldn't happen that way
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		and i think i think if there was more attention paid to uh what's being uh spent and more accountability that would help enormous enormously too are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how who or how that would come about i'm not uh sure but that's an an an area that i think needs to be uh looked at
 	
 	
 		yeah it it really sometimes seems that there is there's nobody out there uh watching out for uh for we the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and making sure that the money is spent wisely uh
 		and i don't know that just sort of seems to be unfortunately part of the just how the system uh operates now uh we
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gee</ENAMEX> is there anything specific that you think uh uh in the way of federal programs or whatever that would be eliminated to try to cut federal spending
 	
 	
 		well i think uh there could be a lot of consolidation of programs
 		uh looking at of course there they have been a lot of talk to begin with but looking at and the  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s a big uh
 		area that uh has taken a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX> recently but i i do not see the point of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different services
 		uh i do not see why they could not have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> military service
 	
 	
 		and just eliminate all that high level bureaucracy
 	
 	
 		that's right because a lot of the monies are spent uh with insiding within those departments
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about bringing home all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX> and letting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> defend themselves
 	
 	
 		uh
 		basically i'm in i'm in agreement with that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i would think that there probably needs to be a uh monitor or not a monitor uh
 		or courtesy you know yeah a presence but not a
 	
 	
 		well we'll always have a presence there but we don't we don't need to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> overseas
 	
 	
 		no well witness witness the the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> too even with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> all over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> uh it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> to gear up
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and so what was the point of having them to begin with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah another area that's that i really think ought to be cut is is direct uh foreign aid
 		
 		
 	