
 
     		
 	
 		uh i get most of my news uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> really i read the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Chronicle</ENAMEX> and sometimes i'll read uh like the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Times</ENAMEX> i don't subscribe to either but sometimes i get a hold of copies of it um how about you do you you mostly get news from TV or newspaper
 	
 	
 		yeah i actually get most of my news coverage off uh computer networks
 		however i do also watch television news uh usually in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> once a day and i read the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> most everyday
 	
 	
 		oh uh that's interesting you said computer networks um what uh what sort i'm fairly knowledgeable about oh okay that's interesting
 	
 	
 		uh well well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> for example have a has a uh a news wire and it's uh it's picked up and actually available um at my office
 		so it's no fee subscription i'm uh very easy to to read at my leisure and um it's sorted by category for example so i can read certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> or topics
 	
 	
 		oh is
 		is it is it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> news wire or is it uh something that's that's a little bit different from that
 	
 	
 		well it's similar to that but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> which is um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>'s news wire
 	
 	
 		uh okay so that that that's interesting okay yeah i've had i had access in the past to uh  uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> news wire and i found that was that was pretty a pretty good way to get news
 		um i've never uh used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> news wire
 		but uh yeah it uh do you do you get any uh do you read any news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> or anything like that for sort of like a broader like more long term analytical sort of approach
 	
 	
 		um well actually not uh i do uh follow um
 		uh
 		uh i don't know how to how to describe it um
 		so it's a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> which which talks about issues that are relevant to me in a more broad sense it's a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>  but uh but not um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but not like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> or uh or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Week</ENAMEX> or or or one of those kinds of things i i'd like to say that however um that i'm overwhelmingly disappointed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> in general except for the raw news wires
 	
 	
 		uh interesting in what way in like in sort of like uh a quality a quality or sort of the orientation in terms of like view point or the way the news is presented or whatever
 	
 	
 		um i i think that it i think it has to do with  uh
 		i personally think  i i have a problem with their viewpoint and i personally think that uh  that there's a strong bias
 	
 	
 		go you well you won't offend me so go ahead and say
 	
 	
 		there's a strong there's a strong bias in the media
 	
 	
 		yeah like liberal a liberal type of bias
 	
 	
 		yeah absolutely after after all who who who writes are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who are trained to write and they're that's a liberal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh a liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> at least from academia and uh the other thing that i always notice is that whenever they write about something that i'm
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in i find their descriptions to be
 		wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they generally make mistake on anything technical at least but
 	
 	
 		and
 		it
 		that's right well even if it's not technical if it's um social thing or or whatever it doesn't matter if i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in it they usually make mistakes which leads me to believe that the things i'm not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in that they're telling me lies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah do you by mistakes do you do you mean just like honest mistakes or do you think they're deliberate sorts of things
 	
 	
 		i i think both uh by deliberate um  i mean mistakes mistakes of omission or uh  or uh bias toward the particular viewpoint particular liberal view point that they have
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh uh well give an example uh you you we'll go out of the printing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> i know of cases where um for example in television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> where they'll show clippings from
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> event and describe another event but with the attempt to give you the impression that what they're talking about is the same thing that they're showing you
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		which is sort of like a deliberate bias um which is which is rather disturbing i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> does that
 	
 	
 		hm that's disturbing uh
 		i haven't really noticed them doing that but
 		whatever again i don't watch TV news that much now if i had access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> i would watch TV news more um i don't you know but i don't usually yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't have access either although i did at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and uh it was i did during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> and it was addictive
 	
 	
 		yeah did you did you think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> well the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> coverage would be kind of uh uh abnormality i just wonder i guess
 		i'd be curious to know what you thought as to as to how like say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> TV news compared to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> networks
 		um you know whether you thought it was more or less biased or whatever but i i guess you wouldn't  you probably if you just watched it during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> that probably wouldn't wouldn't tell you much
 	
 	
 		yeah well during that small sample i would say that everyone was just about just about the same except the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> who also had radio then television programming so if at a particular time you wanted to get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the latest and greatest news you could do that by um turning on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and you would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	