
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay should begin
 	
 	
 		okay all right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i can begin this um basically i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the the benefit program we have here is really quite good i'm i'm pretty pleased with it they cover uh just about everything vision dental medical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you name it and for me this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> job i've had where they've covered that much so i'm pretty satisfied myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um what's your situation
 	
 	
 		i i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		our benefits package isn't uh isn't quite as good in in some ways uh you know overall i'm satisfied with it we don't have the vision care we do have the health care and the uh and the medical or the dental
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		no i work in i'm in a on the professional administrative and technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and i effectively i run the telephone switch at uh at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see okay
 	
 	
 		uh so the uh the the benefits uh probably the main thing i like about the benefits is the uh
 		the uh very generous vacation time and sick time we get
 	
 	
 		oh no doubt
 	
 	
 		we get we get fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days a year</TIMEX> sick time and uh we get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty four days a year</TIMEX> right from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day one</TIMEX> when you start work you get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty four days a year</TIMEX> uh time off
 	
 	
 		right oh that's good yeah that's one of the things i guess i would change about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX> is uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i used to work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Research Institute</ENAMEX> and being a uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government organization</ENAMEX> you got quite a few holidays off
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but here you don't get that you maybe get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's really unless you unless you have some vacation time or some some sick leave or whatever um you kind of have to finagle your way around to get that time so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's that's kind of a drawback i think but uh i don't know what do you consider most important you think in terms of of the different benefits
 	
 	
 		well i think uh the the health care of course is an important in has to be the single most important benefit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the rates that we keep paying seem to keep increasing uh
 		you know i'm i'm a little disturbed about that but i think that's a national trend and i don't know that uh i don't know what the solution is to it it's bigger than just the benefits part
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i don't know if you saw on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> they uh they basically reviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s plan or The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> Plan toward uh nationalizing health care and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's kind of an interesting plan it's kind of cold though they've essentially made up a list of uh
 		oh all the different uh
 		medical medical maladies that you can have
 		and they basically made a cutoff <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six hundred and eighty seven</NUMEX> and below will not be covered by by uh subsidized health care and and the ones above would
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so it's kind of like drawing this line and and if you have it great if you don't you're kind of out of luck
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um it  was an interesting show
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i think you're right i think health care is probably the the most pressing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh the pressing one but i'll tell you i i i don't mind having dental you know sometimes dental costs can be
 		um
 		just about as expensive if not more and i know historically a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> i think carried dental as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rider</ENAMEX> along with the medical
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i'm not sure that's that's widely followed any more i'm not sure how how does uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Hampshire</ENAMEX> handle it
 	
 	
 		well we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different plans that we can subscribe to under dental uh depending and and the cost between them is very is very little i think it costs me something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> for the dental plan
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but it pays uh a substantial amount i mean the examinations and and uh checkups <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year or every six months</TIMEX> are free
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it it covers the bulk of the dental expenses
 	
 	
 		is that uh let me interrupt is that the same for both uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and and also staff and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is that generally across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> do you think or
 	
 	
 		uh yes it is the the benefits plan is different for operating for what we call operating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> which are
 		considered to be uh clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel accountants</ENAMEX> things like that as opposed to what they call the P <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> which i belong to
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and but the main i think the the health and all that and the dental is the same for everybody and the retirement plan but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the main difference is in the uh the way sick time is accrued and and vacation time is accrued
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh for the operating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> it's on a seniority it's uh you know based on how long they've worked there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh that determines how much uh vacation time they get
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm kind of interested because i'm actually that's the route i'd like to take when i finally get my degree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is to uh is to teach in university
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm a doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but um
 		yeah that's that's interesting that's one of the things i'd like to think about is in what kind of benefits they would uh they would cover and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> programs uh belong to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T I A A uh C R E F</ENAMEX> retirement fund
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		right and in the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Hampshire</ENAMEX> uh
 		
 		
 	