
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello Ann</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello Chuck</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>
 		i attended a conference here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah State University</ENAMEX> on recycling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i was kind of interested to hear because they had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and lots of different places
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		they
 		had basically decided that there is going to be a real problem here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a few years</TIMEX> on solid waste
 	
 	
 		um i didn't think that was a new revelation
 	
 	
 		well it's not too new
 	
 	
 		right
 		so what what is is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> recommending now
 	
 	
 		oh
 		they really didn't propose any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> actually they were
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was pretty negative about the things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was doing even though he was from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he had a lot of uh facts to to give and
 		things like how many solid waste <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> were being shut down and
 		and uh
 		uh one of the most interesting things that he was talking about was recycling of of news print and he was talking about um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX> and how they went and collected all this news print
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they could sell it for a while they were able to sell it for some amount per ton and now at this stage of the game where they have gotten into  recycling they've collected so much news print that they have to pay to have it hauled away
 	
 	
 		why that's a that's a common problem now that seems that has happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
 		and i try to recycle all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> that come to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and after a while i just quit taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> because i couldn't recycle it anymore
 		which isn't good for business on the other end either i suppose
 	
 	
 		yeah we're doing some here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cash Valley</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> here there's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've actually got a kind of a nice set up we've got a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> here that actually take uh recycled paper
 		and shred it and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> it with chemical treatment so that it's not
 		a fire hazard and make it into insulation
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they can actually use as much recycled paper as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> can get to them because they're actually buying it and shipping it in from outside
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		so one of the real keys it sounds like to getting recycling for uh paper or something like that to go is to
 		get some sort of business to actually want it once you've collected it
 	
 	
 		right there has to be a a reuse for it i mean that's why they recycle
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i think is the most interesting is with the recycled bottles and all that  uh the industry seems to be doing with the recycled polymers
 		uh everything from uh waste baskets to carpet to the no stick i mean the sticky slide rugs under the carpet and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they're even putting it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadways</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and they're making clothes now that are recycled
 		like the recycled plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Coke</ENAMEX> bottles and and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk cartons</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		and there's a paper presented at this conference from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>
 		and he was kind of hired to do a study by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was like environmental protection and the other one was
 		oh i can't remember what but the basic idea it was presented to him was
 		how can we maximize the amount of energy that we can get back from recycling and minimize the volume of stuff we are putting into our landfill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the solution that he came up with for plastics
 		and it was really quite amazing because he says well the best thing to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> is to burn them
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		he came to the conclusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> is actually one of the biggest problems in landfills cause it's
 		it's low weight but it's high volume so it takes up a lot of space
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and there's almost no energy there's very little energy value in actually doing a lot of the recycling but there's a lot of energy in it if you can burn it and use it to produce electricity
 		so his solution was to burn plastic collect it and burn it
 	
 	
 		huh
 		well it's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX> so that makes sense like a carbon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> of some sort but  what
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's more than even paper or something like that there's more energy in it per pound or whatever
 	
 	
 		what about emissions
 	
 	
 		well that was  he didn't deal with that he just said burn it he didn't talk about cleaning it up or anything like that so it's not very practical is it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay
 		no well that's interesting i bet that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> at the uh conference then
 	
 	
 		yeah well real interesting
 	
 	
 		did it change anything for you
 	
 	
 		um
 		not too much i'm
 		uh i got a bit actually
 		
 		
 	