
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Toby</ENAMEX> this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian White</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and our topic i guess <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> is on capital punishment and how we feel about that um
 		if you don't mind uh how do you feel about capital punishment
 	
 	
 		well my position in general is that i'm supportive of it but i'm not supportive of the way that it's currently administered
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um
 		it takes so long with uh the appeals process uh that it's uh uh simply impossible to say that it's that it's consistent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of justice uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if if the penalty could be executed swiftly and surely upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who deserved it when there was uh evidence uh beyond a
 		a reasonable doubt that they had committed a a crime worthy of it then i think it should be done
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and that way it can be a deterrent a deterrent
 	
 	
 		that's right but as it stands now it's not a deterrent we just had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> here in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> who has he's been on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventeen years</TIMEX> and just had his sentence overturned for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time uh on a technicality
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		everybody knows he did it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		this last technicality was simply because the language of the decision handed down by the jury uh explaining uh saying that he should get the death penalty was not precisely as it is stated in the statute that it should be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		and that was it i mean it was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a very</TIMEX> simple i mean they fully intended to give him the death penalty uh they had a unanimous decision but when they drafted the uh decision
 	
 	
 		the response yeah
 	
 	
 		uh  they did it wrong  and it was just a very minor
 		very minor uh mistake but it was enough for uh the state supreme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to say that the uh that the decision was invalid and that they had to empanel a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to consider the death penalty again
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		that kind of thing uh and and and the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> search and search for those kind of things just uh just disgusts me
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and with
 		uh with with it being that way
 		it ends up costing us so much money so much more to have the death penalty than to not have it that uh i'm almost inclined to say do away with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the the problem that i see is uh what do we have instead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		if someone gets life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> they are generally released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> if they behave well
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we have had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and commit uh another murder
 		uh
 		that just shouldn't be so but i say uh i could tolerate getting rid of the death penalty if we could have life without the possibility of parole
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right right i tend to agree with you uh i'm kind of uh torn between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> items however i i definitely believe believe in due process that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is found guilty
 		so that we're not ramrodding a a guilty verdict on them that it's uh up for review in uh the appeal process
 		however i tend to agree with you that well i don't tend to agree with i definitely agree with you that
 		there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are going to make sure that every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> is crossed every I is dotted and to make sure that everything is just right otherwise you know someone gets off on a technicality now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		not only in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> is that costing us
 		money and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> and wasting our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> and uh clogging up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> but also
 		when the  uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> the homicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> and so forth when they're researching when they are gathering the evidence they're they're bending over backwards uh
 		in typically what i believe is an open and shut case where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is guilty there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eyewitnesses</ENAMEX> they saw it happen they have testified what happened um
 	
 	
 		there's video tape of it
 	
 	
 		they
 		yeah exactly  exactly
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is as sound mind and and so forth he's he's not an idiot uh he wasn't acting i i don't know you know in that case
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we're we're spending money in the in the judicial system we're spending money in the law enforcement area trying to verify all this kind of information
 		and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>'s guilty i believe that if we have cash capital punishment that it should be executed swiftly
 		that it should uh be taken care of not after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven</TIMEX> levels of appeal but after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple</TIMEX> levels appeal of appeal
 		uh under certain certain circumstances
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those circumstances would be
 		
 		
 	