
 
     		
 	
 		so how do you feel about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um  you know i guess that it's pretty deep feelings uh  i just uh went back and rented uh the movie what is it <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Morning Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh  got that uh uh some insight there to to kind of help me put together  the feelings i really appreciated the the little uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw that as well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> class where the uh the uh fellow just wouldn't do anything you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s gouging gouging your eyes out what are you going to do  you know wait for him to finish me off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh it it was uh good to remember the uh that that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> philosophy
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well uh were you over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		that uh
 		no no i was kind of an in between uh finally drew a high draft number and you
 	
 	
 		i'm i was much too young i was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty seven</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um in a way both my well uh both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> were um draft age but neither of them wound up going over which i think they were very happy for
 	
 	
 		well i personally uh you know uh i just went in limbo i had a passport and was ready to go
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or um  out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or or join special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> either one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i i just didn't know  so uh
 	
 	
 		well um so well do you do you feel that it was worth what we did over there or
 	
 	
 		um yeah just a second
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you restrict access cause a lot of times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trying to cut them out okay
 		sure now  well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> um what was that again
 	
 	
 		um do you think i mean do you think our investment the investment in lives and money was worth it
 	
 	
 		no not not really
 	
 	
 		i totally agree with that
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		um well what what effects do you think it's had in our country
 	
 	
 		downside um  uh  well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Blythe</ENAMEX> says we should uh uh
 		yeah go into the grief that that's there and we're our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> have always avoided that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so it's pretty serious really uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of things that aren't being addressed
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well i think i think that you know that's pretty typical of the of the entire entire involvement over in that you know that nothing was really addressed it wasn't it wasn't you know it was never we we announced that we were going to war it was it was such a gradual
 		and subtle you know the um you know increasement of of force that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonkin</ENAMEX> uh resolution and was it a dolphin or a torpedo  things you remember that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i vaguely vaguely remember we um we had a we had a um spy ship torpedoed or something or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah only only it was foggy and  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> finally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said well they they weren't really sure whether it was a dolphin or a torpedo
 	
 	
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		isn't that something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		so um do you do you do you think that like our um  for example like in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this this past</TIMEX> war the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> war
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh that  you see it seemed to me that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was going going to extraordinary lengths to um
 		you know prepare the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for war yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hey Mark</ENAMEX> uh i've got to go um we'll um see you i guess <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our five minutes</TIMEX> are up according to me are they to you
 	
 	
 		okay
 		uh i wasn't really keeping count count but i guess that's good-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	