
 
     		
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Melissa Brigette Moore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		what are you doing
 	
 	
 		nothing
 	
 	
 		i'm just sitting here trying to
 		eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> before i go to a meeting
 	
 	
 		are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 	
 	
 		yeah what are you doing are you at the office
 	
 	
 		how funny  huh
 	
 	
 		where are you
 	
 	
 		i'm at home
 	
 	
 		are you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		cool
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know like listen to us we're like trying to volunteer
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay are you ready for me to push one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do we know what we're going to say
 	
 	
 		about crime
 	
 	
 		yeah okay i'll push one
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay so what do you think about crime in the big D
 	
 	
 		well
 		i'm worried about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>  because i just got a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		are you
 	
 	
 		so i'm worried about it
 		getting stolen or anything happening to it at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i don't know i think in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's a lot more scary just because it's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i mean in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> and stuff i know lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't lock their doors or you know leave their windows open at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> because it's so much smaller i mean it feels safer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i know that it happens here but it's not near like it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more trustworthy i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have reason to be i guess
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't it doesn't matter where i go i lock my doors
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i know lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that'll leave their doors open you know if you have to go get something like
 		get a book or something from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you can just walk right in
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they're always unlocked or something and
 	
 	
 		gee i don't think i'd ever do that if i wasn't at home
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		see i know and there're only like certain
 		you know neighborhoods up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> that are that you wouldn't leave your doors unlocked you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but besides that i don't know it's fairly safe i think
 	
 	
 		God even up in like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Highland Park</ENAMEX> i don't even think i'd leave it open seems like that'd where they'd really go for the big houses
 	
 	
 		really
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> can be pretty bad though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it depend on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know though because i think that way of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> and then uh
 		like i was talking to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that lives way out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and she was saying how bad it is out there and i would think it would be less
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i would thinking it wouldn't be as bad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i guess it just depends because there're certain part of the cities too there's no way i would ever i wouldn't even leave my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> alone in south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see i know i know that's scary
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		um
 	
 	
 		i don't know though but i still think like out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> when she said that i was like what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was like no way and she goes yeah she goes you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get broken into a lot because they you know it's real easy to get away with there you know no one can see them carrying out the stuff if no one lives nearby
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was like well that's true but besides that
 		i don't know and i think it's just getting worse
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's what scares me about living out in uh like off in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i used to live out in the country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that kind of scares me because i think
 		you know you always hear about all those murders and it's weird to think about but it happens  and that's the scary part
 	
 	
 		i know
 		see i know
 	
 	
 		and i don't like living out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i like living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where i'm close to there might be more crime or as they say but it just makes me feel safer because i'm around someone
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		because you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and stuff at least you know
 	
 	
 		yeah if i scream someone's going to hear me
 	
 	
 		i know someone's got to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know that's scary though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it just keeps rising
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i can't imagine
 		i don't know what's after i've been here so long it's like i well you'd have to pay me to move back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i don't like now now that
 		i'm away from it and i can look back at how you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is and stuff yeah i don't like it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't like it at all really
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know i think it'd depend on
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i don't know where you live i know that's not right though i think that but i don't think that's really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't know i guess i'm sure there is
 		a bunch of thieving of thieving going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> it's just not around you or not that you know of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i don't know i mean uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of summers ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> behind us got robbed
 		and
 		you know we were everybody was looking out but ever since like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> after that nobody just even paid any attention any more
 	
 	
 		really see that's sad i would think like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> theft is a really big thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		wouldn't you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that or
 	
 	
 		especially here where we have so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know i know
 	
 	
 		everybody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> and we've all got cars
 	
 	
 		see i know
 		i don't know because that's
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i don't know if that is though that's what that 'd be my guess car theft for sure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i don't burgalies burgurlaries i can't say that burgalies i don't know i don't know if there'd be that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that would be just have like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that come in and burglarize and take like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TVs</ENAMEX> and stuff that they could sell real easy whereas someone like cleaning you out you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess that would depend on it too
 	
 	
 		yeah a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> he was gone all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> but he has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> here by himself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> got in and robbed him
 	
 	
 		no way
 	
 	
 		yeah he has this he has this like gorgeous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom set</ENAMEX> and that's the
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		
 		
 	