
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we're supposed to talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> crisis and should we be involved and uh what's it going to cost us in the long run
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		are you ready
 	
 	
 		i guess so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> crisis should we be there
 	
 	
 		oh dear that's a hard one that's really hard for me because
 		uh you know i really i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> and i think you know eventually you know he'll be of of drafting age and i think gosh do i want him to go and yet i'm proud to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and i know that we have a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would give anything to live in a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> anyway because we have so many wonderful things that they don't have and yet i don't know whether i'd be willing to give his life for for this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and yet
 		and yet i know that i that and i i when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it was always the tired the tired excuse that we went to war to save us against communism
 		but i'm not sure that that that's the reason anymore
 		i mean not sure that communism is is as strong as it once was and i'm not sure that that that's the reason why we're like we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> supposedly so
 	
 	
 		well you realize why we were
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> why we invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> why we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> why we attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> and we we're why we are still fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well with the
 		well it's because of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		no i really believe it's because
 		i think it has something to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> don't get me wrong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam is Saddam</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">madman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes i agree with that
 	
 	
 		anyone that would
 		use chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to fight his own people
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well yeah he's uh a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> very definitely
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		obviously that has something to do with it
 	
 	
 		oh sure sure
 	
 	
 		and
 		and if you know i can see that
 		he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> was the non aggressor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudis</ENAMEX> are our allies
 		we have several treaties and several alliances
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudis</ENAMEX> that range back for probably forty years
 	
 	
 		yeah many years
 	
 	
 		you know they've been our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> through thick and thin
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they were at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> border
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and ready to storm into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
 		shouldn't we try and help our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		certainly but what at at what cost you know that's the uh the thing it came out it came out wonderfully supposedly i mean everything is and we won
 	
 	
 		what did we lose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> lives
 	
 	
 		yeah and that that's wonderful but what if if that wasn't the case what if we would have lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would that would it have been too much of a price to pay for that i don't know see and i think there are a lot of things that we don't know but
 	
 	
 		oh of course our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars thieves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
 		oh sure well and there's a lot that we
 	
 	
 		and that's our own fault because we elected them
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's true but i think there's a lot that we the public doesn't need to know i think there's some things we shouldn't know just for national national security sake
 		and i you know i think if we did know i think there would be a lot more chaos than there is because i don't i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could handle it so i think there are things that we should not know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> shouldn't know but i also agree that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		you know
 		it's uh
 		i went on jury duty here not long back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> they were asking him if if you could believe a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s reputation was so tainted that he couldn't be believed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> being selected
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snickered</ENAMEX> and couldn't keep his head up you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> said well can you share it with us what you what you find so funny he says well i already told you my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> a lawyer
 		he said that when he graduated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after his bar examine there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he told him
 		dad you know how to tell when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> lying to you his lips are moving
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh  oh
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are lawyers
 	
 	
 		oh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> background yeah have a law background you're right
 	
 	
 		so by definition all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are liars
 		the fact that they take our money
 		and don't do what we think is right makes them thieves
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true  yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		so what's it going to cost us in the long run there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>
 		are we going to lose more lives there
 	
 	
 		see and i don't know i don't know i can't tell the future that's what scares me so much about it i mean i thought the war was going to go on and on i really was surprised when it ended so quickly and
 	
 	
 		well we hit them
 		with more
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX>
 		than we used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years the last three years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know yeah
 	
 	
 		and whenever
 		you strike on open terrain with that sheer volume
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's
 		nothing they can do about it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it's not like we
 		threw
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> aircraft over there all by ourselves and said this is wrong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we were there the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> were there the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> were there this is with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> backing
 	
 	
 		um right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and to some level even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was behind us
 	
 	
 		um-hum right they were
 	
 	
 		so
 		honestly if
 		there is was
 		a well perceived war world wide this was it
 	
 	
 		oh sure sure
 	
 	
 		but
 		what i can't understand is
 		then many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> youth
 		didn't fight wouldn't fight
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's okay for us to go expend our
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		lives like so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the desert
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's not their job to fight for their own land
 	
 	
 		yeah that is very  it's very strange uh and yet you know see that's another thing that that's difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> their culture is so much different than ours that
 		you know i've heard from many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we could not even begin begin to understand how they feel about things because their values and their perceptions are so much different than ours
 		and um they just don't think the same way we do their culture is completely different and almost opposite
 	
 	
 		and really from all i can indicate from all indications the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
 		beliefs if you will
 		are more similar to our own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwaitis</ENAMEX> aren't even helping rebuild their own country
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX>
 		young
 		won't rebuild anything they won't work
 	
 	
 		huh i didn't realize that
 	
 	
 		yeah it was on the news last night
 	
 	
 		oh my word
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Army</ENAMEX> is doing it all
 	
 	
 		hum yeah  see and that's another question you have to ask is this our job is are we should we still be there even you know
 		i don't know the answers to that those questions i think they're tough and i think you know it's i don't know that anybody knows the answers i think they know what they believe but i'm not sure they really are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent sure
 	
 	
 		well they talked to uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> yesterday
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and her biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> in life was
 		that she couldn't get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're kidding that's unreal
 	
 	
 		and do you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 		no and don't plan on having one either ever so
 	
 	
 		well i wouldn't mind having one
 	
 	
 		oh i'd love to have one but you know
 	
 	
 		but you know i'd like to uh make sure that i have a job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> first
 	
 	
 		sure sure that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it it astound you realize that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> gives every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man woman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> money
 	
 	
 		uh no i wasn't i didn't wasn't aware of that no
 	
 	
 		for nothing
 	
 	
 		for doing nothing yeah
 	
 	
 		for nothing for for for doing nothing for sitting on there keisters
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh that ought to give their programming trouble shouldn't it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		they do nothing they hand them money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> and they're part of
 		
 		
 	