
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		are do you work outside the home
 	
 	
 		uh yes i do full time
 	
 	
 		and do you have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		i uh i also work outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> full time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i do have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		it makes it does make it very difficult i think that um our culture has um
 		broadened quite a bit so that it is very acceptable for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to do so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		do you think it's gotten easier on you personally you know as far as
 		at work
 		uh you know other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how you interact it's gotten easier on you
 	
 	
 		um well yeah yeah but i didn't i
 		i never found it difficult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> my i'm i'm in the medical field and so i don't i i'm not in a field that is typically a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s field i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so i i haven't um  oh breached anybody's confidence on i haven't tried in you know going into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah right yeah yeah i'm an engineer
 	
 	
 		what is typically a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s role are you in a are you in a job that
 	
 	
 		and so  so i have i have uh uh problem even when i was going through school
 	
 	
 		yes you are you're challenged frequently
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i found it to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s world and i got a lot of static from that
 	
 	
 		yeah it it
 	
 	
 		my and it my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first few years</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i found it to really be hard
 		but now that i've been there for a while it's it's kind of a deal you have to prove yourself
 		and after i've been there for a while now you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i'm just kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i'm um you know respected and and and i do the same things they do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm sure not necessarily sure i get the pay the same pay but i'm pretty sure i do and
 		and i feel a lot better about it i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that had just turned forty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and she tells me horror stories
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure
 	
 	
 		of what it use to be like you know you know always getting um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">belligerent</ENAMEX> comments like you ought to be at home having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> instead of doing these blueprints and things like that things that would just make her cry at work
 		but she couldn't cry in front of them because they'd do it more
 		you know so she's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		she you know builds me up and says be a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and and present yourself professionally and
 		you know builds my confidence quite a bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's why i ask you that if if you thought maybe times his changed made it easier on you at at work
 	
 	
 		uh  for me personally i don't think that um
 		my sex really has much to do with um
 		with limiting me as a matter of fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um employer</ENAMEX> wanted a female for my position
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do have trouble um i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician assistant</ENAMEX> which is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		somewhere between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and a doctor
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i um frequently see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> seeing them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it is a it's not uncommon that the um
 		it's it's typically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> males
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		typically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> do not want me to be their medical you know provider their their medical care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> that day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they um they really have a problem with it and they'll and they will almost always ask me to see the doctor
 	
 	
 		that is so strange
 	
 	
 		well  not not when you think of their culture though
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and their culture i i'm talking about the ones who came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> not the ones that were reared in the states
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'm talking primarily about um you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are over here on work thesis
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that sort of thing but their culture is still very much thought
 		not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s thing and i'm a blonde and and and they are just like you know who is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> why is she in here telling me anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 		this little young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so they um
 		so that's that's that's the only place i've ever even had a problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		regarding my sex sometimes my size is one limitation because i assist in surgery too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes i wish i were strong as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but um or the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well let me ask you this how have um did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> set you back or kind of went off track a little while
 		you know this is this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s an issue i'm on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s subcommittee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s initiative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> and we were discussing this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> matter of fact
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have taken career kind of jobs
 		you know and and  decided to go in and have one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and then got back on track
 		and they didn't see that as a setback but
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't
 		i don't see how i can ever get back on track i don't see that as being a possibility i will i will never work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		in other words if you wouldn't of had
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy hour weeks</TIMEX> again
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's what they were saying before they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they were working like crazy people
 	
 	
 		i mean i don't i
 		yeah seventy hour <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks every week</TIMEX> i mean it was nothing i mean that was what i did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> and but i don't not only
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i can't any longer my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works a full time job outside the home too
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and not only i mean i i physically cannot do it because of day care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't want to the desire is not there
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i am not someone i i i didn't i didn't think i had the desire to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> even
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		and yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">childre n</ENAMEX> had transformed me and and and the mothering has transformed me to the point
 		i don't  if if something happened and i no longer had a job
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i'd be okay
 	
 	
 		i don't even think i would go interview again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i you know it's it's i mean i love what i do but i love my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so much more
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there's
 		there is a guilt that goes along with leaving them to in the hands of other people
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		that aren't you
 	
 	
 		and a fear
 	
 	
 		there's a fear there too i'm not really afraid of what might be happening happening to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in an in an abuse issue but i'm afraid of what they're missing i'm afraid of what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		of of what's not being uh you know uh
 		discussed discussed with them or what or what opportunities are missed
 		that i could fill in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that fear's there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah i i hear that uh there's all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> i'm
 		i'm one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>  and
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> a lot of them have uh small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one or or two</TIMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> because we're all fairly young and
 		and i hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> saying that a lot
 		you know and i think that is a culture change that you know their lives have changed since they had children
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they don't want to work that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty hours</TIMEX> anymore they want to hurry up and get home you know i can't wait to get home so i can play with my son
 	
 	
 		right see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so and they have the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> as not necessary an abuse
 		guilt but you know thinking well you know if i i could spend more time then they could learn so much more
 		you know
 	
 	
 		just just learn about me i mean learn what i want them to be learn the things that are truly important to me because if you just tell them it doesn't count
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		um-hum right
 	
 	
 		it's what they see routinely that they remember
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's that they see routinely that you deal with the you know with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> in a in a nice manner
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that they see routinely that you are
 		um you know doing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> study or prayer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or whatever you are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they need to see that instead of you just telling them well after you go to bed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i
 		uh you know stuff envelopes envelopes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crippled Children's Association</ENAMEX> you know that doesn't count they need to see what it is you spend your time and your energy doing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		in order to get part of you otherwise they grow up with parts of their child care or there care givers
 	
 	
 		that's right their nannies and you know right day cares that's really interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah it's it's it's a tough thing i don't if you if you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i was going to say if uh when i get to that point i'm sure i'll know it i see it from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> like i say the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are experiencing this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know a lot of them one of them just had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> and he has totally changed
 		from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this seventy hour</TIMEX> work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to somebody that goes God i'm ready get out of here you know i need to go to day care
 	
 	
 		it's incredible
 		it's
 	
 	
 		and he routinely calls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 		you know like can i talk to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> you know and and uh
 	
 	
 		it is the most life changing experience i have ever ever i mean i i had no idea i never even wanted children
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh then we were blessed with one in an expected fashion and i mean i just i i can't believe it i mean i i can't believe this is me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and neither can anybody else
 		you know i mean but it's just phenomenal
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that'll
 	
 	
 		it is absolutely phenomenal
 	
 	
 		that'll me too and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> they'll go oh my God you've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are you fixing to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> they won't believe it they'll pass
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	