
 
     		
 	
 		well i'm having a hard time remembering  the last movie i saw
 	
 	
 		well i was too  i i thought i saw a lot of movies but i guess i i haven't seen any really recently
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess uh i can remember seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> that was uh well that's uh that's an excellent film i i highly i highly recommend that in fact i guess they're bringing that back out
 	
 	
 		well i haven't seen that
 		that's what everybody says
 		oh are they
 	
 	
 		and uh they're adding fifty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to it or something like that
 	
 	
 		see that's why i don't want to go see it because it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> just to start of it i can't
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		i can't sit through a movie that long
 	
 	
 		so it's going to be almost <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> before it's over
 	
 	
 		i know i don't think i'll see it
 	
 	
 		or beyond yeah beyond that uh
 	
 	
 		well i hear it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s movie anyway
 	
 	
 		oh i wouldn't say that no because i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i went and i think she enjoyed it even more than i did
 	
 	
 		really
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so uh unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> i guess the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> movie we'd seen before that was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> i i guess i'd have to admit that probably was more of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s movie than a
 	
 	
 		oh was it yeah
 	
 	
 		than a than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s movie
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of like you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steel Magnolia</ENAMEX> is to me was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s movie
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's what we we saw that and i have to agree with you i think that's more of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s movie than a than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s movie
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah uh i was trying to think of the last movie i saw oh i saw i saw Ghost that was good
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		oh okay yeah we saw that on video that's that's that's another thing i guess that uh it's kind of
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		kind of curbed uh us going out so much is that uh there was so many movies i didn't see when they came out beforehand that uh i know are coming out on video that you
 	
 	
 		yeah going out
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you look in the paper and you and you go well i can either see this or i can see this movie that i really wanted to see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> and didn't see
 	
 	
 		right
 		i want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> have you seen that
 	
 	
 		i haven't and and i
 	
 	
 		i hear it's excellent
 	
 	
 		i i hear it's excellent and it's probably something i'd i'd enjoy but i i heard that it was so uh kind of gruesome in scenes that that and that was the part i probably wouldn't like but i heard that uh the acting was was great and it was a really thrilling movie
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that in fact i read something in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX> i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who plays the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the psycho</TIMEX> or the villain that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		that uh he's getting letters from just all over you know the world and all that and and he suddenly become uh like a real screen idol or a uh
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like a a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> you know he thinks it's funny but i guess uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in particular think it's such a scary movie and that uh that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that they just identify with not identify with him but they they like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> i i wouldn't say like like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> but they're so fascinated by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that uh they write him letters and and say how much they liked him and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what it is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at work told me not to go see it by myself at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> or see it by myself at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>  so i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's probably that's probably a good idea unfortunately i think i i don't really enjoy movies with a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in them so uh
 	
 	
 		i don't either i myself i like romantic comedies myself but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i'll i'll go see a drama like uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Untouchables</ENAMEX> came out which is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> movie well this is going to be a rut isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		my gosh you're you must be a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of his
 	
 	
 		i just so happen i guess we just see those but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> actually talked me into going to see that and i didn't really want to go see it and it was you know it was kind of a a bloody movie but uh it was done in such a way that you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and all that i mean you are not going to avoid that so wasn't as
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i
 	
 	
 		it wasn't like they spent you know long shots relishing every drop or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i guess the last movie i saw was at Scenes From the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bette Midler</ENAMEX> and i i guess you just have to be a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> fan which i'm not i think you either hate him or like him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we
 		we we did in fact i think that is the last movie that we saw was Scenes from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		and i thought i thought it was terrible
 	
 	
 		yeah so did we we thought it was really lousy and it
 	
 	
 		yeah i i like her but i really don't like him for some reason in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place trying to pass him off at age forty just almost was too much more than i could handle you know
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah
 		he he's not forty anymore that's for sure
 	
 	
 		Lord no he hasn't seen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> has he
 	
 	
 		plus uh
 		plus there's something about seeing those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> walking through a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> just like and nobody paying attention is just like no no and especially with him carrying a yellow surfboard that was just like
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		isn't that the truth
 	
 	
 		this this is real realistic and you know if i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bette Midler</ENAMEX> go by and he's still carrying a yellow surfboard i wouldn't notice him i wouldn't even see him
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		i believe i would too but and then the money they spent on that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that shrimp or or that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sushi</ENAMEX> or something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> i mean eleven <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> or something ended up spending nobody spends that kind of money i don't think
 	
 	
 		and
 		oh yeah it was just a
 		it was just a
 		
 
 		yeah and i i just can't believe uh that you could use up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> watching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> to store in a mall
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just uh in fact that was the funny part of it was sitting there and just seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> shots going you know i could go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Park</ENAMEX> or i could go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Collin Creek</ENAMEX> or something like that and see that so
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 
 		right
 		right that was a terrible
 	
 	
 		so uh it was just not really fun at all
 	
 	
 		no i came i had asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> to go with me and she decided to she had to fly so i thought i'll go see it by myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm glad i didn't ask her to waste her time now because
 	
 	
 		
 
 		or money
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't i mean that was a horrible movie i
 	
 	
 		and we went to an early show on that one so we didn't uh
 	
 	
 		in fact i think i went to one of the early shows i didn't have to spend a bunch of money on it i think i got in for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two seventy five</TIMEX> or something i would have hated to have spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven dollars</NUMEX> on that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh gee yeah tell the truth but that
 	
 	
 		but she usually plays some pretty cute movies like that one with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Nolte</ENAMEX> that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beverly Down</ENAMEX> and Out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> wasn't she in that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i didn't get to see that i didn't get to see that but uh but
 	
 	
 		she was cute in that and uh i think i hear she was good in Beaches i didn't see that
 	
 	
 		i didn't see that either that was something we'll probably rent a video on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		i want to see that movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh A Kiss Before</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss Before Dying</ENAMEX> or something like that i've just seen advertised but i guess i haven't kept up on the movies that are out right just coming out right now
 	
 	
 		you die before yeah something like that
 		i know i just see it advertise on TV and it really looks like it is going to be a
 		thriller a good thriller
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum that uh sounds sounds like you are pretty much split between romantic comedies and thrillers then
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i am i really don't like to see thrillers by myself but uh i will go see them i
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i guess i guess the only real movie that we we wanted to go see and haven't gone to see yet is is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Class Action</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Hackman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i want to see that that's another good one
 	
 	
 		because uh he's usually i hear he's good in it but that's i guess he's good in almost everything he does so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i know it i've never seen him in anything bad yet
 	
 	
 		and uh so we're we're looking for one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> to to see that
 	
 	
 		and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i used to i really did like was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Streisand</ENAMEX> and then i saw her in that movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nuts</ENAMEX> and that was a wasted don't waste your even at a dollar movie that one would have been bad oh
 	
 	
 		i didn't see that no
 		
 
 		that good i think that's what everyone said that it was a pretty lousy movie
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh it was horrible and i really did like her until that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but gosh not any more ooh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> she hasn't been in a movie well maybe that's why she hasn't been in a movie in a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's right i don't think she's made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> since then either as a matter of the fact that i know
 	
 	
 		yeah i i guess i guess i don't tend to even though it seems like we've been to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX>'s movies maybe that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s uh input more than i but uh but i guess i don't rely on anymore on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		star value i don't really go see movies because it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that looked like a bad movie just in the coming attractions and i said and i said boy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i know it how about did you see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen that i haven't was that good
 	
 	
 		oh that's good yeah i liked that that was a good movie
 	
 	
 		and  that i heard that uh and i don't particularly like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX> i guess the only movie that i that i liked that he was in was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentleman</ENAMEX> and even then you know that was kind of pushing it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh but i heard every even if you didn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX> you probably would've liked that movie
 	
 	
 		oh i'm a fan of his
 		yeah he is good i really i really did like him i'm a fan of his
 	
 	
 		uh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah he's uh he's okay in my book
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX> is cute too but i i didn't really know i hadn't heard of her too much until i saw this movie and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Tracy</ENAMEX> did you see that
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen that no no we didn't go see that
 	
 	
 		nah it was
 	
 	
 		i heard that was more of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s movie and uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wouldn't appreciate it because they they've never heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Tracy</ENAMEX> other than you know like i've heard of him all my life but
 	
 	
 		yeah when you when he was actually in the funny paper and
 	
 	
 		yeah but they don't know him except for uh probably uh the movie you know so i don't think they would appreciate it as much as as older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would because they you know grew up with him but i was kind of disappointed in it a little bit uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		that probably
 		yeah i i probably couldn't get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to go see that i think the last time i got to see her something like that was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> it took me a it took me a
 	
 	
 		yeah and i didn't like that you know why i didn't like that movie it was so dark i couldn't see
 	
 	
 		well that's true i think that was the feel that they they were after was everything was really dark and and and kind of foreboding and
 	
 	
 		i guess
 		and i don't like to have to strain my eyes and try to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on the screen that that was one i i watched on a video at home and i maybe that was it maybe
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that that might have been something because i think that i don't think that's movie that would have been as good on a on a small screen
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i mean you really it really had to be on a big screen i think especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicholson</ENAMEX> to come across because because i mean what he did was so corny
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know like it it's like they they spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX> setting up that line about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bats</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">belfry</ENAMEX> you know it's where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> is climbing up to save what's her name and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he's up there and it's like all these things are are falling on him and it's like they they work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all this time</TIMEX> just when he gets to the top that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joker</ENAMEX> can say something about well looks like we got bats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">belfry</ENAMEX> and it's like
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i think they've been pushing to try to get this joke in for a long time yeah i hear a i hear a second <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> movie is getting ready to come out too yeah i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny De Vito</ENAMEX>'s in it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		oh is it
 		oh now that would be good i like him oh did you see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roses</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess he's
 		yeah i no
 	
 	
 		i loved it but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i knew didn't like it but i thought i was funny
 	
 	
 		i i liked it till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a half hour</TIMEX> from the from the end it looked it looked like it was going to be a funny movie and and until about until it got to be almost too much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well now that was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movie i or the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movie in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages</TIMEX> that i have seen twice i went back to see it and when i saw it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time it wasn't as cute but it was i just roared through it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time and that's why i probably
 	
 	
 		you know when they were
 		really
 		yeah
 		it
 		i again i think <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first hour</TIMEX> was really everyone was laughing and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i were really enjoying it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i think it was when he finally drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> or something like that and she finally trying uh i mean it gets from from little things like throwing things at him and dropping things on him to to where she's actually
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		trying to kill him
 	
 	
 		trying to kill him and then i almost got real furious and and it was like a whole mood change right here and that whole chandelier scene at the end it was like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i k now it
 		oh i know it and i was so shocked at the ending i didn't think they would die
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i really didn't i was so shocked
 	
 	
 		and and and it was funny because we usually like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael uh Douglas</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Turner</ENAMEX> i think we've we've liked everything like uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX> yeah he plays
 		i have too
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagged</ENAMEX> Edge you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh yes that was good oh that was good
 	
 	
 		and and i and i didn't but i guess you know she i mean she she's seen a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Turner</ENAMEX> movies than i have and she  the only ones i ever saw were Romancing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> and and and those kind of movies but she likes them and
 	
 	
 		oh you didn't
 		that's a good one
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay
 		she's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she i was really disappointed i think we we were both disappointed in fact for some reason although it looked like it was going to b e funny
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah well i did i don't know maybe i got a warped sense of humor because i like i said i just roared through it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time and then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time when i saw it but it see it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month later</TIMEX> that i saw it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time maybe if i had waited longer and seen it a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 		
 	