
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so um you said you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but um you're interested in the topic
 	
 	
 		well yeah and um actually i'm very interested we are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are thinking very soon um about having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i think that i am just um
 		a little bit
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> brainwashed or whatever by just thinking that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are so wonderful and cute and i can't wait to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i don't see the real responsibility of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and an actually how dramatically
 		your life can change when you do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		do you have kids
 	
 	
 		yes yes i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who's now uh eighteen and he's a sophomore in college
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and it it does but i was very lucky in that i was um teaching at a university and so basically and lived within walking distance
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i was able when he was little just to um leave him with a neighbor in uh one of these carry cots
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then go up and teach a class and come back
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		because i could do my work at home and my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who were working on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s degrees and stuff would come to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i would meet with them there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it was really ideal and then later on um when he was gee maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and three i actually took him then i changed to a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but it was still within walking distance
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		and um he spent a lot of time in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> because i was uh department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um you know really didn't interfere because all his life he had sort of been used to there were quiet times
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so and that worked out great
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful how is it now i imagine you said he's a sophomore
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so this is is he living at home
 	
 	
 		yes he's commuting it's um about
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		gee he commutes forty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> a each way but he has to allow <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> going to school because it's too too chancy for him to miss classes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and so actually we don't i mean we still spend a lot of time together in the sense that we are always together for dinner and and
 		um then you know he's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> studying in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		and he also works and so um he usually calls me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at when he gets home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> i mean not not checking in but more gee you know missed you you know what with this is what's new type of thing and i think we have a very good relationship from that standpoint but i think it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		unusual and i think part of it is that that we were abroad for a good part of the time
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		until till um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		where what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i was actually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		oh how nice was he raised bilingual as a bilingual was he bilingual yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		bilingual yes yeah actually um
 		he he was more in a sense raised trilingual in that i spoke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spanish</TIMEX> to him when he was a baby
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and then but he always answered in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> because he heard more <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then when we first came to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> he picked up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> when he was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and he had heard me talk <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> on the phone but you know he hadn't he really didn't use it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that is wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i i
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i am <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> actually my background is um my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		where are you from
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i wish that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had taught me <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> when i was younger it was really a sort of the taboo language
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when i was little um you know there was the whole and and there still is
 	
 	
 		cause you they were newly in this country
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were born here my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> moved here um
 	
 	
 		ah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> shortly after they moved here
 	
 	
 		where were they where they what village
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		um-hum from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX> all of them actually
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and um i just i think it's a real shame because now i don't have the patience and i don't have the ability you know at my age to start learning a foreign language
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but when you're a  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you just pick it up so naturally
 	
 	
 		yeah but see there's a big big issue there because my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> at home so that we couldn't understand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and and my um nieces and nephews are not learning their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s language
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that i think this is a a tendency in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is because it's a melting pot so i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had the advantage of we were actually living outside the country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so there was a reason for him to learn it
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really hard
 	
 	
 		yeah do you think that your being in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics um</ENAMEX> helped your son
 		he sounds like he is very responsible and um you know seems to be concerned about his studies
 	
 	
 		well i'm not so sure that it's the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> as much as spending time with him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've been concerned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX> since i've been back with the number particularly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area where i live now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um  with a seeing how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come home to empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and like in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> we live in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouse court</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year olds</TIMEX> that come home and they're locked out
 	
 	
 		oh jeez
 	
 	
 		and you know some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> sort of feel sorry sorry for them and and
 		you know would be very responsible if something happened but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> aren't willing to to pay that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to sort of be in charge and and i think this is
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		i you know i've just seen so much of it here in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that you wouldn't see in in certainly not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> culture i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah oh no that for sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> are more important than things so
 	
 	
 		and then everyone wonders why why like you said that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year old</TIMEX> you know why <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months from now</TIMEX> he's on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		he's a terror well he's a terror he just you know climbs on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> walks around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> threatening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with sticks
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh jeez
 		oh well he has no discipline i mean no one is there to tell him what's right and what's wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 		right now would you continue do you work now
 	
 	
 		yes i do i work full time and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> actually is going for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> and uh would like to teach
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> um hopefully somewhere in the south i i i'm from
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and i i'm fed up with the cold weather really between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um ideally i would um i want to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and i'd like to be able to be home for a year
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i really just selfishly don't want to miss that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s schedule hopefully will be flexible um
 		in that he could do a lot of his work at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i'm not sure i i still want to work i think that's very important
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to keep that up and i don't want to um you know i don't want to go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> without working outside the house
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		but i think that him being um a little bit more flexible with his schedule will really help us out a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that that's nice thing about teaching
 	
 	
 		right right that you he'll be able to spend more time which is so important
 	
 	
 		right and i imagine that obviously your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> were a lot lighter as far as work load
 	
 	
 		right actually we traveled extensively because i was doing archeology and so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		you know he was always able to come with me on all my travels because a lot of the places i went by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> of course
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		and i mean you know i was living in the middle of it and i took every advantage and and you know he doesn't dislike travel now he might not like it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know he might not feel compelled to travel because he has seen a lot but he's very comfortable traveling
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so
 	
 	
 		well he has done more and seen more than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do in a lifetime it sounds like that's wonderful and it it sounds like he really appreciates it too
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 		right you know that that remains to be seen but yes i think so i think so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		does he have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>  oh
 	
 	
 		no
 		no and and and i find that interesting because he's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> ahead in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and so he always you know was treated like little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> needed transportation they'd say oh he can't drive so
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		you know when he's a senior he can drive some of the the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> around type of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he didn't he didn't get his license i mean he was just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> when he graduated from high school so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know he he has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> but he doesn't have any you know he hasn't really gotten into the social thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  he's i think that's all right he's going to it looks like finish his degree <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> before he gets too involved
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum well that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's i would love when i was little i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and they had enormous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and i would love to have a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> it seems so expensive though
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to think about raising a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> besides just the the essentials you know clothes and food and this and that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i really feel like there's this whole um you know you have to keep up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> or whatever they say and uh you know it just seem like when i you know watch
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		but you don't have to keep up i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> appreciate it more if you don't
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i think if if things are special and are for them they see that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are being bought
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are being bought by their parents
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i hope so i mean i look at these toys on TV and i just think oh my God they didn't have those when i was little
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and they don't need them and they don't even appreciate them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean that's my feeling i think you know from what i see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a token you know you don't have me so you have all these material things
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah that's true
 		well it's interesting well i don't know i think i'm ready for it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> we got married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and i thought oh my God i'll never be ready for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i i definitely think i am now
 	
 	
 		oh very good and it sounds like you have good values and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	