
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have any strong feelings about gun control
 	
 	
 		i have  pretty  strong feelings about it yeah i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> ought to be controlled
 	
 	
 		uh i agree there should be some control but uh how strong of uh a control do you think there ought to be
 	
 	
 		well let's see on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i guess i vary i actually started out as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> in my youth
 		but having looked at murder statistics in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> um it's so dramatic that i think that i'm probably down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a two</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a three</TIMEX>
 		in terms of control however no i'm sorry maybe up to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		okay
 		that's  yeah okay got the scale going the other way
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um open the almanac <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and it just has murders of by by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and you look and you look at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and and it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six eleven four</NUMEX> and you get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and that tells me something about
 	
 	
 		but if you make owning a a gun a crime only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> will have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> i've heard that before and that's probably true
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 		
 
 		that's i mean the other problem is there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> out there if you ban sales of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> right now there'd still be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		sure uh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		would it would really be nice to make it a little harder to get one so that every punk in the world doesn't doesn't pack a rod
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree with that i think that some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are just far too lenient uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> are very easy on uh gun ownership being able to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> all it takes is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh sign an affidavit uh saying that you didn't commit any felonies
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i think that ought to be uh tightened up i favor uh uh holding uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> say for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> or whatever until uh you can check out whether somebody is legitimate or not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that might stop some of the uh impulsive crimes but uh things that like that are planned uh selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> things of that nature i don't think you're ever going to be able to stop that
 		there's just too much of a demand and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to get ahold of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> no matter what the restrictions are
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i think that you're right it would be the pretty much the same problem that that prohibition  is in fact pretty much the same problem that drug control is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want it and they're willing to pay for it they'll get it
 	
 	
 		and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> just as a hobby and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> in particular they're they're not uh buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to commit any crimes at all just uh uh pursuing their hobby
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it it's uh ones uh say the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> specials uh uh
 		the semi semi automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> uh assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> things like that that uh really have no place uh for a sportsman
 	
 	
 		yeah that's certainly true i mean i own a handgun myself  i've actually never fired the thing but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		but i went out and bought it intending to to learn to use it and so on but i never did
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't see any problem with owning a gun for self protection but uh education is is a big part of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to be educated on how to uh how to how to store their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> uh so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can't get at them and so they're not a threat to the rest of the family
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		right right
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't get that type of education they don't have any kind type of safeguards on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i certainly just walked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and bought <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> and a box of bullets i suppose i could have gone and blown my own brains out or anyone else's who was who was nearby
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		although i must say i have a healthy respect for the thing
 	
 	
 		yeah uh gun control legislation is uh is really tough to beat i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> is so strong and they lobby uh uh a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh it's going to be really tough to uh add uh gun control type of laws to what we already have
 	
 	
 		yeah it's um
 		it sort of amazes me that that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were really concerned about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dying and if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died in that war it would have been a mess and if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> had died
 		it would have been considered a national calamity and yet that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> die uh from gunshot wounds i mean i think that we have our values in a in a sort of in in a funny place
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah uh yeah i'll have to agree with that it uh i never really correlated uh those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incidences</ENAMEX> say crime at home uh versus an international war
 		but uh
 		yeah i guess i don't know how to how to place that
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean in some in some fields we seem to have this really profound respect for human life
 		and in other fields we don't i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> places where we're willing to take our licks
 		but you know we're willing to accept <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty thousand</TIMEX> highway deaths a year
 	
 	
 		yeah uh that's that's true uh and uh when it gets to the point where it's unacceptable where the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find it unacceptable they may find cause to write their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX> and lobby for some stronger controls
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah we are very tolerant a very tolerant society and uh it takes a great deal of uh abuse before we get our act together
 	
 	
 		yeah in some areas but i think in other areas um
 		i don't know i guess this this this this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> came to mind where where um
 		well war just comes to mind  you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple a hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get get blown up and it's and it really shakes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to it's roots maybe just because of the way it happens
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		but you know we'll go all out uh to save uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with a rare <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> who makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> will get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> in contributions and and all kinds of medical aid because that one life is considered so precious
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when it's viewed somehow when it's viewed in i don't know as as a single life it becomes very precious and when you view it as a statistic whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> or smoking um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just don't see those as individual lives somehow or they don't they don't uh relate to them personally
 	
 	
 		i think it depends on uh who's leading the crusade and how strong they feel about it take for instance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mothers Against Drunk Driving</ENAMEX> that used to be just a very small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> started by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and now it's a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> they they're very powerful uh they collect a lot of money
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it i think it's made an impact i mean it it's made a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cut down on their their drinking and driving because the laws are enforced stronger now
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWI</ENAMEX> convictions are very serious
 	
 	
 		yeah they are and and it's really changing the social structure of things i know i went out with a bunch of people
 		i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and we were just sitting around drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> asked us which one was driving she didn't want to
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		wasn't going to serve that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> anything
 	
 	
 		because uh they're liable anybody who serves anything to anybody is liable can be sued
 	
 	
 		hm yeah i didn't think about that i sort of thought that
 	
 	
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> i think it ought to be the same way
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> ought to be held responsible for things that happen with those weapons
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought that was the case i mean if uh if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> grabs my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and goes and shoots somebody i would really have the feeling that they're going to come banging on my door
 	
 	
 		well i saw a talk show just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> where uh there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> on the show and her uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had been killed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> by one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s handguns
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		when only the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were at home they apparently had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> handguns that were uh in plain sight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on top of the refrigerator one in the on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom dresser</ENAMEX> and one somewhere else but uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and uh and grade school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at home and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> got shot by a gun got killed
 		and apparently no charges were filed against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the gun who happened to be a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum  i don't know what that says it's pretty sad
 	
 	
 		so it's i guess they say accidents will happen and uh  uh you know it's just hard to say who's at fault for uh things like that that happen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but somebody's got to be uh um
 		somebody's got to be held responsible
 		ultimately
 		so i don't know i think the law should be tightened up on on gun ownership but i can't see a total ban on it at all uh
 		because then you're still going to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and it's not going to help uh the situation uh there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to break the law they're going to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah it's well it's just too late i mean there are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i've lived in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are not available even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> don't carry them or it's so hard to get and the
 		and the law is so severe for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> caught using them that by and large uh they don't
 	
 	
 		well they have a lot tighter controls on importing things of that nature too you can't get them through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know like in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> there where there uh where terrorism is so much of a threat uh the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> have uh automatic weapons
 		you know and uh i don't know what the penalties are for trying to smuggle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like that but i imagine they're quite severe
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no i think by the  by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the the year</TIMEX> nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> there were probably enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> i mean it's just always been a way of life here the wild wild west
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i've heard it said that that's one of the reasons why we're not as much a threat to be attacked by other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> because everybody and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s got a gun at home
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and what are you going to do about that You got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> here and
 		it's uh it's more than just an army
 	
 	
 		well yeah that's uh that's a point although uh if that's the case why are we spending all this money on all of this high tech weaponry i wonder
 	
 	
 		well there that's your your professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> uh that's your first line of defense
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		that that's for your your mercenary forces that go across overseas and and attack other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> but at at home here
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	