
 
     		
 	
 		okay yes we do have pollution in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and it
 	
 	
 		how bad is it do you have smog like they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it it some i think it depends on uh you know what the how the cloud cover and like right now it's uh
 		it's kind of overcast you know just it's hot and the sun is trying tries to shine through but it it's it's holding in this this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and i i think so and uh we have uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm depends on whether you have some sort of temperature inversion i take yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena Texas</ENAMEX> which is sort of between here and you know heading toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX> i mean it's still part it's part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> metropolitan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what do you think is your primary cause of it
 	
 	
 		well i think it's industry and i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i
 	
 	
 		you do you really think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> contribute a lot now that they've taken lead out of gas
 	
 	
 		i don't i well maybe not but it it sure it sure seems you know it i i know that when i'm when i'm behind a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and uh sometimes
 		uh i can really smell especially diesel and things like that you know comes right in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to my air conditioner and you know my head and my face i'm so stopped up right now i don't know if it's uh if it's partly from what's blooming you know right now <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen</ENAMEX> and stuff like that that's part of it but um
 	
 	
 		hm my goodness
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think a lot of it's industrial i also think uh that uh there is a certain amount that comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> but it's mostly from older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> i don't think the newer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> are as polluting uh frankly i think that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that um
 		uh if uh i i i heard a story a while back something effect that if they could just pay to get <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> or take all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> off of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that have been
 		uh manufactured say before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen seventy five</TIMEX> that they could cut the automobile pollution by over fifty percent just by getting rid of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that are still left remaining
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you mean uh fifty percent pollution total from that comes from
 	
 	
 		yeah from from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that is not from not total but just from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so that i think would be a tremendous help and i happen to drive an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model car</ENAMEX> because it's very economical and it just keeps getting uh
 		gives me good service and i don't have an incentive to get rid of it long as it keeps running good and not costing me any money on the other hand i know it's a much more polluter than any of the newer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model cars</ENAMEX> i have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't have any incentive to get out of it until it dies and uh that may be part of the problem also
 	
 	
 		right well
 		do y'all have pollution in your country part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh from industry
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah oh uh yeah it's it's uh pretty heavy up here i think but i think it's mostly industrial is what i really uh believe is the the main problem and
 		and uh
 		and uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh i don't think are paying as close attention to it in this area as they frankly should i i we we seem to have a high uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rate up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really like what kind any particular kind or just all kinds
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh
 		well uh for instance breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> seems to be pretty rampant and uh i think of course prostrate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>'s sort of bad for everybody
 		but uh this this this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was like uh second my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s a registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and i think this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was like <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> from the top in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uh cancer</ENAMEX> rate
 		for just all kinds and i can't help but believe that's not partially caused from pollution i just don't know exactly what it necessarily is but i just can't believe this now we have a lot of pollution being caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorofluorocarbons</ENAMEX> uh fluorocarbons
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		which is the like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">freon twelve</ENAMEX> and freon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two</TIMEX> they use freon <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two</TIMEX> in air conditioning systems in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and the like and heat pumps and they use freon twelve in car air conditioners and that's also what's causing our atmosphere to lose it's ozone layer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i can't help believe if it's sufficient enough to make the atmosphere lose it's ozone layer that it's not acting as a pollutant in our lungs also and having all kinds of effects and
 	
 	
 		well what can we do about the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> the air conditioning problem
 	
 	
 		well they're working now i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> and several other chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are working uh feverishly to try to come up with a substitute for fluorocarbons and whoever does is gonna make a a mint because if they ever come up with a reasonable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in place of fluorocarbons then uh
 	
 	
 		is that also what's in uh hairspray aerosol
 	
 	
 		well they used to be but they made them take it out of that
 	
 	
 		even uh so so the aerosol is still aerosol but it doesn't have anything that's damaging
 	
 	
 		right
 		no they they they made passed a law and made them take fluorocarbons out of the aerosol containers
 	
 	
 		um-hum well that's good
 	
 	
 		and that was a move in the right direction we are doing some things to try to correct the problem but there are more things we could do and getting rid of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> like i said is one way to help correct the problem
 		uh uh just trying to i think be careful uh with the way you handle garbage i notice in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> i don't know if you're doing it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> yet or not but in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> we have special containers now we have to put all our cans and bottles and plastic pieces
 		uh you know containers in yeah
 	
 	
 		here they've just started started doing that it's it's you know you're not you don't have to but most you know i i know i am i save
 	
 	
 		yeah well we are doing it pretty religiously in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> too but they uh in one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> here they're actually doing a trial program of having a trash police
 		they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that goes around like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> and she spot checks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s trash and if they find a bottle or a can or anything like that in your trash they'll fine you fifty bucks i think the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fifty the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 		you really oh
 		is that right
 		well we need to do something we need to get serious about it
 	
 	
 		yeah you right you got to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> incentives and surprisingly enough just handling of trash uh can cut pollution
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> from uh uh from just throwing it in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dump</ENAMEX> or or or or whatever else they used to do with it maybe used to burn it they've stopped that up here too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that that will cut pollution too because you get a lot of out gassing from these things i think decaying and trying and trying to for instance cans and bottles they never go away at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well on on the other had i don't guess they're polluting but plastic containers and the like uh they may be
 		ah i'm not sure of that
 	
 	
 		how much does uh planting more <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and things like that help
 	
 	
 		oh i think that's very important to do i i really think that uh trying to get along with your environment and help it out is a very very important thing and uh that can help to cut pollution i guess some i i don't know how much
 	
 	
 		i have too
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> actually act as filtering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in terms of pulling various <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> out of the air i would hope that they would help some though that's for sure
 	
 	
 		well i think uh it seems like there was something going on around around here that you know we have all these chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refineries</ENAMEX> and those kinds of things and that  they burn off a lot of stuff and some of the stuff that they weren't supposed to do that
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		somebody found out you know like in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> they would go ahead and do it anyway i think they got caught but i wonder how much of that kind of stuff you know goes on
 	
 	
 		oh good
 		well that uh that i think may go on a lot
 		and the primary reason i think it may go on a lot is just as you said somebody happened to stay up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late night</TIMEX> or something i don't think we have a adequate policing
 		uh especially particularly on industry
 		uh we have good policing at least in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and and uh several of the surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and probably yours too of car <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> because we have to go down uh once a year here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and get our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s exhaust systems checked for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> content
 	
 	
 		well we have to uh we have to have a state inspection <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> do y'all have that so which i i don't i would assume
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh no we don't have a state inspection but anytime you sell a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or buy a car it has to be inspected in this state
 	
 	
 		so i'm  i'm assuming that you know they check  they check everything for safety or
 	
 	
 		i don't know uh it that's something that you'd have to just chec k with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> but in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> we have to uh pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight dollars</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> and go to a an emission <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> once a year
 		and get everyone of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> checked that are have been made starting in nineteen seventy three
 	
 	
 		but that's all they check for they don't check how good your if your tires are good enough or your brakes are good enough or
 	
 	
 		no no we don't have inspections like that now i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> they check that every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		we do that every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's a good idea too not not not that it necessarily has anything to do with cutting pollution necessarily necessarily but i think it's a good idea the emissions check though is required in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and it's also required in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 		uh a sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to to this and that's that goes a long ways towards cutting pollutants
 	
 	
 		well i'll have to check i'm not sure if if our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> inspection every once a year has to do you know if they check the
 	
 	
 		um-hum well if they don't i would imagine in time they'll get along with it they'll get around to it and if they don't then that's something i would certainly certainly uh uh suggest you'd be willing to uh um be for in terms of uh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		emissions
 		oh i would  i'm for anything that cleans up the air or the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or or or anything on that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i agree now that's another area we hadn't even discussed and that is <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water pollution</ENAMEX> and various of the other types of uh
 		of uh like food pollution i mean you you hardly ever hear hear anybody say anything about food <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> but i think there we have a pretty good handle on inspection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so
 		uh hopefully we're not ingesting too much in the way of uh pollutants in our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> but water pollution uh
 		i've worried uh especially the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX> about just how good the water supply we have in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is for drinking and the like i know a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to bottled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well and that's not necessarily the answer either because they found out that that's just comes out of somebody's tap so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		tap yeah
 	
 	
 		but a lot of these uh some of this well you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have well water in fact in this area too and you know and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you don't get it tested you don't necessarily know what your what your drinking on i know i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know have that and you know you have to wonder if that you know it could have an adverse effect on them too if they don't if they don't get it checked
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i'm absolutely for drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> as long as you first of course have it checked because it seems uh when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> growing up down south uh i used to go out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> were and we had a well with one of those draws that
 		i forget what you call those things and and that was some of the best tasting water i mean i can still to this day taste that water
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		when we were when i was growing up i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntsville Alabama</ENAMEX> and their water supply came from uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		spring and it was like ice cold spring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and i guess parts of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> still have you know get that but uh that was that was really wonderful it was really really good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		oh i bet it was yeah the it once it's been filtered and if it's a deep enough well filtered through all the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> and everything i think that uh it depends of course where you are a good well though i think is very healthy
 		
 		
 	