
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		uh i live down in the south western part of Blacksburg
 	
 	
 		Blacksburg okay i've been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> have you ever heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Tech</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sounds vaguely familiar
 	
 	
 		VPI
 	
 	
 		yeah okay
 	
 	
 		yeah okay that's
 	
 	
 		yeah i i hadn't been down in that part of the state really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well we vacation a lot how about you  quite frequently
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i wish we did
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well retired early so we're we take trips pretty often
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		where all you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> go
 	
 	
 		well we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> every Fall
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then that's kind of a family visit and a vacation all up and down the coast
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> so we go out there
 		and we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and down oh we were just out recently at the outer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all these places that i've never been
 	
 	
 		is that right  where do you go
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		what type of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it really depends i mean uh
 		seems like i do a lot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> lately um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um  fiancee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we've been out there a couple of times and um i uh went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> so i've gone up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> on occasion to visit friends
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		uh
 		i'm a real big baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so i usually try to combine it with uh catching a couple of games somewhere
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> do you follow
 	
 	
 		i'm uh i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> but uh i uh oh you're you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		red sounds good me too
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh i usually try to catch whoever's in town though i don't specifically i you know go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> to see them play the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red the Indians</ENAMEX> play the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		uh that's about it we don't i mean we do a lot of little trips around here um and um
 	
 	
 		ever go up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> in the mountains or
 	
 	
 		not that much we've gone out to um uh a place in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Falling Water</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		have you ever heard of it
 	
 	
 		i've heard of it i've never been there
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's really neat it's this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> built on on a waterfall and it's uh really cool  um of course we keep picking crummy weather to go out there uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time we went out there was uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">hurricane Hugo</ENAMEX> had come through
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		oh gee
 	
 	
 		so i mean they they didn't have any power and it was really cold and and rainy and uh we went up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year later</TIMEX> and it was better but not a whole lot better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um where else did we go um
 		we've gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and uh had a good time down there
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 		did you go down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX> have you been down there
 	
 	
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> has with her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> but i haven't been down there um i hear that's nice we're going to get down probably down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norfork</ENAMEX> sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this</TIMEX> Summer just to see why catch a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we were down well when we came back from the outer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> we came up due <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Norfork</TIMEX> and spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a night</TIMEX> there with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portsmith</ENAMEX> and then went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX> and spent a night
 	
 	
 		hum spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> and a lot of money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard uh i'm not real interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX> because of the of the price attached to it we just we i
 	
 	
 		yeah but it's a pretty neat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to just go and walk around if you like to walk it's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to just walk in
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah we all do that
 	
 	
 		you can go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and not go in if you're not
 	
 	
 		oh okay so i can wander around without
 	
 	
 		yeah you can wander it's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to wander in
 	
 	
 		oh okay i just have it pay somebody to get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		oh okay i didn't know that yeah i think um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know they do the whole with you know paying a ridiculous amount of money to get  get into one thing or another but they had a good time so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		we didn't do that really this time we just
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> visited around
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		we've done it a couple of times and that's enough for us  probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i was um we use it live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and um my um up up around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and um there was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was starting to to do stuff down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was working down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> for like um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> or so
 		um actually i think it was closer i think to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full year</TIMEX> and you know we'd he'd fly down there on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX> and fly back on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX> well any time we had a school vacation or something like that we went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i saw i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> and i really have no great urge to go back now
 	
 	
 		oh
 		that's great as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> though isn't it i mean
 	
 	
 		oh it was great because uh well the times that were really fun were when uh we had vacation but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> didn't so we basically had run of the park um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX> i mean there's still a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX> but there was another um  another amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> down there <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Busch Gardens</ENAMEX> um there was nobody there when we were there we got we won a log floating ride like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> straight times we just get get done with them and they go oh do you want to go again and we'd say sure
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		have you ever you've never been down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epcot</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'd like to sometime but
 	
 	
 		that's good we we really enjoy that we've been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times and probably go back again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've never been the farthest south i've been on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> so i um keep wanting to get south further you know i thought i would go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple summers ago</TIMEX> but never did it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		uh-huh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> is a really nice place to visit
 	
 	
 		my um  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and they've gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> a couple of times and had a real good time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's a real pretty place
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> we'll get down there although
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know when we're going to have vacation to do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we're um we're planning getting married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> and our honeymoon we're going up to this um
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 	
 	
 		um place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Door County</ENAMEX> it's up by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Bay</ENAMEX> it's a place my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s also wanted to go and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> or is it on uh one of the lakes
 	
 	
 		it's um
 		uh i don't if you've ever seen a map of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> but there's kind of like a little
 		a little thing sticking out uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the Lake Michigan</ENAMEX> that's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Door County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh okay that would yeah that would be really nice
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah they call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cod</ENAMEX> of the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we're thinking that'll be a lot of fun she um she had this uh book of pictures from it that were really nice kind of like a travel guide
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh sounds good
 	
 	
 		so um that that should be a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		well i don't know what our next trip will be i guess our next well i know what my next trip i'm going to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first the first</NUMEX> one so my next trip is going to be to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that'll be fun
 	
 	
 		yeah in the middle in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well yeah you won't even notice it though
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		well
 		they'll be air-conditioning anyway so
 	
 	
 		yeah is that is that how you got into this uh this you know uh on the data base
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s working as a temp at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and working on this project
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		yeah i was i was just i mean most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've talk to are from are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so when i you know when i heard you were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> i was like oh okay there's somebody different and you said oh i got somebody down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i go okay that the connection right there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		that's it yeah
 		i talked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i never asked him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> how he was connected i don't think he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> employee
 	
 	
 		um i um most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> there's been a couple of other the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um most of whom are like me that work in in speech <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> that are going to use data base eventually
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		so um it was fun i actually yesterday i ended up talking to somebody else from the same lab i'm in
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		well we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> end in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> with real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that had just moved to back <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and she's uh working on this project too i mean she's talking
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on the project too and uh we got back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and i got a call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>  and it was her on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI Network</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh that's neat i haven't uh i haven't had something like that happen just uh just getting the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from the lab
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		you're sure have a nice town uh my uh sister lives on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Norman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh does she yeah that's nice out there
 	
 	
 		just
 		yeah um we keep wanting to get down there and visit them over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and it's never really works out
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah it's real pretty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		traffic not much else we do for vacation really uh just so we don't haven't been able to take really any
 	
 	
 		are you a golfer
 		no me either
 	
 	
 		no no
 		are you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys golfers</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh nope
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		not too much into sports
 	
 	
 		except our outside  though
 	
 	
 		just walking that's all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i don't think there are any trying to think if there are any minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> down in that area and i'm know real sure there are
 		um
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when um i was thinking i might be minor league but
 	
 	
 		oh there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem Salem Rebels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem Rebels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		Buccaneers oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Buccaneers</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um yeah i maybe seeing them um in a town <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just</NUMEX> west of here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX> has a um has a minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that plays in the same league with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX> and uh
 		i think we may be seeing them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh is that right  up there in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they're out of town yeah
 		um
 		that's a nice little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've never been up there i've never visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> i'd like to go just sight see a little bit sometime
 	
 	
 		oh there's there's some nice things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Harbor</ENAMEX> and the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquarium</ENAMEX> and all that are very nice um they've just done a um  you known i you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquarium</ENAMEX> is one of those things that you know because everybody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	