
 
     		
 	
 		what's uh
 	
 	
 		well what what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> do you drive do you usually drive
 	
 	
 		right now we i've got a uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness well we're we're we're sort of sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> family i guess that's the way we were raised
 		and uh uh we were overseas for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> and when we came back we suddenly find out we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> licensed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> in the family
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		yeah  and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and we bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Car Rental</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of them we bought an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olds Calais</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX> Skylark
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh for you know they each had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one thousand miles</NUMEX> or something like that and turns out that's a pretty good place to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> because they maintain them and they can show you the records they've gotten all their maintenance on schedule and everything like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh then we've got an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy Spectrum</ENAMEX> that we bought new my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> in college when we bought it for her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we've got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> that we bought used so we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> licensed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical chairs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i bet i bet
 	
 	
 		yeah one short  and uh but you know it's interesting the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> even though my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> uh was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> forever and ever ever and we were in the retail milk business and he had all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> milk <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we bought <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> and all that and it was almost like and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> was our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and it was almost like the minute we got old and bought anything like a but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> it'd be like going and spitting on his grave  but uh
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and we got older and got away and then we thought well you know you still could buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> products and it was probably not that bad but uh we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in nineteen uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty one two three and four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course you don't buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> products over there but we bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> and i have never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that i've loved more i just can't afford them here uh but i i just loved that car
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we bought a uh we lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five eighty six</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> and we bought a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Telstar</ENAMEX> which is somewhat similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> it's sold in the in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Far Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> more
 	
 	
 		um-hum i
 	
 	
 		then here but we really liked that and have you had experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> other than the ones you've had
 	
 	
 		well yeah we had uh we had these are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i have ever purchased ourselves the others were hand-me-downs through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and those were always <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buicks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolets</ENAMEX> and um we were real happy with them  but all the ones that we ever had were the you know eight cylinder
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah the big the big yeah
 	
 	
 		really rugged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 		and all we had heard was was a lot of negative press about the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and we both drive  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty five miles</NUMEX> round trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		and so we wanted a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when we got ready to buy we needed a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to get better gas mileage  and quite frankly we were afraid of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know as far as durability so we kind of
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		when when we had our larger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> we didn't mind um
 		keeping them up you know doing the maintenance and everything on them  as long as we didn't have to do it very often
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but once they got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred thousand</NUMEX> miles on them  all of them you know  it just kind of seemed to be the magic number for them
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it seems that something goes every month
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		and i'm afraid we're gonna be in that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> with all of ours you know we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eighty sixes</ENAMEX> and an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> and we'll probably be there with all of them you know it's the same thing you know i don't know whether you uh classify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skylark</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calais</ENAMEX> as small i guess they're intermediates
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but uh we went on a family trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of us and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five five</NUMEX> of us never go anywhere together here
 		everybody everybody's heading off in their own direction  and i rented a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick Le Sabre</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big car i had since i had my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Impala station wagon</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy six to eighty</TIMEX>  and it made all the i i had forgotten what driving a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's like a yacht
 	
 	
 		it was just nice it floated
 	
 	
 		yeah what we had we sold our our we we traded in our Le <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabre</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a great car it just we ran ran the wheels right off of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah and
 		and uh you know i've read i'm in the quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i'm a quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and we're we're uh we deal we sell i'm in the semiconductor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and we sell to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Chrysler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM Delco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there is a amazing i am just uh really impressed with the with the quality consciousness that these those these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have put into their procurement and it's  uh it's come about as a result of the competition from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh uh i and you know we used to think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> products were tinny i mean i was growing up
 		i was taught that when i was growing up you know that that that real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> products and you know and peons bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> products but just with the quality requirements
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> is putting on us and the way they come into our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and they're really
 		uh uh stressing this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> in quality and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> are doing that but i really think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s got a leadership leadership position in this right now and i think it's showing up in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> are getting a very good quality reputation right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh uh we went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> a while back to a basketball tournament and we were gonna be meeting some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> down there so we decided rather than drive one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> down we'd rent
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and we went up to the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and we were gonna get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olds Eighty Eight</ENAMEX> or something he said i'll tell you what for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a dollar</NUMEX> a day more i'll give you a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> Towncar
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and we drove that down and i hated to turn that back in when we got back we had that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> and i absolutely loved except i wouldn't wanna have to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> it in tight places all the time
 	
 	
 		i bet
 		no i wouldn't wanna have to pay for the gas either
 	
 	
 		uh but i absolutely loved that automobile  and you know it wasn't that i'd driving around down there we might have got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighteen miles per gallon</NUMEX> but on the trip down and back i filled up
 		both coming and going so i knew what i actually got on the trip and it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twenty four miles</NUMEX> a gallon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you know we just got it out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and put it in cruise control at about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> and let it let it float
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was pretty nice are you are you are you planning on getting any additional or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a nice car
 		no time soon um we're
 		our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we won't have anymore licensed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> for about thirteen years  yes  so we um so we don't plan on purchasing anymore anytime soon both of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are getting
 	
 	
 		hm oh yeah yours is small
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around sixty thousand miles</NUMEX> on them we drive a lot
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah you probably got another another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand</NUMEX> if you maintain them uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've got probably we'll get something in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple years</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> will graduate from high school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and and he's gonna go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland College</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> behind us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's right you know in fact our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is adjacent adjacent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> property he wants to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Tech</ENAMEX> and he's probably gonna have to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to get some grades in order  but uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> when he goes out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> he wants a pickup
 	
 	
 		a pickup
 	
 	
 		and i want a pickup i may get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and not let him have it but we have been looking at these red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> they they're very popular around here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		these uh red uh red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickups</ENAMEX> and uh we'll probably do something like that uh uh incidentally uh
 		uh i don't know uh the uh the credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> has got a deal now where you decide what you want and you call this number  and uh they go negotiate the price for you
 		and and or or send you to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with whom they've already got a deal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> just bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup</ENAMEX> and he got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three thousand dollars</NUMEX> off the sticker price doing it this way
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh uh you know you you figure out the options go around look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and get the best price you can and then go call this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and and tell him what you want and he'll put you in touch with a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> at that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>'s place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm gonna try that the next time i buy one
 	
 	
 		i think that'd be a good idea
 	
 	
 		and and so you know i can go around and comparison <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and see if i can get a better negotiation on my own but  once uh one thing that's a pain in the neck buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> is negotiating
 	
 	
 		yeah i've we've
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we've we've kind of been the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX> that will say this is what we intend to spend this is the car we want will you sell me this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for that price
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and for that price
 	
 	
 		and and we've had we with our when we bought our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was like you can't do this to me and we were just like okay fine we we won't then you know and he's like no no no but
 	
 	
 		we'll go somewhere else yeah
 		yeah and uh and i i think that's probably the way you got to do it when when i was young
 		i went in and bought a uh or made a deal on a sixty this is nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> i'd first come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and made a deal on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impala</ENAMEX> convertible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i just loved and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> gave me this deal you know i told how much i wanted to pay  and for every fifty dollars he'd have to go in and check with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> and then i'd have to sign something saying that if he could get this rate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we would go ahead and buy uh uh if he could get this rate i promised to buy and i left there on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> just totally exhausted i i was only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years old</TIMEX> or something  and i i left there and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh i'd never done this before because i'd always bought my previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> bought his milk <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> from  and uh uh so
 		i i got back and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> that lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> i did asked me uh uh if he'd heard i was gonna get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and asked me what i paid for it he said well hey uh before you go buying anything he says call this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX>
 		it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> up there  and i called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and made an appointment to come up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just driving fifty miles out of town it was a difference and i mean it was a difference of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> but this was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only twenty five hundred</TIMEX> is all we paid for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>  and uh
 	
 	
 		goodness
 	
 	
 		uh so i called back the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and i told him that i'd left him a check for tax title and license and everything  and i said i wanna cancel my order and and don't try to cash the check because i'm gonna i've stopped payment on it already
 		and he says oh somebody's taking he said what did you get a deal for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX> and i told him he says somebody's taking you for a ride and i said no somebody took me for a ride
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX> and uh uh and i i find that uh and for the longest time then i drove up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">and the</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> died since then and and some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> taken over the business and but and since then i hadn't really
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		
 		
 	