
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes um how how do you feel about uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> has reacted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i i i was uh it was favorable i i just uh i think the sanctions would have worked uh but it would have taken longer and uh now with all this stuff coming out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s book and everything uh
 		and then i saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> program last night about all the uh funding of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> uh back as early as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nineteen eighty six</NUMEX> so uh
 		has there been a different turn and then i don't think we projected what was going to happen uh after the war well it got over so fast so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> book you are referring to
 	
 	
 		well it uh just came out uh i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> it's called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commanders</ENAMEX> and it's uh it says um big story in the paper about it today <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> trying to comment on it that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Colin Powell</ENAMEX> was uh was against uh an early uh he he was for sanctions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it seems like there's you know always somebody digging things like that but i'm not for sure we know exactly what what all happened in that situation so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we we were so uh fast to get over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX> syndrome is that i i'm afraid now we've tied ourselves up there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> for
 		a long period of time
 	
 	
 		right that was that's my feeling i was i was very against our involvement so so quickly and um uh
 	
 	
 		i
 		yeah i just think the i think if we had been very i i mean if he had that good of a correlation through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> then they could have uh
 		they they could have made sanctions work i'm pretty sure uh with that much support you would have just penalized any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that uh broke the embargo
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right i think we're very naive as far as that part of the world's concerned
 	
 	
 		we are we are i think uh you know in in uh
 		we've just misread almost everything in that we always seem to be getting in bed with the wrong fellow for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next next</TIMEX> tenure or next thing down the road and uh
 		then we can and we don't seem to read <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> correctly so uh i don't know it should be a mess it's uh not going to be anything we're going to get out of very soon
 	
 	
 		right right in spite of all the promises
 	
 	
 		so
 		right that they they can talk a good game but uh being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> it's uh
 		you know you read all that  clear back at least to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX> with all of the mess after first world war
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we just uh we're still very i i uh you're you're absolutely right too naive um we just if we do find so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to in in any area of the world we don't listen to them so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't know be be interesting to keep watching i guess but i'm just afraid it's going it's going to break us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and i'm i'm not sure we're sensitive to to other cultures
 	
 	
 		so
 		not very much uh in in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> we're trying we're i happen to teach at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> with tremendous number of international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
 		and cultural diversity is just something we really don't understand and it's uh it needs to be uh taught from the earliest grades with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> in such disarray i don't know if that it doesn't look terribly hopeful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum but i'm not sure it's something you can teach i mean
 	
 	
 		well you can at least uh give give uh uh give them the awareness of the different cultures and uh you know have all sorts of um at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least</TIMEX> you know let them know what
 	
 	
 		awareness maybe
 	
 	
 		that that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do things differently than
 		than than maybe in their own neighborhood
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so and and when when when those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are around if they if you can get them to meet then we're all pretty much alike
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's uh it's something as you know as i said won't go away so uh
 		it'll be a good topic for me in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> for a long time since i teach history so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right and um what about the whole situation with with the refugees
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i would just think if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was so successful in lining up the correlation to prosecute a war then he should be equally successful in getting that same correlation to push the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> to um
 		uh somehow persuade those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> they were promised that nineteen uh nineteen and that
 	
 	
 		um but what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		well that's the same thing they uh they haven't been waiting quite as long even though they've been waiting since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty eight</NUMEX> uh that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that that becomes a different matter simply because you're dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and and they seem to be more intractable than ever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shamir</ENAMEX> can't can't retain his leadership if he if he backs down the slightest bit so uh
 		i just don't see us uh you know i don't think there's anybody of of major stature on the scene of like some of the great statesman of the past
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or at least we thought they were i'm not for sure that they were they they seem to have gotten us into some of these messes but
 	
 	
 		um-hum well do you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> should even be involved i mean as as the world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the sense trying to resolve the issues or should we have just stayed out of it
 	
 	
 		well
 		well
 		i wish we could stay out of it but but the oil's not going to allow us to we absolutely need that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> that's the major thing if we didn't need the oil and and if we didn't have the ties with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> we could probably stay out of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but i'm not for sure that we're we're not destined at least for
 		the foreseeable future as long as we can keep our head our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> above water to be the the world's leader
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is probably if if he can keep that correlation together especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> and and and be sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> can kick in some of their money
 		um they may just have to i don't know what type pressure they can put on uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> there too because now that the war's over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> have gone back just about to their own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh cold selves and uh i wouldn't have necessarily fought for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwaitis</ENAMEX> they uh they're nobody likes them in that part of the world uh but it's it's just such a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		such a volatile uh area i mean there's just no stability there period that's what's
 	
 	
 		right but but in a sense i don't know that i i that i would say it's good but in i'm sense in a sense i'm glad that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> wasn't more changed by by the situation because i mean we really don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i don't think it's our role to westernize the whole world so the fact that that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> could just sort of pull back and and and remain you know culturally sort of clean is is interesting
 	
 	
 		absolutely not no
 		yeah i think you're right i it's not our uh role to make everybody like us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah but it's just uh for those who who may have wanted to travel in that part of the world uh that are up in the age i am it's going
 		eliminate that for awhile i just don't think it's going to be too dangerous to be any place in there
 	
 	
 		right right
 		well you know i mean i i actually lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty eight to seventy</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> and so i mean it's it's been dangerous for sometime i'm not sure that it and it's you know changed that much
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 		yes
 		yeah well uh i i i i haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX> but i've heard what a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that's just totally gone to uh ruin
 	
 	
 		well see that's it it really hasn't
 		but but exactly it depends whether your talking whether one talks physical or or sort of um cultural culturally i mean it obviously changed a lot
 	
 	
 		it hasn't well see that's what we get from
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because it's more a survival <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are still intact it's still beautiful
 		you know there's there was garbage on the corners when i got there and there's garbage when i left but i mean this is just a different uh cultural aspect i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> don't come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> and and you really don't want the garb age in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean i traveled extensly extensively in the area too and um so that you know many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> are still the same as they were before for traveling
 	
 	
 		right okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		right
 		i that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the world i've i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north Africa</ENAMEX> a lot but not um i haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX> or
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> or uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> i would love to go there
 	
 	
 		yeah i was never able to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> it was i never could get a visa so even before i mean even when things were good in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle East Americans</ENAMEX> weren't really given visas to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um but it's it's a very beautiful part very interesting historically of course which was my interest is art history
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so um
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i think we've done them a good job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> then
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for this little project they're doing
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		in fact i just talked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> awhile ago so uh
 		he was checking to see if i was going to stay in because i've been so busy with this presidential search i haven't had a chance to really do any calling myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i see
 		i see well great and um you know have a good business trip
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		anyway
 		thank you and you continue your fine trip bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay thank bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	