
 
     		
 	
 		all right <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX> what kind of hobbies do you have
 	
 	
 		too many
 	
 	
 		too many
 		not enough time for them all huh
 	
 	
 		i have
 		i uh
 		have photography or i read a lot i also uh work with computers as both hobby and
 		and work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		and uh
 		those are the main ones i suppose i also design kites
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		wow that's interesting interesting
 		well what all do you have to take into consideration when you design a kite
 	
 	
 		the ones i like are the ones that are simple and cheap
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have one that i made from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that uh
 		you can't get much cheaper than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">old</TIMEX> newspaper
 		but it doesn't have any sticks or anything of that sort
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it flies like a sled in other words
 	
 	
 		
 
 		are you uh have you made any money off your hobby
 	
 	
 		oh no no my hobbies are hobbies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so what do you like to read when you read
 	
 	
 		i read uh both nonfiction and fiction
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		most of the name brand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and so forth
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> does that take up
 		do you uh
 		watch any TV or anything like that or
 	
 	
 		oh yeah everybody watches TV i suppose but i uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i uh not married to it let's put it that way if i have a good book i would rather read it than watch TV
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's good
 		that's cool
 		um
 	
 	
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		me i uh i play chess
 		i uh
 		lift weights
 		play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> ride <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> that's my exercise part of my hobbies i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i read usually the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> or some other type of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> literature
 		um
 		let's see
 		
 
 		i like to play cards
 		uh
 		don't watch any TV though because we don't have a TV
 		but uh every once in a while i'll sneak over to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and we'll watch a ball game or something
 		uh
 		we're just we're pretty much new in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so we're just trying to get into the lifestyle like we'd like to go see a rodeo sometime and
 		and we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i went to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranger</ENAMEX>'s game
 		and we'd like to go a few more times maybe see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX> pitch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		should have been out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly that would have been the best were you watching that game
 	
 	
 		well we got to see the illegal broadcast that channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> had at the end of the game
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they were supposed to just show a quick flick and they it turned out that was the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">batter</ENAMEX> that he was pitching to so they just stayed on the uh
 		network and i understand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> got themselves in a little trouble they'll probably have to pay a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		compensation of some sort for that
 	
 	
 		oh that's terrible
 		should showed a little bit of yeah
 	
 	
 		but we got to see it anyway so
 		they showed a little initiative
 	
 	
 		showed a little bit
 		oh yeah get your priorities in line see a little bit of history
 	
 	
 		right
 		where did you uh come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> from
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both
 		went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> and she got a job with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> down here
 		so i kind of followed her down here and i'm looking for employment or schooling or something on those lines
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX> is far enough away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> to be uh away from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most of the the blithe</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> is associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they uh i work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		actually i've been with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		in research
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> originally came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> so she's from that turf up there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwestern Corn Belt</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i was in the
 		Kokomo uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> uh late on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> uh out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delco Electronics</ENAMEX> out that way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		were you just out on loan or something or
 	
 	
 		they uh well we had we do a lot of uh
 		work with automotives that's lots of T i parts
 		on automotive uh things that don't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> bug on them
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we make uh
 		anything anything that's uh metal clad for example aluminum bumpers that are metal clad and all sorts we have we make  we make that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 		the uh
 		a lot of the sensors that go there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when uh automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chokes</ENAMEX> were common in automobiles well
 		we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent capture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> market we made all the automatic chokes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Chrysler Chevrolet</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		all that so there's a lot of things like that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> makes
 		that even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> don't know they make  for the most part
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no kidding i don't know that so the more a car becomes computerized the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> becomes involved
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a lot of electronic stuff there as well but what i described was mainly uh associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metals</ENAMEX> and sensors which is mainly what our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Attleboro Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		huh
 		so how did you like Kokomo
 	
 	
 		oh i liked it fine
 	
 	
 		how long were you there
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two days</TIMEX> we we were out visiting uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delco</ENAMEX> to show them some of the uh computerized map things that we had that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you said something about uh
 		the blithe of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh
 		do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well we we haven't
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		been contaminated yet shall i say with the blithe
 		but there's some older areas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Cliff</ENAMEX> that are pretty
 		you wouldn't want to be out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> let's put it that way in that area
 	
 	
 		yeah but that hasn't reached <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> yet huh
 	
 	
 		no no thank goodness
 		and it's all the way across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> it's on more on the south side than it is the north side anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i guess all the older <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have that
 		have that problem you say you play cards do you play bridge
 	
 	
 		oh i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that taught me how to play bridge we we get all these transplanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> not too many i don't know any one that's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX>
 		now really uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> has been trying to teach us how to play bridge and we liked it we played a game called euchre which is
 	
 	
 		i'm familiar with it
 	
 	
 		you know euchre hey that's cool
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		yeah my uh i was in the uh service right after college the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> war going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i played uh
 		all sorts of card games that we got out of uh book of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoyle</ENAMEX> of which euchre was one that we learned
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		pinochle
 		uh
 		flabbergash ever hear that i bet that's one you haven't heard of
 	
 	
 		i've heard of it but i've never played yeah i read read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoyle</ENAMEX> too not the whole book but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		looked through some of the games
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey euchre</ENAMEX>'s a
 		big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> game <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> game is with dominos playing forty two
 	
 	
 		with dominos
 	
 	
 		right
 		it's it's a bidding game also but not like bridge you only go around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time with dominos
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh you probably haven't even heard of it but i'm i'm telling you that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that's a very uh very well known old timers
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> game lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh play that
 	
 	
 		so at least i got the scouting report
 	
 	
 		yeah in fact that used to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> don't believe in playing cards so you could but it's okay to play dominos so you
 	
 	
 		so far
 		
 
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty two</NUMEX> is called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> bridge
 	
 	
 		that's funny
 		wow do you do you play cards a lot or
 	
 	
 		oh no i i like cribbage also that's a good game for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		play backgammon or anything like that
 	
 	
 		uh i haven't
 		really gotten serious about it like the resurgence i played it in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not until until it came back so to speak i haven't played that with the
 		the doubling bet and so forth
 	
 	
 		i figured a uh a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> would be into chess
 	
 	
 		well i uh had no one around me when i was growing up i uh solved chess problems and have several chess
 		problem books you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> and foremoves and that sort of thing which i enjoy but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i didn't have a uh anyone else around me uh when i was growing up that was all that interested in chess i know all the moves and i can follow the game and that sort of thing and enjoy watching
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> play
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i participated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time with a uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> master
 		we used to have a chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">club</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and uh
 		we actually had a grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> in the area who came out
 		and played all of us  simultaneously you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he also played us uh blindfold chess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one one</NUMEX> on uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>  and uh as the game was going along uh he says uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and if you play chess you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> is a long way ahead  and uh we all looked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and couldn't figure out how he could possibly mate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and sure enough he mated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> just like he said he would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		wow that's scary
 	
 	
 		but he played us uh on a round robin where he walks around the tables and plays everybody
 	
 	
 		how long ago was this
 	
 	
 		oh it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> like uh probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		remember his name
 	
 	
 		no it's too long ago uh i really don't but he was he was something else we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> who's really uh in the professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> if you will he used to go to the matches all the time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and his
 		let's see i've forgotten let's see the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> and then right out of that's master what's the one that's just under master
 	
 	
 		expert
 	
 	
 		expert yeah he was expert
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh he gave him a run for his money when he he had to be playing all of us but
 		if he passed you uh twice uh you were out in other words if you hadn't moved when he went around so the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> he beat well the faster he got around and uh so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	