
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		i'll let you go first
 	
 	
 		well i think i don't know how your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> work back there but we support our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here with property taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the land <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> are the ones that pay the school tax
 		so if you're renting a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or doing anything else you're not
 		actually contributing to the education of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and i think that's wrong i think everybody should contribute to the education of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> even if they had to raise the sales tax by one percent
 		then everybody going through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would be supporting our education system
 		so
 		as it turns out we don't really have a
 		tremendous education system because they don't have the money they need to run it
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple uh years</TIMEX> down in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> down there that got taxed to death for the uh Plano uh school system
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh  i've you know i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> doesn't have a state tax and so all the things come out of the the property taxes
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and i was uh really shocked at the amount of taxes i ended up paying i was i was better off paying a state tax  back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> where  than i was uh paying the uh property tax down there
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you would be
 	
 	
 		uh what they did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> to get around that is they uh they developed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX> tax solely for the purpose of paying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>  that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX> were getting including the uh educational services
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh the tax was administered by um
 		the uh rental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that actually was managing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> so when uh long long time ago when i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> i would pay a rent
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		payment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> and a tax payment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		gee
 	
 	
 		and the tax payment went to pay for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that i was
 		getting as a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of that particular county
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		and uh that's the way it worked here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> we have uh
 		a certain portion of your your property taxes uh goes to education but also a portion of the state tax that you pay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		goes back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> that you live in
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		to pay for the educational system
 	
 	
 		oh well that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		and so it it works out nice it it it makes it so that the
 		uh whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> now i i know the concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is quite a bit different than it is here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Collin County</ENAMEX> uh would only equal about maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighth</NUMEX> the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore County</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> are much larger
 		you know in the the whole state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> i believe there's only like uh fifteen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gee whiz
 	
 	
 		and so uh you know each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> has their own school system an and it works out real nice um
 		the the the flip side to this is are we getting what we're paying for and i don't believe so um a lot of things have come to head um recently and i heard a report because of uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the emphasis that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> was putting on education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know um him running as our education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and then finally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years later</TIMEX> getting around to doing something um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they said since they imposed the federal regulations on education in other words they came up with this federalized system where everyone in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade would be taught basically the same thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then at the end of uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school year</TIMEX> they would be tested and then they go into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade and everybody in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade's basically taught the same thing so when they came up with these this nationwide system of public schools
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh they gave some figures out and since it's inception uh they've the price has gone up per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> the prices paid by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty three</TIMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so they're actually spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> and that's real dollars you know that adjusting it back to to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> you know when it started uh probably you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and what they've said is that we haven't had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> improvement in education
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		we've actually gone backwards
 	
 	
 		well they say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are some of the lowest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that our high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> can't even match the national average
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know our school system down here is
 		no where near perfect but they keep complaining they don't have the money to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah well they they've been having some problems uh even here in uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore City</ENAMEX> which is a a pretty good city good good sized city
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh they've been putting a lot of uh stress on it and of course speaking of stress the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are all getting stressed out from trying to you know do everything they're supposed to do and of course they've uh been cutting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> salaries because they say we don't have the money to do it and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yep
 	
 	
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> are costing more money and and everything uh but the uh a lot of emphasis now is being put on you know when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> used to be taught
 		you know like uh uh each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is individual you know they're not all the same
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they need to take things at their own speed
 	
 	
 		and
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> do horrible until like <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade some do horrible you know until they get to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like tenth</NUMEX> grade and then all of a sudden everything clicks in you know and then there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that you know read well at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know seem to excel and so that the you know one of the things i heard proposed on uh one of the public radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> up here was that we should go back to teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at their own speed
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it'd be a lot better
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has to learn at his own rate they can't keep force feeding things to each other and
 		or you know at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and uh
 		and on top of that they they make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> feel inferior
 	
 	
 		um-hum because he can't do it
 	
 	
 		because he's not as good as another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> his same age i mean it's like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know that's ridiculous
 	
 	
 		and it's not that he can't do it he just can't do it quite as fast or
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh you know i have uh i i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> total and i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> already and i have i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that are in uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade this year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		all right
 	
 	
 		and prior to their um
 		when i when they were in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they were identified identified as being slow
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so they put them into special programs and then we actually held them back in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade
 		and
 		it wasn't until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years um last year</TIMEX> my uh they're they're a set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the the uh boy twin started doing real well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		all right
 	
 	
 		and it it it everything started to click in for him and he knew what he n eeded to do um and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> it it happened for uh for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh all right
 	
 	
 		she just has been
 	
 	
 		jumped on out there
 	
 	
 		really doing grea t <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and she has the right attitude towards school and everything and i think it's just a matter of everybody has to find their own path i remember when i was in school i did horrible
 	
 	
 		that's good
 		yeah i did too up until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ninth</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		up until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about</TIMEX>
 		yeah about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh eighth</NUMEX> grade i i i started to to come around and realize an and basically i got interested in math and uh never really did well in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> but you know once you got interested in something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and things started to click in place
 		then after that you take off
 	
 	
 		yeah and see when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> growing up and going to high school if i wanted to take a little electronics course i had a electronics course i could take but we lived out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and we didn't have all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		fancy stuff to worry about you know we had our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> out there and our agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know we had just about every thing that we needed but they don't have it anymore
 		there's a lot of things that they don't do in school anymore
 		our our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> High down here and they go to school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and half days</TIMEX> a week
 		so
 	
 	
 		jeez
 	
 	
 		that's pretty weird
 	
 	
 		yeah it is um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> had a uh real culture shock um when we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> i guess i don't know if you've heard about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> school district but they're uh they really stress <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		no
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and uh God if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is not an honor student well then  you're something wrong with you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and that that's kind of the way they are there
 	
 	
 		gee
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh when we moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> um i moved to a uh a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore County</ENAMEX> which is a northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's basically a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> once you get above about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> way point
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we lived you know in the northern part of the county uh we went from a uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">middle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that served fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five square</NUMEX> blocks to a uh middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> that served fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five square miles</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it was just a complete culture shock because i mean they they're riding on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> with uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that you know are a sleep because they got up at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three o'clock</TIMEX> and were doing chores and you know it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i can imagine
 		yeah
 		yeah that would be quite a shock
 	
 	
 		and they had uh agricultural they had an agricultural course uh i forget what it was called uh but it goes along the the lines of industrial arts but it's  agricultural and where they had to raise a small animal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four H</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		had to learn how to drive a tractor
 		they actually had to go take a driving test on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX> i mean they just couldn't believe this and it was great they loved it
 	
 	
 		all right
 		all right
 	
 	
 		i mean they really enjoyed the courses
 		um
 		and it you know it made school fun for them again because prior to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was just a big pain a drain
 	
 	
 		yeah just something you do everyday
 	
 	
 		yeah and it was you know it was like  kind of like the way we feel about going to work
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah just something i have to do everyday
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh up here they seem to have made it uh a lot of fun for them and they they seem to really enjoy it
 	
 	
 		that's good our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> went into
 		school politics and made vice
 		
 		
 	