
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		great um currently i'm not doing a whole lot of exercise in any type of program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm mainly do a lot of walking um i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a little bit <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX> and um the best thing we found to do with him is to walk around so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i kind of take turns
 		um at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a fairly regular</TIMEX> exercise program
 		but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of months</TIMEX> i've changed to a a new residence
 		and everything has gotten kind of turned upside down all this space that uh normally would be dedicated towards the exercise area is uh covered in boxes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um what did you do when you exercised when you did exercise regularly
 	
 	
 		well i had a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a little routine that i i did for uh warm ups and then i did some uh very
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		mild mild say light weight lifting
 		nothing and i'm not trying to make big bulging muscles just trying to try stay as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> as i can stay in my old age
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		well right now um
 		i try to when it's nice out it's been raining a lot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> but i try to i have a bicycle and i like to cycle a lot
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i we have entered a few rallies that's pretty popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i don't know if it's up north but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> will sponsor a rally and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> and ride <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over hilly terrain</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> miles
 		which that's a lot of fun um so we try to ride ride during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> to stay in shape for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">um TI</ENAMEX> where i work has uh a fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> so
 		a lot of times after work or maybe on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> we'd go over there and lift weights and do the treadmill and um
 		they have stair <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> and all kinds of new machines that are fun to ride and
 		and workout on so
 		i try to i'm trying to stay in shape on a regular basis
 		i used to get into it and then get out of it based on my schedule so i'm trying to stay in in shape on a regular basis now
 		but it's a big commitment we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> yet so that's a lot of the part of it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's that's a plus uh i have a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> left living at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they do take up a big part of my uh my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> and weekend
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's tough being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and trying to do all the things that you should do for yourself too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's uh something they don't tell you about when you're growing up
 		yes when you become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> most of your life is going to be dedicated to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's why uh they they uh really stress
 		um at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> they really stress staying in shape but like in staying fit overall fitness you know no smoking and all that but
 		it's it's hard to find uh a actual exercise regimen that works for you you know
 		because like i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that cycle they take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> behind them on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> and i don't know if that would work for me because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i wouldn't want to pull a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> over hilly terrain but you know it's really hard to find something that works
 		and it you know to find time
 		to do it and stay committed to it like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days a week</TIMEX> or whatever
 		i think maybe walking or running would probably work because you it doesn't take much time and much money or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well there's you you have to
 		uh what i found from my experiences you have to budget time for yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then uh the you you can use what ever rationale you want but basically the healthier you stay the longer you'll live
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh you know if i spend a little bit of time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> or a little bit of time every other day doing something for me to make me live longer well then i'll be around a lot longer
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i'm taking the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> away from now well you know get the enjoyment of me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years past</TIMEX> where i would have been if i hadn't taken it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so if you kind of think of it as a rationale like that it works out fine
 	
 	
 		yeah um i've been learning a lot lately about
 		um i've been reading a book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Cooper</ENAMEX> i don't know if you're familiar are familiar with him
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> of aerobics and all of health really he's kind of redid
 		um uh just pretty much
 		the  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innovator</ENAMEX> of the whole exercise thing um and he was talking about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things you could that cause
 		aging are smoking inactivity and what was the other one
 		i think it was yeah obesity so if you can control those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> areas then you are going to live longer you know
 		because those are risk factors so
 		anyway it's kind of a tip
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh i've done a lot of study over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and i found that uh
 		probably one of the worst things that uh anybody can ingest is chlorinated water
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah um the research i've done and uh i've actually been in the drinking watering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty three</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's amazing that uh you know like prior to like nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> there were not very few <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there were none prior to nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> in nineteen oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> they started experimenting with chlorinating the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in nineteen thirteen most of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> had chlorinated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and then after that we started having the hearts attacks
 	
 	
 		man
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Price</ENAMEX> wrote a book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coronarys Cholesterol and Chlorine</ENAMEX> you can usually find it at a health food store
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know they had it in health food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano i</ENAMEX> used to live in Plano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr Price</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Dr Price</ENAMEX> yeah and it's amazing he makes the in you know it's a very small book and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s very opinionated
 		um but he makes a very good case against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorine</ENAMEX> there were no <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX> before we started using it and he says points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and uh or eating diets
 		that quadrupled the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> that we're ingesting now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they weren't dropping dead of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		that's really interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah he did some experiments on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arteries</ENAMEX> are very similar to ours
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh proved that ingestion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorine</ENAMEX> causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arteriosclerosis</ENAMEX> which is the clogging of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arteries</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know he's uh there's been a lot of reports since then and this whole thing about you know first it was stress then they went to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> and now they're saying what's cholesterol well there's good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> and there's bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's it's amazing what he points out in that book and that um in fact he even uh there was a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toxicologist</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>
 		who did work back in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> who wrote a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr Price</ENAMEX> in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX>
 		and in this letter he praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Price</ENAMEX> for the work he did back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> on this
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> had been doing experiments on non human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">primates</ENAMEX> and proving that ingestation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorine</ENAMEX> causes arteriosclerosis
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> never published that report
 	
 	
 		and what's the name of this book again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Coronaries Cholesterol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chlorine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll have to remember that that'd be really interesting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> wants to go into med <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neurosurgeon</ENAMEX> so he's really interested in the heart
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and he's in fact he's a well heart too i mean he's uh
 		he's done a lot of research on
 		like how your heart
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX> reacts reacts to exercise
 		sorry he just made me laugh um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 		anyway
 		i have to remember that
 	
 	
 		yeah there's there's a there's a lot of good information out there
 		uh about health and a lot of the uh a lot of the myths they've been passing around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
 		are starting to realize aren't true i mean i'm all for having a diet high in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> and all that because that's that's good for you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but to to believe some of the things that they you know and i don't think anybody should be going out there and eating a high high fat diet
 		but to think that that solely alone is going to cause something like arteriosclerosis is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just hard to believe
 	
 	
 		if you get a chance read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Cooper</ENAMEX>'s book on controlling cholesterol
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a real good um he talks about that talks about
 		high risk factors and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah i actually
 		eat pretty much anything that i want
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've had my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> checked and uh you know a few times and i've never been above uh like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and fifty
 		never
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		uh i mean i
 	
 	
 		you have a good ratio of good to bad cholesterol
 	
 	
 		um
 		you you
 		well what they tell me but i mean you know
 		everything's like within uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent and all that kind of thing you know
 		they leave themselves wide open so they can't be sued
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but uh we've uh i work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> site in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hunt Valley Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and we've had a few of the health fairs up here and
 		you know i've always come out aces
 	
 	
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		and i'm you know i'm not really that big on on watching what i eat
 		i i do eat you know some health <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> that are high in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		low in fat and all that kind of stuff but i mean as far as being really concerned about
 		ingesting too much uh chlorine i'm not or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> i'm not worried about
 		
 		
 	