
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well um i don't have strong feelings about changes to be made in the uh jury system do you
 	
 	
 		uh not at all in fact i'm graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past semester</TIMEX> i've taken two criminal justice classes and have discussed a lot on trials
 	
 	
 		oh well then you must know a lot more about this than i do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think i think uh
 		the system the system right now you know should you know is fine i think it should be by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should have i mean he's just there
 		kind of like the referee
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't i don't even think that it should be unanimous either um
 	
 	
 		well what about the idea that one is only guilty uh when proven guilty beyond a reasonable doubt
 		i thought that was the point of uh a unanimous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> was the idea that if everyone agrees
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then there shouldn't be any reasonable doubt but if there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't agree
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		um then there must be it seems to be there must be at least a reasonable doubt for some people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		i don't know i uh
 		you you rarely hear you hear of course there's cases where someone has been put in in in uh prison
 		uh falsely accused but uh
 		more than likely the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are on the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> know what they're doing um i mean you
 	
 	
 		really have you served on a jury
 	
 	
 		never
 	
 	
 		i never have either but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> my few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have uh say just the opposite
 		they say they're uh remarkably incompetent
 		and uh don't know what they're doing and say one thing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> and then as soon as they get in the back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> they just start letting all their prejudices hang out and to to air and all that
 	
 	
 		huh well you would think that they would get that in the uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX> and defense are choosing the jury
 		you would think that those would come out and i i i know they automatically when you go through uh
 		when you're chosen is you're automatically like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> in criminal justice or something like that that you're automatically no they don't want you on the jury
 	
 	
 		right in other words they don't want anyone with experience anyone with particular experience or knowledge of the legal system
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		uh-huh exactly uh
 	
 	
 		and they tend and since anyone can get out of it who
 		basically says they don't want to do it i mean you know it's it's anyone can get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> just about
 		and uh so it it's um it's not really my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> that if i were arrested let's say i were arrested falsely or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and put up for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i wouldn't feel that uh i would be being tried by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> i'd be i mean i'd be tried by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had nothing else to do and weren't very knowledgeable about certain sorts of things and uh i don't know i i get a little bit nervous about it and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i've i've never
 		i've never even been called to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty
 	
 	
 		yeah i i was called once but i was out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and apparently i apparently they thought i served so i didn't i didn't make any noise about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i came back and they said the record showed i served but i was out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> at the time so i'm pretty sure i didn't
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		yeah i um
 		i don't know i think the i guess there's a lot of problems with the
 		legal system
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah well i  i i don't know i definitely feel like we need to keep it at least unanimous because um
 		you know there's the classic sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Kill A Mockingbird</ENAMEX> kind of story where you get you know jury which
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		can have all kinds of prejudices and things that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> at least officially isn't supposed to have though of course they can too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um it seems to me that if you could just have a simple majority or something you could pretty much browbeat you know
 		browbeat the jury a majority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">of the</ENAMEX> a majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that's hard to say um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's it's uh you know saying well look we don't like the way he looks and let's uh let's throw the rascal in jail and stuff
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you also get a lot of um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> are extremely uh and from what i hear i i have i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> wist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> testimony
 		and they say that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> are extremely vulnerable to uh sort of emotional pitches you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> will want to uh
 		oh i don't know show the show the mugging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> you know show what the nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> he was and what a family life and basically get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to be very sympathetic with the victim
 		and uh or or uh if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that was uh you know harming harming some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> or something like that they get very much well you know it's just a big faceless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company corporation</ENAMEX> let's let's make them pay as much as possible things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so not i i mean i'm the problem is i can't guarantee that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge judge</ENAMEX> would be necessarily be much better than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> but i'd be real nervous having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> not at least fully agree
 		on what the settlements would be on things like that
 	
 	
 		right i um
 		i uh i don't i i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should just make the decision alone least with the jury you have twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that are gonna decide
 		you know you're the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s fate
 	
 	
 		well how about having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury jury</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> work together on it somehow i wonder if that's possible
 		i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s time is worth too much though
 	
 	
 		uh exactly i was talking about judge
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they pay that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> they pay those jury <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> very little money compared to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>  he makes more money in an hour than all twelve of them put together
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 		probably yeah
 		yeah but um no it's it's sad though that um
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> though that
 		you you somebody's life is in twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s hands and sometimes those twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could care less
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh or they fool the the defense in thinking that they're you know because when they go through those processes they kind of pick out who they want
 	
 	
 		oh of course it's it's political maneuvering the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side is looking for someone whose face they think will you know want to hang everyone and the other one is going to look for someone very sympathetic they're not looking for someone whose going to be the most reasoned
 		or sensible or rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> neither side wants that they want to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> that's going to uh be most persuadable by their arguments you know
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		um i wish it were a little bit harder to not serve on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> actually i mean i know
 		it it it's tricky because i know you know an awful lot of intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who just well i'm too busy to serve on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> so i'll tell them that and they won't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or just you know just answer one of the questions the wrong way because you can do that you know they just say do you believe in such and such um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well
 		i guess it's just that maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are you know upset at court
 		you know if it was if it was a a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of theirs though that was innocent and then they'd want to be on that jury
 	
 	
 		right course they'd be they would be barred but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh if everyone would take it i think if everyone took it seriously
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i mean
 		something you have to do
 	
 	
 		yeah well it sounds like we both need to get out there and serve on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i i hope we're called up before too long
 	
 	
 		yeah i would love to be called i'm ready to go  they j ust haven't called me up yet
 	
 	
 		they will they will eventually
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well it was nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	