
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 		well we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> now yeah
 	
 	
 		um yes
 		yeah it's um it's very hot in fact i've been cleaning because i live in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> so i can't do very much gardening other than balcony gardening
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know i have the little flower boxes with um a variety a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and i do enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> but i don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> or anything that i can do gardening really
 	
 	
 		oh you're you're you're not the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> you need a house i guess to go through all of that i have had a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the only recommendation i would have for someone who hasn't gardened is uh one get a couple of good books of books of course and usually they have talk shows here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great uh talk shows that go through everything that will grow here which is the opposite probably of what would grow up where you are you know so
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		uh in fact you you could easily do that now listen to turn on a talk show up there and see if there there's got to be some gardening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> on the radio that says when to put your grass in and and what kind of grass to grow up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and everything so i uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for someone who doesn't garden i'd say that that's my biggest recommendation is to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so you enjoy gardening
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i like it a lot uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's a lot of work i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> i'm i'm with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> you are you with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> up there or okay
 	
 	
 		no no i'm with a defense contractor
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um
 		where was oh yeah no i i like it i uh i always know that why i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> when i garden though i mean it is dog work and it is tough
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> down here uh
 		the part i don't like i guess would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from December</TIMEX>
 		through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> where you have to rake leaves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		forever it seems like and the wind blows all the leaves on from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> after you rake yours so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		other than that you know those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> when it's pure dog work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the rest of it's very enjoyable just going through the experiences of of putting little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in or whatever i i haven't had to plant any <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> because i've got so many but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but i do listen to that talk show there there is some great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M i</ENAMEX> don't know
 		uh maybe you've heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&M</ENAMEX> down here but there's some great uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that have been well trained and again uh to
 		to uh recommend gardening for this area
 	
 	
 		um yeah i'm sure it is you know different in the different areas um i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and i do go home on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and that and uh mow my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and different things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah you probably have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rye</ENAMEX> grass up there we grow bermuda and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Augustine</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		oh i would have no idea  no idea whatsoever
 	
 	
 		right yeah see you would have to learn that though see
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like i said i'm just a balcony kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> with my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and my flower boxes and my herbs on my window sill and
 	
 	
 		um
 		do you have much luck in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter</ENAMEX> don't they they're freeze it freeze out because the roots are all in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter</ENAMEX> uh or do you have to start all over every year
 	
 	
 		yeah i have to start all over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> well except i do have some um
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some day</TIMEX> lilies that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i don't do anything with and they seem to come back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX> and i leave them on my balcony even in
 	
 	
 		in the same pot that's that's amazing
 	
 	
 		in the snow and the winter you know in the ice everything because here you know not as severe as the snow is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> but here we still do get some snow and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i grow a few things in pots but we have to bring them in here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX> because usually
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh if it's not below the ground so you can insulate the roots from freezing you know the pots will uh will die everything in a pot will die
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you can bring them well we do bring stuff in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh it's quite time consuming by the way i don't know how close you are to getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or anything but it's quite uh but i would definitely do it
 		i'm all for doing everything whether whatever subject you pick uh do it the knowledgeable way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		don't go out there and start digging holes uh
 	
 	
 		right right i agree with that
 	
 	
 		get some books of whether it be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as as well as uh not your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> of course they usually know nothing but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh listen to still then there's always a gardening part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> for communications
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		as well as i bet there's a talk show up there right now that you if you turn the dial around you'll on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that you'll find someone probably in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		discussing you know what we do up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> to get something growing you probably don't have to do much over there the soil's probably so good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		our soil's not very good down here we're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ice age</TIMEX> it it it's pushed a lot of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limestone</ENAMEX> and everything some parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> you just can dig a foot down and you hit solid limestone you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">wow uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh i think all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that are here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> were planted kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Appleseed</ENAMEX> type trees
 		where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have come from i'm sure when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> were here there was nothing growing in this part of of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's so scrubby
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and i think that we even got our famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred year old</TIMEX> uh pecan <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and all that too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we we call them native pecan <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> but they grow wild here
 		they're eating pecans though pecans are probably not taken from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> they're probably only in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh right i'm
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pecan pie</ENAMEX> and all that
 		it's what they call pecan pecan pie up there in in the East
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh you don't sound like it
 	
 	
 		i've worked on that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		with some chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> which i shouldn't do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		go ahead you what how many times you called by the way or how many times have you been called
 	
 	
 		um i've been called a lot  at the times though it's been not very
 		appropriate i guess that i haven't been able to actually participate i've participated probably in about maybe i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> calls
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know i've called a couple of times but most of the time i notice that um you know it takes forever to get a call through
 	
 	
 		oh yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that's what i'm saying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i was i got to laugh because i tried it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> and uh i thought everybody was gardening i thought well no no this is a great subject because they're out there gardening you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i didn't tell you what our weather is like it is beautiful here today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's like eighty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five degrees</NUMEX> here
 	
 	
 		it's not quite that hot yeah we've had a real nice mild Spring uh
 		you might have seen if you've seen the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about all the tornados here that were north of us
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know if you get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> i don't get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> but it's here at work in fact i'm at work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> believe it or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but uh they have uh TV's in the break areas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there was some some heavy tornados uh i guess in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were killed you'll see that on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news
 	
 	
 		oh my uh-huh i'll have to make sure i catch that
 	
 	
 		uh
 		tornados uh which is not the right subject but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they blow through here all in the Spring i guess it's related somewhat to the weather you know and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and all that that uh sometimes they do essentially nothing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the weather men <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> were all alert say hey there's something really terrible going to happen and they they sure were right but it wasn't in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">north</ENAMEX> of us yeah look at the news tonight they'll they'll they claim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty odd</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were killed up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City Kansas</ENAMEX> somewhere
 	
 	
 		i'll have to make sure i catch that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anyway back to planting
 		uh i have never studied it is very interesting uh subject uh
 		when you when did you get a house uh you your <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> grow up so well up there but i'm sure you have plenty of trees
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that is a key thing for shade
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and keeping your bills down uh
 		i guess you have mostly pine <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> but where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> are you all
 	
 	
 		um right now the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District Washington</ENAMEX> um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax Virginia</ENAMEX> it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fifteen miles</NUMEX> west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh do you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cherry blossoms</ENAMEX> and everything there or not
 	
 	
 		yeah there's there's a few not you know nearly as many as what's actually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> but um they're definitely enjoyable right now i know the azaleas and everything are out are beautiful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		yeah azaleas grow all over we grow those here too although again we have to prepare the soil
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you probably have nice big pine you probably have all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> and everything that's one thing i noticed about
 	
 	
 		yeah there there there is a vast variety here of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> like if i look out my window right now i can see you know couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pine trees some oak trees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have you ever been down here
 	
 	
 		um no actually i haven't
 	
 	
 		okay it's it's interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh
 		it is wide open uh and flat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and again as i said i think the when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> were here there there weren't any trees but the the civilization has brought all kinds of experiments with all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and uh
 		a lot of them have done well uh they they do have some pine forest areas in west in west in east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where you have native pine <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> but here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they all were planted by the classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Appleseed</ENAMEX> and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Johnny Pecanseed</ENAMEX> whatever you would call it you know because there's a tremendous amount of pecan <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that we use for you know uh for eating
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they thought that was going to be a great boom crop uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hundred</ENAMEX> and fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> because they are all over the place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
 		what else
 	
 	
 		um oh well  i guess that i really don't know that much
 	
 	
 		how many how many subject i i the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> are usually pretty interesting i i'm i'm of course i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI'er</ENAMEX> so i'm hoping this works <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is very good uh
 		has done a lot of experiments in the speech uh synthesis synthesis can't say it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they've come out with some new products uh some new in fact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> they came out with some new math uh you might see them in your advertisements uh new math uh Speak and Math uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh devices they they have had <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Speak and Spell</ENAMEX> and all that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but they've come out with some different ones
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX> and uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and everyone ask me what what are they going to accomplish out of all this and i said well you're not going to have to type on the computer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> you're just going to have to talk to it
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know so you it's going to be much faster
 		of course you know the classical thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped</ENAMEX> too <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who can't type very fast or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like i can of course
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh not that i can talk very fast either but uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum but then what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that um i i i personally work with someone that that is deaf and cannot speak she can speak but she can't
 		speak very clearly and she in fact is a data entry person i mean she types away all day
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	