
 
     		
 	
 		so the topic is vacations
 	
 	
 		all right that's a good that's a good topic huh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think so
 		i enjoy them
 	
 	
 		where did you go on your last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh the last was back down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> to visit parents
 		it was
 	
 	
 		to what
 	
 	
 		the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was back down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock Texas</ENAMEX> to visit family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but that's not the tradition for us
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		what's your out of the out of the state type where do you like to go
 	
 	
 		uh we enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> real well last year
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what kind of uh vacation spots are there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain National Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's just like any of the other national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> it
 		you know there's camping and fishing and hiking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX> watching and
 	
 	
 		i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> took me there when i was real young we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain National Park</ENAMEX> it was real pretty
 	
 	
 		oh it's
 	
 	
 		got to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pike's Peak</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we usually try and drive up there oh once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		you drive by yourself up there
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		to the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX> of the peak sure
 	
 	
 		oh that's tough i don't i don't think i could do that
 	
 	
 		oh it's not bad at all
 		it's it's a beautiful drive
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		now i admit up there the altitude is kind of
 		interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you get a little lightheaded and giddy but it's fun
 		you know take along a picnic lunch and
 	
 	
 		sure is pretty up there
 	
 	
 		oh we love it
 	
 	
 		you have mountains all around you
 	
 	
 		uh
 		no they're only to the east uh i mean to the west of us
 	
 	
 		where you live
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springs</ENAMEX> you know it's right there at the very foot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockies</ENAMEX>
 		you know and once a week we drive up into the mountains usually you know usually once a week once every other week
 	
 	
 		wow that's neat i'm jealous  there's hills in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i enjoy hills
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too i've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you ever been out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for uh vacation
 	
 	
 		no i haven't you
 	
 	
 		or business
 	
 	
 		uh once to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> but just a little day thing on business
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i went to uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> on a cruise for my honeymoon
 	
 	
 		uh that's nice
 	
 	
 		it was really neat i had never been out of
 		really out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> much out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		did you enjoy it
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		did you enjoy it
 	
 	
 		yeah it was great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was really pretty down there
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> got to eat some different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> and meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from a different culture and
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah really did there in fact one uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that
 		sat at our table every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and they had never been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> so they were really enjoying it and they were telling us about all their trips
 	
 	
 		oh
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they had been to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX> and
 		it was neat to meet different people
 	
 	
 		so the place that i went that we've gone on vacation that i think i enjoyed the most
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really i've heard it's really pretty up there
 	
 	
 		well
 		we uh
 		was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we went during the drought
 		i'm sorry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> it had been dry for a whole week
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		it didn't rain for a whole week
 	
 	
 		yeah  that would have been nice that would have been best time to go
 	
 	
 		yeah somehow we picked the right time and uh
 		walked down on the wharf and i think we ate seafood every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> for
 		well not quite every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">meal</TIMEX> but most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> for a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it was wonderful uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Science Museum</ENAMEX> the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> really enjoyed it's
 		very interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Sites</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yes it was it was super and uh
 		went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Aquarium</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's right down there
 		on the
 		right there on the ocean and
 		down there on the wharf by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">piers</ENAMEX> and all and
 		you walk down in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> a glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the bay is circulating over your head and you
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		you can watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> swim by and sharks
 		oh it's
 	
 	
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		yeah and then there's walrus and sea <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> and porpoises and oh it's it's amazing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's the vacation you recommend huh
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		without a doubt
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> is beautiful and the mountains the mountains to the east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard it is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are just incredible
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i rode a ferry for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in my life
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		you know up there
 		you go from the mainland to a whole bunch of islands around there by ferry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		instead of by bridge
 		and you drive your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> on you park your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> you set your brake you walk <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> and you have a beer
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> or whatever depending on the time of day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's amazing
 	
 	
 		and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is on a ferry and it goes across with you
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that's really neat
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and
 		there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> literally that
 		everyday take the ferry you know and drive on to it yeah
 	
 	
 		to work
 	
 	
 		live on an island off off shore from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		that's really wild
 	
 	
 		and
 		you uh everyday they drive on the ferry they go upstairs and have their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> coffee
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		take for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty to</TIMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour and ten minutes</TIMEX> that it takes to get across and
 		you know depending on where it is
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour and ten minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well in some places you know in some areas you know depends on how far they are commuting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's really interesting
 	
 	
 		oh it it's strict i'm i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Texan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		out there in the land of no water
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		and to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live on the water <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> is kind of odd to me
 		you know it's it's a different life style
 		than we are used to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it is
 		i've been wanting to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Texas</ENAMEX> and see different parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> because i haven't lived here very long and i haven't really seen much
 		so what are some good things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> to go visit
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX> real well uh
 		there's uh one of the
 		areas down there close to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX> is
 		i forget the name of the island but it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird sanctuary</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with all kinds of wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">whooping</ENAMEX> and sand hill <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cranes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pelicans</ENAMEX> and it's very pretty uh i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio Grande Valley</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		real well of course you haven't lived until you have been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antone</ENAMEX> to the uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boardwalk</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah the river walk oh it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you need to go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Spring</TIMEX> when all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> are in bloom all up and down through there oh it's just simply beautiful
 	
 	
 		i've heard it's really pretty
 	
 	
 		and of course always when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Texas</ENAMEX> had to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> go down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antone</ENAMEX> just
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah and go to uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lone Star</ENAMEX> and uh you know
 		make my annual pilgrimage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lone Star Brewery</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh El Paso</ENAMEX> is kind of neat in kind of a funny way you know go across the border and all uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Davis Mountains</ENAMEX> are interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		out there in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		down by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bend</ENAMEX> what's that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh now the right time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> to go there is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of winter</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		because
 		there's a beauty to the desert that it can most be it can best be appreciated when you are not burning up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know whenever you've been kind of cold where you are at it's most enjoyable
 		to get you know to get warm
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's nice uh
 		down there in the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio Grande Valley</ENAMEX>
 		closer to where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio Grande</ENAMEX> empties into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> that's interesting i love the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Hill Country</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> is neat for for an occasional visit
 	
 	
 		i've heard to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin</ENAMEX> too a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say to go down there
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's a fun few days
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what's there to see in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> is real pretty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there's a lot of little limestone lakes and caverns around that area <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marble Falls</ENAMEX> and all that's real pretty uh
 		i would say definitely go see that part and uh
 		i'd say go to uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midland</ENAMEX> once just for the heck of it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know why exactly
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		you know find out when they are holding
 		the
 		petroleum fair uh
 		
 		
 	