
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay  uh where do you stand on gun control
 	
 	
 		was a loud one
 		i'm against it
 	
 	
 		again your a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i i uh your against gun control why why
 	
 	
 		yes
 		you you can't enforce the laws you got why do you want to pass some more
 	
 	
 		that's a good that's a very good point very good point i personally
 		i guess i would be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> they said pick a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because i i'm i think i'm dead smack in the middle i think that
 		if there is going to be a ban on gun control that it should be enforced like you said and i feel like if there if if there is a band
 		put upon us it wouldn't be a forced enforced just like um there's suppose to be working on a drug problem suppose be working on our education problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things like that and those aren't being enforced but at the same time i want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> protect themselves because things like the drug
 		the drug war is not is not helping and i feel like i have to protect myself when i go out somewhere because there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they're crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		that's correct i don't know how maybe that's i agree <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent i just uh what irritates me i guess is that they keep wanting to pass gun control laws that do nothing but take away your your constitutional amendments
 	
 	
 		you know and so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that is that is really not gun control is not the problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and all they're doing is look at this new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady Bill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> waiting period that does not deter anybody who really that wants to buy a gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		there's spots here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sixth Street</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eleventh</ENAMEX> east east of the interstate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you stand in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> down there and buy anything you want
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		i mean you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whether you want <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">guns drugs</ENAMEX> women anything uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's just it's just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i mean they're legal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you can get them anywhere if you want you can get it
 	
 	
 		true
 		you can make two phone calls if you know if you know anybody here in town uh
 		you can make two phone calls and have automatic weapons
 	
 	
 		uh that is a shame
 	
 	
 		the law's just you know it's
 		they can't enforce what they have you know and i'm not a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> peculiarly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he was on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the on the talk shows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> on there and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady Mrs Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> but you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he he pulled this big stack of papers out that was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about oh four feet</NUMEX> tall and he said these are all the current gun laws you have the books if you can't enforce these why do you think you can pass another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and enforce it
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady Bill</ENAMEX> won't do anything but just make it harder for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are honest to buy one those those that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> which are the ones that are refusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place uh they're not going to walk in and buy one anyway
 	
 	
 		the reason i think i'm so cloudy on the issue is because i mean it it i want to protect myself but at the same time i don't want anyone to have a gun that could harm me
 		you know what i'm saying
 	
 	
 		well uh the uh proper solution is education of the masses
 	
 	
 		and so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you've got to educate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in in using the weapons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and you know our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forefathers</ENAMEX> you know everybody carried a gun here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know for you know a couple of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right but everyone weren't they weren't going around killing each other
 	
 	
 		that's true unless of course there was you know
 	
 	
 		trouble yeah
 	
 	
 		sufficient sufficient provocation which we have basically the same something now it's just that all the honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> as it were no longer carry <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to defend themselves because only only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		but do you think more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now are carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and weapons
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean just to i'm talking about the regular like
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh i have a class license
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Blow</ENAMEX> on the street
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">firearms</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine owns a gun shop in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i go up and help him you know work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and stuff like that and it it's amazing the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and the reason they're buying them is they want to give their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> one to carry in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> will come in and they'll look around and they'll try and find a small <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to fit inside their purse
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 		i mean you you have to because i i mean i don't have a gun it just scares me to have one but i feel like that very soon i'm going to have to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> just because i would probably feel safer
 	
 	
 		and
 		well if you get one you know
 	
 	
 		right now i have a knife under the seat in my car
 		uh if i'm going anywhere at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> anywhere i mean if i'm just stepping outside my door i carry something on me if i'm you know going up to my door and i don't have anything i put my keys in some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> like position in my hand you know
 	
 	
 		you're single i take it
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		are you single i take it
 	
 	
 		yes yes i am i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> but you know he's not always around
 	
 	
 		yeah okay
 		yeah
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh before we got married uh she didn't carry any sort of thing and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i've got uh
 		i've acquired you know her you know bought several that i give her to carry one of them she carries in her purse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's some in the car i i always have one in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> when i'm driving any place
 	
 	
 		yes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> that that got me you know put the knives here and there and you know just different things and
 	
 	
 		you know knives or mace or something but uh you know
 	
 	
 		yeah and i have mace on my key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> i mean i have a lot of you know little things that
 		but i don't i don't like to have to carry them you know uh but you have to
 	
 	
 		well it's a sad state of affairs when have to but uh you know they're are more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> getting broken into and everybody says well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> no it's not because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> it's because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and actually they're breaking in
 	
 	
 		no no
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and and using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> although you do have those that you know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiot</ENAMEX> who ran out and grabbed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AK-47</ENAMEX> and shot everybody up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif</ENAMEX> ornia
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> now that's just
 	
 	
 		you know that we're talking about somebody whose crazy having a gun law is not going to stop him because he's going to find one
 	
 	
 		lunacy that's
 		yeah
 		he'll find some other way whether it's a gun or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> or what
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California Hawaii</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> have these and uh
 		now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey</ENAMEX> had the stiffest gun laws
 	
 	
 		oh do they
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but you know where where are the most crimes committed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> was you know you know was shot and killed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that bought a gun in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> which has a tough gun law
 	
 	
 		uh uh uh
 	
 	
 		and you know i mean this clown out in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> he uh had a criminal record you know <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> long
 	
 	
 		and still got a gun
 	
 	
 		but he still had not one but several
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there was one not too long ago but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six months</TIMEX> uh
 		he shot up that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allstate</ENAMEX> or or or that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMC</ENAMEX> credit place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		well he went out and bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		you know and he had a criminal record
 	
 	
 		and i mean if you find
 		if you offer a uh enough money to somebody they'll go get you a gun you know if your not eligible you know come to me offer me enough money i'll go get you a gun you know there's probably a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		and there are people
 		yeah they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing that so i mean the the solution is not to pass more laws than you can't enforce because they're they're going to pass one now they're trying too either the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Staggers Bill</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady Bill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		either way they do it it's going to cost you and me more money
 	
 	
 		right and not probably going to help too much
 	
 	
 		because and and and we're going to increase the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> that's supposed to handle it and
 		what are they going to do they're going to punch your name in the computer and you're going to come up as no you're not a criminal and no and no you have no criminal record you know and yeah you can by gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that doesn't say that you're not going to walk outside and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days later</TIMEX> shoot somebody
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		you know there's no substitute for people
 	
 	
 		a lot a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in jail you know it's their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shooting or why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know not everybody has shot someone before
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are not the prime uh weapon used in killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in crimes of passion or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's knives and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> bats
 	
 	
 		uh-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">huh baseball</ENAMEX> bats
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i could see knives yeah stabbings and things
 	
 	
 		see you can walk down the street carrying a baseball bat and nobody thinks anything about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and how many times have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walking down the street carrying a baseball bat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you figure what little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaguers</ENAMEX> on their way to practice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang members</ENAMEX> just as easy
 		if you
 	
 	
 		i didn't know baseball bats was like that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's uh it's quite a deal
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		nobody pays attention to a baseball bat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and you you can see a baseball bat in the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and nobody no cops going to give you a ticket for a baseball bat in the back of your car
 	
 	
 		that's a very deadly weapon
 	
 	
 		yeah so why you know
 	
 	
 		i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> blow at that and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		or knives you can have knives everybody's got knives of course you're limited you know you can't have switchblades and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are used but so is everything else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you're going to ban that if you're going to band <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> i've got an article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> where they had where they had uh used a satire
 		where someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> had suggested all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> because they were used for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> of drug regulated crimes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they immediately decided well lets start banning the public telephones
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		bless you
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		and they said well let's band the public telephones too because the public telephones are used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> of drug related crimes
 	
 	
 		very true
 	
 	
 		makes about as much sense
 	
 	
 		a lot of sense
 	
 	
 		but you know the to my way of thinking you know uh i'm a i'm you know i spilled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> on the ground you know for in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> does not trust me enough to have a gun after that then i don't trust them enough to govern me
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i'm kind of radical on that i just you know
 	
 	
 		you sound like you're pretty strongly
 	
 	
 		well i i see too much of it and i see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come into the shop up there and you know and i buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and and they haven't got the faintest idea what you are doing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and they want to buy a gun now i think there should be some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ID</ENAMEX> card that you carry
 	
 	
 		right
 		what do you think about making some kind of application or something
 	
 	
 		there's an application you fill out now
 	
 	
 		do you okay
 	
 	
 		it's a yellow form
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh see that's it's just another piece of paperwork it asks for your name your address and phone number and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> where you birth and all and you know and then there's a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> questions you answer and
 		if you answer no to all of them that means you're a good American
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you such um seriously and
 	
 	
 		yeah uh uh uh
 	
 	
 		it's a little yellow form you fill out and it puts the name and the serial number the gun who bought it and the date like that and that stays in the gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and it never goes anywhere
 		it stays right there we've got boxes full in the back room
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well that's a lot of help
 	
 	
 		and and the only thing that it's used for is if uh if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcohol Tobacco and Firearms</ENAMEX> come down and does an inspection
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they look through and if they look through and if they look through your legal logbook you have to log it down in and out well you got
 	
 	
 		and they probably really do that
 	
 	
 		and they and
 		they don't come out very often
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've seen them once in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		but they come down once
 		
 		
 	