
 
     		
 	
 		all right well tell me all about your reunion planning
 	
 	
 		well we uh uh this will be uh uh the reunion for not my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> but my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> and then my great and then my grandfathers so it's a couple of generations
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and these were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> who came across the plains
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> were are quite large and so we've had we spent a lot of time trying to gather up
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> names and addresses of all the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are involved
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it takes a lot of time and planning
 		um good activity the what
 	
 	
 		are you going to do it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX>
 		are you going to do it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well interesting enough we're going to we're going to do it over an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight day</TIMEX> period
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they will not everyone won't be there for the whole time but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> can come in during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that eight day</TIMEX> time and kind of meet on the on the living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> level
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		like i will come there kind of early and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> will come so that we can get acquainted and then
 		uh it goes back the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the generation before</TIMEX> will join us and they may meet kind of individually in this camping area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then uh toward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the week</TIMEX> there will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> specific <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when we honor these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> my the grandfathers and the great grandfathers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so it's kind of once more combining the whole group again
 		but uh it's it's it's uh it requires a lot of uh logistics for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who will have to meet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a lot of uh arranging for activities
 	
 	
 		what are some of the activities
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well uh course you want to do some kinds of things that which will help them to get to know the ancestor that you're honoring
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but besides that if you have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and and different ages you need to try to find things
 		that uh that they will just have like to do together so that the next time somebody says reunion they won't run like
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX> winds
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so it has to be pretty fun too i think uh we're we're going uh going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> to uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and it's a a pretty good size area where there'll be hiking and and then there will be uh
 		oh just uh general kinds of things like uh swimming and whatever during the uh in the area roundabout which they will do during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when they want to
 		when they're not uh uh rehearsing or whatever for a part of the the play and then we'll kind of get together and and uh work out some small
 		oh vignettes or or uh acts or things like that Musical numbers
 		and the fact that we're together early during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> will help us to get together to prepare those things for the for the programs at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it it we're real excited about it now always before we have only had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and uh
 		we only did it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the last time we doing we were doing it every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and we decided last time we would wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a third year</TIMEX> because it came across so often that it was kind of hard to get there and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back East</ENAMEX> and course i come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so there's some of us come from quite a ways
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and so we we had a little longer and decided to try to hold it
 		uh in a situation that was a little longer like a camping situation something that wasn't too expensive but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> could be more of a vacation situation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to come and participate in while getting to know their ancestors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so that maybe they'd be attracted more to bring their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 		now i've never gotten all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to come before but this year i have uh several married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are coming en masse so it it it looks to be a lot more interesting activity
 	
 	
 		this is what how did you pick uh
 		the place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> is it central location or
 	
 	
 		well uh the ancestors came from there
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh and we we were holding them there because there were some living ancestors up until
 		uh fairly recently at this point in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> that we're honoring
 		there's only well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety three</NUMEX> and she won't go this year because it's just too hard on her
 		but uh and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> but all of the all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are now gone they they've passed away in the meantime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so uh at that point we were going for that reason we were going there
 		but it just there just more of them there still than there are other places the rest of us are kind of strung around some but we're but you know if you if you're talking about convenient for the biggest majority it still is there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		also we had a we had a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> who was in charge of it in general this time had some access to this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> which was a big factor
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		whether we'll be able to do it there again but there are other kind of arrangements like in in uh
 		in some of the areas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> you know where they ski in the winter time you can make some pretty good arrangements for uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> uh activities and things like that
 	
 	
 		how
 	
 	
 		so we might do something like that also sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> will will rent out uh areas for doing things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay how long in advance did you set the date
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		well we knew generally the time of year uh that we wanted to do it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> but we could not set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the date</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first of January this year</TIMEX> because this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> where they have it
 		uh they allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the vicinity to make their arrangements ahead of time and so we kind of had to take what was left
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so we we feel pretty fortunate to have gotten in at all but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i think you need to plan on you need to be sure and plan uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a year</TIMEX> ahead of time or you're going to lose people
 		you know they have to plan their vacations that far ahead a little bit
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if not exactly at least know generally what they're going to do
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of important to to know quite a while ahead of time
 		uh the last time we had one uh i was in charge of it and my goal was to write a history of my
 		of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and his  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and sisters
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was a history of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> but there was no history on them so i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two years</TIMEX> before that compiling and and writing the history and then we gave it out at that
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we're not we're we're combining it in the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> before and so we're going to do some um
 		uh acting out of of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and try to help them get better acquainted and mostly it's a different kind of thing so we're we're just kind of playing it by ear and seeing how it goes i think
 	
 	
 		wow sounds like you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s really into family
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah we're kind of like we kind of uh well we like each other and we liked our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and so we figure they the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> ought to get to know each other and
 		and we are scattered enough there i have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who live here but i also have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's it's really neat to be able to get acquainted get around with them you know
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and  you're younger
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		uh well i'm married and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is from a large family
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		living and she has
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that has no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that's living and my deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> that has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with and no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so i have like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not very many huh do you do you enjoy your do you enjoy your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s large family though
 	
 	
 		not very many no
 		it too it's it was a large transition let me tell you because they had to meet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> they only had to meet me and i had to probably meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five or thirty</TIMEX> people
 	
 	
 		was it is it
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so getting names and faces and jobs and where they live and everything straight was a quite a task uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i still kind of balk at it because they're really into family too and like
 	
 	
 		you don't feel quite involved huh
 	
 	
 		well they try to involve me and if i allow myself to be involved you know i'll fit into the picture but uh they uh they make a big deal out of everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you have to try it you'll like it
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i guess so uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it really is quite a lot of fun and uh um uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i'm just not used to it because our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has a reunion about once ever <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and and it's about a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> show up so no one there's my age so i just kind of sit there and hang out but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX> has a lot of cousins
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that are our age and you know so we get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		cousins get really get really close sometimes almost closer than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		it's yeah it seems that happened with their family
 	
 	
 		especially
 		right especially if they live fairly close together so they get a chance to see each other
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's kind of special
 	
 	
 		yeah there family was pretty well centralized everyone kind of stayed around the the uh the grandparents
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for at least for a while at least while they were growing up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now they've kind of moved out a little bit but not too much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	