
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		what's the uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> law has a uh
 		what does it have it has a death penalty doesn't it
 	
 	
 		oh yes yeah they just uh started it again too just late or within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>
 		you know for quite some time just about every one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> had given up the death penalty
 	
 	
 		but now it's coming back into favor
 	
 	
 		uh yes well they find it is more deterrent
 	
 	
 		well my sociology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX>'s taught us that it was not a deterrent
 		uh but now that's just what they said uh i don't know maybe maybe if i went back and took a sociology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> now they'd say it is a deterrent
 	
 	
 		well uh if you
 	
 	
 		maybe they've changed their minds
 	
 	
 		you know compare the figures i think that's where they're uh they're coming from
 		the uh
 	
 	
 		maybe that's it maybe that's it because that was back in the seventies
 	
 	
 		oh there yes they are that was before the uh uh they adopted the death law again
 		but uh i i myself am in favor of it uh particularly for uh
 		well i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has a good good law uh crimes murders related with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think i agree but i think it ought to be expanded to include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		i i think they're they have they're working on uh something in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm not sure what it is i just remember seeing a uh kind of a synopsis of it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well why stop at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> why not go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		well uh i'm i'm personally very in favor of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh why should we let them set in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and work on their college degrees
 		after they've mowed down a class yard full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or tried or tried to or done their very you know given their best effort at doing that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> yep
 	
 	
 		i i don't care to support them
 	
 	
 		well i don't either but uh uh but there is something to be said about
 		or uh uh just just for the sake of argument i'm taking the a con i'm i'm against
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh you know yourself how many times have you heard where uh uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> was wrongfully arrested
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and served time at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">penitentiary uh</ENAMEX> just recently this uh black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> served <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> was it
 	
 	
 		and then there was the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that uh robbed and shot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">furrier</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for robbery
 	
 	
 		and she was set free too just in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> examples in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> recently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but she actually killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">furrier</ENAMEX> or someone she was charged with murder
 		and then then they decided it was a case of mistaken identity or something i didn't i don't  i didn't retain all those facts very well but i know what you're what if we make a mistake
 	
 	
 		that's it
 	
 	
 		and that's not one of those things that you can turn the wheel back and reverse everything
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well right now our laws are so liberal that uh
 		even with the death penalty in effect i don't think that uh
 		
 
 		they're going to use it uh too frequently uh unfortunately i like you say yes let's have it
 		uh unfortunately i like you say yes let's have it put them all give them all a shot get rid of them
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		why should they be sitting sitting in uh prison getting their college degree
 	
 	
 		well i guess though where i would have a problem with it if i were on the jury
 		that that put that handed down the death sentence because it was my judgement the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s guilty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now that's tougher
 		it's easier to say it on the telephone and everyone agree that yeah the death penalty's the way to go it's a deterrent to crime they shouldn't catch themselves in that circumstance anyway but to be the actual one of the ones that decide that would be tougher for me
 	
 	
 		yes very true i uh i agree with you there uh
 	
 	
 		i think i'd probably do it but we could never say what we would do if we're not in the circumstance it that's that's that's a real easy  thing to say that oh sure i would but i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i myself wouldn't want to be on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> like that
 		uh i it it's uh that's an awful lot to uh to expect of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to uh to kill somebody is what it amounts to
 	
 	
 		well yes but
 		you know that's what they did
 	
 	
 		it true very true but they they did it because they have a warped mind for some reason
 	
 	
 		or rather than have a warped mind it was just the only way to get whatever they wanted
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh
 	
 	
 		and they they wanted something worse than they more than they respect the human life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah exactly
 		well anyhow i guess we both agree that that it is it should be in effect
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hang them yeah
 		yeah i agree it should be in effect also i agree there should be a lot of care in the enforcement uh so i guess i would say i want it to be in effect but i want
 		maybe
 		well i'd i now i have a problem with this too i think our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have too many opportunities for them to go back and get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more chance
 	
 	
 		oh that's true well now any uh just believe in just about any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the union uh uh a death uh or uh yeah death verdict is an automatic uh appeal
 	
 	
 		that's correct it is  it is
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		uh yes i'm inclined to agree with you i think so there should be a limit as to the number of appeals
 	
 	
 		now there's some and maybe now i don't remember if this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or not that has something about all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>
 		can be sentenced to the death sentence
 	
 	
 		um um well no
 	
 	
 		convicted drug dealers
 	
 	
 		not just for dealing in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> it uh
 	
 	
 		is it what is what's the rule
 	
 	
 		there are certain circumstances and i don't remember what they are
 	
 	
 		it's something of the distribution they're on the distribution end
 	
 	
 		uh yes
 	
 	
 		they're not selling them they're distributing them it's for the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> is what it's reserved for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they they are in effect killing people
 	
 	
 		oh oh yes yes i i believe it's any capital crime related to drugs
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i think that's the way it's worded
 	
 	
 		is that how it's worded
 		i knew it was there but i i or proposed or is it proposed or is it passed
 	
 	
 		i do believe that's in
 		uh i wouldn't swear to it myself but i thought it i thought it was in effect
 	
 	
 		i believe it is i believe you're right though i think it is
 		and i have to agree with that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i think it certainly should be one of the options
 		uh i've been fortunate with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> so far that i know i qualify that heavily
 		because you never know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but to the best of my knowledge we haven't had a major problem yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it just touches so many young people
 	
 	
 		oh it does uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> myself
 		and the youngest is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty eight</TIMEX> so they are all pretty well grown up and they all went through it you know going through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and knock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> that uh
 		they have not
 		well i won't say they didn't try it
 		uh i wouldn't know but uh they i doubt very much that they're they're using it now in fact i'm sure they don't
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are about in the same age bracket i thi nk let's see the oldest
 		is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two</TIMEX> and the youngest is probably <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty seven twenty eight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so it's the same age bracket
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and i think one of each experimented very slightly with pot and i think that was the extent of it to the best of my knowledge
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's usually the way it is it it's just uh
 		try it out with their peers
 		and none of them even smoke they don't uh they never been strangely enough uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and i both smoked when they were growing up
 		now my my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> she quit uh
 		well when she was pregnant with the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and she never started up again
 		and i just quit oh about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen months</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's tough
 	
 	
 		yes it is i and it seems to be getting tougher as time goes by
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> hasn't quit yet
 		and
 		he knows he should and he knows and he knows but he hasn't
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i do respect the fact though that he refuses to smoke in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with me he he's
 		very conscious of of passive smoking and he's concerned about it but
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		hasn't quite made it yet
 	
 	
 		well when i was still smoking i i felt that way if i was in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> seated at table with uh non <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> i would
 		try to pick a seat a a my
 		seat where the smoke would blow away from them
 		or i'd hold the cigarette under the table
 	
 	
 		yeah i've seen all of this yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh but uh now i'm on the shoe's on the other foot
 		uh i'm aware of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> smoking now
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX> will actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> will not smoke in anyone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> except our own
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		he will get up and he'll go outside
 		you know and he he's so when we're invited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> he will not smoke in their house
 		which i think is good because there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are very particularly if they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh and he's you know he tries his best but the actual quitting he hasn't done he changed brands to a brand he doesn't like
 		he put up all of his ash trays he will not smoke in a comfortable position you know
 		but still  he's done everything the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Smokers Anonymous</ENAMEX> tell you to do except quit smoking  it's a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it is long process
 	
 	
 		well the
 		there's a trick i use they used to leave my cigarettes in the glove compartment
 	
 	
 		oh how neat
 	
 	
 		and every time i wanted one i have to go outside and just take one
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at a time
 		and uh that that's gets to be uh a deterrent
 	
 	
 		he has his in the kitchen
 		
 		
 	