
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		yeah okay
 	
 	
 		um
 		do you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't do you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> are you are you working at all
 	
 	
 		yeah i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCNB</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and let's see the question was what benefits you consider most important i think uh definitely medical and dental insurance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um life insurance long-term disability uh vacation
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		vacation
 	
 	
 		oh yeah don't ever think of those as a benefit but they sure are
 	
 	
 		yeah and um
 		i think what i don't like some of the policies that our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has that i don't like i don't like their sick leave policy their short-term disability policy and i would like to see them do something about um child care
 	
 	
 		yeah what is their sick leave policy
 	
 	
 		oh it's only like i don't know like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days a year</TIMEX> which is way below the national average
 	
 	
 		is it paid
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh do you get penalized for taking it off
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		the reason why i said is um <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> uh the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 		um they have i'm not sure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to five years</TIMEX> they have a certain number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> they have um unlimited uh personal time off but
 		if they miss more than say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hours</TIMEX> in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three month</TIMEX> period they get penalized for it so really they don't ever huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's not even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> that's not even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> and what if you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> and you're sick for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		the problem is with that is that we work <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> or we work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twelve hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> so no one could even take off a day for pay you know PTO um because they get penalized for it
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they lose their certification pay which is like fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> an hour for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three whole months</TIMEX> so it's really not a very good benefit
 	
 	
 		wow
 		no that's in fact  i wouldn't call that much of a benefit at all
 		i think you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get sick and if you get sick usually you're sick for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a day</TIMEX> and then you know if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> get sick
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have to take time off for that and um
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the biggest thing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come to work sick but when their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get sick it's like well i can't afford to take off but i have to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and i think you know it varies from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> keep track of it and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> don't and it's really unfair you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's true it is it's not really uh consistent
 	
 	
 		but i think you know at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCNB</ENAMEX> in any any work place being a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> i think that child care is my greatest expense and um
 		you know it's it's getting to the point where you just can't afford it anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah i really wish that somebody in big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would take a hint from like that movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine to Five</ENAMEX> did you see that where they had the child care right there on the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right there yes
 	
 	
 		that was so good and that would help the morale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i think so much
 	
 	
 		yes very much very much
 	
 	
 		because i hate to see that i mean probably ninety percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work for me are single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and they have to you know use child care at least for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple hours</TIMEX> a days
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't know i i really think a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> needs to take responsibility for that
 	
 	
 		and i think they should even do something for when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are sick you know provide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		although i know that's not very comfortable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when they're sick they probably just would rather stay home but um
 		you know  my options are you know to either call in sick to take to take him to one of those places that takes care of sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um
 		you know and that's about it you know a lot of times i don't have the option of staying home without you know i just can't you know there's something going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> or you know that i have to be there for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i know a lot of um what i do like though is i see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> taking off and they take turns with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		you know staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but that's still you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are sick a lot
 	
 	
 		i know it's real i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> yet but it's tough
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		um
 		what kind of uh
 		how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation days</TIMEX> do you get a year
 	
 	
 		well  i get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's great for how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you been have you worked there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i got that when i started because i was because i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> of the company
 	
 	
 		oh wow that's great
 	
 	
 		so it depends on if you're an if you're not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> it depends on how long you've been there i think you get like a week <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your first year and then two weeks</TIMEX> and then you have to be there like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> to get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks or four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> just start out at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> and then they go up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		depending on i'm real happy with the vacation i guess you know you could take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation days</TIMEX> if you had to stay home but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> isn't doing very well so like i'm i'm negative vacation because i've only worked there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and i i get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days every six months</TIMEX> well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every about two three months</TIMEX> we shut down for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> because you know there's no demand for our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		i've heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that do that
 	
 	
 		yeah and so we've shut down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks a year</TIMEX> whereas we used to only shut down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		and so it's kind of hurt
 	
 	
 		yeah and you have to use your vacation pay for that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and luckily my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> has maybe you know allowed me to work it off but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know go in the hole and uh take you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> without pay and it's tough
 	
 	
 		oh can you collect unemployment
 	
 	
 		um i don't ever but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work for me do yeah
 	
 	
 		do they
 	
 	
 		i mainly the reason because i'm salary so i don't ever lose pay i mean i just go in debt for vacation so yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		well that's yeah that's not not very good are you satisfied with your insurance
 	
 	
 		um yeah mainly because i haven't had really had to use it much i mean
 	
 	
 		does your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> pay for it or do you pay for it
 	
 	
 		yeah i have to pay for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> which is kind of expensive for him i mean it's like
 	
 	
 		do you have flexible benefits where you can get sort of like pick and choose
 	
 	
 		sort sort of yeah um the reason why i don't know much is because i don't real uh i haven't really had to use like my medical i know they increased the deductible <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> which kind of hurt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know and after that they pay like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eighty percent</ENAMEX> and the dentals the dental covers quite a bit but like i said i've never really been sick or anything so i've never had to use it
 	
 	
 		well i think our our insurance we have to pay for part of it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> pays for part of it but
 		it's expensive but i don't think it's out of line with what other company you know with what other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do it's just that in general it's it's expensive
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and you know i don't i don't like it do you have uh um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that like match savings
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's fifty percent matched
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		how
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> i know are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent matched yeah like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris Semiconductors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 		where are where
 		for a new job
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		ours will only match <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five yeah</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to ten</NUMEX> percent of your salary
 	
 	
 		really
 		ours is only up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> though
 	
 	
 		oh okay well then i guess that's makes a difference
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because i mean i only put in like a real small amount because it's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> you know after after after that you put it in and you get like interest interest i mean i've saved quite a bit it's helped me a lot but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		you have to roll it over to an IRA if you ever quit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know that's still a good deal
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm glad that we that we have that um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that i worked for before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCNB</ENAMEX> was just they were just starting it and uh i think that's i think that's great
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah it teaches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to think of the future i think
 	
 	
 		well yeah because retirement plans now are so bad i don't know about your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> but our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> tries to keep base salaries low and they compensate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> more with bonuses
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and incentive pay rather than raises because it cuts down on their expenses for the pension plan because your pension's going to be based on what your salary was
 		not what your salary plus bonuses where and your your bonuses cut ultimately end up being fifty percent of your salary
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		that's kind of a rip
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are going to that now
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> didn't even give raises <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no they gave uh a few bonuses but for the most part no nobody in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> got raises
 	
 	
 		really
 		gosh that's pretty bad especially with you know inflation and i i've noticed that the cost of living i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and the cost of living has just gone up incredibly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that three years</TIMEX> that i've been here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah your housing housing mostly i guess is where i notice it
 		but you know in in you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids kid</ENAMEX>'s get more expensive as they
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 		
 	