
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay credit cards they leave a bad taste in my mouth
 	
 	
 		uh yeah they've sort of left a bad taste in my mouth too i've been sort of
 		irresponsible <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and i'm still paying for the the my own stupidity
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well the thing i hate about them i went through a divorce
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i will never own another joint credit card
 	
 	
 		oh you're
 	
 	
 		because uh even if in the divorce decree one is agrees to pay it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you're a cosigner on it they'll still come after you
 	
 	
 		if the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> doesn't
 	
 	
 		if the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> doesn't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that that's that's a rotten deal
 	
 	
 		oh i'd i'd say so and isn't it isn't it now on those those cards was it
 		um
 		mostly her that that ran up the bills yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> worth
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't imagine any anybody letting somebody charge that much on a credit card
 	
 	
 		wholly smokes
 	
 	
 		but uh they call me i sent them a copy of the divorce decree and told them i refuse to pay it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's got to be like
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		close to
 		what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> bucks a month
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and they said well i'm sorry even though the card is in her name you you're a cosigner on it
 		and i i threatened you know legal action and everything i i don't know i've sent them a letter and i said i want this removed from from my credit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rating and uh haven't heard anything back but i haven't run a credit check either
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah you might be worth your while to
 		run one of them
 		thirty dollar uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		credit checks just to
 		find out what it says
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but uh
 		that's uh i'll never own another joint
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card
 	
 	
 		i need to find i need my credit card mostly for uh just government travel you know um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and uh
 		i uh i have to go on
 		uh travel quite a bit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors facilities</ENAMEX> and when i do i have to have the hotel and all that kind of stuff but i've been trying to
 		curtail my use of it to to nothing except with the exception of uh
 		of them those type things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i also found out something else uh for your information and i don't know if you're married or not
 	
 	
 		no i'm not
 	
 	
 		but uh one of the credit cards the uh the account was paid off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh it was paid off for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> never even used it
 		and then all of a sudden i got a phone call from them saying uh uh she's behind in her payments and i said well i don't care she's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh they said well your name is still on file as cosigner
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 	
 	
 		so even dormant
 		credit cards you have
 		uh you you have to go and send them a copy and tell them you're not responsible for any bills
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh it it can turn into a mess
 	
 	
 		sounds like it so the the credit card was inactive
 	
 	
 		yeah it was inactive and i never sent them a copy of the divorce decree or anything because they wasn't even mentioned in the divorce decree as to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> would pay what what
 	
 	
 		when you
 		right
 		right
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		because the the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> it was you know don't and it was dormant
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		guess the the bottom line is uh
 		you got to be
 		darn sure you're marrying the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> when you
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		when you do that too but uh
 		i guess a divorce in any
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">circumstance</ENAMEX> doesn't normally they're
 		sir
 	
 	
 		either that or make or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">each</NUMEX> each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> have their own own uh credit card not a joint
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's for sure i know i happen to know of a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> i used to date her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> ran up
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> in credit well i guess they're they are both responsible for the stupid things but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		had a similar situation and then
 		it was almost like he couldn't get a divorce
 		because uh
 		uh i guess she didn't even work or anything and then he would've been
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		strapped with everything
 	
 	
 		yeah he would have been stuck with everything yeah
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i remember
 	
 	
 		about the only credit cards i have now are are gas cards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they're in my name only
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 		i know i'm
 		about uh
 		thinking about doing a getting a consolidation loan just to
 		lump everything together so that and it's down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> payment and then just get rid of all these old accounts and just work on a cash only
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		little yeah
 	
 	
 		system because uh i'm just i am very sort of irked at this
 		at these credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and
 		you know they got you
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh you'll get letters in the mail where they want to increase your credit line
 	
 	
 		and
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		and it also makes it bad because you can't deduct that interest now
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		you know at least you used to get some relief by being able to deduct deduct all that interest and finance charges
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		can't even do that anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i remember uh
 		was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> or they did away with it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well you uh this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this next time it's zero
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well remember my
 		refund on my income tax was a lot bigger
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> than it was this year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's for sure
 	
 	
 		yeah about only the only interest you can deduct now are is a house payment mortgage interest and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and taxes
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		credit cards you can
 	
 	
 		i can't even declare that here because uh in my situation because it's uh
 		uh
 		not until i sell it
 		the the way it works for me because i own it as
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		jointly with my father
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the
 		they've changed those or it's a ends up getting classified as a rental property and it's not
 		classified as a regular family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwelling</ENAMEX> so there's some reason we can't
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		declare any mortgage interest
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you do you or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> either one have it homesteaded
 	
 	
 		um do you mean do we do i live in it or
 	
 	
 		no no homesteaded
 	
 	
 		what
 		what does that mean
 	
 	
 		uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		uh you get a uh
 		a big tax break if you if you
 		call what they homestead it you have to sign a piece of paper that says this is my primary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> and and i live here
 	
 	
 		oh oh and
 		well that would be an interesting situation because i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and uh because i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and um i'm living here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> so i can i can't even vote here
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> but i can't vote
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		that's crazy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's only fair because the reason i'm a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident resident</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> is because they don't charge military income tax
 	
 	
 		oh that's so
 	
 	
 		so and so it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas Texas</ENAMEX> doesn't either
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		at least now
 	
 	
 		yeah or
 	
 	
 		they're they're talking
 		about instituting a uh state income tax
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		everything else that that would bring in money the
 		uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want it but the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and so forth won't pass a bill to do it like a uh lottery
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they've been trying to get a lottery  i think the last poll they had here
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy</TIMEX> percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> voted wanted a lottery
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and yet the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted it down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas House</ENAMEX> voted it down
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they all they want to do is increase property taxes and
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		put a income tax in
 	
 	
 		well
 		i don't know
 		just
 		getting back to the subject of credit cards i think the best uh
 		thing
 		maybe is that even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> charges the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fee is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> card is it makes you pay it every month
 	
 	
 		it makes you
 		right it makes you pay it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i do have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> but i got it through uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diner's Club</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as well yeah they
 	
 	
 		it's a it's a yeah it's a
 		yeah it's a corporate
 	
 	
 		they force us to have yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diner's Club</ENAMEX> and i had an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> of my own i probably if i was smart i'd get rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> and get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		stop paying that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fee on it but
 	
 	
 		yeah and if you're late on this on my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> they write <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		since it's a corporate corporate American
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that that's not good
 	
 	
 		and if you don't pay it you get a call from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> saying why hasn't this been paid
 	
 	
 		yeah oh jeez
 	
 	
 		so you don't dare run up anything on it that you can't you know that you can't pay that's that's the problem with credit cards it it's
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't think of it as cash
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		they think of it like uh monopoly money that hey i can just charge this
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and pay it wherever i feel like it
 	
 	
 		yeah it's like going oh i'll have that money by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX> and then end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> comes around and you get your insurance bill comes and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a few other things and then you're like oh jeez hey
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that feeling
 		
 
 	
 	
 		huh
 		
 
 		so i guess the the secret's not to have credit cards
 	
 	
 		yeah oh well i'm getting to just about to that point myself so
 	
 	
 		well i guess we've been i'm surprised they hadn't beeped in and said your <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> is up
 	
 	
 		yeah really they've been
 	
 	
 		they've been uh even before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> here lately they've been saying
 		you should cut it off
 	
 	
 		oh really i haven't i it i actually haven't timed any of them i just kind of go into conversation
 		ends on it's own or uh or that uh that they do come in with that so well anyway it was nice
 	
 	
 		well listen i've enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		yeah it's nice talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> and uh
 		
 		
 	