
 
     		
 	
 		yeah i think um this is a tough subject because uh when you come from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh the political views are really different
 		i uh i i guess i've had to discuss a number of what might be considered controversial issues
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess like i like and though nothing i guess nothing is as as awful as abortion but like gun control
 		and uh day care and things like that and there are some very different views uh of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> connected with the program which i thought was really interesting you know
 	
 	
 		well now you say you say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> what are are you are you referring to yourself are you
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah well being in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> is um is sort a um is probably liberalism  is a is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hub</ENAMEX> of liberalism  you know compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh you know very um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in many ways uh very liberal very similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> uh i  aren't actually as liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> is a very liberal uh
 		state so so where where here we have um we have gun control laws we probably have some of the strictest gun controls laws in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> vote for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so it really is a different um
 	
 	
 		uh well of course uh you talk gun controls down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and you're asking to be lynched
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's true i talked to a i had to talk about gun control with somebody and i talked with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who actually
 		you know had had had just purchased a gun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> and was going target shooting you know and it was very different it was a whole different view it's really um
 	
 	
 		hm um-hum
 	
 	
 		this has opened my eyes to thinking you know at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i just sat here and thought well how can anybody believe that because i'd really never met <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that did
 		and now i talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do so that's it's really interesting
 	
 	
 		well it's very true now i'm a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> by birth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although i claim <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> as my home now
 		uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> living down there but
 		but i also have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> living elsewhere one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> but i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and i kind of like it down there but they had a gun control law which went a little bit too far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think uh well in your words they were a little bit too liberal
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah isn't it funny
 	
 	
 		i mean they permitted they i believe if i'm correct i believe they permitted to carrying concealed weapons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they uh  quickly did away with it i think in the next session they they uh modified it
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's still legal to own or possess <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well you can possess them here too but they have to be they're registered and uh like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the the Brady Bill</ENAMEX> that's currently being discussed nationally and whatever is very well supported here in gun control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the the one week</TIMEX> uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> delay
 	
 	
 		you have the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> waiting period
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's uh that's
 	
 	
 		well i don't mind that too much now i'm i'm with the NRA myself and uh uh really the only the objection we have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is uh you you give a little and next thing you know uh somebody's somebody's trying to take more
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's very true that's and that's the way most i guess most of the um
 		the political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> work you know the same i know the abortion issue with right to life and right to choose and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and both of them are uh both want the extent of extremes so that they don't give anything for a balance you know there's there's always that difficulty
 	
 	
 		well then tell me do you consider yourself a liberal
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um i would say i'm probably liberal yeah
 	
 	
 		well let me ask you this then how is your what is your feeling
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		about uh uh expressing yourself by burning the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag
 	
 	
 		well i'll tell you
 		i i think you know if they if they didn't give as much coverage to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> that burn the flag
 		it would never happen do you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		it's only because they make a big stink over it but i i guess actually i believe that if somebody wants to burn the flag i guess that's their opportunity their their their right in the sense of freedom of speech but i i would never
 	
 	
 		well now wait a minute there there you just said it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's their right by freedom freedom of speech what does speech have to do with burning a flag
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's freedom that they i think the idea of freedom of speech goes back to and i uh uh the the the whole aspect of being able to display your
 		uh
 		your ideas you know the what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> stands on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> stands on is that they can do that
 		uh though i would never even consider it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a million years</TIMEX> to do it myself i i i think uh
 		you know but i i still what the stands flag stands for i guess to me is that if somebody wants to voice their opinion or display their opinion openly and if that is a a way that they can show their opinion then they should be allowed
 		uh
 	
 	
 		now uh well i i still go back to
 	
 	
 		unless the burning unless the actual fire hinders somebody's health and well-being you know but i i think that's i guess that's i think that's my opinion yeah i guess you feel differently
 	
 	
 		then would you condone the burning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">capitol building</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no but i think that's that's the it's that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>'s money if somebody buys their own flag and and burns it that's fine but that that's you know that's destruction and of of uh
 		public property and whatever
 	
 	
 		uh then you don't draw a line between public property and uh uh uh
 		what a public uh
 		symbol
 	
 	
 		no i don't know i guess the symbolism oh i think what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> stands for is the right to be able to disagree with the government
 	
 	
 		uh yeah but here again i go back to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> amendment you can disagree by speech freedom of speech
 	
 	
 		uh i think that's what's made democracy
 		yeah
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		which has nothing to do with action
 	
 	
 		well that's that's true yeah but i think i i guess
 	
 	
 		now i am i am adamantly against that
 	
 	
 		yeah i i guess i guess the idea you know they always keep saying like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers um</ENAMEX> there uh of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> for the judicial the judicial bench
 		and they always talk about that they they feel that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> believes in the framing of the constitution what the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> the ideals the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> set down and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i believe that the idea of burning the flag is is in my understanding of how it was framed is that you this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> the thing about this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is that you can disagree with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and you can display that
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		uh i guess yeah i guess and and so that as a freedom of expression and speech and whatever i i think that that's viable  um
 		as long as it's your flag and and you've made your your point i think yeah yeah because realistically like for you for you you don't think it's right
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and i would never do it i i love this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> too much and that symbol means a lot to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i guess it's just one of those things where if they if that's what's something if a need for them
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well here again we uh even though you uh
 		physically you agree with me you you wouldn't do it yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah yes
 		no
 	
 	
 		but nevertheless you maintain that it's it is the right of of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> to burn the symbol of their country
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		uh
 		um so long as it's their possession okay you're you're that's fine up to there except that uh the what that flag symbolizes is uh uh is this country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i used to know as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> but all i remember was the red in the flag represented <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> that that was shed to to create this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and to maintain it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and to me that's
 		uh uh a a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that ever  uh carried a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> or killed for his country
 	
 	
 		i agree there too i agree with you there too i i the um
 		i i it's i find it you know personally disgusting but i don't think that i don't think that uh
 	
 	
 		hm um-hum
 	
 	
 		we have a right to stop somebody from that you know the same i don't know i guess i get i get all all mixed up inside when
 	
 	
 		it's very easy to do
 	
 	
 		yeah it gets when it's uh it's an emotional issue and you sit and you try and think about it logically and and and you know you try to say to yourself now emotionally this is a disgusting thing uh but logically
 		um even you know for instance the pro-life pro-choice movement uh you know i don't know anybody that actually supports abortion
 		but they would vote pro-choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you know that's just a disgusting thing you know somebody an abortion means it's somebody's in trouble and that it's an awful thing
 	
 	
 		well i think it should be permitted under certain circumstances circumstances
 	
 	
 		you know but
 		yeah
 		but it that's uh that's what i mean see most but but realistically when you think of it it just sounds like such an awful thing and it evokes an emotional response i think that's the hardest thing i don't know if i could ever be a judge
 		because some things emotionally just aren't you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well tell me has it ever been decided when when is a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> a human
 	
 	
 		no no i think the um
 		sometimes i guess what did i read recently the um the the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
 		uh point is is always the point of well it's at conception
 		but then um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and argues with others that conception is a biblical term and there's no concept of conception in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> or biology
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so then that so that throws out that idea it makes it a religious discussion then so it's i don't know it's very it's it's uh you know it's a it's a topsy turvy world and it's really something how
 		um political ideas and viewpoints within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can vary so much and also within um
 	
 	
 		or they on their own within the own uh society it can vary
 	
 	
 		within a
 		yeah and how yeah how it'll sway from one extreme one extreme to another
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think that uh
 		you know i i just read something i think in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> uh about about um protest on
 		
 		
 	