
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Michelle um</ENAMEX> could you give me a few ideas on what you think is wrong with our public school system
 	
 	
 		um i don't think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> back the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> enough any more like with discipline and and such and i think that the um because of that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are starting to lose
 		oh i don't know lose interest like you know before like they would really try and help you i think and i can see the difference from when i was in high school and my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> are in it now
 		where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> like they can't discipline you whenever you are you know so they just don't even care any more
 	
 	
 		yeah  i'm not sure if that's if that's a condition of of the lack of interest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or if that's a condition of the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX>
 		um  i've got a brother-in-law that was was teaching in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> and they have a  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a a</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		fairly a transient population you know they're um only stationed there for a short period of time so
 		most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> never get to finish high school uh there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two years</TIMEX> and then they have to be they're shipped off some place else  and he teaches uh  he teaches English and he teaches uh shop
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it got to a point where he said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> were coming to him just about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> having him downgrade his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> exams because too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were failing them
 	
 	
 		oh that's not good
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah so in that particular school system um that was that was one of the problems and
 		i guess one of the reasons the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> uh were were putting so much pressure on him was uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were going to them saying you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny or my Mary</ENAMEX> is smarter than that and blah blah blah and they can't fail and so
 	
 	
 		oh you know and that's really bad because that's really hurting them in the long run because up here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> now um we are so far behind the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		they are so far more advanced than we are and a lot of them even know their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> grammar better than i do and they can't speak it as well but i mean to write it is probably better than the way i write it
 	
 	
 		um yeah because they uh they care it's something that they want to learn um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm sure you're you're more uh fluent in other things the things that you're interested in than some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too uh
 		i've been out of school for a long time so you know when i went to school i it was in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> and they had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> grades in the same class
 		so when you're i think it was uh  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second third</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> were in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> so when you went through the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade
 		and you graduated you went to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade you just moved to the second half of the class on the other side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> i found looking back at it now that
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		when i was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade i knew just about everything that was there i had learned it from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade and the same thing with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> i had learned it so it's the amount of teaching you get i think uh
 		um you're like a sponge when you're young you absorb just about everything that they can throw at you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		today
 		well you're you're closer to it now than i am um
 		did you go to high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i did
 	
 	
 		okay so that's you're you're native then
 		to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> so how was your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> did they have with the split out like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were going to college so they took certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were shop
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay yeah we had um college advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and if you were going to college you could take them or if you didn't want to go to college you didn't have to take them but they were optional you know they were there if anyone wanted to take them just because you were going
 		if you if you wanted to take them and you weren't going to college you still could they didn't limit it to just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wanted to college could take them um our math i think we were very strong in our math we were taking tests and our math
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		was um placing like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third and fourth</TIMEX> in like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> where you had to send them in
 	
 	
 		oh that was good yeah
 	
 	
 		and our and our you know for our level and stuff like that you know they had the placing we're placing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third or fourth</TIMEX> but our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> i feel was way below
 		i don't know if i'm just more math oriented but like even on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>'s i scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred more</NUMEX> points on my math than i did in my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and to have that big of a spread is unreal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah um
 		and we were just the opposite up here um i took the same algebra class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in a row same book same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and that's only because of our school system but as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> that taught English which was very unusual for our school system so our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> was
 		probably better than
 		than most of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> in in the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		up here now we're finding that more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of are pulling their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> and they are tutoring them at home
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah i work with uh a couple of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i work with you know share the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> are doing that they've pulled their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> out and they get a much rounder education
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and why that is i don't know i think it's too much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> at the top
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		also i don't know the level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> today are they dedicated like they used to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> or is it just a  it's just a job so they can get the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> off
 	
 	
 		i don't think they are
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how about college
 	
 	
 		i'm very disappointed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> at college they're only required to be in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hours</TIMEX> out of the entire week
 		some of them only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> classes
 		and at the most they probably spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hours</TIMEX> in their classes and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hours</TIMEX> that they're required to be in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten hours a week</TIMEX> they're probably making more
 		i know they're making more than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and he you know he's making like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty five thousand</NUMEX> and a lot of them have like other part like i know a lot of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> and computer
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>  they have other jobs like some of them may be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> and they do accounting you know and this is just to me it seems like it's a hobby to them and i don't and i've even expressed to some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> i don't think it's right
 		as i think they should be spending more time and too they they teach the same class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX> well i know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> he comes up from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> you know and he hasn't changed his tests
 		or  even his you know presenting material in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you can get the notes off someone else and never go to class and just go for your midterm and final and as long as you study those notes from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> you're still going to do fine in his class
 	
 	
 		that's incredible that's incredible
 	
 	
 		and i i i don't think it i don't think it's right at all  just like you're not even teaching any more you don't care you're getting paid whether we show up or not i mean uh i i just i'm very disappointed with the
 	
 	
 		so when he files his lesson plans for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> he just he just drags out the old ones and just files them and nobody even looks at them and all that is fine and
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh yeah he just has the same outlines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> after year
 	
 	
 		so he's getting away with it so is it is it his fault or is it his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
 		or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that he has to respond to report to
 	
 	
 		i i don't know because you know we fill out a student evaluation form <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every semester</TIMEX> you fill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and i know
 	
 	
 		and who does that
 	
 	
 		me and along with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> we we have the same complaints <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX> and nothing seems to be getting done so i don't know if they even
 	
 	
 		who does that go to though who does that evaluation form
 	
 	
 		it's supposed to one's supposed to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> himself and um another is supposed to go to like the administration
 		i don't know if they're just doing it to satisfy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> so they think that we're doing something
 	
 	
 		that's what it sounds like
 	
 	
 		or  <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">th</NUMEX> ey're usually really using it but i know we complain about the same thing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		do they do they ever publish any results um
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		how about the student newspaper
 	
 	
 		um what about it
 	
 	
 		would it be wise to put an article in there say you know we're doing these evaluations and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> we're we're making the same evaluations but yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s not looking at the evaluations
 	
 	
 		oh well you know they've even done stuff like that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are now telling us that these do you know apply they please fill them out properly you know we are really are using them they tell us that but we don't see  any you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what do you think uh can be done
 	
 	
 		i have no clue what you mean i don't know what else we can do
 	
 	
 		as far as um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well one</NUMEX> other's things probably is i don't know if it happens down there but every time the contracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' contracts come up it's just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school season</TIMEX> starts and they all go on strike
 		so they close the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> down until they get what they want
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what's the matter with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> doing the same thing say hey uh we're we want a quality education and we're not getting it let's go on strike you know then see what you're going to do it'll create a lot of headlines that's for sure
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> had a walk out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>
 		
 		
 	