
 
     		
 	
 		i'm actually at work
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and happen to have uh weekend duty here
 	
 	
 		oh okay what <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> do you work in
 	
 	
 		i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Building</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay
 	
 	
 		we we pull mostly evenings we are having there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us uh facilities <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are covering the off shifts
 		just to have somebody here uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to uh
 		see if they need anything
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay
 	
 	
 		oh the how many calls have you made
 	
 	
 		i've only made a few um
 	
 	
 		okay i'm uh getting close to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty this</TIMEX> is the
 		yeah hopefully you have a lot to talk about in this one but i don't really have a lot in this one usually i can talk for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on most of the subjects they pick go ahead you first
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay our topic for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is invasion of privacy so i got a good one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay good
 	
 	
 		when the phone rings and you've got a recording and this always happens like around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five or six o'clock at night</TIMEX> it rings and you get this recording and then it won't go away and any any of the type of solicitation that where they call all the time you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		there are evenings especially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> well we must get in the neighborhood of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from three to six</NUMEX> calls about that time of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call that's where you want to jerk the phone out of the wall you know your sitting down to eat and the phone rings and it's like
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't want anything thank you very much
 	
 	
 		yeah i the worst one i guess is like you when it's a recording i think i don't mind so much someone calls and it's uh
 		and it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesperson</ENAMEX> at least you can chat or whatever and say okay now we want to go and then when when they actually start off with a a computer and expect you to talk to a computer uh that's where i draw the line i just hang up immediately you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		shut my other radio off here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's that's that's real irritating to me
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh i guess they get their name i'm i'm amazed the i was i was question about that uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> would be everyone seems to have an answering machine and i have one too and they say that they can tie up your answering machine and just have a big long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they catch your answering machine
 	
 	
 		they can leave their whole spiel on it
 	
 	
 		yeah they they can erase all your others you know because if you have
 		i think that's the way it is no mine i guess if it's full it will not take it i'm not sure but they can certainly uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> your answering machine so someone else calls you uh and your answering machine is full you know it won't erase
 	
 	
 		um yeah that a
 	
 	
 		but your right that was a good one
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's a high irritant for me drives me crazy
 		and it doesn't matter if you have an unlisted number or not because a lot of times these computer things
 		will just
 		make up numbers at random and just call them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it really
 		really doesn't make much difference as to whether or not
 		you know you have a unlisted number or not and they pass around uh cards that have everybody's name on it like if you order something through a mail order catalog
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know then you'll start getting a bunch of stuff in and a bunch of stuff and a bunch of stuff because they sell their customer list or they sell their catalog list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to different companies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and everything
 	
 	
 		i've got one it's not really an invasion of privacy but it's uh annoyance for me in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> phones you know i they're they're great for an office but this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> next to me who's not here just so i could talk about him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he uses his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> phone all the time and it carries over and so not only would you hear it seems to me that you talk longer for one thing you kind of yell into it
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and so he yells into it and you hear the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> too so it's kind of a double annoyance he actually uh ruins my privacy you might say because the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are so open anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that i'm amazed that in fact i'm i'm about ready to say something uh if he's even thought of that that's a real
 		uncourteous thing an an invasion of everyone else's time and and concentration to just be loud i don't know whether that's an invasion of privacy just being loud and
 		and annoying you know uh that's perhaps not quite an invasion of privacy but i think it is and you we both picked phone items there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		go ahead do you have any more
 	
 	
 		let's see i'm trying to think oh have you heard that that i'm trying to think of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it was there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that was going to
 		uh be giving out information
 		about your financial status
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's that's a good one too yeah i heard something about not that exactly but go ahead
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um i work in the computer science <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and so we hear a lot about things that are that computers are capable of doing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh this was a software program
 		that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was developing that was going to have X amount of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> financial history and information on it
 		and they were going to sell it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> who would up in turn solicit you for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">business et cetera et</TIMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they finally uh stopped production of it because of all the hullabaloo it caused because it was such a big deal and i wouldn't have been too thrilled about it either i mean there was a lot of stuff going on about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i uh heard something similar to that i listen to i'm a uh uh
 		a talk show person
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and other words when i when i do my chores i put the radio i'm a radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i guess is what i mean and so i listened to was it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five seventy</NUMEX> which has continuous talk on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Sperry</ENAMEX> and everybody i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterinarians</ENAMEX> and all that and uh i don't know if it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or whatever it was talking about when you make out a financial a financial application
 		all that information on there is really not necessarily even a your social security number you know they you should just put down the basics and put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> A where you don't want to answer
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whether it's your personal salary or whatever uh if your just making out a credit card application you don't need to put down
 		and i was curious as to what you know what specific things you you did have to put down but he says social security you don't need to put that down there which i thought was surprising so maybe there's something along that same line where you know in all these
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		financial uh applications that you make out you don't have to put all that stuff down there it would be nice to know what's what was
 		of course of course they could say well i can't give you a card and you could say fine but you know some things will be private you know but he said just put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N A</ENAMEX> and he said usually you'll get approved anyway because they just want your
 		money anyway they want your card
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but if you don't feel like putting it down just put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> A you know
 	
 	
 		um-hum well that's real interesting i know that a lot of times they ask for information that they don't really need on several things
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know your credit application and that all all they ever need you to do is give them permission to to pull a credit thing on on yourself and there it is that's all they really care about they just want that credit history to see if you're a liable person
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you're going to go ahead and pay your bills on time and things like that
 	
 	
 		i haven't i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> down at the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> but i heard that they were really upset about the drug thing and we seem to up here have just breezed through that and apparently some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are having trouble that i don't have any trouble with it
 		uh it's kind of unusual here we are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> you know
 		the biggest location and and it just breezed through and wasn't really no one was i guess was really too concerned about it uh
 		yet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> there there were whether it was a class action or how far it got i don't really know because <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 		only had a few things on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> News i think about it that they were objecting to but uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> object to that which i don't mind
 		uh problem at all you know
 	
 	
 		oh i know that there's several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've talked to that really have a problem with it and i'm former military so you get kind of used to to going through stuff like that you know you don't pay any attention to it i mean once you sign over your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> might as you know you just kind of
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah right
 		right
 		
 
 		i know
 	
 	
 		kind of blow it off but so
 	
 	
 		i know yeah i served my time too yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have who have been down that route or have had it to deal with anything like that have learned you know
 		it's just one of those things you just do it and be done with it and don't worry about you know but i do know that there are several sites i didn't i wasn't aware that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> was one of them but i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson City</ENAMEX> was one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh did they object too
 	
 	
 		yeah there's there's several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that have been having real trouble with the issue
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the but also on things that i'd heard too from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> meeting was that
 		there were people
 		uh there were the same places where they had a real bad problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fighting it were also places they had a big bad problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> usage too
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm i'm all for it i
 		uh it doesn't bother me that whether they do it in high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or you know carry it to wherever you want to carry it really uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh of course that would really be a big thing in a public school but uh i'm saying certainly at work i have no problem with it uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i think it is they they found that it's been very low really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess maybe at the locations though i don't know if they have it done but done it by location i don't really know if uh they need to publish that really
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think it's a
 		necessary thing to publish it they just need to deal with it and  on an individual basis i mean if they're going to do it just deal with it and be done with it
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right
 		but i think that was an actually actually a good thing that happened uh i never considered it i guess it's an invasion of your privacy but it's something that is for the good of so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know to have everyone uh take the test randomly and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and hopefully maybe some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will convince other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that well uh i might as well get off you know if i want to stay so uh you know if that was an invasion of privacy maybe it was good
 	
 	
 		um or
 		well i think it's a safety factor too because you know when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are inebriated whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or whatever they are very unsafe for the their coworkers you know it's like
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fireman</ENAMEX> and i can just imagine if you know  you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> being on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they go there and and you know you've got somebody that's supposed to take care of you and they fall they fall out because of the drug issue you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean you can forgive somebody because all of a sudden they maybe get hurt or whatever that that you can understand but the blatant use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		will uh be a problem
 	
 	
 		go ahead you got me more i this is this is a tough one i don't really haven't thought about any of this they had gardening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and auto repairs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i could
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	