
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">okay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> time well what do you think of about the budget here you first
 	
 	
 		oh well i think it needs some drastic uh
 		drastic drastic help  um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i i think there's a lot of waste that that could uh that would be cut out
 		if we could get uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to be less less of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		and um
 		i i think it needs to be given a really high priority because i i think it has a horrible effect on the economy and and what we can do as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and everything else
 	
 	
 		i know that we're affected uh directly uh at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> because of uh
 		the defense budget cuts but i certainly think that's one of the the things that they're doing already which is uh which which was  needed to be done for probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		sure
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		although with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> situation and all the world situation changing the way it is uh
 		it certainly needed i the obvious one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all talk about that i still don't understand is uh i'm at work let me turn my radio off here
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is uh
 		all the foreign aid i you know it's over it's a fifty years roughly since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't understand why we're i understand that we support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> but why do we have to give them cash
 		rather than just selling them
 		military things at a discount or something i don't get the idea the idea of giving people <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three billion dollars</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right i i have a hard time with that too now i can understand
 		uh for instance the uh
 		the situation in say the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> where they needed some cash to jump start their economy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't see where we i mean i think it's crazy to be just pouring money into an economy that's obviously mismanaged for instance um
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i think that we should give humanitarian aid and that's it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i think we can loan <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or or relief relief aid or whatever you want to call it but i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		not cash money i think you can send them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> in other  words i think that helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to send them money i don't i don't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		see under any circumstances where you send anybody money
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure i understand the i i guess there's a
 		a a reason for that and i i just don't know enough about it to understand the sense of it because
 		it's not an obvious i i mean on the surface there's no obvious reason why we should be doing that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i have to agree with you there
 	
 	
 		i'm amazed that neither neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or or the which i guess they're independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> too
 		why they don't talk about it i mean they don't bring it up at all why you would think they'd be real having a real campaign with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or the other
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		and they never talk about it they just keep doing it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that there's some kind of justification there and i don't know what it is
 		and i don't know if i agree with it or not yeah
 	
 	
 		i i just like to hear them talk about it you know i like to hear some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> at least
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		say well let's let's bring this before let's examine every one of our foreign aids
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and look like like they did with the defense with the military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> they they investigated all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rightfully</ENAMEX> wrongly wrongfully whether which ones should be closed i don't know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		at least they looked at it i think they should look at foreign aid and say hey which ones do we not need to give you know
 	
 	
 		right well you know the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other</NUMEX> thing is that you have all this this this all this partisan politics
 		where you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's representing a particular state
 		and he says well my my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> it would advantageous
 		if the  if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> spent money to uh you know to investigate uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato blithe</ENAMEX> or something you know and that's and there is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of that and
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		i know that is amazing
 	
 	
 		and that is just a horrible waste of money i think and it's and it's done because some
 		constituent  you know i  well it's done because they want to impress the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are going to vote for him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh if if there was a way to get around that and i think i think some of that could be avoided if we put uh uh a finite term on on some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> um
 		uh  uh you know stay in office um
 	
 	
 		oh i agree with you there
 	
 	
 		i i think they would have they wouldn't have time to i mean they'd have to
 		i think their incentive would be to go out
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or and making their mark on history and they wouldn't even be wasting their time on little piddly stuff that's just draining draining money
 		uh instead they'd concentrate on doing something that was significant um i would hope so anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month or so ago</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> i think it was
 		where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> i think it was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and i probably will will screw that up but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he wanted to start
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		another drug <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in his state
 		and no one was asking for it but him
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and he got the money approved got it approved by tagging it on to some other bill
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it didn't you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsman</ENAMEX> asked him what what no one is asking for this why do you you know
 		and it was just totally a boondoggle i mean it was just uh him wanting to build something that nobody wanted
 	
 	
 		yeah sure
 		right well that's that's you know that's the catch word <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is drug you know drug fight drug
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean he got himself
 	
 	
 		but the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> wasn't asking for it he was asking for it you know which didn't make any sense at all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah  i don't know  he it looked can look good on his resume resume
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it is amazing how the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> just start are totally in another world once they get elected
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah oh yeah and well you know it's like
 		i've i've really gotten cynical i guess as i've gotten older but i've i've been watching you know the the campaigns and stuff and it's it just it's just amazing how little anybody really says
 	
 	
 		right or well duh i thought you were going to say what they do
 	
 	
 		oh that too
 	
 	
 		i i've been trying to go over in my own mind when they say
 		we're gonna really if you vote for me we're gonna control crime and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they don't do anything nothing they don't have they had any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or anybody every done anythin g against crime and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		right right
 		well
 		no
 		no i mean and because it's you know  and it's because nothing is black and white
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know you just can't go up and go up there and say well we're going to we're going to stop crime now
 	
 	
 		right yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		if it were that simple somebody would have done it a long time ago
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 	
 	
 		and that's what kind you know they there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that says well we'll we'll never raise taxes or we will raise taxes or you know it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who says you're never going to raise taxes
 		doesn't isn't realistic about what he sees about what he's doing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who says well we should raise taxes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		will raise them but but it will all it the money will not help anything that's what kills me um  you know the for instance here here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they're talking about uh an income tax
 		well i could almost support an income tax if they reduced or got rid of the sales tax
 	
 	
 		right yeah you can't double up yeah
 	
 	
 		but nobody's talking about that they want both you know  no i know and they never go away they just get higher and there's more of them you know
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		exactly they never go away
 		the
 		the funniest thing i heard lately about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> uh joke was uh
 		uh do you know how you can tell it when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> is lying
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		his lips are moving
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah my favorite yeah yeah yeah my favorite one about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's made it to the top because he didn't have what it takes to make it at the bottom
 	
 	
 		that that that that see that covers is all you know
 		right yeah but it it is the budget thing is just and i don't know why they don't talk about it logically it's always always uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		again the only thing i guess they're doing logically now is the defense which is certainly hurting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> to a degree although we've done so well with the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> War we got a lot of good positive press
 		with all the exotic uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX> and i think we'll get a lot of those you know but uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you you need to close so many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> and you need to cut out some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> or i mean some uh programs and all
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and they're doing that i think that's that's really good even though it it hurts a lot bit you know
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah the the problem is that the budget is so complicated
 		and what they're doing are the things that are easy they're making the easy choices
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well then that's probably true
 	
 	
 		and and uh um
 		and it's and i think part of it is that the budget you know the the economy and the budget is too complicated
 		for a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> i mean they can't comprehend um
 		you know what it takes what it needs they just don't have the expertise the other thing is they can't it's too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's not in their
 		political career interest to make some of the hard decisions that are going to need to be made
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and so what you do is you do the obvious things you know and and they they don't really help all that much i mean sure they help some and i'm sure
 	
 	
 		right
 		i don't
 		go ahead i was going to say i know you mentioned it but i don't know why we can't change the laws where there the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> and the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> just have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> or or terms because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think that uh is you know you don't want someone in there forever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> go in there forever and that's that's their whole life then
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s life and every one of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> gets on it has got a job you know it's ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well uh you know i think uh it's got to come from the you know it's it's got to be
 		you know there certainly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> aren't going to introduce that as a bill so so so you know if something like that's going to happen it's usually because somebody's
 	
 	
 		right there you go there you go
 	
 	
 		you know somebody has gotten angry enough and has got the time an the energy to to you know have to to develop something from the from the you know ground swell level
 		you know where you get a petition up and you you know get signatures and you call for a referendum and it's not easy it's not easy
 	
 	
 		no that's true
 		maybe that long-term though i think that is a a factor that is to keep the
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh rotating you know keep them moving uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and not get the career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah there's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> i thought that keep saying will that that never was meant that the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> would make a career it was just something that you would serve like in the military
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then you'd be done you know
 	
 	
 		that's right well you know it and and what was supposed to be uh so healthy about our our former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is that these were
 		regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were who you know these were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> and the janitors and the uh who were in there for their brief period of time to do their to to to serve proudly and
 	
 	
 		right right
 		right
 		right
 		right
 		
 		
 	