
 
     		
 	
 		anyway what are your what are your first comments on that
 		subject
 	
 	
 		uh  my first comments on the budget
 		i would say there has
 	
 	
 		what would you start cutting first what would be the first thing you'd cut
 		defense
 	
 	
 		surprisingly no
 		i would i would cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> systems and let them self-support
 	
 	
 		mean private enterprise
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		have private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise enterprise</ENAMEX> do it
 	
 	
 		you mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh they're already talking about it i mean they're talking about um
 		having it uh as a
 		you know business
 		uh to
 		uh you know to so the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't have to deal with it
 	
 	
 		i hadn't heard that
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah because i think it's all funded either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> or federally funded so or uh obviously so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		but to me
 	
 	
 		but see they're
 		they don't have enough um
 		um
 		you know there's there's not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and that and that uh to continue funding it they think they need to
 		maybe have uh you know private you know business
 		private enterprise come in so
 	
 	
 		well see the other way i'm thinking about is they should be self-supporting like um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> make
 		license <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plates</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> or small industry inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> anything to where they can be self-supporting within themselves in other words they're in there for a purpose put them to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rather than sitting there it's the same thing like the whole criminal i shouldn't say criminal but the whole police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> i feel the same way
 		uh someone gets picked up for drunk driving he should put enough in there that goes back into paying for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> being out there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's self defense you know self-defense on that point
 		um
 		as far as my defense
 		budget
 		uh they're cutting it back now what <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> percent i wouldn't want to see it cut any more than that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but again i'd like to see something on the other end back into education but not in the education we have today
 		so i'm lost on that one
 		i would like to be a little more
 		into investigating some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the world and their educational problems
 		and to come up with something a little better than what we've got
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah its tough to to say what um
 		you know what uh as far as this  that good or bad or what but uh i was just talking to somebody else and
 		all those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> they pay all the way through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 		they so uh
 	
 	
 		well not so much pay i'm not trying to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> put out any more
 	
 	
 		no yeah i know what you are saying but i'm just saying that even the differences uh is that you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to go to through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and etcetera but here
 		it you know it's just up to high school
 	
 	
 		yeah but see we don't even push the fact to the high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that there's other means of education out there rather than college
 		to go either as an apprentice which they they do in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> just doing this which i think would bring the education back up
 		you know why not an apprentice out to a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and learn from down on the bottom as a wood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> or
 		you know just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX>
 		you can learn on the job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which of course again which mean would mean again our education budget will go down if this is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> i mean it's not going to be overnight
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but that would come down
 	
 	
 		i think the program you know that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason uh
 		you know we do have the education is that what it takes for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to bring somebody on board uh
 		they're not willing to you know to put that you know
 		the training for only a certain amount so
 		um it's you know
 		as far as the technical side
 		but uh
 		even like one one of the biggest things now is like
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paralegals</ENAMEX> and stuff i mean they they're trying to get more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into that field but they can't just bring somebody in
 		without even having gone to you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in that area before they can work
 		you know for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		excuse me i see it being done i know of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that works for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> that has had no training whatsoever and she's training her
 	
 	
 		um-hum well yeah i i'm well yeah i you know i'm assuming that it can be done uh my perspective is that you know i've been with a couple of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> now and it's like they'd are unwilling to put the time in
 		you know they want somebody you know when they then when they bring them off
 		bring them in that they have something you know a certain amount to contribute obviously there's uh uh you know there's a lot to learn
 		uh after that but
 		but uh that's true i'm i'm sure there's a lot of um
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are small you know small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that could uh let me change my channel i've got a cordless phone let me see if that clears this up
 		
 
 		is that better
 	
 	
 		yes  wow
 	
 	
 		okay
 		and
 		yeah it was a cordless phone and all of a sudden we had a bad uh frequency there or something so we had some interference so i changed that
 	
 	
 		yeah it sounded you were calling from around the world somewhere
 	
 	
 		anyway so um
 		but uh you know i think uh
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		they maybe they need to uh help promote that more give incentives like uh if they do bring somebody on they will pay some of their costs or give tax breaks or whatever it is you know for them to train people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know stuff like that programs like that you know i don't know you know what kind of options they've got
 	
 	
 		well that's something about what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s supposed to be doing something similar to that right now
 		and uh they have jobs out on you know bulletin boards so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know what is open for an apprentices in different fields
 		but see that again would cut some of our budget down for education but build up our education with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> per at high school level
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which i would like to see rather than so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> getting out of school they're they go on the unemployment list before we have turn around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they don't have any education i don't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and i'm for college but there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't want their higher education as far as quote quote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is concerned they've had it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i just heard something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> it was like only
 		it was either <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">sixty percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> percent
 		go to college
 		and then out of that percentage only so many
 		can get their degree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i thought that was interesting
 		but uh you know most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i knew have gone and got their degree so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but
 		there's a lot of them out there that haven't
 	
 	
 		yeah well i just you know i uh was basic in a you know middle upper middle class area and
 	
 	
 		so that's
 	
 	
 		yeah so i think uh that demographic area there you know a lot of them do go on
 		and they go to college etcetera
 	
 	
 		well it seems to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are get out of high school that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have gone to college and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> here and college there that are really not interested in going to college and forced into it
 		usually are your drop outs where if they're said hey it's just as advisable to go into something you enjoy and you like
 		because you can get just as far as being a journeyman carpenter or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electrician</ENAMEX> or plumber or anything else like that make as much money and if they enjoy it more they'll make a lot happier life for themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		question you threw that question on me about the deficit put it on your shoe now what would you do
 	
 	
 		well as  as far as the you know the deficit that's a whole nother
 		uh my perception of the budget you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and they have so much to spend and there's not enough money to spread around but the deficit basically is that the trade surplus between the other countries
 		and that we have more money or goods you know more money going out and too many goods coming into this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know  and um
 		you know part of that problem i think is still you know uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> still does not let us compete fairly in their country
 		and and obviously the the demand for their goods is quite high here so they can get their goods in here
 		and um you know to start even that out we need to continue to you know at least threaten that you know we're going to give them higher tariffs etcetera to raise their prices to you know ours
 		but um
 		it's just that uh
 		they're in
 		i think you're you're going to find that just because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> you know there is such a demand here the market you know and uh
 		uh the money you know money being spent and the goods flow in and we don't sell you know we don't uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> products abroad as much as we bring in so
 	
 	
 		were you watching i think uh one of the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> i couldn't even tell you which one i watched but they had on there where the
 		the output from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was basically from smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> rather than the larger ones are exporting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	