
 
     		
 	
 		i pay a good deal of taxes i guess because i i make a fair amount of money and uh the taxes that i pay um i guess as a as a general statement i feel i
 		i guess i get my money's worth for
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure though whether i feel
 		i guess i am sure that i feel that in general though
 		uh the allocation uh of the taxes in certain areas isn't isn't correct
 	
 	
 		well i'm sure that uh probably every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would agree with you on that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because everybody has a different idea of where the money should go
 	
 	
 		well i i lately i guess um uh or at least for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty twenty years</TIMEX> or so i've felt that the expenditures of our taxes into high
 		cost uh defense items at least in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> have been uh there's been and extraordinary amount of
 		money spent there and i'm not really sure that that we've gotten our money's worth there
 		uh regardless of the outcome of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Desert Storm uh Desert</ENAMEX> Shield uh situations
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i guess my particular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> is that having participated in the military military off and on over the over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of being called back and things of that nature is uh i've found that you know there's an extraordinary amount of waste i take that as a
 		as a given in any military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah no argument here
 	
 	
 		yeah and i guess i i should imagine that that that what the what the problem why i i'm i'm a little concerned about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is that this uh rather uh quick and
 		and easy i don't know i shouldn't say easy rather quick victory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">in</ENAMEX> in the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> uh uh over the uh Iraqis uh
 		might lead us into uh a false sense of security that we can do that against any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> i'm i i don't know what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> that would be but
 		uh i i'm just getting nervous again now hearing the voices come up that there has to be increased expenditures in that area
 	
 	
 		yeah well of course uh a lot of uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and things were expended in the course of fighting the war and the and the inventory's going to have to be restocked
 		uh on now i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and one of the things we were told is
 		like they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Harm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> which <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> for and they used up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> of them in in the war
 		so they're going to have to do another contract to restock that to get ready in case something else is needed
 	
 	
 		yeah but it it it it would that be uh well let's see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven thousand</NUMEX> that's about a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">per cent</NUMEX> uh i i should imagine that
 		that would be to keep it at a level those levels i guess that that were originally appropriated was was when
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> threat i guess was perceived as being
 		a greater one i don't think there's very much of a threat there today
 		i do worry about what nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> are left in the territories uh in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> over there and who's controlling them but
 	
 	
 		that that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		i i don't know what amount of what amount of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware</ENAMEX> would stop some fanatic i guess from doing anything
 		uh that would be irrational
 	
 	
 		well of of course now we used up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> per cents <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">per cent</NUMEX> of that inventory in a matter of just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh uh uh TI</ENAMEX> also makes the  missile which was the the TV laser guided bombs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and a big percentage of that was expended as well that  that was that was just a matter of
 	
 	
 		what what is the name of that
 	
 	
 		uh it's called Paveway
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and uh a big percentage of that was used up during that conflict also
 		so those those are two
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> stands to to gain some some short term business to restock that
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i i'm what i'm uh i guess uh it concerned about talking about the taxes in general and
 		that that was an area that i i perceive as not being the best expenditure for the amount of dollar that we're taxed for
 		uh in the area of defense or perhaps we have paid too much there i don't know it just seems to me that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> now the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">and</ENAMEX> and it's
 		it's a cliche i i but i see it myself i see where the infrastructure is sort of breaking down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no doubt
 	
 	
 		i i i don't know uh i know i'm familiar with some some upbeat school areas so i don't totally agree with the the great
 		uh uh with the with the great expenditure expenditure of effort and time there but i guess overall because i guess i'm not associated with what ghetto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		and uh rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> are like i i should imagine that would take an enormous expenditure
 	
 	
 		yeah as a matter of fact in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> um
 		we've had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX> funding system declared unconstitutional
 		by the a state judge
 		and they and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> just passed what they called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood Bill</ENAMEX>
 		which basically what it does
 		is it takes extra money from the more affluent school districts that are that are you know come from local taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and send them to other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that are not so affluent
 	
 	
 		that they don't have a broad based income tax that funds the educational system or is it all funded out of local taxes
 	
 	
 		uh well
 		okay to give to give you some perspective this this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that i had lived in for sometime
 		in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty three</NUMEX> was funded <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">sixty five per cent</NUMEX> by state funds
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then we had a number of education reforms
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> said hey we got to do this we got to do this we got to do this but they forgot to put in the state budget
 		the money to pay for it and they dumped it all on the local school districts
 	
 	
 		sounds like the way the federal and state system works now yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		really so
 		so what ended up happening was was a was a shift we went to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">sixty five per cent</NUMEX> state funding to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">sixty five per cent</NUMEX> local funding in a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 		and uh
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		uh do you mean a a complete reversal
 	
 	
 		oh complete
 		complete it's all shifted to local districts
 		and now even the money that's been raised for the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> is being
 		is going to be siphoned off and sent to other parts of the state
 	
 	
 		because i guess they can't raise that money in those those poorer districts huh
 	
 	
 		that's right and and i have i have no problem
 		with uh a certain
 		uh floor level minimum level that's a standard uh that everybody uh ought to be able to have uh but i am opposed to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		any attempts to restrict um local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> from taxing themselves above that to provide above the minimum
 	
 	
 		yes i see what you're saying uh i uh i i do i i guess i am a strong uh a strong and staunch supporter of some subsidy
 		for any forms of education i mean by that i mean
 		i'm a product myself i have uh a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a</NUMEX> a background of uh being uh getting my college education through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI Bill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so did i my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s anyway
 	
 	
 		what but  uh when i look at it to me uh it doesn't really make any difference it was a marvelous opportunity that i couldn't have done
 		i don't think i would have gone on unless i had that financial
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">easement</ENAMEX> made possible
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and i i don't really care what it takes to qualify whether you're uh an an
 		whether you're a veteran or whether you i don't even know if you have to perform community service or unless uh or or you promise to even do something in the future i think that uh the
 		that that
 		the subsidy itself or i gu ess the enactment of that form of legislation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would give many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who i i think i i think i perceive the fact at least what i read is that some younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel that education is priced out of their
 		uh out of their uh budget i know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> uh adjourned and uh they had completed a fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">per cent</NUMEX> increase in the
 		in the uh state land grant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> which which isn't i mean to me it doesn't sound like a mot of money but i guess it would be for fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> they went from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh for an out of state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> the tuition went up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty five per cent</NUMEX> i don't know what that would be
 	
 	
 		yeah they had to they had to raise uh community college taxes here
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> too
 	
 	
 		but that uh i guess that goes along with the general idea that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had to uh was expending so much money on defense uh that
 		that the program now is a uh program now is uh fees that that fund these things i guess that's trickled down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now establish uh don't have enough money so they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they must charge fees uh i i i'm not too sure of that reasoning
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i guess to get back to the main topic i don't know whether i pay too much taxes i
 		i i travel extensively in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and see enormous uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay pay uh a great deal
 		in taxes they tell me when i sit and talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there they tell me they
 		they some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> they pay uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> or in
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> in some cases <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in my income level at least allege that they pay up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of their gross income in taxes
 	
 	
 		oh oh i can believe that
 	
 	
 		but but i'm not too sure when i put my property tax in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> tax my income tax
 		and these myriad of uh now it costs me money to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> some sort of a tax to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> some sort of an airport departure tax
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh uh a tax a sales tax which is getting to uh quite high levels i'm not sure that i'm not up fairly close to that
 	
 	
 		well i guarantee you you'd be paying a lot more in taxes if if uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> had
 		more say
 	
 	
 		you really think so
 	
 	
 		yeah i really do
 	
 	
 		but i mean what what's what's happened here is is is i feel that that in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 		uh my taxes have gone up they haven't gone down i pay  uh quite a bit more taxes and and and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		every everybody is
 	
 	
 		but that's been a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well what what what they've been able to do is slow down the rate of increase
 	
 	
 		well i
 	
 	
 		to keep it to keep it becoming from becoming even more obnoxious
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well this has been really interesting and i've enjoyed our talk
 	
 	
 		okay uh i guess i just push something here push <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> again right
 	
 	
 		no you just uh we just say say good-bye and that's it
 	
 	
 		just hang up
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Don</ENAMEX> good talking with you
 	
 	
 		nice talking with you too
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	