
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the basic question is too much
 		and
 		i don't know my my opinion i guess here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> they announced that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> second was the uh tax day that's when you everything you've earned so far has gone to taxes
 		the rest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> is yours
 		that represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a third</NUMEX> of your income
 		and i don't know uh who came up with that figure but i think it really comes out to be more than the third
 		but uh i i don't know i find myself in a position sort of like selective
 		approval almost like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> campaign where you agree with most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> but uh don't agree with some of them
 		and
 		i think that we could have less tax
 		by cutting out some of the
 		the uh
 		programs that we support
 		but overall i guess we're pretty fortunate nature <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as far as the amount of tax that we have to pay how do you feel
 	
 	
 		well i i've lived overseas you know it's with in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and i see what kind of taxes they pay in other countries
 	
 	
 		yeah i've done some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> overseas in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and of course know about the we hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> with their
 		uh social program but you don't hear what the cost is same in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> much higher tax rates
 		but the
 	
 	
 		it just seems as if
 		from the time i've been following politics which was i guess about seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> really got interested in politics and keeping up with it
 		it just seems since that time the bureaucratic machine has just gotten so out of control
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and then they scream about that
 		that or the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> scream about they're going to try and not raise taxes but they vote in a raise for themselves every year
 	
 	
 		oh yes that that's the uh the type of thing that really irritates me where they can get significant increases when everyone else is facing layoffs or or cutbacks or
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> equating it to a personal income situation
 		and yet it's almost automatic or it's hidden and
 		uh i think they need to bite the same bullet that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> do
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the other problems that i have recently is
 		centered on such things as the trip by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta Georgia</ENAMEX> to play golf
 		and i realize that constant communication is necessary
 		especially when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had his
 		heart rhythm problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> but
 		we can always send <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> for someone i think if if they're out of pocket
 		rather than accepting it as the norm for a nice golfing trip
 		so that's what i meant about the selectives some things i think we're doing extremely wrong could save a lot of money
 		but other things uh
 		like i enjoy seeing money spent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> i think it's one of the nicest national treasures and i love to see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of uh any background roaming through and seeing such great collections
 		but
 		then when when we talk about all the foreign aid that we give away
 		that bothers me a lot
 		i don't know how to solve the problem though when as you said the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> gets out of hand regardless of who you vote for
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> continues too
 	
 	
 		i i have trouble understanding the entire concept of foreign i understand going into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where they've had natural disasters
 		and going in and giving relief aid that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but paying for their these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to run their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i think it's way
 	
 	
 		i i've got a big hang-up with that
 	
 	
 		it's way out of hand i'm almost turning into an isolationist
 		which is not not a good attitude in in global uh communications and everything that we have this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> but it's a matter of uh
 		i hate to see money thrown away and that's what i really i equate to some of our foreign aid policies
 	
 	
 		it just seems like they keep saying we're helping this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or we're helping that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		and they
 	
 	
 		wouldn't our money be better spent helping here at at home
 	
 	
 		i agree i think that's
 		i have some problem with social programs at home in terms of making it too convenient to be on on welfare
 	
 	
 		that's something i would and that subject in itself i'd love to see that entire thing revised
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i i think when you get to a point where it's more economical to stay on welfare than it is to get a job you've got a basic concept problem
 	
 	
 		something's got to change
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and turn drastically
 	
 	
 		but i i think uh if we're going to waste money i'd almost see rather see us waste it at home
 		than overseas too and that there's some unusual
 		things which can occur in the foreign aid uh
 		by a stroke of a pen i think our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can forgive foreign debt and that's a lot of power vested in one
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in our system of uh
 		governance
 		and i've seen that happen
 		over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> and you and i are paying for it
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX> it comes back a lot to the same thing that you said initially you've been overseas and have seen
 		other places
 		and i guess we're still fortunate but i think we're just i just want us to be smarter
 		than we are
 	
 	
 		well we've got
 		it's not like this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> doesn't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with the knowledge we've got it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are willing to make change
 		but as long as you've got career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> that spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five to forty five years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 		playing power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> they're not going to do anything to tap tap out the well
 	
 	
 		yeah well your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> to the north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> just voted for state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> term
 		no let's see
 		i forget was it one term or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> term
 		fixed
 		uh incumbency in other words they can't be reelected reelected after
 		i think maybe the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term
 	
 	
 		now that's something i would love to see happen not only in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> but in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		federal
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terms then they got to sit out one
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it takes away the issue of of a lot of the uh special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist groups</ENAMEX> and everything else
 		creating the incumbent uh
 		about
 		invincibility invincibility
 		but
 		there's another problem with that i'd we've got some good ones and i hate to see them leave
 		but it i guess it's hard to to really uh
 		identify which are the good and which are the bad
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> seems to be putting them all back in
 		and i thought this last election would be different but it it turned out it really wasn't
 	
 	
 		and i think
 		the thing about the ones that are really up there doing what they were elected to do it doesn't matter if they're in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or not if they have to sit out a term fine they're going to be able to do things behind the scenes
 		either in the capacity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> or in
 		working within their party of of the state or national level to get things enacted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's not going to slow them down at all
 	
 	
 		uh it doesn't solve the non elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats bureaucrats</ENAMEX> either that's
 		that's an issue i think that really fits into it because there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that sit
 		in the same position and really don't give a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hoot</ENAMEX> who gets elected
 		they still kind of run the show and and setup all the roadblocks and the
 		the uh
 		horrendous regulations and everything else
 		but it's uh
 		it's our system i think now we have to figure out how to really manage it well
 	
 	
 		i think compared to the other systems that are out there without a doubt we've got probably the best system it just needs some fine tuning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh i think that's right
 		well
 	
 	
 		well the quest ion is who who's ready to put their hand on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> wrench and tighten the first bolt
 	
 	
 		yeah How do you feel about the information we get uh
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that that affects us as far as the uh
 		knowledge to to elect the right people
 		i have i have a real problem federal register for instance
 		uh you can have almost put anything in there you want to
 		no it's not in the federal register what's the uh the congressional record
 		uh someone can put in information retroactively to that to show that they supported something or uh
 	
 	
 		trying to get
 		the um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to actually truthfully
 		report what they did vote for what they didn't vote for when they were actually on the floor at their desk
 		is almost is going to be impossible to do
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 	
 	
 		there is no accountability of them
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		at any given time if you've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	