
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well i'll tell you why i feel so i feel strongly about this topic i don't know a whole lot about the immigration laws but i do know that in the where i live and i teach school
 		there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Orientals</ENAMEX> that have come here and there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too which is not neither here nor there but the fact is that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientals</ENAMEX> that are here are very affluent
 		uh very wise in money matters and have taken have taken over a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and have really
 		kind it's kind of scary because they're so bright they're all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that i have that are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> are really far above
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are unbelievable because they are just on the way up and money is their main goal
 		and it's kind it really is kind of scary because there's there's just oodles of them and you can not believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that have been taken over by Orientals
 		and it's kind it's kind of scares me not that i don't want them here and not that i don't appreciate the fact that you know that they have rights too but  on the other hand you feel like almost they're they're invading us to the point where they're going to take over
 	
 	
 		right actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> once said that that perhaps um what we should do is is buy a little square of land some place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> and and that might be the solution
 	
 	
 		i think probably that's a good idea because i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> for about for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten years</TIMEX> before i came here and i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it it really and there is there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here because we're so close to the border and and they are wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and i'm not you know i don't want to deny them their rights just that you you feel like when you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		were born and raised here and you worked real very hard to make this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> what it is
 		uh it scares you when you feel like somebody's taking over and a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> plan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> to go back you know to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> or to you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> or wherever they're from
 		and take with them a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dollars plus a lot of power in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies companies companies</ENAMEX> and it's kind of scary  and you know i don't know i don't know the immigration laws that uh that well and i do not and in fact i don't know them at all i don't know how many
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they allow in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> per year or if there's even a i don't even know if there is a number that they allow in anymore do you know anything about that
 	
 	
 		um-hum no i don't i don't know i lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> for sometime and i i do believe there must have been some sort of quota system because uh i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 		were in a sense not qualified is the wrong word but certainly were deserving to come and it seemed to take them a long time or or there was a lot of uncertainty as to whether they would be able to come
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so i would guess that you know there are quotas for different places
 	
 	
 		i would think so too it
 	
 	
 		uh you know i i i think there's something about being able to to claim um
 		imminent danger or i'm not sure what the terminology is maybe political
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		asylum yeah there there you go you got the term and maybe that's an an issue with a a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i don't know
 	
 	
 		asylum of some sort
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yeah i i guess i haven't been in a situation where it's it's been threatening to to me uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		well i teach in the suburb of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to school in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		and uh with very very good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> and they're considered you know one of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in the state both of them you know and it seems like a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Orientals</ENAMEX> make sure that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to these schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're head and shoulders above a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> here and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in this area are very bright and come from you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> or semiprofessionals and and uh very interested in their education but
 		uh i think in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> i'm not if i'm not mistaken in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six</NUMEX> high schools
 		the graduating class valedictorian and salutatorian were uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know they're just extremely bright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and also they value learning
 	
 	
 		i was going to say i'm not sure i i would guess that it's not that they are any brighter but they just maybe work harder or
 	
 	
 		well i i think things come easy for them too but i do think that they have that work ethic that we somehow have missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> i don't
 		they uh don't want to work for anything they want it to come to them but and be there but they don't want to work hard and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> work really hard and and they have
 	
 	
 		right right maybe but maybe part of that's the problem that here we've we've let this value slip
 	
 	
 		yeah i know i agree with that i agree with that
 	
 	
 		and they need to have some competition
 	
 	
 		but what i see is you the competition is there but instead of meeting the challenge they're starting to resent them and it's causing you know i think some some problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's too bad
 	
 	
 		it really is it because we see a lot of racial problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area anyway especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and it's mainly Black and and and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh there is some there has been some resentment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Black</ENAMEX> community because they've started <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> there and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> resent them coming in and taking their money and there's been some violence because of it
 	
 	
 		oh that's really sad
 	
 	
 		it is it's it is very sad so you know i really i i've i've always prided myself on not being prejudice and being
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know um welcoming welcoming everyone that wants to come here and even when i was younger when when i was in college i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> because i lived up north and i was very into that the human rights part of everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i i've i've become very cynical in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three four years</TIMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well and it sounds like you feel that there is need for change maybe the
 		uh you know the
 		there is too big of a concentration coming all at once to to allow for adequate melting into the society
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well and exactly that's exactly true plus the fact that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do come for a short period of time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two three four</NUMEX> maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> and then go back
 		and pick our brains which is wonderful and take all that back with them and and uh plus a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dollars but in in the long run maybe that's going to make a better world too you know you just don't know
 	
 	
 		right right exactly
 	
 	
 		and and yet you know with uh with uh
 		there's somebody on my other line but i'm going to ignore that um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		anyway i just you you kind of you don't you really don't know what to do and and
 		i don't i want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to have values where they're accepting and so forth and both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are really tolerant more tolerant of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics Hispanics</ENAMEX> than they are of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientals</ENAMEX> for some reason they feel you know like they've taken over they feel like uh you know they're taking some of the
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		the rewards that they should have and and i really don't want that to happen but but it's happening
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right right
 	
 	
 		and i think a lot of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> feel the same way too so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i really do wish i knew about quotas and really wish i  hi  i really do wish i i knew more about immigration laws because i have no idea any more because they've changed a great deal
 	
 	
 		right
 		i would i would suspect that they have
 		well i guess um
 		i don't have much  much more to contribute to the topic
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i don't really either i wish i knew more and probably if i did i might be a little bit more uh tolerant
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		perhaps and i and even if i i really wish i knew the situations they were going back to or coming from you don't know any of that and you feel you know you can't put yourself in their shoes or really understand them unless
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and for some reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orientals</ENAMEX> are very
 		uh my good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> calls them pushy but i call them very that they know what they want and they go get it and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and so forth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		goal directed
 	
 	
 		well pardon me  yeah but in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and things sometimes they can be very impolite because they can they get in front of you or they
 	
 	
 		goal directle
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		um they take something that you had in mind to get before you did you know just going for it they take it quickly and uh they don't think anything of that and i don't you know that's makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> resentful too and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		and yet they have they have a right to be here and i know that but it's it sometimes it's gets touchy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so and i'm sure it's a lot different you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> you said what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> are you from
 	
 	
 		yes
 		up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		oh okay my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> used to live there in that area and i i'm sure that it's a lot different there uh it's a lot different in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> than it is here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well no i think i think there as i recall in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> there were were an awful an awful lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities minorities</ENAMEX> yeah and uh of all of all varieties and
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		with the same uh you know some of the some of the same problems that you've mentioned but um i don't know i guess i wasn't involved enough to to um
 		really stop to think about it
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i you know since i teach i see that see it and and i feel and i love the example that most of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and give the
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and yet you know i can see why some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are fearful that are fearful too and and it's a kind of a touchy situation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i wish that we could all just learn from each other and not feel threatened but it doesn't happen that way all the time
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so anyway it was good to talk to to you too and have a good trip in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> all right well thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		well it was good talking to you
 		and i hope
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and have a good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> all righty bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	