
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh we're going to talk about our lawn and garden garden chores do you have either one
 	
 	
 		well i don't do anything with the lawn really but i do gardening both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and vegetable gardening
 	
 	
 		do you
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		um i we have enough property that we uh can have a little bit of a garden and that's fun well actually we've always had one even when we haven't had big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> because um we enjoy that we love fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and
 		it's just one of the things i enjoy doing
 	
 	
 		so do i i would i had rather be outside than inside any day
 	
 	
 		so would i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you work during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> uh outside the home
 	
 	
 		yes i do uh so i manage to fit in my gardening chores afterward i work for a school system so i'm able to do that um because i get at home a little earlier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i can still do some some sorts of things but
 	
 	
 		or you sneak out in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight</TIMEX> savings time starts and with your cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and see if it has grown overnight
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i unfortunately am not gardening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i love gardening in fact
 		i was presented at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty no about thirty years ago</TIMEX> with a life membership uh from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> of uh garden clubs
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and it wasn't because i was so good but i organized a very large garden club but i still have uh
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		it well it's always something that seems so odd to me but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but that's that's i mean you really feel you can accomplish something and to help other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too that's neat
 	
 	
 		yes it had really nothing to do with uh actual gardening or flower arranging or anything like that it was just that i happened to organize this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that was about seventy people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		that's wonderful yeah
 	
 	
 		that isn't yeah that that those numbers were were great but it
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think it sounds good i've never belonged to a garden club because i've always been more interested in just doing what i can do my on my own i've never had the time really to get involved in the organized
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		sort of format but i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do it and and enjoy it very much
 	
 	
 		well and actually i think that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden clubs</ENAMEX> that i've been aware of in the past
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are only <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> what i would like we've spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last twenty years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> just moved to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh we were originally originally of course from this area from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> but uh
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX> uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden clubs</ENAMEX> that i would have wanted to join
 	
 	
 		my word
 	
 	
 		and you would have because they do all kinds of uh gardening and not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do um-hum um-hum
 	
 	
 		for heaven's sake
 		well um there aren't men's gardening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> in this area that i know of they're they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but um and usually they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> type things you know where they have a little luncheon and they do their thing but um <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> are primarily the emphasis
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i think so too
 	
 	
 		um whereas i enjoy vegetable gardening almost more i do <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> sort of look pretty but i
 		i really like to do the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes and and i have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last ten ten years</TIMEX> being a florist
 	
 	
 		being what
 	
 	
 		being a florist
 	
 	
 		oh my well what a wonderful thing
 	
 	
 		it was nice it was exhilarating uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> uh many of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple</TIMEX> when uh we had such an economic slowdown
 	
 	
 		oh terrible yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah well tell me what's in your garden <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> since i don't have one
 	
 	
 		okay well uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> i'm just in fact i was going to go out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to buy some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> so i could put them in i i always have geraniums and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and then i have a shady area that i need to uh be concerned about not getting something that has to have sun so i've discovered that uh impatiens that tried and true is turns out to be about the best thing to use there along with coleus
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they uh look pretty and in my front garden uh but i like the vinca which is something i hadn't they look sort of like impatiens you know but they're not quite
 		and they're better for the sun areas um and of course you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are old very ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers marigolds</ENAMEX> and and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yes do you have trouble with uh red spider on marigolds
 	
 	
 		in my
 		no i don't i don't know maybe this climate is a little better
 	
 	
 		maybe it's
 		yes um-hum um-hum
 	
 	
 		um but in the vegetable garden we grow um
 		usually well our favorite is something called white half runner green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> now that's
 	
 	
 		well do you isn't that funny so is my favorite
 	
 	
 		well you know why because i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s um favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bean</ENAMEX> she always she always grows you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different varieties but that's the kind that produces the best
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah
 		yeah well i think it has the best flavor
 	
 	
 		and and they're wonderful and i pick them when they're very young and have very little string and then just steam them a little bit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> picks them when they're fat and she cooks them for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> with some fat back
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh well i like them in between i like them in between
 	
 	
 		and they're good both ways
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		the flavor is better i think in between
 	
 	
 		oh in between the size wise yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yes yeah um-hum my mother
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> doesn't think they have any flavor the way i cook them
 	
 	
 		well and i no i love them well that's the yankee way but i think that's like another vegetable i love them that way just the thrill of
 	
 	
 		oh of course
 		yeah it is they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> that way um-hum
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum in fact i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who is eighty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years old</TIMEX> canned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred</NUMEX> quarts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		my does mother <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty ninety this year</TIMEX> and she lives in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and uh she would do that if uh if we didn't tell her that she'd better not
 	
 	
 		yes um-hum yes
 	
 	
 		but she doesn't have that big a garden but she has a bigger one than i do and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know so
 	
 	
 		really yes
 		and she tends to it herself uh-huh isn't that wonderful
 	
 	
 		oh yes oh yes oh it is it's great it's it's really her joy and i guess suppose that's why i enjoy gardening because you know growing up with it we also grow um yellow and green squash um much to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s chagrin
 	
 	
 		i think so too
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh we grow a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> uh there's just no replacement for fresh grown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		so we enjoy that um we grow i i have been trying to grow watermelon and cantaloupe and get teased by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but i actually was successful for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		wonderful bet you showed them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm going to do it again that's right and we grow broccoli
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i have been
 		very uh happy about the new way of controlling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the uh worm</ENAMEX> that gets in broccoli
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um Bacillus</ENAMEX> by using the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus thuringiansis</ENAMEX> which is the uh little well in fact that's what they use for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gypsy</ENAMEX> moth i don't know if you have had that problem there or not
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but it's you know it's a problem that's that's moving south from from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> area and they devastate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> so they they spray the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sprays</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two three</NUMEX> times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> when the uh caterpillars are are coming along because what they do this this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus um</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX> ingest it and it expands in their in their um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digestive</ENAMEX> tract and they die
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's the same technique that is you know for any of the other uh little varmints that get in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> so it that's really very nice because it's a non-toxic way of of handling the problem
 	
 	
 		great well we could chat we could really talk gardening a long time i'm enjoying hearing you so much
 	
 	
 		so
 		well it's nice hearing you talk and i'm i wish you uh good luck have you just recently moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		yes uh no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> uh so yes recently <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> and it the weather is wonderful i love it  it's just terrific you know  rains a little too often
 	
 	
 		oh so well that's not very long
 		yes
 		oh that's great that's great well i hope you have a an opportunity to garden again
 	
 	
 		oh i think so i have a little spinach
 	
 	
 		oh well good
 		
 
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	