
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so how do we fix the national budget
 	
 	
 		okay
 		damned if i know um
 		i don't uh i suspect uh let's see  i suspect we should do what everyone says we should do we should cut spending and maybe even raise taxes but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> knows you shouldn't one shouldn't say that
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i i i suspect we should probably have an independent auditing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> go in and look at how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> spends money
 		and work from there
 	
 	
 		that would probably be good
 	
 	
 		because i because i don't think they're very good at it
 	
 	
 		but
 		something
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> hasn't been looking at
 		is
 		the source of the problem
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		the true source of the problem
 		is A that we do spend too much
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but also B that we don't take in enough
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		why why why why do you say that actually
 	
 	
 		uh
 		too few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are working
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		if more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were working and meaningful
 		good paying labor
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and paying taxes
 	
 	
 		rather than using taxed
 	
 	
 		and the tax structure was fair between
 		the
 		lowest and the highest income <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 		then we would have more money there to play with
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting yeah that's probably true i mean well we also we'd be spending less because all the money that that normally goes to support those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't working it's back in the system
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so you're right that's a real neat idea well what but i mean what can you know at at some point what can you do to sort of raise revenue i mean to raise jobs i wonder
 	
 	
 		well
 		i
 		hesitate to say we ought to spend ourselves
 		to
 		affluence
 		but in fact
 		in some cases that's what we ought to do
 	
 	
 		oh okay so
 		start when
 	
 	
 		not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reaganomics</ENAMEX> thank you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but that is not gonna work uh
 	
 	
 		uh what i was thinking more along the lines of
 		is start going to space
 	
 	
 		hum
 		and that way just create more jobs
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		or whatever
 	
 	
 		at some point there there will be
 		enough
 		jobs
 		for
 		most of the able able-bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum um-hum well that's a neat idea
 	
 	
 		we also need to uh
 		assure that there's some work in the private sector
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what that's what you you think space would do that much for that or
 	
 	
 		i think it would do something for it i think we would fill up new technologies
 		but i think we should also
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		do something rather radical
 	
 	
 		like what
 	
 	
 		legalize marijuana
 	
 	
 		oh you think you think that would uh have a major effect well that would put a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> out of business for a while anyway
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		that that might have a um a good effect on on on crime anyway
 	
 	
 		yes uh okay i think it would
 		take some of that money
 		out of the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> i think it would put
 		reduce the amount of carry on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> advance from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> to another
 	
 	
 		that's probably true
 	
 	
 		i think that
 		i think most importantly
 		it would give the federal government something new that they could tax
 	
 	
 		and probably a lot of
 	
 	
 		and probably a lot of and really receive some revenues from
 	
 	
 		yeah but that's potentially you know
 	
 	
 		uh if you
 		look at prohibition
 		historically
 		it's repeal
 		helped the federal government a lot
 		in tax revenues
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		no i'd never thought about that
 	
 	
 		then i think once we put
 		money back into the coffers in the coffers of the federal government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and get the federal government
 		to where
 		there's money there again
 		we should reduce
 		the amount of money
 		and this would have to come rather quickly
 		and would have to come come originally also
 		where we're not paying
 		in some cases we do pay more for
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to live then they can earn
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in the true minimum wage
 		environment
 	
 	
 		that's true we do often times they are paid more yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		you can't
 		deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the right
 		to supply
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> better through whatever means
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's just sensible on their part
 	
 	
 		that's just what on their part i'm sorry i missed that
 	
 	
 		it's just sensible on their parts to go after the
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		the the greater amount of income
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so if you
 		lower the amount they make and
 		raise the amount of true minimum wage jobs not those that are affected by the federal minimum wage
 		then
 		more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will get off welfare
 	
 	
 		that that maybe true that's very true
 	
 	
 		you know give them a true incentive to want to work
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then
 		don't
 		start
 		letting more
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> in
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> until we figure exactly where we're at with unemployment
 	
 	
 		right that's uh
 	
 	
 		reduce
 		immigration
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or eliminate it entirely for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> unti l we get our own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in order
 	
 	
 		yeah and maybe even reduce along along the same lines maybe reduce imports as well i think
 		
  
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely absolutely
 	
 	
 		i mean we don't need to buy other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s stuff right now
 	
 	
 		that's right when we're in a wor ld of hurt
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i don't i'm not going to say
 		that we ought to reduce
 		reduce them through legal means i think we ought to just tax them severely
 	
 	
 		right well that that's what happened in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> though and other places they tax us quite heavily i mean they tax <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> imports quite heavily so we could do the same thing i mean just and you know they may get
 	
 	
 		it seems only fair
 	
 	
 		right it does seem only fair i mean why not
 	
 	
 		and i think really if we got all those that are able-bodied into the work force
 		reduced
 		the amount going out for those purposes created new jobs for that work force
 		there would be plenty of money
 	
 	
 		i i think so
 	
 	
 		and then at that point
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		quit spending on space
 		force it all into the into the private sector
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh really i love the switch
 		well at that point you might we it it it wouldn't be a problem anymore possibly you know we would be
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		we would be able to keep it wherever we wanted to in space or the ocean research whatever we wanted to do
 		but i think that would be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh uh</ENAMEX> space was just a convenient
 		place for me to go because
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that would put a lot of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millspec</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> work operates to the same demanding specifications that would put a bunch of defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> back to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		is compared to defense well that's a good idea well i well the other thing and the other thing i i i think we seriously need to do is um
 		like i say have someone go in and look and you know and find out where it is we're paying ten <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> per toilet seat or something
 	
 	
 		you know what causes that
 	
 	
 		greed i suspect
 	
 	
 		uh no
 		your
 		your your buying large trunk
 		uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> specification
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sheets of paper
 		for building a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BVD</ENAMEX> underwear
 		for the federal government
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twenty two foot</NUMEX> tall
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		if it was all on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> by elevens stacked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on top of another
 	
 	
 		for making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> issue under wear
 	
 	
 		for making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> issue underwear
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to just understand
 		those legal requirements
 		and operate within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> guidelines
 		costs the company
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a huge amount of money
 	
 	
 		well its potentially a fault of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> than i mean that could be thing like that should be i mean
 	
 	
 		yes a huge amount of it is not the fault of the contractor
 	
 	
 		right well that's a i had never heard that before
 	
 	
 		uh
 		a huge amount of what you hear on about the seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> dollar hammers
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine hundred</NUMEX> dollar
 		toilet seats
 		doesn't come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the industry it comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> that don't know anything about it
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh
 		my job is
 		government tooling specialist
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you know about some of these things yeah
 		
 		
 	