
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Jim um</ENAMEX> what are they doing down in your uh neck of the woods for recycling
 	
 	
 		we have recently the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> has started a a situation it's pretty much volunteer as far as separating
 		oh paper and bottles and you know cans and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it's not exactly curbside yet they've got these little igloo like things sitting up in various parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where you can take that stuff in if you want to
 		the biggest thing that they've done is uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX> we had been on the plastic trash bag business where everything was just uh put in uh plastic bags then set out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>
 		but uh they came through with these big green uh plastic dumpster kind of things uh where you put everything except lawn trash
 		and then they  they
 		we got these uh paper sacks to put uh lawn debris and stuff in supposedly uh you know it can all be mulched at once the paper sack and everything
 		only problem is you can't get anything in the paper sack
 	
 	
 		oh that's they're they're too small
 	
 	
 		yeah they're too small on the top and they're they're smaller than most grass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchers</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing so
 		they just started this uh oh maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month or two</TIMEX> ago
 		and uh
 		they uh
 		the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> you know they're just starting to use them now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> is starting to you know be cut and everything we're getting a lot of complaints about them but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you know i i realize the whole the whole recycling trash thing is a is such a problem because the landfill and all that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true right
 		um
 	
 	
 		i don't know what are they
 		they're probably doing more than that up there i'm i guess you all started this sort of thing long time before we did
 	
 	
 		yeah well up  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> i i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know i travel back and forth which isn't too far it's only i only live about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> miles from the plant
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i live right up in the uh in the northeast corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> is is in uh is in the like the south uh southwest section of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> it comes down like kind of a neck so
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't have for to travel but i live in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we started recycling they made it mandatory in in our town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they gave you uh uh little blue containers that you put all your your uh your bottles and cans
 		and like the plastic milk jugs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you put those in there and they recycle those  and then you put your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in a separate or either you put them in a a paper bag or or you tie them up with string
 		you put those in a separate bundle and they have a special truck that comes around and they pick them up curbside
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then the rest of it is just you know goes to the landfill i guess or whatever they whatever they incinerate it maybe
 	
 	
 		yeah we  uh we're coming to that here you know in the metroplex is getting big enough that um it'll happen i i grew up in a
 		uh kind of a a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> where that just wasn't a problem matter of fact till recently we burned trash you know we had the big barrels out in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and when it's filled up you just put a match to it and burned it well course that's that's almost unheard of anymore
 	
 	
 		and that's  right
 		that's what we used to do too <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> we used to do the same thing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah we used to burn leaves and burn grass you know and all that
 		as far as what to uh to do to encourage recycling i guess a lot of states
 		i have noticed on uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Coke</ENAMEX> bottles and and whatnot we went i've got some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
 		and uh there's a big thing up there what is it nickel for every bottle or some such thing and you know people
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah we do the same yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actively go out and and uh seek them you know i guess that's one way of doing it you know is to make it worthwhile
 	
 	
 		yeah all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> around us <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts New Hampshire</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> do it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>'s the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that doesn't put a nickel deposit on the bottles
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but every other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> does so you don't you don't see any trash along the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that throw bottles away there's other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that come along with plastic bags and they pick them up and and i guess they can make of a you know it's like working a part-time job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it's all free just takes time and if you're retired and have nothing to do
 		um
 	
 	
 		well course there's uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will go after aluminum cans and stuff down here because it's just uh there's not a per can value on them but there is a
 	
 	
 		oh just on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX> content
 	
 	
 		just in the metal recycling itself i've
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i'm not sure what it's what a can is worth now it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> cents you know you've got to get quite a few of them to really make it worthwhile but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		to make it worth it yeah
 	
 	
 		it turns out that uh on a  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> there's enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans and stuff along the road to make it worthwhile yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both graduated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> their uh master <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has has uh uh  a land grant college
 		uh would used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown University</ENAMEX> now it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what we learned down there is that uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifty percent</NUMEX> when you when you mow your lawn fifty percent of all the nutrients are in that top section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kind of rake it up or they catch it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> catcher and they throw it away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you if you mow properly and just let it lay in there you refertilize your own soil besides building up a base
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's what  we've been doing that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX>
 		and you don't have to worry about uh fertilizing which causes a lot of thatch and all that kind of stuff so there's more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too are aware of that up here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they're not going out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> they're not going out for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertilizers</ENAMEX> and stuff so they're letting it you know uh
 	
 	
 		our soil situation down here in this particular area we're in a real hard black gooey gummy awful black clay situation
 	
 	
 		oh so
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		summertimes it cracks when it heats when it gets
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you could lose a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in the cracks  sometimes
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh so i
 	
 	
 		i was watching uh  i was watching the news this morning uh national news and they were talking about uh i guess they got a a recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dump</ENAMEX> for tires that caught on fire
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they were saying that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>  they recycle their their
 		all the tires and make like a a some kind of a rubberized <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> and they incorporate that with uh with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tar</ENAMEX> and they use it on their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and they say the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> last a lot longer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		there was a thing in the local news here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> there's a little town down south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mansfield</ENAMEX> and there's some tire recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> wants a permit down there they say out of every tire you can get a gallon what amounts to a ga llon of diesel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>
 		and like you say several pounds of this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon black</ENAMEX> and uh material for for making <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and anymore there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple pounds</NUMEX> of stainless steel
 		in most of the uh the tires yeah because the steel belted tires and uh
 	
 	
 		oh for the steel belted that's right i didn't think about
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's a totally gas fired operation they say there's no exhaust whatsoever you know most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of tire yeah tho se burning tire uh
 		see there was what was it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> i remember here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> reading <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> that had been on fire for  long period of time you know it just smolders and the black smoke pours out of it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		there could be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> up here some place i'm not really sure um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> they had one catch fire here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and they had an awful time putting it out
 		but our big problem down here course is uh tires laying around down on the ground and stuff uh collect water and then of course that becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquito</ENAMEX> breeding area and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that's right too yeah i didn't think of yeah
 	
 	
 		that can be a real
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> was uh is in the process of building  a a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> to burn tires to generate electricity
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		so i guess that's kind of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of a</NUMEX> a recycling process
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the uh  all the all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> eventually are going to go on this like the recycling that we have now it depends on on each individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">municipality</ENAMEX>
 		uh we went on it quite early because of the town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> said yeah you know we think it's a good idea
 		but the state i think by nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety three</NUMEX> every every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has to go on this recycling program so it's like a forced
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um which is good i think
 	
 	
 		yeah what happens to us anyways as you can imagine in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you've got urban areas that are probably as compact or as you know densely populated as just about any place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but then
 	
 	
 		yeah well you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> got
 	
 	
 		then you run into uh areas you know they've
 		we've got a statistic down here that they like to use you know you can take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the world and pack it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> about the density of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and then you'd have the rest of the world to grow <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> in because there wouldn't be any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s probably as big as this whole state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah uh the panhandle the the there's well there's several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> too for that matter that are bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we had a our  our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> rep i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSEG</ENAMEX> here
 		
 		
 	