
 
     		
 	
 		i was  i might have had it sitting there somewhere
 	
 	
 		no i well can you hold up let me i've got a portable phone here let me just turn it on real quick i can go over to where i think i might have it
 	
 	
 		okay okay
 	
 	
 		okay let's see here i just
 	
 	
 		it's it's it's supposed to be on the instruction sheet but
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah here we go
 	
 	
 		i didn't see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on mine
 	
 	
 		let's see  just a second oh it doesn't
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um  gee if i was at work i could give you a number i tell you what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		call this number in the in uh uh during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day nine nine five zero three two seven</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero three two seven</NUMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		and and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who answers there'll be able to help you
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> happens to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">in</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that does this
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay that'll work okay let me hit one now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay uh in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> they are doing a lot as as as far as recycling goes uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>'s a pretty small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and so a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess they want they take they take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> more than i would think that a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> does
 		or they can because they're smaller and so they're doing all kinds of recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> and the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are doing all kinds of things and i'm a i'm a news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and so i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		report on a lot of the recycling things that they do and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just last week</TIMEX> they opened up a new recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> uh so now they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh in an adjoining community uh Hewett
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they are doing uh curbside recycling which is something a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are starting to look into but for some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> it's very expensive
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> just uh just started a program where they uh they gave everybody these big plastic garbage cans
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what they're doing is on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> they pick up the regular garbage and these plastic garbage cans but on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX> uh if you leave they have these special huge paper bags
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and if you put your clippings in that they'll pick that up on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's a form of the curbside yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah right and then as i understand it they're uh they're planning to um start giving everybody containers to put <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> in to to recycle that as well so
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know even uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart Department Store</ENAMEX> i don't if they do it there they have the recycling bin right outside the store
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and it's got glass <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum plastic</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah i know all the the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> here have a a bins when you walk in if you want to recycle your paper bags or plastic bags
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right the plastic bags
 	
 	
 		so uh i think it's great uh um i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are being indoctrinated into the whole idea i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> came home <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um she was all excited because they gave her an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> to call to find out where your local recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and she called it and turns out the the nearest one's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> which is about i don't know forty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> to an hour from here but
 	
 	
 		wow
 		do you recycle yourself at home do you
 	
 	
 		yeah we um in fact i've got a car full of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> that we're trying to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh here's a sort of i guess a a setback uh there were a couple of places that used to collect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> just around here and we went to all of them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and none of them had bins for for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		i don't know if they just discontinued it or
 	
 	
 		it's kind of rough doing the newspaper i understand because the they can't recycle the uh i guess it's the sale papers that have the color on them
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and so it's kind of hard for them to i guess uh separate all that
 	
 	
 		yeah i know we don't sort that out um
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i don't think anybody would you know i don't think they can put the colored paper on there or something so that should be pretty difficult
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't recycle myself i live i'm single and so  i guess if i had a family i'd probably be more aware than now that i am single but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		right i i you probably uh eat uh fast food type stuff and uh on the go
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah especially on my job i'm hardly ever home so you know my
 	
 	
 		yeah well when i was single i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> too i so i uh i can identify with you um  uh i know that a lot of times that you're working double shifts and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">odd hours</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		you just eat when you have something to eat
 	
 	
 		you just go in and you don't know when you're coming out
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so but uh let's see what else are they doing
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> jeez i'm all out of recycling
 	
 	
 		i know uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> collect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> here and uh and uh in in fact the there's a the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at the end of the block come by every once in a while when they want extra money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they come by uh collecting aluminum cans because we have places that you can go where you can the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has places where you can just dump the aluminum cans but uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 		right my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> before all this recycling stuff started i guess well not before it all started but she would collect the cans and you go like in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarkets</ENAMEX> or whatever and you put the cans in this
 		bin thing and it spits out money yeah that's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah well that's where that's where these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> take their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that that freaked me out when we first did that i thought okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		you you don't get rich on those right right huh
 	
 	
 		we got like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight cents</NUMEX> or something  yeah exactly
 		uh so at work we do recycle we have a little recycling bin for our cans and bottles and uh those go out
 	
 	
 		yeah the where where i work they just started a paper drive and in fact everybody has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> trash cans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		uh one is for your normal crap trash and one is just for paper and they uh they had a big campaign for it and there's a list of things that you're allowed to put in the paper bin
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know and but they they're pretty good about it it doesn't you know you can have the staples in them and the paper clips on them and the plastic windows
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		they take care of all of that but they don't want certain types of paper uh they don't want anything you know they don't want you know like transparencies overheads you know they don't want any of that in there
 	
 	
 		wow
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		just regular paper and
 	
 	
 		right they don't want the garbage from your from your lunch in there um and uh and there's uh even little um uh this uh board
 	
 	
 		hm
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> that that shows uh has a it's a picture of a tree
 		with a with a squirrel going up and it's like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a gauge and the higher the squirrel goes up the more trees you've saved
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it shows you how many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> uh have been saved because of the recycling program at work
 	
 	
 		so like
 		so that gives you kind of an incentive
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		well that's great if you know that like a lot of things you pick up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> almost everything says
 		recyclable or this is made from recyclables or something it's it's amazing it really is it's amazing to me how fast i i'm sure recycling's been going on forever and it's just
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess everyone is picking it up now you know but it's just amazing to me how much it's come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> since last <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> Day you know everything's i mean recycle recycle everywhere you go
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh yeah
 		right well i know when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> uh which was quite a while ago um we used to collect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and take them to the there was a uh
 		i don't know what it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that it was a paper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> i guess it was that was fairly close to where i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond Virginia</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you could you bring your papers in to sell them there i remember doing that when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 		i remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> used to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Coke</ENAMEX> bottles in and you get like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten ten</NUMEX> cents or something like that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah sure yeah
 		right that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess that was a form of but now it's just like perpetrated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> into the you know society it's like if you don't recycle you feel you feel almost uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know like you're doing something wrong or you feel guilty almost so hm
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah well that's good i mean we're such a we're such a um throwaway society
 	
 	
 		yeah wasteful um-hum um-hum
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's nice because you know uh if you talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who grew up during the depression
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nothing was wasted i mean everything and nowadays it's like you know nobody darns their socks i mean if you see a hole in it you throw it away by a new pair of socks you know kind of thing and uh i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		throw it away that's it
 		yeah we're spoiled very spoiled
 	
 	
 		yeah i you know i guess i believe the propaganda if you want to call it that that uh um you know we're uh
 		we're we we have limited resources and uh we really should think about uh conserving them instead of wasting them
 	
 	
 		right i know i'm doing the story big story i'm covering now is of about our landfill here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what was it i think twenty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four million tons</NUMEX> of garbage that we throw away
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		everywhere everywhere <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> could be recycled
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		wow
 	
 	
 		like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty four million</NUMEX> to and i think that accounts for uh i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one quarter</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the landfill space
 	
 	
 		
 
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so i mean i just learn all these little
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh propaganda things
 	
 	
 		you can't always i mean it'd be nice if you could if the landfill space was reusable but it isn't it all it it isn't always i know sometimes it is
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		not at all
 	
 	
 		i know there's place called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Trashmore Trashmore</ENAMEX> which is a a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> that they built on top of a landfill
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and i can't remember where it is i think it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> or thereabouts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Trashmore i</ENAMEX> haven't heard of that one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's like the big stink around here this landfill thing they're wanting to expand it and a lot of the community the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that live around the area don't want it expanded because you know they say it'll uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh poison their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and you know poison the air and there's an elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> right across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and all kinds of stuff so it's a pretty pretty big issue
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well yeah i i guess uh you know the scary the the scary part is that you don't know what the effects are you know fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years from now</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		you know it's easy to say well we'll build a concrete hole and and nothing'll happen and then they'll say well the only way to test that is over a long period of time so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right that's what a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are saying that it may not hurt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> but they're looking in the long run you know and they're saying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">well forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years from now</TIMEX> we'll
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and there's
 		and there's no way to measure that i mean you you know you the only way is to take the chance and see what happens forty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years from now</TIMEX> and who knows what kind of havoc you've created
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want to wait
 	
 	
 		uh by the
 		no nope
 		
 		
 	