
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so child care your views
 	
 	
 		uh well we only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> right now and another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the way and right now i'm i'm home with her during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 		i if i was looking for outside care i probably would stay away from professional child care centers
 		and try to find if i was close to home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with the same values and possibly religious faith or something similar so that she would be raised in an environment that would be
 		similar to what we would have in our own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> as as parents
 	
 	
 		and what religious faith
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Latter Day Saints</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		that's that's good
 	
 	
 		that's what i would try to do
 		with a teaching background i've um had a little bit of experience with some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> day care type situations but i've seen some good ones and i've seen some really bad ones
 	
 	
 		uh they do seem to be at the outside edge of both extremes don't they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and everything in between yeah because there's in most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> there's nothing to regulate them
 		and so
 	
 	
 		and whenever
 		they are they seem to
 		regulate the good toward the bad instead of bad toward the good
 	
 	
 		right by trying to get them to conform to concern standards they uh kind of uh eliminate a lot of the
 		uh
 	
 	
 		better situations
 	
 	
 		yeah the the uh what am i trying to think of that
 		not the imagination but the creativity in in the situation and so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's that that's very well phrased uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so have you ever used outside child care
 	
 	
 		no i haven't we've had like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in and babysit for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but i've never had um
 	
 	
 		real day care
 	
 	
 		right she's she's not even a year yet so
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		we haven't been in you know a lot of need yet
 	
 	
 		our step <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		most of the day care has been provide for by Grandma
 	
 	
 		yeah i like that situation that's usually real good
 	
 	
 		but
 		quite honestly what i believe to be
 		the best day care situation was while we lived up the pass of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodland Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was uh
 		ex school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that uh
 		did
 		a small amount of before school and
 		and after school you know kindergartners or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-dayers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in her home
 		and they would read and play
 	
 	
 		have a relative structured a structured
 	
 	
 		seem to be
 	
 	
 		activities and not just you know stick them in a corner and say you're on your own
 	
 	
 		uh yeah and uh
 		despite
 		our beliefs
 		she was uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the more um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">charismatic Christian</ENAMEX> faiths
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it worked out wonderfully
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that um that
 		i guess if you have the opportunity to pick and choose and you've got the time and that uh
 		i don't know if the resources are the proper term you know just the the know knowledge of who's a available then you could probably find some really good care
 	
 	
 		uh yeah but i don't know that it would be state approved
 	
 	
 		that's true you can get somebody somebody willing to babysit but actual
 		you know that's sometimes different on a done on a different scale
 		i have even considered you know babysitting myself i have a teaching degree and uh
 		thought well you know i could structure and then for one reason or other decided not to
 		but i think if you take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in well that was how it was this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> we've recently moved here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> i think if you take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in on more than a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> a day bases you have to be licensed
 	
 	
 		i
 		now i don't know what the current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> laws are
 		but i
 		but i do know that the license doesn't seem to
 		guarantee quality
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot of times you might just need to go now and feel file for it just like a business you may not have to prove any type of qualification for it i don't
 	
 	
 		uh
 		now here i believe that
 		child care
 		meets by and large certain standards for
 		uh
 		balanced food if they provide food
 		cleanliness
 		and
 		levels of supervision
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		levels being defined as
 		number of of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> for
 		number of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		that's uh kind of a minimum there that you're getting your covering basic care there and not
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would like to see
 		done with there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know like the educational activities the supervised play and
 		so forth
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is uh agnostic
 		and i'm a
 		backsliding Presbyterian
 	
 	
 		i like that term
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yet
 		i really believe that this
 		charismatic
 		care
 		or the charismatic belief when emphasized on care
 		or semi charismatic i might say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was quite good
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a good influence for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yes very
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		and and
 		uh
 		the care is what i guess you should emphasize in the term child care instead of the child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah a little bit of love and and attention is what most of them need
 		you know even if it's
 		not a real educated program you can have good educational program and and
 	
 	
 		and not have any care
 	
 	
 		right and and that's not certainly what you want for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or what you would give your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> yourself
 		and so
 	
 	
 		and i'm not sure that really
 		child care per se should instill
 		any
 		education per se
 		you know what i'm saying
 	
 	
 		well even educated play uh supervised play can teach without and i'm not saying talking about sitting down and teaching them math or or or something like that but just kind of promoting social skills and uh
 		you know like my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that she want be an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for long but you know she was an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or maybe your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> not having yeah
 	
 	
 		proper interface
 	
 	
 		yeah just
 	
 	
 		it's just just correct ness of of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> skills if you will
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right those basic things that uh they would
 		that you know maybe a little bit of uh
 		i don't know if manners is a is a good term or not but you know dealing with other through uh
 		proper mannerisms and politeness and so forth you know that sort of thing you'd want your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to learn that
 		from been experience with i mean someone else certainly you wouldn't want your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s day care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to yell at them and scream at them and say do this do that you know you'd want them to
 		promote politeness and niceness you know the things that you would want any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to learn
 		and usually that's done through example not you know an actual sit down learn situation so
 	
 	
 		uh yeah uh
 		it's a very broad issue
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it is
 	
 	
 		and
 		you know it's a shame but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing child care
 		earn almost no money
 		they operate at you know um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of a you know we're talking large child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> now we're not talking somebody that does <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">or three</NUMEX> or or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		who really doesn't really put a lot of overhead whatever into it you mean somebody that has an actual establishment
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> earn almost nothing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know i i did that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> so i can i can vouch for that
 	
 	
 		and and that's really a a shame too because
 		do you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> both work
 	
 	
 		no just he does i'm i'm here during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> with her
 	
 	
 		well that's wonderful if if you can make it that way
 	
 	
 		well we we decided to live with a uh uh lesser budget so that we have that that's more important to us
 		you know  as as uh
 		there may come a time when i will be working again you know but right now that's what we've chosen and we wanted to have several we got her and we've got another on the way and
 	
 	
 		well like i said
 	
 	
 		may have another one soon after that so
 	
 	
 		that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> if if you can pull it off
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but
 		more and more
 		we're being forced into a situation we as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are being forced into a situation
 		where
 		you've got to have
 		
 		
 	