
 
     		
 	
 		okay what did you buy
 	
 	
 		okay a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry what
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah one of the new ones
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um i'd i'd probably buy another this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> vehicle i've owned so i would probably purchase another one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i would be more selective in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> that i purchased it from but as far as uh the quality seems to be there um it's quiet it's it handles well um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i believe i'd get that or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX> one of the two
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		no not
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		if i had the money i think i would love to own a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and why would that be
 	
 	
 		i don't know i from what or either that or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> just because they're put together so well it seems like they last forever
 	
 	
 		what's wrong with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know they're they're not as nice looking
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh  uh meant to me i don't know i'm sure there are some that are but everyone i've seen is kind of plain but
 	
 	
 		what
 		what what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> are you calling from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		where're you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> yeah well that's uh that's um
 	
 	
 		if i had money um had the money i mean that's just i know i never would own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but uh
 		i don't know i like my actual favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> is were uh like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Thunderbirds</ENAMEX> of nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> i really like that style body style
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't own one of those neither
 	
 	
 		what do you presently drive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um Mercury Topaz</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um fun
 	
 	
 		cheap taste cheap taste in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well there nothing wrong with those uh
 	
 	
 		yeah they're all right it's it's a good car i mean i've never had any problem with it
 	
 	
 		they're they're nice vehicles
 		they're nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> nothing wrong with those it um
 		
 
 		it's just everybody has their own taste but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> are expensive my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> and it it's nice i mean you know it's okay an
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sorry i roped on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volvos</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sorry i roped on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volvos</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		oh no no no no no no no it it i i kind of wish we would have maybe gone for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GL</ENAMEX> rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DL</ENAMEX> but because they it is the safest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> on the road um oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh is it see i don't much about them i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah they're the safest that's the reason why we mainly got it we got white and it's the safest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door and it's good for if you have a family which we do we just we just dominated everyone out and so it's it's uh um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they're kind of low to the ground after driving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> you know i presently i used to have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">eighty Z</ENAMEX> and i'm a tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		they're hard to get around in traffic to see because you can't see a car ahead of you but they're fast as lightning and all that crap but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> i mean you're sitting up on top of everything and you can really see real well and i just it's it's so comfortable and
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so you're what are your feelings about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i like anything besides <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> course everything has <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> parts in them anymore i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		why not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> i don't have have any i mean those are the kind i usually end up liking the most
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say they they don't last long but i've never had any problem with
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Cougar</ENAMEX> and he's never had any problem with it either so
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		that's the way it goes i guess
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what are your i guess this is your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah i was real hesitant but it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know uh i mean i think <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are great course you've got to have metric wrenches and stuff and they're easy some some of them are easy to work on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> being a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cylinder is very easy to work on uh excellent warranty i mean just unbelievable warranty
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and and uh course <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> isn't too bad i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> would probably make a good vehicle uh but all of it has to do in my opinion with the service and the attitude of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of the dealership
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't send my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middlekauff Ford</ENAMEX>
 		there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middlekauff Ford</ENAMEX> in Plano
 	
 	
 		where
 		okay
 	
 	
 		their just their attitude is just slimy and and uh i've written a a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middlekauff</ENAMEX> and i've told them that matter of fact i got another letter <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Ford Division</ENAMEX>
 		they're still concerned about my attitude and it it will never change about that place and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh anyway that's my own personal comment i guess but
 	
 	
 		yeah this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that works for me just bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> down there and she they they had a problem with they uh
 		took their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camaro</ENAMEX> in to get it traded and they they hadn't signed any papers and they had all ready uh taken it in to paint it and everything and everything was stolen out of it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um wouldn't reimburse reimburse them for anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middlekauff</ENAMEX> wouldn't she needs to find herself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> she'd she'd come out like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX> on that one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so i've heard some stuff about them but um
 	
 	
 		so have have you been using well anyway
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		that was i was asking you some questions about the telephone and how long and how many have you been doing but that's they they don't want to hear that but
 	
 	
 		oh just just about a week
 	
 	
 		is that all a week
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		good Lord i think i started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> oh God i've i'm like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> some phone calls
 	
 	
 		so
 		really
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		that's why i i wasn't sure if this was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time around or what
 		well look i've enjoyed speaking with you
 	
 	
 		yeah you too
 	
 	
 		and keep smiling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> thanks bye
 	
 	
 		bye bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	