
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i will i guess i will start and say that i keep up uh with current events
 		mostly from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> areas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'll tell you what they are and uh then you uh would you please uh tell me how you do it
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i think i keep up better with what's going on in the world from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> but i usually am introduced to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> by television
 	
 	
 		and then if something that struck your fancy then you pay attention more to that kind of topic then when you get the newspaper
 	
 	
 		exactly in more detail
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i also take uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> and i enjoy that a lot and uh i get a lot of uh i think pretty good detail there
 		and uh i'm pretty i'm pretty satisfied with i think those and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who are who are very knowledgeable
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes
 	
 	
 		and how how do you
 	
 	
 		well basically the same thing i i know uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s favorite radio station in all the world is KRLD
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he we wake up to KRLD we go to sleep at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KRLD</ENAMEX> and i used to just really argue about that and battle that and i don't so much anymore because
 		i do want to keep up and know what's going on and
 		it helps i don't often uh have time to sit down and watch the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> news kind of thing but
 		if i'm around during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the daytime</TIMEX> and have a chance i'll switch on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 		always have watched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> ever since we
 		got the cable
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh you know coverage that provided for that and have always enjoyed it and am glad to see them getting a little uh boost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> since the uh war a little more uh recognition and credibility
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i've i uh
 		have access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> all of which i
 		rely on more i think than what i get over network
 		TV news
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and like you you know knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who is uh in the oil industry internationally
 		and travels a lot to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">third</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and all around and i feel like a lot of times what we get from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> is far more valid
 	
 	
 		wonderful
 	
 	
 		then you know but that's only in a real specialized area you know that's not that's just political it's not the medical arena it's not technology particularly although sometimes it overlaps
 	
 	
 		of course
 		
 
 	
 	
 		into those kinds of things but i don't think i would be satisfied if all i had was just television
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		you know the uh the newspapers i think
 		you know they uh i think a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> of what i get out  out of the  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s not on the front page
 	
 	
 		i think that's right too well especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i uh
 		i have really enjoyed being able to have access to that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of years</TIMEX> it uh
 	
 	
 		don't you find though that it's hard to find time
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		to yeah to the reading is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> if i don't read it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that it comes in then if they start piling up on me then i have to just forget about about it usually
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well and you know you just take a a newspaper just your your regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> average big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> newspaper
 		there's more information in one
 		than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an entire month</TIMEX> magazine you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> periodical
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and
 		a lot of times i'll just take the whole thing soon as i get it and i take out the sections i want trash the rest otherwise you like you say the the stack of paper is so large
 		
 
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		it's unmanageable just in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> situation
 	
 	
 		it really is and especially if you're trying to
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		save papers for recycling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		just terrible job
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh i think i enjoy uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and i i get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insight</ENAMEX> and i don't like that magazine very much
 	
 	
 		i i'm not familiar with that one
 	
 	
 		it looks like a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it is not written as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> staff uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> do
 		but i i like some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> because they just choose certain subjects i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and deal with a
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well i'm a nonfiction oriented kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> anyway oh i enjoy a good novel
 		but you know given the choice in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> when they're all lined up i'm much more apt to grab the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News and World Reports</ENAMEX> than i ever would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> or
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCall's</ENAMEX> or although i've you know i read those kinds of things too occasionally and and and find things that are current and
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		updated but i don't know i just just my particular
 		predisposition i
 		i tend more the other way so i try not to ever find myself in a situation without something to read because my reading time comes in
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		little snatches  i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so by the time i get around to
 		actually reading i have you know i may have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes</TIMEX> of slot
 		to read so
 	
 	
 		i guess you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well they're good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh well of course
 	
 	
 		and this you know this is another reason though i think that ah
 		makes me real aware and encouraging because i know there's always a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a tidbit</NUMEX> of information that's going to come across some
 		i'm either gonna read it or i'm gonna hear it that they can turn right around and use in a report
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		so if i hear a statistic that's interesting or whatnot even just driving in the car i'll make a little note and uh
 		you know of where that came from and the time i heard it and whatnot so they can use that in a bibliography
 	
 	
 		well you are passing good information on to them aren't you
 	
 	
 		i hope so i hope so i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> tend to watch news for the sensationalism
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love to watch the news but it's not always you know you wonder if it's for the right reason
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		not just the gore
 	
 	
 		they've heard it though
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but i think it's a good habit to
 	
 	
 		sure it is
 	
 	
 		to establish uh
 	
 	
 		it has been nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		thank you so much and uh
 	
 	
 		enjoyed it a great deal
 	
 	
 		i'll uh just be anxious to tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that there's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		there really is  it's beautiful
 	
 	
 		and that there's she's not falling off the face of the earth
 	
 	
 		it really is beautiful you will enjoy i know she will enjoy it
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> hopes to come visit before too long so we're uh we're anxious to point that way sometime take care and have a good day
 	
 	
 		oh
 		good
 		thank you you too
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 		
 	