
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh you know i when i was much younger uh than i am now i i had wanted to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 		and uh
 		seems like i it it was something that i i really wanted wanted to do
 	
 	
 		can you speak up please
 	
 	
 		seems like wanting to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> was something that i had really wanted to do when i was young
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't believe they accept you after you you know after you're married and you have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and all that so i got into that and i wasn't able to
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		to uh participate
 	
 	
 		but
 		they will accept you later in life also
 	
 	
 		oh they will
 	
 	
 		yeah after your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		then there's no age limit
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		your kidding
 	
 	
 		no i'm not some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have
 		been involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> among other things were retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 		uh there was a retired plumber that went to uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Uruguay</ENAMEX> i think and helped them quite a bit with
 		concepts in plumbing you know providing for a
 		for better public hygiene
 	
 	
 		goodness i'm surprised i really had no idea
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		so do you think that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be required to
 		give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> for the good of the country
 	
 	
 		well
 		i don't i don't really think that they should they should be it should be mandatory i mean
 	
 	
 		why
 	
 	
 		well
 		i don't know i it's that just might not be something that everybody wants to do i mean there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would like to do it and there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get into other things and they get all involved and they just
 		you know
 		don't want to or don't have the time
 	
 	
 		well i understand but if it were told to us that we would find the time somewhere between our
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seventeenth</ENAMEX> and uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> birthday to give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two to the</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the form of maybe building better <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> service or
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> or
 		something you know the military service or something
 		wouldn't we have uh
 		maybe a better class of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't see how that can can
 		make a better class of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to make everybody
 		to make it mandatory for everybody to participate
 	
 	
 		a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a lot of our uh
 		pardon the terminology but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX> now
 		are interested in one thing and one thing only and that's themselves
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		well
 		i don't i don't think that
 	
 	
 		and at least if you legislated
 		giving
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> of their lives
 		or or uh
 		a
 		actually purely giving but but some sort of equitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> then at least
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would have gotten <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> from them
 		where
 		hum
 		they would have given something to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> instead of take taking
 		away all their lives
 	
 	
 		yeah are are you suggesting then that if if uh if i have to go and and do something for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will compensate me in some way
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i i will be compensated for this i'm not just going to
 	
 	
 		give them your time give them your entire life for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> no
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it will be a job of sorts i'm sure that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> pays it doesn't pay well it's not top wages
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		but it does pay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the military
 		for young hiring in soldiers
 		does pay it doesn't pay well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay currently in our country
 		especially in some regions
 		there's an employment problem
 	
 	
 		that that that's true but in even in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> there's an employment problem  there's a lot of uh
 	
 	
 		you're aware of that i'm sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gotten laid off lately you know from  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are out there looking for jobs
 	
 	
 		you know in in another time we had the WPA
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Works Progress Administration</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not familiar with that
 	
 	
 		during the great depression
 	
 	
 		oh i
 	
 	
 		though i can't see why it was great
 		uh
 		that
 		gave people
 		pay that was
 		halfway between relief
 		which was welfare
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		the minimum wage
 	
 	
 		i see
 		and that was
 		that was some  some some program where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gave their time
 	
 	
 		in trade for
 	
 	
 		in trade for
 	
 	
 		money
 	
 	
 		some money okay
 	
 	
 		and
 		and living
 		they gave them food and uniforms and
 		uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> you'll find
 		a great many things
 		public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> that were worked on by the WPA uh
 		dams that were built by the WPA
 		uh scenic overlooks
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we are road our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road system</ENAMEX>'s falling apart
 		our  our national road <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">system system of highways</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> is falling apart
 	
 	
 		well then i guess there are a lot of a lot of things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could do to contribute to the good of the country
 	
 	
 		there there's a lot of work to be done
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i really i really don't see anything wrong with it i just don't think that it should be mandatory that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> have to do that
 	
 	
 		i
 		i can't see the problem in it for a year
 		the
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		what what i'm saying is that
 		if it were mandatory
 		that every person
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right</TIMEX> after graduation from high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that were able bodied
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would give a year
 		well or not give a year but
 		but trade a year
 		then they at least one not more than say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX>
 		then
 		it would definitely effect unemployment
 	
 	
 		all right i wonder if if they didn't make it mandatory if they would actually get enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> volunteering to to to do it that it you know that they would have enough
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i mean i
 		i probably
 	
 	
 		well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico Colorado</ENAMEX>
 		huge numbers of other western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have no real welfare system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		there's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aid to Dependent Children</ENAMEX>
 		and Aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mothers of Dependent Children</ENAMEX> but there's no real welfare system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if we took these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off
 		off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> for a year
 		there would darn sure be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more hours</TIMEX> labor available in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> for everyone else
 		and who knows maybe
 		some of our graduating high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> might
 		would find out
 		a little bit more the
 		what the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> work ethic means
 		you know we have had some problem with that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well yes we have with with uh
 		recent generations i i know exactly what you are talking about i i mean i know several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do not wish wish to work
 	
 	
 		uh they wish only for the paycheck
 	
 	
 		well they wish for the money and they they decide that they're going to get the money anyway they can with you know without
 		uh without without working in the the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really producing
 	
 	
 		job market
 	
 	
 		yeah be it selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 		so what i'm saying they they get the money anyway they can
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		and
 		maybe if we
 		instilled
 		the work ethic
 		you know i enjoy the i enjoy working
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	