
 
     		
 	
 		have you run into any problems with invasion of privacy there
 	
 	
 		well what i consider invasion well maybe it's just invasion of my private time is i we get a lot of those computer generated uh telephone calls
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		where they just you know go through the list and whenever you pick up the phone it's a recording and there you're supposed to hold on for a very important phone call and i feel that if it was so important that they would uh be there instead of putting me on hold
 	
 	
 		oh well that explains that i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> they they did that uh it was a very important phone call from somewhere and they put me on a dead line for
 		oh it must have been <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> and i said well it couldn't have been that important and i wound up hanging up and i've always wondered what that was
 	
 	
 		yeah we uh i don't know why it is but there have been so many of those that um instead of the the sales usual sales calls that you get that they um
 		will just run through the list and i guess wait for someone who's going to hang on to talk to them but uh yeah then we get a lot of those
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		almost sort of like these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> phone calls no  right right no these these are beneficial too too uh for personal uh benefit here so
 	
 	
 		yeah you you don't mind them
 		no most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are looking for me will try to get a hold of me at work that's about the only place they can pin me down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so about any important phone call that i have i'm going to get it at work and if the phone call comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> chances are it's either for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or one of the girls
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i just do not answer the phone call you know i'll let it ring until somebody else answers it and if they say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> it's for you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i says what are they selling  and i'd say <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of the time if the calls for me at home it's somebody who wants to sell me some oil leases or some
 	
 	
 		right right
 		swamp land in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some uh grave <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah we get a lot for uh aluminum siding
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh but yeah what do you all have what do you consider your invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		i consider that to be the invasion of privacy particularly when i'm sitting down at the dinner table and they give me a call and i i have to answer this phone to find out they're trying to sell me something and my dinner's getting cold
 	
 	
 		right right that seems to be the prime time they call is is definitely well between uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think for metropolitan areas they realize that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> work and that that probably the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> work and so there's nobody <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> except maybe school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> after school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so they might as well not even try you know not even tie up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dialing phone numbers except in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		fortunately they have uh sufficient respect that they don't call after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock</TIMEX> and they don't call <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">before eight o'clock in the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right i'm surprised they don't though  uh i but i'm sure if they did that uh there would be a lot more uh
 		public uh uh voice about it that uh we wouldn't go for that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think if i got a phone call at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> it was somebody trying to sell me something i would call the phone company immediately and list them as a nuisance call
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and what's so bad about it is um and they don't i mean all it is is they just go through down a list of numbers i mean they don't know who they're calling it didn't seem like uh it they're just a haphazard um
 		uh at it so i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but i think that's about the biggest invasion of privacy we have uh there are a few others but uh i presume that they have legitimate purposes
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> seems to intervene quite a bit uh one of the other complaints i have is uh have you ever checked your credit with the credit bureau
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh no not yet
 	
 	
 		you ought to do that it's interesting that to see who has inquired about your uh finances because uh they're required to keep track and for i think about the preceding year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's interesting to see who has uh called and inquire about your credit and there's quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that uh want to send you credit cards or uh charge cards you know will ask for a uh credit dump and then
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		send you a letter trying to get you to take their credit card open a charge account with some company
 	
 	
 		that
 		now we've gotten several of those letters as far as trying to um sign us up for you know like you you've been uh approved for a pre you know for a credit card and all this and uh i've always wondered how
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh why now we had a problem not too long ago our
 		uh my brother-in-law recently moved and uh somehow or another we we got their new address on our credit reports because the uh
 		i guess the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or whatever sort of keep up on some of them and uh had uh picked up the new address and was sending all our bills over there
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so it was like okay now wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second</TIMEX> here so it'll be interesting to see how that works out how messed up things will be
 	
 	
 		yeah that takes some paperwork to get straightened out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yup</ENAMEX> so that was a mess
 		but uh yeah it the credit there was a report not too long ago on the news here on uh
 		they were going about how easily it was to get information about anyone and uh you know they got a credit history um you know went through all the moves that they made you know their uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was just amazing the stuff that they got and it was so easily you know it was all public uh information it seemed like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well there are uh lists that go by zip codes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for specific zip codes because of uh you know if you live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elton region</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Falls</ENAMEX> area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax County</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery County</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you're a prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to be living in a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh spend money on foolish things so uh that gets you on a mailing list for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaguars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rolls Royces</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah we're in one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> and uh it uh you get lots of interesting things in the mail in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bend County</ENAMEX> in southwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> the it seems to be the the up grown you know the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the uh new generation or whatever the up and coming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are all are moving out this direction and uh the new it's funny to see how the different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are now changing uh to the um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		new demands and uh or trying to get the different uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so uh but yeah i do you know you brought a good point about the um credit histories the credit reports that uh i feel is an can be an invasion of privacy if it's used wrong
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well there was something on the news just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> that uh somebody in doing their
 	
 	
 		and uh should be so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Master</ENAMEX>'s dissertation or something of that nature uh did a study
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of uh credit card reports or or credit reports and they found that something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> percent of them have erroneous data in there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> data that would prevent that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> from getting a loan in the future or or getting a credit advance and uh the information was erroneous
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so uh i i think everybody recommends that uh well they've they the uh story <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> on this radio suggested you ought to do this about once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> but i figure about once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> is good enough
 	
 	
 		that's right because isn't it uh about fifty dollars to get one oh is it oh okay i was thinking uh maybe i got some wrong information somewhere
 	
 	
 		uh it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> dollars yeah it's fairly cheap
 		yeah well i had it done just to make sure that there wasn't any wrong information in there everything seemed to be all right
 	
 	
 		right
 		but it it's difficult to change those or or easily to correct though oh
 	
 	
 		well apparent apparently not not if you uh approach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and they're they're interested in keeping their records accurate
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh it's just nice to make sure that no uh
 		uh strange records show up
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case i think here recently where some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern Virginia</ENAMEX> uh wound up being arrested for uh failure to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support
 		and he didn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and he had a heck of a time convincing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> that he wasn't the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that was responsible for failing to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support payments
 	
 	
 		oh  i bet his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was like okay come on what are you not telling me here  right the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> life here oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh well i enjoyed talking to you and uh uh you i guess have a nice day thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all righty
 		thank you bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	