
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		now we have to talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> scandal
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		do you have any strong opinions on that
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		uh what are yours
 	
 	
 		i i think uh it's all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' fault
 	
 	
 		well i think there's a lot to be said for that point of view i i really think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> turned on the taps and then there were lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there to carry away the water
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and i think the real problem wasn't the regulation which i supported but that they failed to similarly deregulate the insurance
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i mean i think that was the real mistake they should have seen that coming it's that was like giving away free money oh sure we'll continue to insure insure you cheaply but you can you know do whatever you want with the way you loan the money
 	
 	
 		well
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it should've been do whatever you want with the way you loan the money and by the way when you buy insurance you know they're going to be looking at how you do it
 	
 	
 		he'll pay for it
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		right and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who want to spend it that way sure they'll pay more for insurance
 	
 	
 		that
 		uh-huh i think that would've been a much smarter way to handle it and the another thing that would've helped a lot would be to make certain that  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were going to use the money
 		that we were providing
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		should've had there own at stake they should've have a lot more of their own capital on the line
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when they can leverage just a very small investment into <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> worth of tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX> money and it's turning out to be a lot more than that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they have absolutely no incentive to uh treat it prudently they just uh hand it over to anybody who walks in and asks for it
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		absolutely because i mean their return is guaranteed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they have nothing to lose and everything to gain you see you know can keep lending and keep growing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		then they can take the big salaries and have the all the perks and uh entertainment and so forth and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't pay them back it's no skin off their nose they just
 	
 	
 		sure in fact they've got a strong incentive to uh
 		you know guarantee your money your deposits at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">six percent</NUMEX> and go ahead and invest it in you know the junkiest bonds possible where the theoretical rate of return is high
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because if they win they win big and if they don't who cares  they don't loose right
 	
 	
 		yes they don't they don't lose anything
 		well uh i don't know what could've been done other than the uh insurance regulation but i certainly think that was a mistake and the um
 		i also think it was a mistake to reimburse all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depositors</ENAMEX> over a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> when they were told up-front that that was was was the limit
 	
 	
 		yep yep i agree with you there too uh
 	
 	
 		because uh the promise is
 	
 	
 		this this the whole concept of too big to fail it's just silly
 	
 	
 		yeah the promises don't mean anything now
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		when the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> put <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> in some shaky operation
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh they figure the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX> will bail them out because they have
 	
 	
 		that's right and i also think the first thing they should've clarified was that the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payer</ENAMEX> would give you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred thousand</NUMEX> maximum i don't care how many accounts you've got
 	
 	
 		hm
 		absolutely
 		uh i would've been in a little danger of
 		uh you know i would've had to be very careful about where i put my money but i certainly would have
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		been alert and i would not have just been chasing the highest percentage return
 	
 	
 		that's right and i mean it would've put these money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> out of business
 	
 	
 		on a CD
 		yeah uh i don't think that'd be any great loss  we could do without a few of those they don't seem to be providing very much useful uh service to people
 	
 	
 		which i mean certainly contributed um-hum
 		yep
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i mean if you invest in stocks or whatever you know it's it's not just the responsibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> it's your responsibility you know to know what you're investing in and the kinds of risks you're taking and it seems to me if you're going to put more than a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> or whatever the limit's going to be
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that you should be aware i mean it's one thing to have insurance when you're protecting the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who doesn't have the time to make or the expertise to make these sorts of decisions but it's another thing to be you know supposedly you would think hope that the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depositors</ENAMEX> like
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and everybody else are supposed to be educated about what they're getting into
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes you would and uh uh i don't see why the for large sums of money why it should be any different from investing in a CD i i mean in a
 		uh mutual fund or a money market fund or something like that
 	
 	
 		right absolutely
 	
 	
 		uh there are no guarantees on them
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you uh you trust that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> won't sell because certain
 		brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> will guarantee at least up to a certain point the investments in the funds that they manage but uh then you're uh just at the mercy of them because they could go under
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean there is like for the brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> there is a degree of insurance that the brokerage won't go bankrupt and you'll lose your money but there's certainly no guarantee that for example uh the commercial paper that the money market you invest in won't become worthless and your and your stock price will go down
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's fair enough
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well uh do you think that we're heading for another uh debacle of this sort in the uh insurance industry
 	
 	
 		uh yes i mean there's got to be long long term consequences over this you know just because
 	
 	
 		and we see
 	
 	
 		reimbursing this is going to be a substantial cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are failing because of all their
 		accounts that were these you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> and stuff right um so i mean this things just got to spread
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i don't know how we're going to bail them out because if we're already how many <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion dollars</NUMEX> in the hole where's the money going to come from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and yet the we've got this enormous uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> just sailing out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and um
 		maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who uh bought term insurance aren't going to lose anything except <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> premium but all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> who have money invested in uh uh annuities
 		for their retirement are going to be up a creek and i don't know who's going to bail them out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		yep it's a problem
 	
 	
 		there already there already a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that had switched over from their own private plans to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> annuities that are not getting their benefit checks this time
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and the the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> is saying that we're going to protect those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but how are we going to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hu m</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> itself is already in hock uh we're running thirteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars no billion</NUMEX> sorry thirteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX> in the hole for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next fiscal year</TIMEX>
 		and you know we've got to come up with that money because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> can't run a deficit the way the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can and they're going to have to be laying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off out here in the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some of whom i don't think anybody will miss but when it gets down to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and cops it make a difference
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum well if only it would help you know pull the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firemen</ENAMEX> for a scam
 		right
 	
 	
 		well the
 	
 	
 		pay more taxes if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firemen</ENAMEX> go first
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's absolutely  they keep all their fancy uh perks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> and they uh still do their  and they still have all their
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it's something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the payroll per a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		yeah i i came from out here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i can very well remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> instead of every other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> constitution requires and people
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		consistently voted it down and since they do enough damage every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> think of where we'd be if we let them meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and i really feel that way about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ones too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i i think that if they could all just take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a five year vacation</TIMEX> and let things settle down maybe we could figure out what exactly we need and start over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but anyway
 	
 	
 		yep
 		i think constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> would be probably a good idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yep i i would vote for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's been interesting talking to you and i think we're in pretty much agreement on this
 	
 	
 		yeah it's been good
 		yep i think so too
 	
 	
 		thanks for talking
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> bye bye
 	
 	
 		we'll see you bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	