
 
     		
 	
 		ready
 	
 	
 		okay uh what what what what exactly we're talking about uh industries trends everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> changes
 		well whatever whatever i guess you want to whether things changed over the last uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		all right we'll start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years back</TIMEX> and come forward how's that sound
 	
 	
 		all right good enough here we go
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh let's see i guess some of the some of the things uh civil rights have come a long way i guess in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well yeah i think they have i i really do and it's it's no longer the issue it once was and i'm kind of glad least i i hope that's a good sign that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		uh the times have changed uh more to the more equitable at least
 	
 	
 		yeah and i guess i guess uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights have come with that too i guess so that's uh
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i think they have too i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights have come as far
 	
 	
 		probably not
 	
 	
 		uh i i think that uh in general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would feel like they still sort of getting the bum deal
 		compared to uh say some of the minority groups
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh i don't know uh seems like we come uh a long ways in terms of  the economies of of things uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if i recall back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> we didn't tend to run a debt all the time but we did run a debt a lot with the great society a lot seventies and so forth
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then uh it looked like we just stayed in some sort of a economic economic economic morass ever since
 	
 	
 		that's right what's i guess uh part of that was that uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty twenty five years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> wasn't uh  hello
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> we're there
 	
 	
 		okay that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty twenty five years ago</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> wasn't uh wasn't what it is now so that that's probably caused some changes
 	
 	
 		right i can remember
 		yeah i can remember in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late sixties early seventies</TIMEX> you couldn't even uh hardly find a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what few there were around were very ugly looking things must've been
 	
 	
 		oh yeah like uh like the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subarus</ENAMEX> and uh the old old Datsuns
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they must've been pretty reliable though because some of them they built up a fairly good following and it appears that's the case do you own any kind of foreign car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh no we don't as a matter of fact
 	
 	
 		i don't either i've always just uh i don't know whether you call it buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> it's just that i've always bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fords</ENAMEX> and i guess i'll just keep buying Fords
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh what else what else has changed oh i guess uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> was in there so i guess politics politics in general has kind of kind of gone downhill
 	
 	
 		uh but
 		well
 	
 	
 		in the last because i can i can remember maybe before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> that uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> were really up on a pedestal
 	
 	
 		some of the ethical aspects of political life certainly seem to have gone downhill and certain
 	
 	
 		yeah or else we or else we know about it now one or the other
 	
 	
 		yeah in certain respects i feel like that the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> coming right off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> did tend to bring back a more aggressive uh
 		uh aspect to the human rights issues and the sort of things that democracy in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has really stood for and and you know and uh brought it back to the limelight compared to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> and seventies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that was a positive uh positive thing but it seems like uh
 		uh with all that uh we never seem to be able to get our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in order when it comes to the economic things i i bring this back to that at least uh it seems like we still continue to run uh
 		uh heavy uh indebted indebted budgets and the like i don't see any real way out of it either i might add
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no no i there's no easy answer that's for sure or else they would've uh done something by now i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		yeah yeah i think that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		and probably the only other thing i can think of in the last uh oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> or so i guess is that uh family structures have changed a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they have too seems like that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s might been more uh migratory
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's true
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> and the grandfathers maybe even some great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> occasionally that seems to have been broken apart pretty pretty well including the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> itself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it doesn't seem the norm to have uh have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and and uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and all that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well i hope that's not right i do i do hear these statistics same as you do and uh and uh i i i always felt like at least the immediate family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> mother <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		was a cohesive structure that was healthy and was a integral part of what made this country
 		i don't know sort of a stable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in terms of discipline uh uh i don't know some not necessary discipline but certain social order that's it and i i
 	
 	
 		true
 		yeah
 		but it it it's sad that we're we're losing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> you know beyond that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> don't seem to get close anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's probably got something to do with what you're saying about the migratory
 	
 	
 		yeah in my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> i know most of us are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> just happen to be living up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> though but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> uh we're
 		we sort of like our roots and like to get back and have family reunions and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that may not be the norm for some a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as much as it is for us that don't want to do that
 	
 	
 		i i think you're right i i think that's uh very rare anymore that uh definitely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't at family reunions on a regular basis and uh and a lot of them i guess don't do it at all so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		because i know it's been a long long time since our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> ever did anything like that so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i must say too it seems like the whole flavor of uh war has changed considerably when you look at back at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX> era
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and what all we went through there in terms of what's happened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> situation it seems like uh we have uh made uh uh uh a a rather
 		uh major about face in terms of the way we conduct war and the way we we uh can technologically uh uh carry out a war
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it's it's it's easier to to fight i guess when you can find them  i remember that was the the problem back then you just couldn't find them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they're a little hard to hide in that desert
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean uh not not
 	
 	
 		well uh then too i think the philosophy is changed i was just reading <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> in the one of the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that you can take you know i i i take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News and World World Report</ENAMEX> all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> as a matter of fact
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i was just reading in one of the uh the those news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that uh there's a um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> among certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the military establishment the upper hierarchy uh uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> staff
 		to uh change the kind of way we conducted war in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> in terms of uh instead of meeting the enemy the enemy sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on instead of doing more feinting and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and technologically appropriate tactics like these smart bombs and things like that doing more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		more smart things that are very damaging getting in getting out uh making end runs allowing more creativity at the lower echelon levels for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to slip in slip out and do things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than uh has been the case in the past where the idea was to meet your enemy sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on and the like and i think politically we've changed a lot i think in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum overpower them
 	
 	
 		uh we we <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> got too much involved in in trying to manage the war
 	
 	
 		well it's probably because it lasted so long you know i guess it's
 	
 	
 		yeah and that that's absolutely the wrong way to to go to conduct a war in my opinion when you when you're in a war right or wrong you should let the military establishment handle it and and and give them the job that they're paid and supposedly skilled at doing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and let them get on with it instead of tying their hands which i felt like was not the case in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> but was entirely the opposite in the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> war
 		where they more or less gave it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> and and the rest of the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and just says hey look handle it and they did
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think the military proved itself competent to do exactly what it's paid to do and uh it just goes to give me a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a feeling that uh we did some things wrong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX> era uh and that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should have stayed out of it much as possible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh that i see as a change and then industrially going back uh i i think uh uh industrially we've changed i think we've come through an era of the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years or so twenty ten</TIMEX> of a uh a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that was industrially oriented towards uh manufacturing type industries and i think now we seeing ourselves transitioning into a more technological electronics age where it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		more of a
 		more information processing yeah
 	
 	
 		information and communication and and computers that is really our next industrial revolution
 		and uh you know it wouldn't surprise me the least little bit if we didn't see the whole idea of manufacture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> and the like except to some degree we have to keep a little bit of expertise in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that being a base export to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">third</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and you may find might find even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and
 		and uh uh major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> like uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and the central <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> economies being less and less dependent upon that kind of industry
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because it's uh somewhat labor intensive even if they start robotizing it uh i i i i'm concerned that that would be the case instead the more
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh</ENAMEX> advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> would tend to get more computerized more telecommunication oriented and the like and information is is getting to be uh sort of the thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i i think i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no that's true that's true over the last uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> that's uh that's a definite change and it's only going to only going to get worse i guess in the near future
 		it's going to be  more rapid i guess
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i i think i i i i think we're made some mistakes too for example i think the education system in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has not really kept abreast of what's going on industrially
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i'll give you an example i was talking about i've said for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> because i i my background's in physics and uh i've said for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that the education system in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has not reacted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to what is the actual uh uh uh industrial evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and by that i mean when i was going to school you got your basic sciences
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that was pretty much about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh when i got out of school i had to sort of teach myself everything i've learned uh about computers and programming and and just you know the whole bit hardware in general relative to why you can do things with data acquisition process and the like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh when i was going to school you had to have mathematics if you were in engineering or science or any of the other scientific fields chemistry and biology and the like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you never had to have computers and even to this date in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> it's not required to take computer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> if you're in in the engineering or the science fields
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		unless you're a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> or or or someone in that area and then it is required of course because it's part of the curriculum and uh just as we have to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of some sort of social study
 	
 	
 		or electrical engineering probably yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that it should be required in college in a in a uh uh science curriculum i even think in liberal arts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and time it should be required you have to have a year of some sort of computer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	