
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have any favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in the area
 	
 	
 		oh yes i love uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> foods
 	
 	
 		oh okay sounds great
 	
 	
 		both so uh i could say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enchiladas</ENAMEX> down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenville Avenue</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've been there
 	
 	
 		is uh a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
 		and we like uh stir fry <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hunan</ENAMEX> style over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		have you ever tried the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Goose on Greenville Avenue</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i enjoy
 	
 	
 		they serve a lot of food
 	
 	
 		and good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Goose</ENAMEX> yeah that is a good place where do you like to eat
 	
 	
 		i usually go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Chico</ENAMEX> once a week for lunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursdays Fridays</TIMEX> whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		favorite spot
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Market</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keystone</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah that's good what what other kind of food interesting
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh i like just about everything uh sandwich <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlotzky</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX> that have a variety of food like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chili's</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bennigan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlotzky's</ENAMEX> is probably my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deli deli</ENAMEX> sandwich i guess because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> the uh roll
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galligaskins</ENAMEX>' too quite a bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlotzky's</ENAMEX> is unique as they say different is better
 	
 	
 		sounds good
 		that's true that is true
 	
 	
 		do you typically go out uh for lunch or for dinner
 	
 	
 		well both uh probably eat out for dinner say once or twice a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i eat out for lunch probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times a week
 	
 	
 		yeah i usually hit the favorite lunch spots uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> uh being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El Chico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Market</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlotzky</ENAMEX>'s uh
 		places like that during during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i don't get out too much on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> but uh i'll occasionally go to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> restaurant
 	
 	
 		uh-huh there is a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that is really good
 		uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh La Fontana</ENAMEX> or something like that it's right after you cross uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six thirty five</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i've never been there
 	
 	
 		it is actually the family has not been here even a year in the states
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's real authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food and their deserts are fabulous so if you like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> that that's a really good place to go
 	
 	
 		yeah i live up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> so i usually go to some place like uh A Taste of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i haven't tried that is is it good
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i think it's good it's uh
 	
 	
 		because i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		okay i've been to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primavera</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like that it's a little smaller and they don't have as large uh uh smoking a nonsmoking section to put it that way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh so it it and it it gets gets quite crowded at at uh times especially on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that means a lot to me too nonsmoking
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		um
 		let's see what was
 		uh what about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		steak oh yeah they opened up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffbrau</ENAMEX> here about uh what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> in Plano
 	
 	
 		where you use for a good steak
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that's very good i take uh some some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> there aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple months ago</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffbrau</ENAMEX> and they're dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> so they're real picky about their steak but they were impressed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well that's good because i i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ale</ENAMEX> is
 		a favorite prime rib that they have is is usually what i get and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was real pleased now i haven't had prime rib at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffbrau</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		they don't i don't think they serve prime rib it's mostly just a steak shop uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Steak and Ale</ENAMEX>'s a little more upscale than Hoffbrau
 	
 	
 		really
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffbrau</ENAMEX>'s kind of neat in that they've got uh that market there too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and those uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> with all the crafts so while you're waiting for uh for a seat you get to kind uh to browse around and see what what they've got in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>'s market
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and from what i understand i know on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> passing there they have quite a wait
 	
 	
 		they've got a wait even on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">weeknights</TIMEX> uh usually <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between a half hour and forty five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you
 		really
 		um
 	
 	
 		so uh and it starts uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five o'clock</TIMEX> on
 	
 	
 		well what about fast food what do you grab you know say what's your favorite hamburger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burgers</ENAMEX> uh yeah i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX>
 		uh i do not care for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i cannot eat their Whoppers
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh McDonald's</ENAMEX> i avoid
 		i used to work there as a teenager
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh once you've worked in a place like that uh oh i don't know you don't i'm kind of reluctant to go back
 	
 	
 		yeah i can understand that
 	
 	
 		i know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is prepared
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> tries to be more of a homemade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burger</ENAMEX> so
 		it's to me it's probably a little bit better you know an
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe it's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> hamburger
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arby's</ENAMEX> is good too except i don't care for the roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> is good
 	
 	
 		place
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh well i like just about any kind of food i can usually i can eat anything any at anytime so usually whatever my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> want to go eat it suits me just fine an
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they're opening up a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keystone</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Razzoo</ENAMEX>'s it's going to be a Cajun restaurant
 	
 	
 		oh
 		is that where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flamingo</ENAMEX> was okay i noticed they were redoing that
 	
 	
 		right same building
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flang Flamingo</ENAMEX> used to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cactus</ENAMEX> before that
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flamingo</ENAMEX> never quite made it i went there one time an was not impressed
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i've never been there now this new one is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Razzoo</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Razzoo</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh Cajun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		i don't think so um it it looks brand new in fact we stopped by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time at lunch to uh talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who is redoing it and uh he was real excited and gung ho
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they've got their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> and their recipes all lined up and they're ready to start business
 	
 	
 		well good deal
 	
 	
 		but they're renovating the place right now it will take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about another month</TIMEX> i guess before they open up
 	
 	
 		i'll have to try that what about that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> there have you tried that uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eduardo</ENAMEX>'s yeah i i went there a couple of times i was there for the grand opening
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine and myself were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> he had at that the restaurant
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		but uh it's a little heavy for lunch
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you get yeah too much pasta
 	
 	
 		a lot of food
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i don't really care for that type of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for lunch
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so usually a sandwich uh maybe uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Chico</ENAMEX> once a week or once every other week something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soup</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Super Salads</ENAMEX> is a favorite place to hit too yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Super Salads</ENAMEX> is good
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those things you got to go early you know to find a seat yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah they get crowded real quick
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>'s a little dressier too more of a yuppie crowd
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		let's see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> i think my favorite place is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dinger</ENAMEX>'s over over on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forest Lane</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dinger</ENAMEX>'s i've never tried that okay
 	
 	
 		oh it's very good very good
 		matter of fact it's right by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that little shopping center
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it's pretty good and
 	
 	
 		yeah i stop by uh oh what's the name of this place <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long John Silvers</ENAMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh fish greasy fish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		great yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and then you get into the mood for something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		also in the shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BG</ENAMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zaks</ENAMEX> is that little craft shopping center
 	
 	
 		yeah i sure do
 	
 	
 		there's a a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> if you want just like a plate you know home cooked meal that's good it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BG</ENAMEX>'s
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> they have like a plate lunch special and it's fairly cheap it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two ninety five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fifty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's real good
 		so
 	
 	
 		i don't think i've ever heard of that before
 	
 	
 		that's oh it's just kind of a mom and pop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> like a couple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> an and roll and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		quick usually really quick too so
 	
 	
 		what do you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		i have never tried any
 	
 	
 		there is a place called the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean Rib</ENAMEX> on uh i think it's on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or is it on Custer
 		it's up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's very good i uh really thought it was well it's it's a lot like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		i was going to say how does it compare are the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> different
 	
 	
 		um
 		i it well they have different dishes uh it's not so much just a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> with uh with something dumped on top they uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they've they've got more type uh specialty type uh meals i guess you'd say
 	
 	
 		oh okay more like an entree
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		and and vegetable
 	
 	
 		uh-huh something like that yeah
 	
 	
 		okay okay
 	
 	
 		i've also tried uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		uh i can't remember what it's called but they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh B Bim</ENAMEX> Bap
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B Bim</ENAMEX> Bap
 	
 	
 		it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> with uh fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> on top
 	
 	
 		how wild
 	
 	
 		that and uh Mongolian beef
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		typical dishes there
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well what about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> have you tried <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh haven't let's see i think i've been in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 		and they uh i i really don't care for curry that much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that goes frequents she frequents
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> place over there by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Blue Ribbon Cafe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i don't know where that is either
 	
 	
 		i'm sure oh it's uh right there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> on the west side of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seventy five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she i've never got the courage to go but
 		that's once a week place for her
 	
 	
 		sounds different
 	
 	
 		so yeah
 		well what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> do you ever
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i eat there quite a quite a bit usually chicken fried steak
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		mashed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream gravy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's the only thing that's safe
 	
 	
 		i used to eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food but i lost the taste for that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah the burrito you can only handle every so often
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> are okay but there are better places to go the prices are not that cheap at the cafeteria
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		it uh so not
 		
 		
 	