
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Kate</ENAMEX> uh do you play golf
 	
 	
 		um i have played golf in the past i'm not very good at it even though i'm pretty well sports minded um there's something about holding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> in my hand that i want to hold it like a baseball bat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so i can putt but i have a terrible time driving
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's very similar to me
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		i just uh haven't taken the time to learn the fundamentals of the game i just go out and try to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Athlete</ENAMEX> and think that i can just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know use transfer skills from like you said softball or baseball
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and i've got that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> swing and i hook everything viciously so i have to aim like forty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five degrees</NUMEX> off to the to the right and hopefully it curves back in and usually i end up uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		going from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fairway</ENAMEX> to the other and not straight down the middle
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah like you're supposed to well i even uh took a golf lesson
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> i guess worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf lessons and</ENAMEX> and i had a terrible time trying to remember uh where your hands are supposed to be and over this way and under that way and keep your legs this way and it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		extremely difficult considering how easy it looks when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> do it and so uh i played for a while that way but i can go play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Putt Putt Golf</ENAMEX> really well that's the kind of that's the kind of stuff i can go for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		do you watch golf on TV a lot
 	
 	
 		um i watch some of the things because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is an avid golf <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> he he watches <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every</TIMEX> game he goes out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX> his whole stance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the way he walks is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">golfer</ENAMEX>'s walk  if there is such a thing and so he uh he's gotten me interested in it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i have my own putters and and you know some some equipment but um the only thing that i would probably watch is like things that are local like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Byron Nelson Classic</ENAMEX> that's coming up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and then there's another one out let me see off of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one</TIMEX> coming up pretty soon so i like to watch things that are close uh by to see if there's any names that are familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i we don't have a TV so we don't watch much golf
 	
 	
 		uh-huh no i can't imagine watching much <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> without a TV
 	
 	
 		yeah so we don't go out to the local uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amateurs</ENAMEX> very often so uh uh but you know when i was younger when i was into it i'd watch it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now and then</TIMEX> if if <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> or basketball or something else wasn't on <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and golf</ENAMEX> was always the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the if nothing else is on i'll watch golf
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i don't know it's it's pretty it's neat watching i really enjoy watching the highlights like on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN Sports Center</ENAMEX> when they show the great shots and everything i mean that's fun but i don't i'm not up for watching the whole game like i do for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> or basketball
 	
 	
 		yes yes um-hum
 		right right yeah well at least with now with the with the sports uh and and the TV is um they can get the camera's
 		just at the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are starting to swing so it makes it a little bit faster and um a little bit more interesting but i think it's it's more interesting to go out and watch them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh than it is on the TV and and to follow like one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> along on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and then you you almost feel like you are
 		in doing exactly what they are doing uh it it's so much more interesting i thought than um uh sitting and watching it on TV i think it's kind of boring yeah
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah so you've been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		um-hum uh on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron Nelson Classics um</ENAMEX> was it no it wasn't <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> before
 	
 	
 		so who'd you follow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> gosh i can't even remember you know all those names kind of go together  after a while
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		was it like a big name with a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> or was it one of the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		um let me see because i followed several
 		and i'm trying to think who it is that i was um going along with i don't remember now
 		i mean gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> i all i remember was we had tornadoes about the same time and that was the big highlight they were afraid they were going to go down through the center of the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and that's what i remember the most about that uh but i do remember thinking it was a lot different to be out there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh watching than it was to watch it on TV uh watching than it was to watch it on TV
 	
 	
 		yeah well yeah you're outdoors and you know it's kind of neat that's the only thing that's what draws me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> is just you know being outside on a large wide open space pretty much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh well down here it's so expensive i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and up there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> and you have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and if you're a student i mean you can play eighteen holes for like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> bucks
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> you know it's a big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> championship course so it's really well kept and everything else but you know down here it's it's incredible i've
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've never golfed down here because it's you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> holes for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> bucks or something and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and by the time i i drill a you know a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half dozen</NUMEX> balls into a pond or something you know that's that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an extra five</NUMEX> bucks right there and so
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it gets kind of expensive for the young college graduate
 	
 	
 		sure sure well i know uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX>  since it's warmer weather down here and you can
 		play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost year</TIMEX> round then yeah that's the reason is there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want to get out and go play golf
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> what he'll do is uh he will come down here or go someplace else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> to where it's warm so he can continue playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> i mean this is what an avid golf <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it is just so fascinating and then everything we get for him is all golf junk you know the golf hat the golf you know clock everything because he's he's just he is he is a freak when it comes to golfing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		golf clock
 		has a subscription to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf Magazine</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah he uh he's he's really something
 	
 	
 		that's funny
 		yeah so uh has he always been like that or just in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no see he um it's only been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the past five years</TIMEX>
 		and he's so good we keep telling him he needs to get into some of those senior tournaments and he says oh i can't get in there with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Palmer</ENAMEX> and all those other good people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i'm saying yes you could you know and then that's where you usually can make a little money and and profit this way uh because his handicap has gotten lower and lower and lower every single year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh but no he hasn't gone to do that yet but we wish he would you know make a little mega bucks and pass it along you know to the family
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well if nothing else just get out there and rub shoulders with the boys
 	
 	
 		that's right i know get to meet all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> because i remember sitting on his lap when i was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> watching golf he has loved golf really all of his life and but i remember watching it golf with him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so yeah this is something that uh he can go and see all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he's uh got to watch on TV for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and y ears and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well that's neat
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so too
 	
 	
 		so uh you don't see you uh
 		taking up you know and charging being the avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfer</ENAMEX> in the near future huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i think some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> are going to do that i'm a volleyball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> myself yeah yeah i love volleyball so i'm on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> league
 	
 	
 		oh volleyball
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh play with a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from here at work but i don't even think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has well they may have a golfing
 		i don't know they may have a golfing club you know it's possible
 	
 	
 		i've never really well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX>'s a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> but i've never really seen
 		a golf club but  okay i've seen a golf club that's funny but uh golfing club uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		golfing club yeah there you go  i bet you they do but i just
 		you know i hear about things like the tennis the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis um</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and and uh volleyball and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> but i haven't heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> but i'm sure they probably do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well i don't know there just not that many places to play around here from what i hear there's a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and there's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the local junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> because it used to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> so they've got the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Air Force base golf course</ENAMEX> and it's like
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		playing on dirt i mean there's no grass so uh you know it's not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> like there are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> probably
 	
 	
 		oh no uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and probably higher money better kept
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		i don't know i'm i'm just kind of glad my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s kind of in to it she's she'll play in it about once or twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> but that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah me too it's not uh not something like uh that obsession i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well if it's genetic you'd better be careful
 	
 	
 		i know that's true  well it was nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		likewise and uh maybe we'll get hooked up again sometime all right take care bye
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	