
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right
 		you know like you said i haven't uh been keeping track of what all has been going on in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> myself
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		well other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan</ENAMEX> situation where we kicked out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and his case is yet to come to trial and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't say that i've kept up too much with it i know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombians</ENAMEX> for awhile
 		we were trying to do something to give them the incentive to get out of the drug trade and there was a lot of assassinations and killings and that sort of thing going on down there
 		because they were trying to clean up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> crowd
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but uh other than that uh the only thing i ever hear about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> or some place like that is advertisements to come enjoy their their beaches and the like and what is it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio de Janeiro</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah i know what is it your talking about
 		um
 		i've i've listened to a lot of things going on i mean uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel Noriega</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> thing i think was probably the right thing to do i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was just blatantly going out and shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so i think what they did there was right
 		i'm not so sure about uh what they're doing in some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where we're supporting guerillas that are fighting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know  that are in there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because it never seems to really work
 		we end up throwing in money and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting killed and when push comes to shove we seem to back out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> like we did the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> back uh in the late seventies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so that that that kind of thing concerns me um
 		it's the things that we're not doing that we should be doing like right now there's a big outbreak of uh
 		of course it's a little further south in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> but there's an outbreak of uh uh what is it <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cholera</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX> and all so it's gotten into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it looks like it's going to be pretty serious uh thing there they're talking about it lasting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 		yeah i heard about that that's supposed to be sweeping on up through to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central American American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's it's already gotten into into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> a little bit and it has to do with the fact that uh i mean in that part of the world they just dump raw sewage right into the rivers i mean things that we don't do here anymore because we know how bad it is for you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yet they're they're you know they're steadily steadily doing it down there
 	
 	
 		and their filtration systems i guess haven't kept up with the pace
 	
 	
 		and it
 		they actually don't have filtration systems uh  some of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um but for the most part most of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> flat out pump it right into the rivers
 		and let it float on down and pump it right out into the ocean
 	
 	
 		oh um um um
 	
 	
 		and that's you know that's how they deal with it and you know they're just steadily polluting that part of the part of the world that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the other thing is the uh economic assistance uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		right now we're starting we're starting to talk about having free trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and my God this is something we should have done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> is our closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> they've been in financial trouble for years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think we've exploited them i mean when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i noticed that uh you know you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and you have good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> they sold in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and so did the meat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> that was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they sent back east to sell because they had get more money for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well i don't think uh i i agree with you i think you're right we have exploited but i i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> has had up until for some phenomenally lucky reason has been a rather than corrupt
 		um feudalistic type of leadership everybody sort of on the take sort of like the way uh the uh
 		uh what what was that bunch that used to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so that sort of thing and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> they got in this last time uh he for once is a tried and true and really you know outright capitalist from the word go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he wants to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> backs and really get free enterprise on started
 		and i was reading i think in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> or one of those or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News World Reports</ENAMEX> one of those mags that uh
 		uh
 		they were having a tough time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant farmer</ENAMEX> situation being able to compete with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> farming industry because we have these huge conglomerates
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well he went out using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>  uh
 		uh finances or or whatever you call it he went out and and gathered together a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> who had small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> inside one another
 		and he pulled together sort of like a a commune
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yet he let's them each be a free enterprise uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but they work together in terms of what they organize to grow
 		and they grow massive amounts of things that are common to each other in certain areas and yet they vary their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> in such a way that they they uh can be very productive in how many much of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> they make but they can also roll them over
 		and then they market it altogether as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as a force
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and as a result uh it said that since they started the program of course it went sort of kind of
 		kind of uh rough at first but apparently since they got the program going that they uh the amount of money and the uh
 		uh profit and standard of living that they're able to to reap from it has gone up almost tenfold from this
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		and so uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> may be actually going to finely turn the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on i mean it's always been tough for the southern or or lower latitude <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to be as productive as the higher latitude countries
 		to be as productive as some reason another and as the higher latitude countries
 		i've often wondered if that does have something to do with the the climate being uh so warm that it tends to make work harder to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		but it does seem like that there has always been a preponderance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the middle latitude zones that uh
 		uh seem to always lack in their ability to to develop industrially uh as well as even agriculturally
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that that that probably has some bearing on it
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> also there's uh a uh tradition of just doing enough to get by
 	
 	
 		um yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		they're they're not as motivated as uh as we are and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> farther south
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now you know once you you get down into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> and those kinds of areas i mean their climates are pretty much the same as ours
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah and and they have been uh they have had spurts at times i know i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		that has been fairly capitalistic
 		that have has spurts of times when they did rather well and then they sort of reverse because they have some sort of a military take over or something like that and they go into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> for awhile and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it would just sort of go downhill
 		but uh uh
 		i don't know that that they don't seem to be able to keep any particular stable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> for any particular long period of time
 		in their capitalistic type governments
 	
 	
 		yeah and while we're sitting here talking about it i'm thinking
 		you know we know every darn thing that goes on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i mean we know what's going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> we know what's going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX> we know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germanies</ENAMEX> are getting back together we didn't you know we all know what's going in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we never here anything about what's going on down in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah unless they have a coffee strike or the drug problem gets out of uh proportion like it did for awhile
 	
 	
 		or unless we're sending <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> down there to kick somebody's butt i mean
 	
 	
 		that's right or or unless they're kicking the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>'s butts like they did in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falkland Islands</ENAMEX> something like that where it involves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our allies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we just don't pay any attention to them
 	
 	
 		then
 		you're you're right and um
 		i wonder why that is
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's you know it's
 		it just doesn't make any sense i mean we're in the same uh hemisphere spo to speak i mean you know the same side of the earth i mean
 	
 	
 		could it possibly be because of they're they're little <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and they are all independent from one another where as if they had of somehow or another from their past history formed into a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like our continental <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> did
 		and uh developed uh uh a free enterprise capitalistic type of economy with a common form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that they could have uh uh been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in the world though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i i ask what what went wrong what was different
 		they certainly have the climates in the southern hemisphere uh uh to have been easily as productive and i certainly think they have rich enough land i don't think uh
 		the continental <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">of South America</ENAMEX> as i recall my geography that's been along time ago as being any particularly different or or lacking in terms of agricultural or industrial or river
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		rivers that were naturally there or so forth that they could not have developed developed a uh
 		a pretty uh uh uh by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s standards modern type of economy
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i mean it doesn't it really doesn't make sense to me
 		i don't know you know it's
 		i mean they've never really been a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in the world i mean uh we heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> only when it tried to take over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> had to go down there and kick their butt
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so it's it's like really strange that we never pay that much attention
 		i i
 		you know i just find myself lacking in in a lot of knowledge about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'd like to think i know a lot about a lot of things but
 		you know i have
 		something is amiss here as far as the amount of information that's available
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know if it's intentional on the part of you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the</ENAMEX> powers that be or whether no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> really cares
 	
 	
 		i think that's kind of it i mean i certainly don't tend to think about it like out of the site out of mind
 		uh myself uh in general unless there's some sort of a controversial thing going on that either affects me or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> at large one way or the other politically
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	