
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are you a TIer
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		okay well we might have a difference uh to talk about on clothing uh
 	
 	
 		you sound like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i talked to yesterday
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		you sound like the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i talked to yesterday
 	
 	
 		i am how come we got the same conversation subject
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i was amazed that they had the same subject on clothing too i never have had that before i noticed it on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> occasionally when i call
 	
 	
 		well so was i
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and how could they possibly get the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's ridiculous
 	
 	
 		okay well  have your opinions changed in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last twenty four hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no they sure haven't what other aspects i'm i i'm this is funny you know uh clothing let's see
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i was curious you know if they just want to talk about the words of uh related to clothing that polyester was coming back have you heard that uh i saw it on the TV that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> were
 	
 	
 		no
 		ooh gross
 	
 	
 		they had a new kind of polyester uh whether that they just like to switch materials
 		uh periodically i don't know we might i haven't we didn't talk about materials i
 		i prefer you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX> with very little in fact when i look for
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 	
 	
 		uh i i try to go for the cottons and i don't know that polyester will although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s shirts are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty forty</TIMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		i mean polyester especially in this climate polyester just doesn't work too well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i uh i'm originally from the east and i we used to wear sweaters and things and sweaters are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this isn't necessarily sweater country
 		uh you know i i guess they're not as popular as they were i don't know about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> if you do you have problems with air-conditioning or were you you were uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is that a factor
 	
 	
 		yeah it's always yeah it seems like it's always cold inside
 		and part of my problem is that i'm in and out a lot because
 	
 	
 		that's very bad yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah we've got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> downtown and i have to go to a lot of meetings in different buildings
 		and so i'm in and out of the air-conditioning and you know like i said we have to wear suits and that's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it it gets to be quite uncomfortable at times
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i am too in and out and well of course we don't wear ties and jackets certainly not in this kind of weather the the jackets
 		they don't disappear but they you know they're they're on a hook usually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>'s and again i used to wear them but i don't i don't bother with it right now
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that is a problem uh
 		where did i see an article about where they're about that subject where they're trying to
 		have
 		oh i know it was lunchrooms where they're trying to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to stay at work and so that's why they even downtown this might be applicable
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		where they're trying to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> within walking distance but at the same time in other words you go down in a subway or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and go to lunch and they say that's so much more healthy for you than going out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in the open traffic and going to lunch you'd be better of
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		i'm sure maybe you do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		oh definitely yeah i mean
 	
 	
 		and they they say that's so much more healthy for you to you know when you have to go out or go to lunch or whatever it's to to walk or however and get to a place that is uh you don't have to go in and out of the of the temperature
 	
 	
 		i haven't heard that
 	
 	
 		whether that affects how you dress i can imagine uh
 	
 	
 		the last thing i heard about fashion i think i mentioned it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was that wide ties were coming back
 	
 	
 		right yeah i uh
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		i think i always run a little bit behind It takes me awhile to get used to
 	
 	
 		well i i'm for colorful things and i sure i i do enjoy the uh the newer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> along those lines
 		what do you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and wearing slacks and all that we haven't talked about that
 	
 	
 		oh i wouldn't wear slacks to work
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> don't where i work i mean it's just not done
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		at all but now i have worked places where they do and even then i still didn't
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i might comment on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> how they dress
 	
 	
 		i don't have a teenager i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six year old</TIMEX> and he's still
 	
 	
 		oh you have a lot to experience i have two
 	
 	
 		he's still at the age where i can dress him how i want to
 	
 	
 		right  well have the opposite then  i have uh well one of they're almost now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty almost twenty</TIMEX> and one almost sixteen
 		and i learned early on being surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> here that the
 		i i love to take them shopping but i don't pick anything out you know i i just kind of influence but uh the the teen the junior high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you can describe how they dress you know you you
 	
 	
 		well i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> who has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's a teenager and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> before school starts she has me take her shopping for clothes because they fight  too much
 	
 	
 		i i know what angle that we can talk about here we they want us to talk about clothes around work but uh the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> should dress and
 		i'll give you my opinion i don't think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> should just kind of let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> dress what is the current style not that it's totally ridiculous of course but
 	
 	
 		well i just read something in fact i think it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about how the public a lot of private or a lot of the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> now are going to uniforms
 	
 	
 		public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> oh i didn't hear that yet
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		because uh they feel like there's too much competition in the clothing and it it clearly defines you know class
 		lines in where you know the the Guess jeans and the
 		you know stuff as opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't and so it takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s concentration the thought behind it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't concentrate or worry about what they're wearing what everybody else is wearing and it will take their mind off that
 		and you know enable them to you know study better plus they say
 	
 	
 		right
 		well well whoever said that in my opinion doesn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> who didn't grow they won't do that they'll never pass it that will be like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		this was  they weren't talking about it wasn't talking about actually i i kind of like that idea and i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where they do wear uniforms and uh i i really like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i can uh of course i went to school you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years ago</TIMEX> in college and uh we did wear ties and jackets and this was they have since changed it was an engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> a city
 		it was in an downtown area like i don't know well you can't compare anything around here to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in like no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTA</ENAMEX> here is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> it's not exactly downtown but i guess like that
 		and they just historically since it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> they wanted us to wear jackets and ties and i did my whole college career which is i guess terribly unusual
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		we wore jackets and ties for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and i so subsequently i wanted to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> degree in in after i got out of the service and uh they changed drafts so there was a
 	
 	
 		that is yeah
 	
 	
 		the styles have certainly changed to where i guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> now looks like typical uh college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah i think well i think for a while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were dressing nicer in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> but um nowadays uh i i still i take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTD</ENAMEX> and they um you know they wear jeans
 		and sometimes they don't even have shoes on
 	
 	
 		huh
 		the older i get the more more open to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s ideas uh you cannot be you have to let them come out with uh whatever they
 		not whatever but some of their ideas too and so you kind of back off and see what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i know their clothing is changing you know all the time and i'm i'm certainly open
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to how you should dress uh now of course the subject is work uh or clothes really i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the only again the one thing i am at at work is is certainly a professional look but i'm not saying that that will not change the professional look will look differently from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year to year</TIMEX> perhaps
 	
 	
 		do you spend a lot of money on clothes for work
 	
 	
 		no i really don't it's uh uh
 		go through a lot of shirts and think no i don't really
 	
 	
 		you know i think and and this may be totally unfair and unfounded but it seems to me like
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have to spend more money on clothes for work then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> do because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> can have a few suits
 		and you know a bunch of different shirts and some different ties but you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> practically have to have you know a whole bunch of different suits
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		well you're sure right there because not even when i wore a jacket and a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> when i was up at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> in uh Plano
 		uh we think he just brought the same jacket even that wasn't a that's not a black mark against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and you're right that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are expected to look more everything matches i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and then of course you know accessories you know shoes and hose and earrings and you know all that stuff
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		um it's just i it's outrageous you know because you know you still spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two three hundred dollars</NUMEX> on a suit
 	
 	
 		your work without saying much about it do they ever bring the subject up of asking your opinion on on whether you want things to change on how you dress or
 	
 	
 		no i ultimate  leave and i haven't been at work in awhile so i i don't really know
 	
 	
 		are the ties
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know from what i i went to a concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> and saw some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and just noticed how there's a lot of the wider ties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they're not they're not the same as the wide
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has several locations
 		different sites have a little bit different dress dress like i said at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> it was definitely more formal i think because it was newer and uh  type and many many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wore there was very there was very few production areas
 	
 	
 		do you think it has anything to do with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> of people
 	
 	
 		uh that
 		
 		
 	