
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		is this one of your favorite topics
 	
 	
 		well i love to fish i haven't in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> but uh in fact
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when i married on our honeymoon that's where we went was fishing
 	
 	
 		oh my my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> would love to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> like that i think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well yeah i really do enjoy it but i like i say i haven't been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> we used when after we got married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> after we got married we got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and we used to fish a lot and including you know we skied too but
 		after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> came we stopped and um now i'm i'm divorced so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they have a way they have a way of influencing your life
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't you know and especially when they're little like that it was difficult to have them in the boat we were always worried something would happen so we didn't
 	
 	
 		what type what type of fishing did you enjoy
 	
 	
 		well i liked trolling the best i i mean i like moving so instead of just sitting in one spot and i really do like to fish in the rain
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah i and when it's not pouring i mean but when it's just a light rain i'm i really enjoy that and i find that you we use to catch a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> when it was raining
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah do you do you like cartoons
 	
 	
 		do i pardon me say that again cartoons yes
 	
 	
 		cartoons yes
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the my favorite cartoons is a picture of a a fellow in a
 		pouring a downpour
 		raining oh now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> full of water
 		there are beer cans floating all around and the the line is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> with him and he's got the biggest grin on his face you've ever seen
 	
 	
 		oh gosh i don't know whether i'd go that far
 	
 	
 		no  but when you say you enjoying enjoying the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> that uh you must be in a warm weather climate then
 	
 	
 		well see the thing is when when i i am from originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and i met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and we went on our honeymoon to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> so it was well it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and so it was warm enough but uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i because i don't enjoy cold weather at all so we we uh we lived right by a lake and it was nice
 	
 	
 		yeah have you ever done any the uh ocean fishing
 	
 	
 		no i have not i lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> but i didn't do any fishing we did some scuba diving but that's all
 	
 	
 		no
 		oh i
 		that's that's a nice sport too i think beautiful sights and it
 	
 	
 		yes it's
 		it's it's gorgeous
 	
 	
 		now the only offshore fishing i've done is from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> and caught a nice big barracuda
 	
 	
 		ooh how nice
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah interesting interesting time i've i've been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Lakes</ENAMEX> too and caught some salmon there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i really enjoy farm pond fishing probably as as much as anything
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i've never fished in a farm pond
 	
 	
 		oh you you can get out and it a fairly large pond with a lot of stumps and everything good black bass fishing
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i enjoy walking around the edge and
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		trying to select a spot i've even done some uh tube fishing are you familiar with that
 	
 	
 		no uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that's an inner tube with
 		a special seat in it
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		and you wear waders and you have little fins that you kick around so you move move manipulate yourself anywhere you want in a pond
 	
 	
 		oh how wonderful relaxing too huh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a lot of fun  it is  and cooling
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds great
 	
 	
 		you know the the uh water below helps keep you cool
 		you may be baked in the sun in the upper <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's it's a nice relaxing way and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		gentle undulations of the water you know is it is nice i think
 	
 	
 		oh it sounds wonderful
 	
 	
 		but fishing is a good relaxing sport if you if you don't have patience i don't know if you would enjoy fishing because you
 	
 	
 		no i know i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are really too hyper to fish they have to be moving all the time i think you have to be able to sit and and just enjoy yourself quietly if you can't do that you're not going to make a good fisherman
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no and i think that's part of the lure is is just to be uh relaxed and with the world and no pressure not not worrying about whether you catch anything or not
 	
 	
 		right
 		well in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> that's wonderful to be able to do that because when we our lives are so stressful so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh do your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> fish
 	
 	
 		well
 		real sad to say we don't as much as we i'm i'm divorced and and uh since we've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we haven't now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> when they were little my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> i used to take him fishing and they both have you know gear and we've we've gone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		once or twice but and there's just not that many lakes around here that i'd be interested in in going to and so
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		you know and uh i just uh we just haven't and not that they i think they both would would like it they have gone with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and uh he lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> now and uh
 		he lives in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> area and the mountains are real close and he's taken them up to the mountains and yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trout</ENAMEX> fishing yeah that's fun too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and they've enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		it it's a challenge to learn to use the different equipment a fly rod entirely different technique
 	
 	
 		it is
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i'm always amazed that you can catch a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> on a hook that small
 	
 	
 		yeah isn't that it that is amazing isn't it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i can remember when i was trolling i caught a and we couldn't eat this it was a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock Bass</ENAMEX> and of course they're not good to eat but i mean it was it was for me it was like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and that was big for me and i was just tickled to death that
 	
 	
 		the
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		to catch it we threw it back in but um that was i think the biggest fish i ever caught
 	
 	
 		well you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> they they do eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rock Bass</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		but
 		well we don't in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just don't they don't eat them for some reason so
 	
 	
 		yeah i think if they if they cut around that red streak in it then you're in good shape um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh
 		is that right see we didn't know that so we just threw it back in so
 	
 	
 		well that's a hybrid right it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX> that migrated into the fresh
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that it was a big thing they call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stripers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Fish i</ENAMEX> know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh probably up up there too then
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		have you ever done any surf casting
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		that's fun
 	
 	
 		is it
 	
 	
 		um-hum i could stand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> on the surf and you just have a lot of weight on the end of it and you're fighting the undertow so there's some action going on whether it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> or not all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's a a relaxing time too you
 	
 	
 		would you have to repeatedly cast though in the no
 	
 	
 		no uh-huh no the secret is to cast just over the break of the wave and then the undertow keeps the line moving outward in in you know it stays there for the uh
 		flounder or or some of the other special fish too
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's good good exercise too
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well uh when i grew up when i was growing up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was an avid fisherman fisherman and we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and we would go out in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Erie</ENAMEX> because i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		and we would fish that was before it was so polluted and so yucky it was a beautiful lake then and um we would we would fish and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would i can remember even when we were interested weren't interested in when we were younger and we'd play around the the the lake or around
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and we'd go up into go uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and the rapids up there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids Michigan</ENAMEX> were just beautiful and he would fish he would get his you know his waders on his long boots and he would go out and we would just play by the water and just have a ball and he would fish and it was so gorgeous
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well
 	
 	
 		and that was one of my wonderful childhood memories
 	
 	
 		yeah i hope uh that the future generations have places they can go
 	
 	
 		yeah isn't that scary
 	
 	
 		it is it is and with all the pollution that we do have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it it's bad <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Erie</ENAMEX> when i haven't been home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> but the last time i was home i was just so surprised to see how terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Erie</ENAMEX> was i mean it just was awful
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and it just makes you so sad because at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time it was just a beautiful lake
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and not too long ago really
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX> it's been nice talking to you and i hope you get to go fishing soon
 	
 	
 		it sure has
 		well thank you and you have many good fishing days too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		good night
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">bye night</TIMEX> bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	