
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 		what are your suggestions in making a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion successful
 	
 	
 		
 
 		have a big family i guess that's a start
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i guess so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		have you had any in the last how well how old are you
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty five</NUMEX> so i just got married
 	
 	
 		okay so
 		you have you have been to some family reunions perhaps
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right every four years</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> they plan on having um like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents grandparents</ENAMEX> and all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and then all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now how long in advance do they uh let them know
 	
 	
 		well we plan on it it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third weekend</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> so it's every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so they all know it
 	
 	
 		yeah and then you know arrangements are made like during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> for you know
 		um food and whose whose staying where because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from are from down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> that's where i'm originally from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so um  we usually meet like at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>'s cottage in the um at the lake and uh make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days</TIMEX> of it
 	
 	
 		well that sounds like fun do they all have the small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too that come
 	
 	
 		yeah pretty much
 	
 	
 		so all ages
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh
 		
 
 		you know there's some my age and then there are some a lot younger <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an about four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has uh on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side has an extended family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they don't ever plan it like as like you do i think if you can count on it every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have it in mind so they have to start talking about it or getting their act together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months ahead</TIMEX> to get in touch with everybody because they're rather socially active too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so it has it seems that by doing it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months ahead</TIMEX> they can pretty much get everybody there
 		if they don't you know they'll say oh we're planning to go so and so that go to to a certain place that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> with somebody else and we're already locked in
 		but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months ahead</TIMEX> has seemed to be okay for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are the youngest of very large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		therefore they don't have many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> left
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh the few previous ones i've had uh i haven't known many of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> it really has just been our immediate family
 		and that's been very nice with uh i have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of us who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so uh we get to spend a lot of quality time with each other and that's kind of nice because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s family reunions are so large
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they don't see each other very often we don't really know many of them
 	
 	
 		yeah that's kind of bad
 	
 	
 		it really is they're fun they're a lot of fun but uh still uh they're not done on a regular basis
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you kind of forget what happened  and who they were from the time before
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's it's fun getting together with immediate family a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> are real close and we always get together during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> and weddings and stuff like that so
 	
 	
 		uh those are the ones that are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no the ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		or you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> on that
 		uh-huh where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Lafayette
 	
 	
 		Lafayette i don't know where i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a little north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> about an hour
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's very pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in there i think it's gorgeous
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so
 	
 	
 		well i uh when is your next one uh scheduled now
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well it's like the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was my high school graduation the next one was when i graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> so i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two more years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes well and do you think you'll have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> to take back with you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh maybe i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two more years</TIMEX> i don't know probably
 	
 	
 		maybe
 		
 
 		i mean you need another milestone you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess that's that's what i mean i've been married now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nine months</TIMEX> so that was another milestone i guess
 	
 	
 		yes well i'm sure and have then all of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> probably has not met your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um yeah he's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> so they all met yeah
 	
 	
 		oh is he
 		and and he's living your both living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you work to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI uh-huh</ENAMEX> and does he
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no he's trying to get in med school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well we don't either but uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who uh is working on this project
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yes and
 	
 	
 		are they getting all the data they need
 	
 	
 		well i don't know uh i i have a hard time getting uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the telephone
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh-huh getting through to anybody sometimes i call off and on all day
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but anyway uh i guess we're supposed to be talking about family reunions aren't we  but i got off that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we've kind of exhausted everything i guess
 	
 	
 		yes well um i think we have been talking probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and uh uh we both look forward to going to our next reunions i'm sure
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but it has been fun talking to you
 	
 	
 		well you too and maybe i'll talk to you again okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thank you
 		okay good bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	