
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		okay well i can go ahead and start and tell you mine um we're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and that's where i grew up so i was used to the heat and out here right now um gosh it gets to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seventies</NUMEX> high seventies and it gets very cold at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey</ENAMEX> sits um right on the coast
 		and i don't know if your familiar with the um the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> coastline but we're we're about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two hour</NUMEX> drive south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and it's uh really nice uh it's a big area for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come from the different uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> mostly like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and they usually go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carmel</ENAMEX>
 		and vacation on the beaches so it's it's pretty nice uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round but um cool always cool in the evenings and uh warm in the warm in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> but it's stays pretty cool even uh during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> for as nice as it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um we usually get a fog uh right about oh i guess <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about four o'clock</TIMEX> and it kind of rolls in over the coast
 		and uh then it usually breaks back off again uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX> and if you go just a little bit ways in i'd i'd say <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a fifteen minute</TIMEX> drive in towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX>
 		uh it the weather completely changes and it gets very hot and dry and uh the fog never makes it that far but along here it's uh very  very uh different from the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> type weather
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so what's it like down there
 	
 	
 		well right now we're having the the little bit of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> that we have yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really well at least you've got some
 	
 	
 		we we don't have many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> here it goes from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> usually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh spring usually consists of a lot of rain  excuse me especially thunderstorms
 		i don't know we've got we had one of those blow through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good
 	
 	
 		and i think we got  the same thing in the forecast for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two or three days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		it's
 	
 	
 		have y'all been having any heat waves or
 	
 	
 		uh it's gotten up to uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety a couple of</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> degree
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but basically been in the the low seventies and eighties
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh well that's good for this time of year
 	
 	
 		yeah it's not really been too bad because usually it sneaks on into the nineties a little earlier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 		do y'all have many bluebonnets and stuff up there
 	
 	
 		yeah quite a bit in fact the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>'s just about over for that uh in fact we drove down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus</ENAMEX> last week
 	
 	
 		oh i bet
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh there there were still some indian paint brushes and bluebonnets down along the way
 	
 	
 		oh i miss i miss that
 	
 	
 		funny we drove through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and i spoke to somebody else <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 		yeah we're
 		they had that we came back what day was that
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> and they had a a big rainstorm come through there part of the same thing we're getting now i guess
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		well that's real nice because i can remember um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about February</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> degree weather started in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and just continued
 		so at least y'all are getting some rain up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i'm glad to hear that
 	
 	
 		yeah this that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second or third year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> that we've had a real rainy spring we had a pretty rainy fall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> as well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		y'all weren't getting any of the strings of uh the tornadoes and stuff were you
 	
 	
 		um we had a few down here but but not anything like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> and this is the season for that
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh okay
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		they do they do pop up occasionally around here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh  yeah i really don't miss all the heat here it's i'm getting acclimated to having the cool evenings so we get a bit of a relief
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i'm i'm from here originally so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> i'm pretty well used to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> degree temperatures and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the the biggest problem with with the with the weather and the rain in this area is the the soil it's that black <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX> soil
 	
 	
 		oh is that what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is okay yeah
 	
 	
 		it's kind of sandy you know it's not sandy like most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is so it doesn't absorb
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> real well i mean once it rains a little bit it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's filled up and everything else just runs off so
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> has that same problem when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> come it's a complete it's a complete mess everything floods all the under passes so i didn't realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> had that same problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we have it especially especially as rainy as it's been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> there's a
 		uh there's a section in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dallas</ENAMEX> that has had a whole lot of flooding problems because of the rain
 	
 	
 		huh golly well we could use some rain up here we're like in the bottom of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth year</TIMEX> of drought
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		up here and they they had a pretty good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early spring</TIMEX> and we got quite a bit of rain but it wasn't enough to offset what they had lost over the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh so they're still talking water rationing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>
 		so uh it would seem strange because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> um we had lived out um west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> in Castroville
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medina Lake</ENAMEX> and that area was really going down and they were considering um
 		that they might have to do water rationing and then i thought oh gee i'm so glad to get out of there and get up here to the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> coast where it <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> and everything has <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and there's no problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and then i came here and found out they were in
 		you know in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> drought so i said well gee this is pretty much like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and it pretty much is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of summer</TIMEX> they have rolling hills around here but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they they turn to golden <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">dead grass</ENAMEX> for the majority of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> just because there is no water to keep them green
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um it's a really nice area uh
 		it's just it's just such a change uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> because i had grown up with uh the heat and was used to essentially like you said you have the cold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> and then you have the hot
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer spring</TIMEX>  and uh to come here it's kind of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the temperate</TIMEX> weather <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round it's kind of like um spring i guess if you uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		except and then in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> and then it seems sort of like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> um early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> or fall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round so it seems like we only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> springs which is or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two seasons</TIMEX> and that would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> and fall and we never really get any of the other ones
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but it is it's a really nice uh change of pace
 	
 	
 		i guess i'd prefer that
 	
 	
 		yeah to the to the heat i really don't miss the heat um we do a lot of you know when you do a lot of outside like running and stuff out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just so much easier up here and you don't have to worry about the high high humidity does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> get high humidity
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		we we it's pretty dry we get some when it's this rainy but it's nothing like i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> it's nothing like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or is it pretty dry
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for instance it'd be or east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is a little more humid
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> has been increasing in humidity over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> because i had lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about twenty years</TIMEX>
 		and it just seemed like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> it just got a little more humid a little more humid and here it's uh well it's right by the ocean but um it's not the same as at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus</ENAMEX> you you get that humid salty
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		feeling in the air but here um the well the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is extremely cold up here you can lay on the beach all you want but if you want to go wind suffering or diving or swimming you have to wear a wet suit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		and a thick wet suit at that because it's just extremely cold and i for some reason i guess it's because of that cold uh ocean
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that the air is always cool it's never humid or sticky or salty feeling so i really like that about this area
 		and uh we just hadn't expected it we were used to what uh uh gulf coast uh weather was like and we came here to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> coast weather it's just completely different and it's much nicer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> breezes make a lot of difference in that
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it does and the um the air doesn't feel anything like it does along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">gulf coast region</ENAMEX> but um but we like it so it's a nice change so we'll be here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and we thought well we'll take advantage of it and see what all the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> coast is like
 	
 	
 		that's nice
 	
 	
 		and uh so it's been good
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and we lived there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nine months</TIMEX> and that was a real change for me
 	
 	
 		oh i imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> i imagine gets really humid doesn't it
 	
 	
 		um parts do we uh we were over in the in the western edge in the mountains
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and they have of course some pretty severe
 		storms uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">storms snow</ENAMEX> and that type of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they're so good about clearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> that you know it doesn't usually bother you very much
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah  not like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where everything comes to a stand still you know uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and and their springs and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> are pretty mild too it never gets real real hot there
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh yeah i'll have to try that out because i had heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> was sort of like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i've just never really been in that region of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and i guess i'm going to have to try that area sometime and see what it's like because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are from that  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> region really like it
 		and uh they like they get the snow but they said it doesn't really get messy and it doesn't really hang around that long and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh they the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know that are from there uh
 		they always miss it and they want to go back  nothing seems quite as good yeah but anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well funny as we were talking the weather came on and there's a flash flood watch and
 	
 	
 		well
 		oh gee whiz
 	
 	
 		more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three or four days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh gosh oh well i hope it moves up this way but i'm sure it won't
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe we can send you some
 	
 	
 		yeah because we could sure use it
 		okay well you think that takes care of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the time</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i think that'll do it
 	
 	
 		okay well i sure appreciate hearing how things are going in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		well i enjoyed talking with you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah good luck to you okay we'll see you um bye
 	
 	
 		uh-huh you too

 		bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	