
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay i uh i think in general that the the
 		uh one of the biggest change in in uh the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the last
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> is the fact that because of the uh
 		probably the national debt as a matter of fact but the uh impossibility of
 		of uh making ends <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> even in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that which has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> work out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and probably that is the biggest uh change of her role that she now has to
 		um not only be uh mother
 		um nurturer or whatever but she also has to to help earn the
 		earn the income that comes into the home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and it has
 	
 	
 		oh i i'd agree with you i think that is one of the big big changes
 	
 	
 		right
 		it has uh
 		uh
 		has a lot of effect on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and it can be positive and it can be very negative
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and uh i think a lot of the problems that we that we have in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in education
 		a lot of the problems we have in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> a lot of the problems we have in in uh
 		uh juvenile delinquency whatever probably can be laid right at that door
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		because uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who does not have the kind of underpinnings that you can get
 		uh with uh with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> in the home whether it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or the mother
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it just does not have the same kind of opportunities as the one who does
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's the kind of uh
 		what would it be uh uh calming influence or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think another thing it gives them the feeling of of uh the importance of their position
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you know and and course most of their problems come from uh lack of ego
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		as opposed to too much ego
 		most of them uh do things because they either want attention or because they
 		they feel
 		that they're not worthy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so they they do things that they're not
 		not what the the norm would like them to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that it is always kind of negative
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		what what do you feel about how do you feel about the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>  being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that make that gives you a different
 	
 	
 		well i mean i i i agree with you substantially i think uh
 		i think getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> because of you know declining standard of living we're not living as well as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did or making as much money um
 		and um that was probably to a degree true for them i mean it's no longer the case where um many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can afford to have one parent
 		stay at home and raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or whatever so a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are opting not to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are working and you got to rely on things like day care
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		uh to raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and certainly that's not going to be as stable an environment as uh when you do have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's probably
 	
 	
 		taking care of them and i i agree with you completely i think that's that's certainly having a lot of effects on our society
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so do do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		no i don't no i'm single
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		um but um
 		the i mean i think that's one of the major things and i think that's had a lot of side effects in the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> get treated in society
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		i guess one of the things that
 		we can concern ourselves with is is how
 		things are likely to continue to change uh in the immediate future
 	
 	
 		i i think that's probably true i think one of the problems is that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in their
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meddling</ENAMEX>  tends to encourage that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		instead of discourage it instead of giving you a break so that maybe a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> could stay home and do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something satisfying in another area you know i i think there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who need to do things other than just
 		be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> but i think that's possible
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean i don't think that education or anything else starts at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it starts in your head
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and any  anyplace you are you can educate be educated
 	
 	
 		i agree with you i agree with you
 	
 	
 		and so it it doesn't mean they have to stop doing all the things that they might want to do and uh and so but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the environment
 	
 	
 		and i don't think it i don't think it even means that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> necessarily have to stay home and raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> either you know i mean it should be optional
 	
 	
 		no no nor do they have to stay home all the time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		there are lots of ways that they that you can do this but the but the problem is that they have so little choice
 	
 	
 		right well i'd like to see for example more flextime in the workplace i mean i think that would certainly help things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think that's right i think that would be good
 	
 	
 		um a greater acceptance of part-time jobs
 	
 	
 		right and have and have and and if if anybody is going to help them decide about uh about day care or something maybe it needs to be something worked out in uh in uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		in uh um  a workplace
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that they can their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can go there so that they can see them so that they can have this uh you know during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some kind of a better uh contact and more uh a better feeling of of the fact that they are the important thing in this
 		household as opposed to the work
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		schedule being the important thing in this household
 	
 	
 		yeah i think there's also a lot of interesting side effects to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> having taken a more prominent position in the workplace i think it's changed the workplace in in a lot of respects
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh interestingly enough it also seems to have shortened uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s life spans so there's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i would imagine that's right
 	
 	
 		there's there's something to be said about you know all the stress related kinds of things that that happen when you do have a full time job
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right it's not and and and the the problem is you see that it isn't just the stress of the work but they but they had plenty of stress before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now they're just doubling their <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> and that's and that's really
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		uh really more than you can take sometimes i think that's true that's true i i think that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		there are a lot of really positive things about the changes about uh uh more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> going for for uh better educations and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all these things i think in uh in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s life there are a lots of
 	
 	
 		they have more freedom
 	
 	
 		right and there are lots of of stages of your life where you can do things that you didn't do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh at some other time that uh if you're better prepared you're going to be able to take advantage of those things maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> or or maybe during sometimes
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i also think there's no longer sort of this predisposition that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> has to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> and the upbringer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i think that's starting to dissipate
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think that's good too i mean there's no reason why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> couldn't do it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right i think so too with
 	
 	
 		i i agree with you that i think someone needs to do it that's important
 	
 	
 		someone needs to do it that's the thing we just we just came from our son
 		just graduated from uh from in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s degree and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and he had just graduated in social services work and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh when she went back they just had a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> and when she went back to work she says okay i'll work i'll work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX>
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> but it has to be the times when he's home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so that one of them is taking care of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> all the time but it's a neat thing to watch because he's as  adept at it as she is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and equally as comfortable and i think that is a neat thing it it'll it'll be neat for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too
 		if you can get a relationship like that but where the where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is comfortable
 	
 	
 		right yeah i think i'm
 	
 	
 		doing those things because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> badly need more of that
 	
 	
 		yep well i i think it will help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> be better adjusted when they grow up
 	
 	
 		badly need more of that
 		that's right badly more well hey it's been good to talk to you
 	
 	
 		yeah it's been nice talking to you too
 	
 	
 		yeah all right have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> um-hum bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you too bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	