
 
     		
 	
 		hi this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> visiting right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Judy</ENAMEX> this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma</ENAMEX> and i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		okay
 	
 	
 		we got a great topic
 	
 	
 		i know i'm sitting here going oh dear  should we give it a try
 	
 	
 		i guess we might as well
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well um so so so what changes have you seen
 	
 	
 		let you start
 		
 
 		what changes uh i guess the biggest i don't know your age <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> but i in my lifetime the biggest is in
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working definitely
 	
 	
 		well actually that's what i was thinking too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um you know just to jump ahead a little bit but then we can back up is it perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in politics is for the future
 	
 	
 		for the future right yeah
 	
 	
 		because i don't see that really yet
 		in positions of power really
 	
 	
 		right i don't see them in positions in power in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> either  not many
 	
 	
 		ah
 		that's true that's true
 		um do you work in private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> or government
 	
 	
 		i did work in government
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and before that i worked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now i'm retired
 	
 	
 		oh are you  that's the best status  yes um i don't i see um in
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		which do you work in excuse me
 	
 	
 		a government
 	
 	
 		in government
 	
 	
 		and i work in academia before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um actually there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um woman</ENAMEX> in our i don't know what you'd call it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and i mean in a sense
 		perhaps um
 		a lot of she gets protected a lot because uh it's almost like a token
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and and it's sort of unfortunate
 		because i think that they don't accept her technically and but she's a good paper pusher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's in a technical position really
 		and you know she should be more technical for what she does
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's sort of unfortunate because it doesn't it doesn't really help the cause in the long run
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um but um
 		you know i don't know and and teaching i still see that that's where most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		in teaching
 	
 	
 		in teaching and you know and it's always been that way
 	
 	
 		but not at the college level
 	
 	
 		right not well
 	
 	
 		we live in a college <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and i worked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> for a while and there are there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> there but they're not the high paid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum not department chairmen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		yeah not the deans and things like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they did have one woman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> but and i guess she she probably did very well but
 		that's the minority
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 		and do you think it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aren't qualified or or just don't or don't want the job or just aren't hired for the jobs
 	
 	
 		none of the above  i think they are extremely well qualified
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know how
 	
 	
 		they're just not selected somehow
 	
 	
 		i think they're not selected
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and course
 		at this university uh this it's a big engineering school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't think there are many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the engineering college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's where the high pay is
 	
 	
 		oh okay but i'm wondering how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> actually major in engineering actually but you know i say that but yet i know two
 	
 	
 		quite an well i think there are more than there used to be
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure there are
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they may not go into teaching
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i mean the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that i know obviously are not in teaching but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it  i suppose in a since i was surprised when they told me they majored majored in engineering i don't know why i but i don't know that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that have majored in engineering either
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it's just because i'm in the humanities it's just
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know it's not not something that i tend to hear about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		yeah it's uh
 	
 	
 		well i met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one one day</TIMEX> that uh had just joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> in agricultural engineering and that really surprised me
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean i i suppose that that it's difficult to really say why because
 		you know there there probably are a limited number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are interested in the subject and well qualified
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and maybe there aren't you know
 		maybe they don't apply for the job
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't i don't know how many go on and get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> in engineering
 	
 	
 		right right which could be you know partial partially cultural anyway
 	
 	
 		that could be that's true
 	
 	
 		so that it might be circularly being the same problem of of expecting not to get hired for the good jobs anyway so why spend your time getting qualified
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		it's a it's a rough
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's a rough a rough situation
 		um
 		and i guess what i what amazes amazes me is
 		the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who are willing to stay home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or and in our case we actually have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who works part-time a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hour day</TIMEX> so that he can take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i'm not sure to school in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and be home
 	
 	
 		that's interesting
 	
 	
 		when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> comes <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is it uh was she the major wage earner i mean did she earn more money that he did or do you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> is is uh
 		well see i don't know anything about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but but yeah i would imagine she might
 		um because he's
 		you you know he's a really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> but he did say that because he was in the humanities and he's now working in more of a technical situation that he had trouble finding a job
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so that maybe he you know maybe she was more qualified but still but still it's interesting that you know he he's been doing this evidently for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good number of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and but it's unusual
 	
 	
 		i i know one uh gal that's she's a CPA
 		and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		and then they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and he he still was the house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he's the one that was going to
 	
 	
 		oh he was even before they had children
 	
 	
 		uh-huh even before that right
 	
 	
 		oh now that that really is
 	
 	
 		she was a little perturbed about it at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i don't know how she's moved away i don't know how it is now but i know uh
 	
 	
 		oh she was
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're we all went out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one evening</TIMEX> and
 		after work and uh
 		she was
 		there was an underlying note that she was perturbed about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i mean i think that would be it would it would strike one as strange if there's no reason for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		somebody to stay home that
 	
 	
 		i don't think there was a valid reason  because her statement was
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		i told him let's face it you're a house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that's what your going that's what you'll always be
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but but yet you know we have to think about that because if if she had opted to stay home we wouldn't have thought anything strange
 	
 	
 		she wouldn't have been that's right uh-huh that's right it would
 	
 	
 		so so we're carrying our own prejudice
 	
 	
 		it wouldn't have been a downer
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah oh gee  i guess we can't win
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because yeah if if somebody does it and breaks tradition you're surprised but
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		oh dear so so
 	
 	
 		i think maybe more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would like to be if they  weren't put down so badly
 	
 	
 		if they could get away with it
 		oh dear you know well i mean it it's an interesting topic yet i must say it's not one that i've given a great deal of of thought to but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		no i don't
 	
 	
 		in the past it's um
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those things that you know seems to happen
 	
 	
 		how do you feel your career has gone
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't feel for the most part that i've been discriminated against
 	
 	
 		you don't that's good
 	
 	
 		no i was a department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> i don't but i don't like administration
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so then i'm uh uh probably a poor example although you know i was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> and could still be i suppose
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh i was discriminated against very definitely in banking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was terrible
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you were you were more ambitious than they would let you be
 	
 	
 		right and the money didn't go with the positions
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i would
 	
 	
 		the promotion promotions came but there were there wasn't comparable pay for the responsibility
 		and i was told you don't need as much pay as i have because your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are older than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has a good job and
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh jeez
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah actually in a since i suppose when i was hired into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> um at i was taken advantage of
 		and and that's true that you know sometimes other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get get higher increments
 	
 	
 		i think
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for you know even
 	
 	
 		i think we are programmed to just take it as it comes
 	
 	
 		right
 		right that's probably true i hadn't i hadn't thought about it because i do like what i do and i just sort of ignore the administrative part of it since i didn't like it when when i had to do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i i figure you know nobody must uh nobody must like it it must be a rotten job for everybody  but i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thrive on it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 		well
 		since i don't have a whole lot more to say on the topic
 	
 	
 		i don't
 		
 		
 	