
 
     		
 	
 		okay do you have any um ideas on universal health insurance do you have any strong opinions you do
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's probably a good idea um i think given that um
 		well given that there're so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't have health insurance it's probably a real
 		smart thing that at least have some basic coverage for everyone i mean you hear these horror stories of people
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and and being thrown out because they have no insurance and having to go to someplace else you know it would be nice if
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		no matter where you are or who you are or what happened you know what happened to you you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and they say okay just just take him don't worry about who or what he is later so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah i feel like there should be some kind coverage made but i i am really leery of um
 	
 	
 		that would be a nice thing
 	
 	
 		kind of a government administrative health insurance or medical plan because i just feel like everything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> takes over is just going to be run much poorly and it's going to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times more expensive as what
 	
 	
 		yeah no that that is certainly true but i wonder about like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> where everybody everybody um automatically has insurance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		right and they have that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> too but i think it is a pretty poor they get a lot lower quality care than we do now i know that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't agree with me but
 		um i know you have to wait real long time to get for certain surgeries that aren't emergencies and you do have the kind of choices that we have here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um i've worked a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and i really don't want to give up having those choices
 	
 	
 		that's true that's something i haven't thought about
 	
 	
 		because i think i mean there is a night and day difference between good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> at least at the time i was familiar with it about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> they just told you what day you had to show up and where you had to show up and who your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> was going to be
 	
 	
 		no oh so you don't get any choices at all or anything
 	
 	
 		no no i mean that yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's a problem yeah because i i mean i know i even
 		even among you know even even now the way we have it now there's
 	
 	
 		it's getting worse isn't it  yeah
 	
 	
 		there are some places
 		yeah i mean like
 		we have an an HMO that allows us to pick our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and we picked a primary care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> and just didn't like him you know and
 		and had to switch because i felt he was a quack
 	
 	
 		right that's exactly the problem there's just so many such variation in it but you see i guess what what they had in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and i guess in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> is socialized medicine so maybe that's like the extreme of it do you think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that is the extreme and what what that i what that i think tends to do though is i think that tends to
 		that probably has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good</TIMEX> and a bad side for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wanting to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> i mean what you get is other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are motivated to be because the money isn't i guess as much for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> anymore so they would wind up getting
 	
 	
 		uh-hum uh-hum
 		right right
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really want to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> but then again you know you don't get those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who'd be good and are real smart and decided hey i i wanna make a lot of money so i will go into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> you know you don't get those
 	
 	
 		really want to right
 		right or that yeah exactly or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> also get the feeling that well geez you know you do have to worry about you have a lot of job security there
 		and it's more of a seniority i would imagine kind of thing instead of having a skill or whatever to advance and so you don't necessarily get the kind of quality control or the kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		i don't know   i think we have to have something i really do
 	
 	
 		yeah and it would be nice to see something where at least
 		right i mean even something that said you know look free major medical to all you know to everyone and then beyond that you sort of work out on your own if you want
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i know i i don't know i  i've having worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and stuff i see it from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>'s point of view and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think the problem with the skyrocketing costs right now is the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> because i don't see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> getting all rich
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> do make money but not nearly as much as insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do i think they are really making a killing and nobody's talking about it nobody's
 	
 	
 		oh right no
 		yeah they're the ones who make i mean they're the ones they have you know decide although i mean the unfortunate part of that is that is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to forget that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> as well
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		so that so that you know insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have to charge a substantial amount for certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> types of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 		given that you know someone decides to have a malpractice suit against them well they could take you know it could be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> i mean unfortunately and and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> whether it was you know i mean i feel those cases where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> was wrong or malicious or something you know but there are you know i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right there are mistakes are made right sure sure yep
 	
 	
 		mistakes you know everybody makes mistakes unfortunately and and it shouldn't be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion</NUMEX> dollar you know industry it should be i made a mistake and this is this is fair compensation not
 	
 	
 		so is i guess yeah i think that's the legal part it coming in to too that i wonder if we should have a limit on how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can sue for
 	
 	
 		yeah that is a big problem
 		that'd be nice
 	
 	
 		or  or i don't know because then that's where the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> benefits if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> weren't having to spend these huge amounts of money on getting insurance coverage
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it would be a lot better yeah and i'm sort of in a in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> run medicine program sort of i'm i'm in a well well i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at and uh
 	
 	
 		you know yeah
 		are you okay at where oh okay uh-huh are what i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> yep yep yep
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Rochester</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester New York</ENAMEX> i'll bet you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> up yeah i was gonna bet that okay um
 		yeah and as as it turns out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has pretty decent coverage through her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and can get me covered as well
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh great yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh which is great except and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> plans they offer what they call the mandatory portion which is basically major medical and then they offer the waiveable portion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		which is which is you know every you know sort of everything else you need so your your your your basic care beyond major medical separate stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh okay</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they don't and even though my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s insurance covers me for everything i still have to pay them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred some odd</TIMEX> dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a semester</TIMEX> for the mandatory portion of the insurance
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		oh no
 		that that that can't be legal
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not actually sure it is or not but no one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> keep sort of fighting it and i'm and i keep meaning to fight it but you know i just don't want to spend my time
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		how can they how how can they make you pay for insurance coverage
 	
 	
 		well the reason the i mean their rational is is they make everyone pay for it so that it it keeps the cost of university health services down
 		and everyone can use it you know it
 	
 	
 		how how does it keep the cost down
 	
 	
 		because everyone is now forced to pay for this
 	
 	
 		oh so they just use the money for something else besides your insurance policy
 	
 	
 		and there's like a
 		uh well no what yeah well what they used it no they what they use it for is is is university health services we have a we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> here and a subportion a subportion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		okay okay okay so you're subsidizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right so i'm basically paying for a welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> now as it turns out as it turns out um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i have chosen to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> as health services as out primary care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> we can do that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay oh good
 	
 	
 		so in in but in effect i am pay twice for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> service
 	
 	
 		you are
 		you are i know and see that's the thing that is the thing now that i'm in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties now</TIMEX> and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i'm
 		i mean i'm very liberal i'm extremely liberal and um
 		and i say but now in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple years</TIMEX> i have gotten to the point where i am saying i just can not afford to pay any more
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out i i wanna keep helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out but i need the federal for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to find a way to do it on
 		the amount of money  you know that i can afford i just can't afford any more it's it's out it's just outrageously
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just starting to get me angry and for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in my life i'm starting to feel like i
 		well i guess it has a lot to do with a lot of the stuff that i find out that i'm paying for now you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's that's certain true
 	
 	
 		i mean i can't afford to have some kind of some kind of voluntary optional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> for myself
 		because our our medical coverage has gotten increasingly worse over say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX> to the point now where even if we need surgery our insurance only covers eighty percent of it
 	
 	
 		right which is ridiculous
 	
 	
 		and right and so no matter what happens to me if i get in to a car accident <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> i have no idea you know  no way of being able to afford the outrageous medical cost because my insurance is now only eighty percent of what ever it's going to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um so on top of that um then what if i  what if we decide to have universal health insurance so i am subsidizing
 	
 	
 		everybody else
 	
 	
 		and and what if they are lucky enough to get into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and a program that's going to say okay well you really need to have those varicose veins or fixed or your teeth fixed or something like that and i'm paying for it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it stuff like that has happened with education and other things that you hear about and it's just wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX>  you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't getting that how come their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids kids</ENAMEX> are getting
 	
 	
 		exactly i don't i don't uh
 	
 	
 		and and i know that it's only in a few cases and i don't want them to to uh cut funding for welfare programs or anything i don't want them to do that because i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they live right on the edge and they need that
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah it's it's one of the strange i i think it's strange as you get older i i i think the tendency is that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get older
 	
 	
 		but but i
 		uh-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and gain i don't i don't i don't want to say more responsibilities but you know things like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and so forth they tend to lose that liberalism they had when they were younger
 	
 	
 		uh-hum right
 		well yeah that's and it's uh it's funny because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> i hear a  quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX> let's see if i can remember it anybody who's not a liberal in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his twenties</TIMEX> has no heart and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's not a conservative in his fifties has no brain
 	
 	
 		that is probably very true
 	
 	
 		it was something like that  yeah and uh
 		i don't know i guess that's what's happening to me but i i i think it's just starting um its
 		i i don't know maybe other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i do you think it's a sign of the times that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are starting to say alright really we really mean it no more taxes or maybe is it my own personal
 	
 	
 		no i i think think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are starting to really mean it i mean everywhere you look you're getting something new i mean you start off you know especially um you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you don't have state tax do you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no no income tax
 	
 	
 		right we have we have federal income tax state income tax local income tax we have state tax on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline um</ENAMEX> you know because our our so on top of the federal tax on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> we have state tax on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> so we're just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		oh
 		wow yep
 		yeah but i tell you um we have incredible property taxes down here
 	
 	
 		or that could be yeah making up for the difference
 	
 	
 		so yeah and we don't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that other states
 		
 		
 	