
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay um i have i have i purchased a gun um recently and um i wouldn't i i feel like that
 		the way i feel about it that uh you know it would be nice if you get could get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> completely although i do like to shoot them for sport but i don't think you're going to be able to do that and to make it difficult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> uh no matter what some somewhere or other so make it difficult for the for the for the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the world i don't think it's going to solve the problem so that's my opinion
 	
 	
 		yeah i think um  i i'm a i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of uh gun control  um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> i think you'd be surprised is is very pro gun control
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in fact we have um they're now introducing some of the more  most restrictive gun control laws here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and uh the um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> did a nationwide nationwide campaign to raise money to defeat uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s um  local state laws and lost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> uh
 		voted in favor to have gun gun control here i think the problem is is because of um  we have there's so much crime in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">adjoining community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 		that um we're hoping that they could you know if they put in more stricter laws then that crime won't reach out into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> which is in a sense a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of that um  i guess they're experiencing now
 		i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> murders or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> murders a day in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> normally associated with automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> so i think that's the um  that's the big press up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> is that they want to remove automatic weapons
 	
 	
 		okay well yeah i
 	
 	
 		so yeah i can understand you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> for and we everybody else in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> supports that and hopefully and hopefully
 	
 	
 		well we have we have a very high crime rate here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we're dealing with uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think what you'll find though is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> is very
 	
 	
 		situation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is pro gun control
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know i am but like you know you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> and you're a sport you're a sport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> that's true and and that that's why you know in a sense
 		how it doesn't it does inconvenience you but it could save lives i think is the way we look at it here and we're seeing so many murders um  between uh in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well do you think though that i mean if you have to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> in order to purchase a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> are they really going to do these background checks and and if they really
 	
 	
 		well i think the i think the long run is is to get um
 		is to get and this is very active in the politics politics here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> now then  the long run there's also there's a bill being trying to be passed right now i guess through federal the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> on um  instant checkups a a total computerized system
 	
 	
 		i've heard about that but they say it's so so going to be so expensive they'll never do it
 	
 	
 		right and it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> away but it it will be
 		it probably will be implemented on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> first because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> is here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and the this will probably be the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that will start to come in faster so yeah it will take a while before um
 		it comes in but that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why i guess the the plan is here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> um because i actually just received uh information from my um uh the um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady Organization</ENAMEX> that um they want this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> bill passed until
 		the um  the new bill until they can actually have a computerized system and i think the idea of the Brady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> is to have this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> waiting period to be able to check up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> purchases or whatever
 		um until they can do it automatically on a large computerized system
 	
 	
 		yeah but what what's going to happen to the uh purchasing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> illegally i meant i meant the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who shot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> was he had he purchased his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many months</TIMEX> before he actually committed the deed
 	
 	
 		oh sure  that's
 		that's true but he had uh he had a history of of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> and and suicidal behavior you know
 	
 	
 		that's true they that may be true but if he wanted a gun
 		i meant i meant you can purchase almost anything you want illegally meant there is a way to get it do you think he's not smart enough to figure that out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well i don't think he would have been i think that his his type of crime i don't i don't think he would have been i think a street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> would be you know like what you find in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		don't think so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they would be capable of doing it i don't think this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> would have i think i think the idea is that they also um my idea too is to remove the automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from the markets you know not to be able to purchase walk into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and buy an automatic weapon
 	
 	
 		right
 		so you think maybe some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are mentally incapacitated that will eliminate some of that which which really
 	
 	
 		right
 		it'll it'll eliminate some of the you know that that type of crime or whatever yeah and
 	
 	
 		i mean if you can eliminate any you're doing
 	
 	
 		right you can do anything yeah and i i think that's
 	
 	
 		you're doing well
 	
 	
 		you know in a sense uh i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that are peace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> and i'm not that extreme Everything they think that everything comes down to
 		you know the whole world but i just think that right now we should do a little bit better checking and and um and i i believe totally that automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> should not be sold in this country
 		um those are you know paramilitary i don't think even sport you know do you know anybody that sport hunts with a automatic weapon
 		see and i don't either so and i do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is a lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>  so it's fun you know it's um but it's just a belief you know i guess we all work towards um what we think will make it a better society
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		um-hum  and everybody's differences of opinion are probably good that's what makes our you know
 	
 	
 		well yeah i'm you know i just you know i just couldn't understand what uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Sarah Brady</ENAMEX> just needs something to do i mean this doesn't seem to be you know what is she really going to accomplish if this goes through i mean it's really not going to solve anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but if you're also talking does this have anything her bill have anything to do with the automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> yeah but it's a start
 	
 	
 		no but it's a start i think i think what you i guess you have to look at things almost just like the i guess the like the pro life and pro choice is that you start with something and if you accomplish it then you increase your objectives and and you move to the next
 	
 	
 		you can't you can't do it all at once you has to do it gradually step by step
 	
 	
 		yeah you can't do it all at once
 		yeah so once if you can um i guess if you can show the put a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> waiting period in you can mobilize for that then you can also um  uh if you show the weakness in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> which is a big lobby you know hopefully you can show enough weakness
 		um from the the the gun control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> you can show enough weakness that you can you know  get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to put a total ban on on assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		i guess once this passes in some areas and then if you after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so</TIMEX> you have some statistics to work on that would show that it that yeah it does work
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's  yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it has cut down at least in this area so maybe somebody else would want to
 	
 	
 		right yeah and see now and if it doesn't work i would be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to say you know just like prohibition didn't work if it doesn't work i think i'd be one of the first ones to say okay you know it hasn't worked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> it hasn't reduced any crime the statistics still show the same so
 	
 	
 		but it doesn't uh won't do anything to uh in other words step if they you know i meant i i still keep my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and you keep your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> if you have one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it doesn't eliminate what's already out there but just
 	
 	
 		well see you already registered i think the idea is to get a better idea of who purchases <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> purchases what type of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and and and also you know the idea that somebody can go out you know a lot of the the mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> you know like that one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> that walked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office</ENAMEX> purchased he was severely depressed
 		um from he'd just lost his job um the he was severely depressed he'd been taking depressant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or whatever and he walked into a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> bought automa tic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> bought bullets drove immediately back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office</ENAMEX> and shot his former
 	
 	
 		oh right
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> you know and i think the idea is if you put a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> waiting period on some of these instant crimes you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> may seek help before he murders you know ideas like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and you know in in all honesty i think all of us believe that uh that um  uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> don't
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		you know that i i think but the idea is to is the the compulsive neurotic by gun killer
 	
 	
 		so do you think there well i guess there are quite a few of those
 	
 	
 		there there are and and they always take a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with them  so i
 	
 	
 		that's the unfortunate thing the innocent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i meant not that anyone should die
 	
 	
 		yeah see and in the back of my mind if we save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> life if if you save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> life you have to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> probably less because if you have a clean record it probably would be faster than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> you know but you have to wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but how would how would anyone how would how if i went to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and and i had been under the care of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> how would they have a record of that
 	
 	
 		you have to wait
 		oh they probably wouldn't not yet they probably wouldn't
 	
 	
 		i mean that's something that's privileged information that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor patient</ENAMEX> type thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so how how is that going to
 		you know how how is that going to work
 	
 	
 		well  they might contact maybe an immediate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and ask them if you know they thought that you were capable
 	
 	
 		oh it isn't you're really talking big bucks to start doing this kind of thing
 	
 	
 		sure yeah but i i think it's worth it you know that's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they have strict gun laws in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and they have and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and they have very few murders by by uh automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> you know even the even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> for the longest time didn't really carry <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX> though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but are are there are there uh uh an equal amount of per capita number of killings by other means
 	
 	
 		no it's far less than what we have in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> we're like the murder capital of the world  in the civilized world you know above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">third</NUMEX> world countries
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure would be nice to feel safe again wouldn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah  and i don't know it's it's just who knows it's an argument i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know but i see that's the thing i totally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent see everybody's point my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the NRA we argue about this over dinner
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> don't care one way or another so they just always say oh just shut up boys
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i'm glad i talked to you because i have some i got some uh information from the other side because i was
 	
 	
 		yeah well and you know what's really funny is that it
 		
 		
 	