
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay where are you calling from
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's coast to coast  it's a little little bit earlier there though
 	
 	
 		it sure is
 		right it's just uh about about twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> here
 	
 	
 		but we're talking about a national topic anyway
 	
 	
 		that's right and i think that anything we can do to improve the federal budget would be  a boon to everybody no matter where they are in the country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		that's the truth and i know that we've we've just come off a national high with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> but now we're facing the same old problems that we had before and that is balancing the budget
 	
 	
 		
 
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s budget is but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>'s state budget is uh disastrous right now too
 	
 	
 		well so is ours we have just been told that we're thirteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX> in the red which is more than the entire state budgets of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		and they're talking about uh cutting uh aid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> particularly the uh university systems
 	
 	
 		
  
 		it
 	
 	
 		and i our local school district is going to have to fire all it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher aides</ENAMEX> to balance the budget so i things are tough all over
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> has always been a leader
 	
 	
 		well  i i hope in this case the rest of you will be spared
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh now what was the proposition number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> that you voted on for
 	
 	
 		oh prop thirteen is the one that uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		limits the amount that uh real estate taxes can rise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> property taxes can only go up a certain
 		amount per year uh until the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is sold or  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> dies and then it's reevaluated
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah that that i think was a a smart move i don't know how it's worked out but it it seemed very logical in fact it raises one of the issues that i've thought about the national budget
 		the budget relates to all of us and so does the tax law which usually is an offshoot of the budget process i've often thought
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> ought not to be allowed to pass any new tax laws say every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> instead of every year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> has no opportunity individual or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> or any other business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> has no opportunity to plan long range
 	
 	
 		well that's certainly true we can get hit uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> at least seem to get blindsided by taxes that are sometimes even retroactive which i would have thought was then unconstitutional  but doesn't turn out to be
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		to the beginning of
 		right
 		uh that's another thing too i've often often wondered seemed to be when i was growing up i learned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Civics</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> has to initiate all
 		tax bills
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't think it's working that way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no it's i don't know where some of these things come from but they look like they're from out in left field to me
 	
 	
 		no what
 	
 	
 		i don't know what we're going to do long range to solve the budgeting problem but there certainly has been proposals why are are you aware of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Commission</ENAMEX> proposals from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> refresh me
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WR Grace</ENAMEX> uh was put in charge of a commission to find government waste uh this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or ten years ago</TIMEX> now and he came out with a whole book
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh yeah okay
 		right
 	
 	
 		of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> i mean it has his name but he was just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> of it of places where things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> purchasing could be rationalized where uh
 		renting of space could be made much more efficient where a lot of the accounting is just you know incredibly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> and could be straightened out and where lots of different government activities are redundant
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and where and there are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every years</TIMEX> budget that are just totally wasted because nobody is running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as if it were a business
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's exactly the point the business or personal budget either one i've
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh we we couldn't afford to do that sort of thing we can't we don't have money to throw around personally
 	
 	
 		no and when you're not responsible and that's really what it comes down to because you know it a government uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> really doesn't care about what the postage rate is
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 		it has no incentive to hold back on expenses uh i happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> to work for a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for a while and
 		it absolutely boggled my mind the way they budgeted because there was no uh an attempt to figure out what it really should cost to do what we should be doing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was just take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s budget add <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X percentage</NUMEX> ask for that and if you hadn't spent all your money by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> run out and buy something quick so that you
 	
 	
 		buy something that's right because you you are afraid your allocation will be cut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		that's right i can remember uh the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> got new electric typewriters because we hadn't spent all our budget money in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> that was just crazy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and the mentality was and probably rightfully so because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> devising the budget uh didn't go back to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> based budgeting they just did it on the basis of what they spend <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> increase and uh go on with it
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		we might come up short <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> if we haven't spent everything <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and so no matter how foolish the expenditure be sure we get rid of that money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> and you know grace uh type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste</ENAMEX> that you mentioned we see often highlighted in the military and the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> but it's uh i'm sure it's widespread to every agency
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		i think uh probably if you just looked at congressional budgets the amount they waste on frivolous things uh with congressional office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		again mind boggling you read about what it costs the new uh house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> or uh the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> to redecorate and my God those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> were just redecorated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		they it they spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX> they're spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> just this year
 		for a feasibility study to determine whether they should build a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> gym at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">capitol</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm surprised it's that low <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's that's not to build one stick that's just
 	
 	
 		oh i know i'm surprised the feasibility study could be done for that
 	
 	
 		well it that's the kind of thing that makes me mad i want to vote the whole batch of them out of office if that's the way they think they should spend our money and just because it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few hundred thousand</NUMEX> here
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		who was it said a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion</NUMEX> here a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> there pretty soon we're talking about real money
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's sad
 	
 	
 		i think that was old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett Dirtyson</ENAMEX> or somebody
 	
 	
 		that's sad and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't realize it we've become sort of blase about the uh amount of money because a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a dollar</NUMEX> a second
 		back in the national debt just a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> a second it would take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> to repay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion dollars</NUMEX> now you know that's that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and that's a lot of money
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		and when we're talking about trillions
 	
 	
 		and when we're talking about adding that mu ch to a budget where it's just already in the hole just the think about the amount of interest we'll be paying on that we'll probably more than double it
 	
 	
 		um have you
 		the uh banking crisis is another another case i was reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDIC</ENAMEX> saying that they couldn't take on another large bank failure without going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and borrowing and i started thinking now wait a minute they're in exactly the same shape
 		uh that they criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> that they're dealing with  exactly the same shape but
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yeah the only difference is the the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> that's right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDIC</ENAMEX> can't go broke
 		yeah because you and i will pay for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> or our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right have we solved anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i doubt it  but then i doubt if we ever will just keep writing to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> and telling him that
 	
 	
 		i i moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> and just moved back to the southeast and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> just passed uh last year
 		a law stating that uh or limiting the terms of the state representatives
 	
 	
 		yeah we did that this year too <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> just passed that in the last election
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it will be interesting to see if we have any any impetus to go on to the national
 	
 	
 		i hope it will
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so too i i get torn thinking about some of the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think are good and having to lose them but on the other hand uh maybe they'll pay more serious attention to the process while they're there instead of the reelection
 	
 	
 		i'm
 		well the thing is
 		yeah what's funny is that everybody says they want to throw out the rascals but nobody wants to throw out his own rascal  otherwise we wouldn't have ninety <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> of the incumbents reelected
 	
 	
 		nobody does
 		that's right nobody does
 		all right right are you working
 	
 	
 		yes i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> good
 		oh i i would uh love to get into another conversation with you about that
 	
 	
 		well it's a fascinating job i get to see all kinds of interesting ideas
 		and i do my small bit to help in uh at least express themselves coherently even if i don't always agree with what they're expressing
 	
 	
 		oh i i can imagine that that whole process is fascinating to me i think i'd like to observe if not participate sometime
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we've got some really really interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we get fifty different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> from all around the world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so we get just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> of intense interaction with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and sometimes we really hate to see them go we'd like to keep them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and lots of times we're not so
 		
 		
 	