
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what kind of  do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah we have one that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen one</NUMEX> that's fifteen and one that's just now <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and we had kind of a hard time finding someplace that would
 		we could put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s because his birthday is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> and he was going to school at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so he started the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade when he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or started
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade when he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you had trouble finding somewhere for him to be before he was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so we could you know we tried to find him someplace where he could learn something
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it was
 		uh
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		mediocore mediocre expensive it wasn't really that expensive but it's really hard to find someplace where you can send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and expect him to learn something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		to learn something and that's i mean that's  even not only toddlers but you know even your older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's hard to find anywhere there really going to learn something and then yeah you do have to pay you know if you the better the place the more you're going to pay
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		yeah but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> pay when they stay home with them anyway
 	
 	
 		true very true if
 	
 	
 		you know my
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> works so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it costs us more for her to stay home more than it does for him to go to the babysitter so
 	
 	
 		um-hum if i had any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i would uh i hope that i'll be in a position to stay home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i'm not real uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> trusting  of a lot of people
 	
 	
 		yeah see i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh especially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i work in the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> and i just see different things all the time
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just crazy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> they're crazy
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		and  and i don't you know it takes me a takes me a long time to just trust someone as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> much less to you know trust someone with my with my child
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well see we took our time and we checked it out and we found a preschool for him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it you know through other
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> where i where i work i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so through other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> where we worked we
 		found a nice preschool it was actually at a licensed preschool you know we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		had those requirements
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i guess that's the best way you know to get recommendations from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or family members
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you know i well that and
 		you know i don't think i would have left him anywhere that would i would have stayed home with him first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		before i left him somewhere that you know they still have unlicensed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">babysitters</ENAMEX> running around up here and
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know i just i i don't think i'd take that chance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i think it's out of sight or out of mind for less than
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i mean you have to be you have to be sure that these people
 	
 	
 		for more than a minute or so
 	
 	
 		i mean not that they're going to abuse your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or anything but you just have to be sure that they're going to be watching them you know that they wouldn't let them drink something or
 	
 	
 		but you never know
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know eat something off the floor you know just simple things that can be harmful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but you you know
 		as far as brittle as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> you never know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't know who you can trust and who you can't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and you hear so much you know on the news about
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		uh child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> and also um senior care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> you know and you hear abuse yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah senior care is getting real bad
 	
 	
 		and so you just you just don't know and you almost want to you know spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> with in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> just to see how it is or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		so you have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at all huh
 	
 	
 		no i don't
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gee
 	
 	
 		no
 		i'm
 	
 	
 		do you miss that part in your life or
 	
 	
 		uh no i'm only i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i still have a little bit of time
 		um it's just not in the cards for me right now i'm trying to get my career going
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i imagine yeah working in the news production anyway back to the subject
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we should have discussed this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> but anyway it's tough it really is it's hard to find
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		good child care and it's hard to find someplace where you can leave your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> that he's going to be fine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and you brought up a good point you know about learning you just don't want a babysitter you you would hope that maybe they'd come home and know some of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s or something you know get them
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah you know and he's he's doing real well it it it has paid off for him he's in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade now and he's you know got a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade reading level and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade math level
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so you know those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early ages</TIMEX> when he would you know when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> are at work and he's actually in child care in a preschool not
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just child care you know we could have sent him to anybody you know there's a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at work that would have babysat him but
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sending him to a preschool where he actually learns something has paid off not only for us his his attitude is i think a little bit
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		tall for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six year old</TIMEX> and
 		you know but his
 	
 	
 		did you take this same uh route with your other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they they were outside my marriage so
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i would say no but
 	
 	
 		i was wondering how
 	
 	
 		you know all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> excel they're they're really good and i guess no he learns from the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> too but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		and it helps that he has older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> you know um just to have role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah seeing like uh in one way we're kind of lucky because they're all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> but in another way we're not so lucky because we don't have
 		another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to share but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we faced that too but
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		he learns quite a bit he learned quite a bit from
 		not only from nursery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but he learned quite a bit from the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know he's excelled and it's paying off for him it really is he's
 	
 	
 		that's excellent
 	
 	
 		he is pretty smart sometimes he's a little bit smart mouthed but he is smart you know yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> isn't
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		but
 		i think it's important i think it's really nice to know that you can
 		find someplace i don't know you know how it is down there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> we have a few that you can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to and they can actually learn something instead of just being babysat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do they have any kind of program like at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> or wherever your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> works
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		um some any kind of day care
 	
 	
 		no not any
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		we just
 	
 	
 		hum because i know they're they're putting that into a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah they're trying to the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is trying to insist on that too so
 	
 	
 		right
 		so maybe that'll be an option for
 	
 	
 		no we don't yet
 		well it would be nice
 		you know there
 	
 	
 		but then i i foresee that being just a babysitting
 		thing not much learning but
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah there's not well
 	
 	
 		kind of somebody to just watch your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> while your at work
 	
 	
 		you know where where we sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first few years</TIMEX> was there was different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> all the time you know some
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> were there in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and then some substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> and they actually taught him something instead of just watching him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and then he they had a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they put on skits and they put on plays and they did the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> thing and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> things
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's you know it was important to us so we you know we took a good look at it and made sure it was going to go that way
 	
 	
 		hum
 		do you think it would have been better for him to have um
 		maybe one continuous teacher somebody to that he could
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh get attached to or is it better the other way with a lot of different
 	
 	
 		no because i think
 		you know as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> growing up i think is a task that belongs to his parents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think he needed to be attached to too even though he did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know he attached himself to a couple of those but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think his attachments at home and you know he gets the idea of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is for and uh you know i have different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> here and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can teach me one thing and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> teach teach me another and
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		no so i i i really can't say that it would be it's important for him to attach himself to anybody
 	
 	
 		right um um-hum
 	
 	
 		he did well you it it with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> i can't say that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because i don't have that experience
 	
 	
 		yeah each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is individual as for as learning and things
 	
 	
 		yeah see
 		but i don't have that experience so i can't say that you know he did well so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think we made too many mistakes
 	
 	
 		right well it sounds good sounds like he's doing real well
 	
 	
 		we tried hard
 		yeah he's doing real well
 	
 	
 		um-hum well good
 	
 	
 		and he learned from it so and that was the most important thing that we wanted was for him to learn not just to sit there and be babysat all day
 		you know babysat sounds to me like
 		well you're here i guess i'll watch you when i get time you know maybe i'll clean my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> maybe i'll cook you lunch maybe i won't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and
 	
 	
 		and they'll probably sit him in front of the television
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know while they do other things yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and i don't you know i don't allow that when he's at home so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		we had a good experience and we really did well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's good that's good
 	
 	
 		so and he didn't
 		he served
 		better than we did you know he gained he actually gained from it you know sure we gained from it because we were allowed to continue our employment and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		continue our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but i think in the long run he gained from it just
 		being somewhere where we learned something instead of just sitting around watching TV and playing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and its important
 	
 	
 		that's probably what i'll try and look for whenever i do have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i don't know when that will be but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know just really look into it will it will take me a long time to find somewhere i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		just because i i just want to be i want to be so positive that you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as well as the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the center you know
 	
 	
 		well you know his his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> didn't go back to work till
 		you know he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we just didn't want to dump him somewhere and make him feel like he wasn't wanted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and we wanted his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of attention at home but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we did what we could and it it worked out real well i'm glad we were so careful
 	
 	
 		it's difficulties but it's it's a lot more difficulties <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> because you have both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> working a lot of times and so you have to find day care whereas you know here
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you know
 		well it
 		most of the time now it's a necessity you can't afford
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		you know i'm not making seventy or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> eighty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		it's pretty tough
 	
 	
 		so child care's a necessity whereas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> basically worked and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> basically stayed home
 	
 	
 		yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom  mom</ENAMEX> was allowed to stay home and there was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> outside of that where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> stayed home and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> worked but not very many that i know of when i was growing up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know i'm forty now but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid mom</ENAMEX> was always at home
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so we didn't
 	
 	
 		i think that has a lot to do with just just all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> how they learn and things just because the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is is breaking
 		you know the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is not there anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah it is yeah it is i'll agree with that it is it's it's not there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i think that plays a big part in in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s learning and you know what they can and cannot do in child care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i would think
 		
 		
 	