
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		um you know one thing that i miss being in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is the opportunity for um
 		job growth just different job opportunity i was talking with somebody from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bausch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lomb</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and she was telling me how she started as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> typist and then found another opening in another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and
 		moved on and so forth and so forth and is now uh personnel uh director
 		and i mean it's just it's there's so much opportunity in a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to uh stay within the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so you're not losing your seniority level but um
 		just to try new things and and see new areas and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and i mean you can in in a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you can go from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> as if if you switched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		well yes you have an opportunity to  to use a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J O B</ENAMEX> system which is a job opportunity system it's most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> most big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think sometime that you get lost in that also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really do i i i sometimes think that
 		a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> may offer
 		well i'm not sure how to put
 	
 	
 		well uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure how to put this but that's not
 		uh perhaps better one on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> uh relations a a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> sometime you can get lost you can you can uh opportunities do arise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the competition is much greater for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well it's true yeah
 	
 	
 		opportunity okay
 	
 	
 		there is a very uh uh at least in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and i know that's not necessarily the way it is all over but the camaraderie within the office
 		when you're with a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i think you're right you could be even uh you can be a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		exactly i and i think you get a lot more support from your coworkers and and often times in a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you are asked to go and do things in other areas that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		may not be your expertise okay but they require you to do this as their as your uh stepping stone or whatever you'd care to call it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and that can get to be sometimes very very disastrous with the consequences of that because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do the best they can
 	
 	
 		uh-huh sure
 	
 	
 		and often times it's not really what
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		was aimed at in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place if that makes sense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i yeah i understand that you know a question that i have for you is um do you feel working working in a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> do you feel that you can see the impact that you make
 		do you feel that you can see like the results i know in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is vital because we are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> really can see the results that they produce
 	
 	
 		yes i can i see that in my job because my particular job is of of a troubleshooting nature and i'm you know it's one of these put out fires things  so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can see the results of that
 	
 	
 		i see yeah
 	
 	
 		but um
 		yes i i'm i i get a lot of gratification from my job but some some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> i guess they go to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and they just go to work for a paycheck every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two weeks</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i
 	
 	
 		but in my particular job i really enjoy it because i do have an opportunity to help other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do better okay and i really like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh i i do feel bad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean obviously we all work for a paycheck but it's nice if you can be enjoying it you know while you're doing it
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah i i i also teach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> i'm a i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> there so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i teach new
 		well not new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> but all yeah all employee any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> really that that care to and we talked about the job opportunity system we have uh a system where we train <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to become what we call automation specialists
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and it's a job where if you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> you decide you want to be uh an automation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> which is a much higher paying job and a much more technical job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then you would come to one of our in-house classes
 	
 	
 		that is great
 	
 	
 		on on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> time
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and and and or on overtime so we don't involve the the uh production process okay of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> coming to our classes and we set up and establish these
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sixteen</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty week</TIMEX> classes at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at uh three hours</TIMEX> a day twice a week
 		for automation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> training
 	
 	
 		that is wonderful
 	
 	
 		when you finish hopefully you've acquired enough knowledge to uh
 		you know move on into advanced machinery type operations and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and that that's really gratifying to me i
 		i see a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> come in and and gals and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> both and some gals that say i've no i don't know a hammer from a
 		a nail or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a</NUMEX> wrench i mean you know and okay that's and that's where we'll start but and we have the other side of the coin where you have you know really advanced people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		coming in and and top notch uh
 		mechanical type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they want to do better so they of come they they jump right on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that is great and that is so smart because with uh everything becoming so much more technical and sophisticated
 		you're just not finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out in the work force that have the skills that you necessarily need
 	
 	
 		no that's a fact and
 	
 	
 		i mean you just don't find them and it it's such such a great way take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you already have and train them
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and train them we sometimes we have to uh simply for for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that we we are changing jobs constantly where we are changing our methods of doing things and we are finding more economical methods and more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and the other thing is we cannot find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> outside to just walk in off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and help us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 		but that would be the same in your type of secretarial job i'm that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> used to have just the typewriter and they
 	
 	
 		uh-huh exactly
 	
 	
 		and then they had word processors and now they've got full blown desk top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> so you know
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		oh exactly i mean it's incredible
 	
 	
 		it is i i'm that amazes me that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say your job amazes me well my job is really nothing i sit there and i watch some little gal make me all kinds of charts and view foils and graphs and
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's i it's you know they use laser printers and all that and it's absolutely mind boggling uh because i could probably turn it on before i get the screen to go completely blank you know and i generally do that
 	
 	
 		wow
 		yeah
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i i was in the same situation i had to learn
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i i had no knowledge of a computer at all i'm a master
 		mechanic but not a computer expert
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but now i'm in to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> and word processing and i can hold my own with that
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 		that is fabulous
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		you know another benefit that that i wish i had more of and who wouldn't is vacation time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know um
 		i think that uh when when you're working and an especially i don't know i mean every job you you say how you're constantly putting out fires
 		you know i i feel like my job is like that too unfortunately but that just it drains you you know after a while it just
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i feel that way and it's a long time to get you know you work for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> vacation per year
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah exactly right
 	
 	
 		and then if you have extra days out for
 		what other reasons uh there may be uh an and we we try to deal on an individual basis with them but you can be penalized for that an and it it's penalized against your merit increases and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		so i mean you are allowed a certain number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of what we call sick time and personal time off but if you you know if you extend beyond those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an and at times we will adjust on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> basis
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		for some unusual circumstances but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost fifteen years</TIMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> vacation it seems to me like an awful long time
 	
 	
 		it's hard
 		is that uh what your company policy is too
 	
 	
 		well no it well in some instances yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay in some instances it would be we start with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weeks</TIMEX> vacation and then it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> stays and then it goes to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long long time</TIMEX> and then after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		but that's still that's a long time you know
 	
 	
 		but that is a long time and especially when you take a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks vacation</TIMEX>
 		i was just talking to somebody about this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's funny it takes you until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to really wind down
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		you know to say okay i i can relax i can sit here for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> if i want to and just not do anything and realize that you don't have to be worrying about something you know
 	
 	
 		i think uh i would like to see
 		i would like to see more
 		well
 		it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were talking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> about going to school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> but they have breaks every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> or whatever it is they have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> off or a week off or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they find that that's much
 		better for them than having the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> off an where they're completely bored like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second month</TIMEX> into i think i think industry really would really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		benefit from that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure how we would accommodate all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being on vacation at all various times but we would always be shorthanded i guess but so that's a problem you know that's a problem pardon me
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's where temporaries come in
 		they could hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temporaries</ENAMEX> to fill in
 	
 	
 		well yes that's and that's exactly what we do in many instances you know where our work load increases an and our vacation periods and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course we have uh what we called an SDS a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summer Development Student Program</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we we put a lot of school um
 	
 	
 		like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> type thing for the summer
 	
 	
 		college
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> almost
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they work for us and and they they go to school back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fall</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and hopefully when they get out of college they consider us to come on full-time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they've uh established themselves with a work pattern an and the you know they're familiar to our
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		our ways and stuff and they're on our records and
 		we find that that's very very helpful
 	
 	
 		yeah i that is and uh it also gives you a chance you know to look at these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and make your own determinations
 	
 	
 		you sound uh like a very young person
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i
 		
 		
 	