
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'll let you go first
 	
 	
 		oh well what's there to say doesn't seem like it's being carried out very well in my opinion
 		seems like it takes so long between
 		conviction and carrying out the penalty that i don't see that it makes any difference to sentence anybody
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like they could die of old age waiting to get the death penalty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i know what you mean um i in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> they they do have capital punishment
 		and uh i've seen uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get convicted sentenced and then just nothing happens just endless endless endless appeals
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh well from what i understand i saw a statistic just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX> um
 		so far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year year</TIMEX> or was it during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> somewhere during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a years time</TIMEX> i think it was they executed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> meanwhile there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty five hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on death row
 		so i i and it's building up you know they're they're convicting them faster than they're executing them so it's really building up
 	
 	
 		yeah what's amazing is some of them have been on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> and uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> i know we have a real problem with overcrowding in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah everybody's got that
 	
 	
 		uh just
 		yeah but i mean in here it's uh to the point where they were letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh commuting the sentences of those that were in in jail for lesser crimes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in order to put more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> and it was just uh amazing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to me and of course they made a big deal out of the the few that got out and turned around and committed a crime within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> of getting out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and being rearrested and
 	
 	
 		isn't isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> where the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy Horton</ENAMEX> case was
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i can't remember refresh my memory
 	
 	
 		it was uh that was the one that was used so much in the campaign
 		in the political in the presidential race
 		uh may it may not have been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> it may have been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> i don't remember
 	
 	
 		um i don't remember myself
 	
 	
 		anyway well the question is you know do you think it it does make a difference in whether or not a criminal commits a crime or do you think it can if it's done right
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think if they if they started executing them on a regular basis
 		uh that i think it might make a difference right now i don't see it making a difference i don't see someone not going out there
 	
 	
 		if it
 	
 	
 		and committing murder because they're afraid they're going to get sentenced to death i mean most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there committing murders like don't care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they just don't care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think in large measure the reason they don't care it's not because the punishment but so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that commit crimes don't get punished
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> don't catch them or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> don't convict them or or they don't serve very much of the time and so uh
 		you know their their success rate is very high crime does pay cash you can make a good living at it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and there's uh there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> that uh have and we just had uh a real big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> bust and
 		of course you know they're they're playing it up real big that it was looked like it was a very very small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> and they just happened to get lucky and catch the guy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i mean uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> has uh an all time record for the number of deaths
 		so far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i think they've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred</NUMEX> dead already this year
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baltimore</ENAMEX> caught them
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of it's kind of moved up and you have to remember that it it it
 		uh there's i think <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that are going to commit murders
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh once you kill off a few of them  i mean if you murder a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> because he murdered your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> or something like that i mean pretty soon you run out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to murder
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah the only consolation is so many of the murders are you know the the violent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going against each other and so they you know society's not going to put them to death well at least maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> they cross next time is going to
 		uh i think
 		i think capital punishment is an appropriate punishment for the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> where we say you know this sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is just not acceptable to our society and we are there by going to remove them from society not temporarily but permanently
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i i personally think life imprisonment
 		i don't think much of life of life imprisonment <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all it's never turns out to be life but second you know why should we
 		the idea of life imprisonment with no chance of parole well that means you're going to put them in a cage you think it's never ever going to be safe for them to walk the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> again well then
 		why bother just execute them because that's that way you're sure they'll never ever going to walk the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so any any anybody that says life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> with no chance of parole i'd say uh give them the death penalty
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah you know it makes sense
 		um you know you have the occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who may have been falsely accused but i mean
 		uh so few and far between uh you know makes good TV movies and that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah and and also um
 		the
 		the thing i don't like about a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> trials and a lot of these appeals is that it's not based on what is true and what is false but rather it's on  the rules of evidence what can i hide and what do i have to tell
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> should be geared much more strongly  towards finding out the truth than they currently are
 		and and that way we can be sure you know we can find out the truth we can find out what really happened
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and base
 		the verdict sentence on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> did not on what we're allowed to let the jury hear
 	
 	
 		yeah i had my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> participated in a uh a jury trial he was he was actually on the jury
 		and uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was accused of killing uh i think it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh and shooting a uh policeman
 		um point blank in the face of course he didn't die and uh this was during a holdup of a uh uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and it came out during the trial that um they had tried to rob another place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> came out with the bag they thought was money it turned out to be a couple cookies
 		and uh you know jumbo <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> and and so they were so upset from robbing this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know trying to do this holdup that didn't work
 		that they quite literally were mad and went into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> to hold the place up and just started you know shooting people
 	
 	
 		just started shooting people
 	
 	
 		you know it's
 	
 	
 		because they botched the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> job and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so now they're going to get even
 	
 	
 		yeah and get even with who i mean you know stupid guys
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it turned out that the you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> survived to the point that he was able to you know identify the guy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course you know they tried to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> look out like he was uh a uh no good rotten drunk
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it was amazing
 	
 	
 		so what was the verdict what was the results there
 	
 	
 		oh he was found guilty yeah he uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		last i heard he uh
 		he beat a push for the death penalty now whether they finally got it or not i don't know i kind of uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stopped listening after a while
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know he would come home and and you know after the trial was over he came home and told us what was going on and of course then they had to go back to decide you know after
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the the penalty phase yeah they've decide the penalty separately from the verdict
 	
 	
 		he had to go
 		right
 		and uh yeah everybody everybody was pretty much you know let's burn him
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's you know that's the way they wanted to do it and he was surprised because he thought there was going to be a problem because he uh you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the case were
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		were a little hesitant on convicting him on some of the charges but i mean when it all came down they just
 		within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>
 		decided the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s fate
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know you just have to decide you know what you well there's really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate decisions there i guess one is did it really happen the way the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> said it happened
 		you know is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> really guilty and you have to decide that but then you have to decide you know as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of society what do i want to do with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who did this thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that will i i've never been on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i've never had that experience i'm not sure i'd look forward to making that kind of decision about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s life
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well it it it went pretty pretty quick from what he said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i mean there's there's there's a lot of other crimes out there i mean besides murder i think uh now if you're dealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> now caught <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than twice</NUMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it there's uh a death penalty associated with it
 	
 	
 		well the thing i'd be most likely to attach the death penalty to is the violence i mean yeah i can handle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you know it's it's wrong but
 		it it's not worth somebody getting executed for but we hear so much about the violence and how it's not safe to walk the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> because somebody you know these random drive by shootings and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'd most likely want to sentence to death are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that just show <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> low regard for human life
 		that you know you never know when they're going to turn or hurt the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> because it doesn't really matter to them whether someone else gets hurt or not
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		and so i go let's these are the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i would like to yeah get out of here and get out of circulation and say i don't we don't accept your kind in our society
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree i i've i have uh a low tolerance for that kind of uh that kind of person
 		and uh as far as uh you know there are some some other crimes that i think uh you know
 		kidnapping um you know when they
 		i mean kidnapping per se has a certain uh
 		fine and penalty associated with it but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just out and out brutal i some of the cases i've heard about over the years
 		
 		
 	