
 
     		
 	
 		so have you got a pet
 	
 	
 		no i don't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would love a pet  i had a pet when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cocker</ENAMEX> Spaniel
 		and i think one thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> is they're a lot of company you can you can tell them anything and they won't tell anybody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right that's like unconditional affection
 	
 	
 		right as a matter of fact i was thinking that same thing unconditional love they just give it and don't expect too much anyway do you have a pet
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> i've had several <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats my cat</ENAMEX> uh
 		was hit by a car <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> but uh i'm gonna get another one as soon as i
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		get back in town i'm going out of town <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> when i get back i'm gonna find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i'm so sorry but that's good that you're gonna get another one  i know some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets uh</ENAMEX> and they just are really
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know the ones who have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are very uh protective of them and i think that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason they have them especially older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know that have pets but they just um
 		really take care of them are and are protective of them
 	
 	
 		yeah i work and go to school and it's kind of nice you know you come home your your pet's there for you and wants to wants a little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> a little attention
 	
 	
 		yeah and and like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> um they really want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> badly
 	
 	
 		and that's it's kind of fun
 	
 	
 		and they've been looking and looking and want you know they'd take anything i think  but um i don't know do you like i guess your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">indoor cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no it was an indoor kind of indoor outdoor it
 	
 	
 		a kind of traveled around traveled
 	
 	
 		it was well yeah i don't i don't care for the smell of a litter box so my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> was trained to go outside other than that it was inside when it wanted to be it was outside when you know it
 	
 	
 		yeah when i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cocker Spaniel</ENAMEX> it it was an outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and uh i think i liked that better uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i think you know i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> but i think that uh i'm i'm kind of like big <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs big dogs</ENAMEX> and you have to have room for them
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> take a lot of
 		a lot more care than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats do cats</ENAMEX> are pretty independent you know you feed them and they keep themselves clean and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		if you if you raise them right you know you don't have to worry about the litter box thing where with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> you really do have to
 		let them out and take them for walks and
 	
 	
 		take them for walks right
 	
 	
 		things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i see all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> going for a walk with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and
 		and i i'm kind of skeptical with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> i'm like i know it'll be fun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> maybe and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> gets to take care of it or something so i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i got to take care a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine's <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> he's just got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> and he was out of town  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> and of course the dog is not trained for anything yet so it's go over there and clean up after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's exciting
 	
 	
 		that's that's a major chore you know if you don't
 		if you don't keep up with it and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> kind of they want the they want the fun part and not the not the work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think it's really important to that that if you get a pet that they're either spayed or neutered so that you know we're not just
 		going on with this pet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and having to just get rid of them that that kind of gripes on me some but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are aware
 	
 	
 		well if you're if you're gonna have a pet and not have it neutered or spayed you need to be willing to you know deal with the consequences take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right right
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		and i think you know when i was growing up we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats cats</ENAMEX>
 		and you know just seeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> you know the the the miracle of birth you know put that in quotes is that's a that's a neat thing to to experience as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and understand and and it was a real positive thing but on the other hand you don't wanna
 	
 	
 		i think that's really true
 	
 	
 		you'd be one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that dumps the kittens off on the side of the road you know they're they're they're getting old now and it's time to get rid of them so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah exactly exactly i think our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is a lot more conscious now though too and  and that's good too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i think that's all i have to say okay have a good night all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay well it's good talking to you yeah bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	