
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Quoth
the Maven
            

            Apropos of free speech and
responsible journalism, what do we say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without
checking to see if the quotation is accurate? Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, in
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conintern</ENAMEX>," nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on right-wing journalism, checked to see if I tried to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intimidate Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> or prevent him from criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist</ENAMEX>,
although they both condemned me for it. Had I said it, I would have condemned
myself, but I didn't say it. I had a conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> before his
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> was published (I offered to help, he asked questions and I answered
them). I said some positive things about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover</ENAMEX> and some critical things, but I
certainly didn't suggest a "line" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> should follow.

            When the nasty remarks from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> surfaced here, I was concerned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> might have
misunderstood something I said and taken it as an attempt to intimidate him, so
I checked it with him, just to make sure my failing memory isn't even worse
than I think it is. He remembers it as I do.

            For the
record, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who did have the professionalism to check was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Ledeen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise InstituteWashington</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>
replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> tells me he most definitely does not remember the
conversation as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ledeen</ENAMEX> does. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> says he has contemporaneous typed
notes of the conversation, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ledeen</ENAMEX> used exactly the words <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>
attributed to him.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revolution Will Not Be Criticized</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is, of course, quite
correct in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">But Is It Art Criticism?</ENAMEX>" description of "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX>
aesthetics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> ." How often have I, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 20</NUMEX> literary reviews for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , cursed as the jackbooted
minions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Podhoretz</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> pounded on my door in the
dead of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, delivering the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politburo</ENAMEX> ukase on the proper
interpretation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> literature.

            But though I may grumble
under my breath, I know my duty to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX>. Once, indeed, on the
occasion of my appointment as a contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> for literary matters, I was
taken, blindfolded, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podhoretz</ENAMEX>'s secret dacha , where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> sits at a plain pine table smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> cigarettes and planning the
glorious overthrow of the reactionaries at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Review of Books</ENAMEX> .

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comrade</ENAMEX>," he said to me,
"our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five Year</TIMEX> Plan for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Aesthetics</ENAMEX> proceeds on schedule. We have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reclaimed</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary heroes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Orwell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel Trilling</ENAMEX>. We have
exposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterrevolutionary machinations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Tan</ENAMEX>. But
still <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Wasserstein</ENAMEX> eludes us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> can never be secure until all
know her crimes."

            "Yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comrade Leader</ENAMEX>," I replied, and every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> has since
devoted every waking hour to this glorious task. Your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28</TIMEX> report on our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> is gratefully received.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Bottum</ENAMEX>
               First
Things <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Standard
Deviation
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX>
is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX> for preferring a conservative view of the world in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">But Is It Art</ENAMEX>
Criticism?" The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comintern</ENAMEX> for trying to have some party
discipline in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conintern</ENAMEX>."

            First, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> first
discussed, such use makes the terms meaningless. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX>
is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX>, then what word is used for describing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it shows a shrill
desperation on the part of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>. One could say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> is narrow-minded, or parochial, or old-fashioned, or many other
things. (I myself find their reviews helpful, if a tad predictable.) To call it
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX>" is simply to smear it, and to smear a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of thought. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> may be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stupid Party</ENAMEX>, but surely every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is entitled
to seek certain goals and to expect its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to pursue those goals.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and
anti-Communist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX>--and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s and '50s</TIMEX>--were indeed
combating real, literal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stalinists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Communists</ENAMEX> were indeed in a
struggle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comintern</ENAMEX>.

            To blur
those distinctions is to distort history far more than a mildly conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, or a lukewarm "conservative" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, is likely to do. It also lowers
the standards of literacy and fairness and open-mindedness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> seems to
aspire to.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tynen Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>

            

               Pro-Magnon
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s excellent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Apologies</ENAMEX>" covered
most of the big ones, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> to the aborigines.

            I am
disappointed that he missed perhaps the granddaddy of them all, one that once
again broke into the front pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last week</TIMEX>. I refer to the apology that
the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> owes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>, whom we apparently wiped the European
floor with around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100,000 years ago</TIMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkie Koehl San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horn</ENAMEX>
            

            I don't
normally do this sort of thing, but I am concerned by your summary, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Other</ENAMEX>
Magazines," of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> piece on attachment disorder. To
characterize it as being about "[o]utwardly normal" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are
"anti-social monsters" is to miss a central question raised by the piece, which
is whether adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are diagnosed with attachment disorder
indiscriminately by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who often don't know what they're doing. It is to
further miss the concern that the language these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX> use (and you
borrow) is dangerously extreme.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miriam</ENAMEX>
Horn
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Land of
the (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sluggishly</ENAMEX>) Rising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NAFTA Math</ENAMEX>" is
right on, except when she remarks that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> "continues to enjoy" much higher
growth than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> growth was considerably below that of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94</TIMEX>, and about the same in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. It's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
grew faster <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> as it emerged from recession, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> it looks as if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will again post faster growth.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
tendency to poor-mouth its economy isn't entirely a plot to divert attention
from its trade surplus--there's actually an element of truth to it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter LandersFar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Economic Review Tokyo</ENAMEX>

            
               We Hold
These Truths
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Patrick Diggins</ENAMEX> is
living in a world of phantoms when he uses the myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> as a hammer to
smash the myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s record on individual liberty and civil
rights in "Nothing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Declare</ENAMEX>," his review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Maier</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripture</ENAMEX> .

            By now we all know that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> was a slaveholder, and that he protected slavery as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> in
order to include the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> in the revolution against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and the formation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. We also know that he viewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> as inherently inferior
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, and advocated their return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. To call these views racist is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> enough in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our day</TIMEX> and age, but it hardly takes into account the liberal
moderation by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> would have been judged on these issues in his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. To actually see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> as one's literal equal was one of the rarest of
virtues in his time. I don't know of many, or perhaps any, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> who advocated
such a view. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX> was as close as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> dared to come on
this issue.

            Diggins forgets, in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discompassionate</ENAMEX> and deluded rewriting of history, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> was no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX>
poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> himself. He publicly declared on many occasions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> would
never be the functional equals of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> in intelligence, ability, creativity,
or social and economic skill, but that they must nevertheless be given their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX> and some basic legal rights. He was never an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of integration of
the races, and felt that they would always be separate and unequal as a matter
of society. He also at times sympathized with the notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>
returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. So how, exactly, does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diggins</ENAMEX> find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> to be such a
sterling moral example, fit to shame <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>
made a huge leap forward in human and civil rights merely by so powerfully
advocating them as a legal basis for political agreements between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. It was a
huge step forward, but neither perfect in conception or in deed, as the
preservation of slavery proves. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s accomplishment was another huge step
forward, but likewise imperfect. He freed the slaves, but had no intention of
making them equal. Yet the direction of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> is clear and unmistakable, and
was brought to an even higher <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> of vision and deed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> and many others in the modern civil rights movement. To condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>
for his failings, you must also condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, but to condemn both is to
throw out the progressive historic tradition by which the present civil rights
movement gains its legitimacy. How will we be judged in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 years</TIMEX>, when
I would hope our ideals and deeds have advanced beyond their present poor
state? I would hope more compassionately and with greater understanding of the
unique fabric of our times, and the humility to appreciate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> steps made
by those in the past, than such liberal mythologists as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diggins</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad</ENAMEX>
Goehausen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Rafael</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
