
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remembrance</ENAMEX> of Things Past
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s criticisms
of tax credits in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Forgetting the Present</ENAMEX>" are too sweeping, and deserve a response.
She is correct to point out the flaws of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">un-</ENAMEX>targeted tax credits intended to
stimulate job hiring. These usually fail. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> find that their
present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> already qualify for the credit. However, targeted credits
aimed specifically at job creation can work.

            Consider an empirical
example: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> instituted an "investment tax credit."
It gave the economy an immediate shot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> modernize
and stimulating jobs in the manufacturing sector, especially in the tool and
die-making industries. When the tax credit was repealed to help pay for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>, the private sector of the economy immediately began to suffer.

            A tax
credit aimed at encouraging job training for former welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> would
achieve similar results. Without a tax credit, business have no incentive to
absorb the cost of hiring these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Solomon</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Glistening With Prozac</ENAMEX>
            

            In an otherwise thoughtful
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teen-age</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midol Junkies</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Kaminer</ENAMEX> says that "we ignore the damage wrought by
laws prohibiting selectively demonized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marijuana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> (while allowing use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>)." Her inclusion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> in the latter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is troublesome.

            While it is certainly true
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> is overprescribed, and likely abused, it is also true that it is a
powerful, necessary therapy for the treatment of severe depression.
Furthermore, to include it in a list with the two single most destructive drugs
in contemporary society is irresponsible.

            For those
of us with lifelong, debilitating, severe, and chronic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> is
literally a lifesaver. The growing popular perception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> as some kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">recreational drug</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaminer</ENAMEX> intentionally or unintentionally reinforces,
is terribly offensive.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Hurrah!
Hurrah! for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yadda Yadda Yadda</ENAMEX>"
            

            I enjoyed
Cullen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>'s brief chronicle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humankind</ENAMEX>'s never-ending search for a way to
communicate the fact that much of what we try to communicate isn't really worth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communicating</ENAMEX>. If we're going to be upfront about the meaninglessness of our
messages, at least let's use the colorful "yadda yadda yadda " to replace
excess <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">verbiage</ENAMEX> instead of the tepid "blah blah blah ." Just think of the
potential for the news media. They could cover <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice as many</NUMEX> stories if they
simply inserted "yadda yadda yadda " into their reports. "Our top story
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>: As the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> nears the home stretch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> yadda yadda yadda . In other news ..."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Dussen</ENAMEX>
            

            
               You're
Killing Me
            

            This is a somewhat delicate
matter. I live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which is supposed to be a democracy. Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> was slain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some months ago</TIMEX> by a smiling ideological idiot.
Therefore, your continual use of "Kill him," as in, "When we told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>
the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> responsible for the mistake, he said, 'Have him killed,'
" takes on a sinister, real meaning.

            I suggest
that you try not to use this joke in the future.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Krauskopf</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
