
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chess Jerk</ENAMEX>
            

            I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Heard</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sore</ENAMEX>
Loser": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Kasparov</ENAMEX> was a total jerk. I closely followed both last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s matches with great enthusiasm, and have always had a lot
of respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry</ENAMEX>. He is a true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> in chess--the best there is. So, I
did not expect him to say all those things that he said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry</ENAMEX>
claims that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> game was the one that led to his downfall, and almost
accused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> of cheating. Leaving aside the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> would not even
consider doing this and risking its credibility and reputation, it is a
preposterous charge because whoever stepped in to help the machine would be a
better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Heard</ENAMEX> is right. Perhaps we need another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the human race. This one has just become another "sports
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jerk</ENAMEX>."

            
               --Philippos
Peleties
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blues</ENAMEX>
            

            I couldn't disagree more with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Heard</ENAMEX>'s article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sore Loser</ENAMEX>." This kind of personification of the computer does
nobody any good. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Kasparov</ENAMEX> does not owe <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX> an apology because <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> is not a human and has no feelings. It is a pile of microchips. There is
nobody to offend.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry</ENAMEX> acted like a human, and
it made me proud to be human, too. I am also proud of his fighting stance at
the press conference. He said exactly what I wanted to say: This stupid machine
will not definitively beat its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>. And then there was a roar of approval
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            Do the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX> deserve an ovation? Not to the same extent. They are
still the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX> in this saga of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> vs. machine. And not one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> could have beaten <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX> in chess--not even close.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K. Hertog</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               I Want
My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
            

            I have one objection to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA Smoke</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rings</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>: The regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> doesn't mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
are living in a childproof world. Sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s efforts are done in the name
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. But the goal is to have fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> become addicted to nicotine at
an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> when information about the health hazards is likely to be ignored. Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> are not moved by the possibility of an early death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four decades</TIMEX>.
But if smoking is addictive, then it makes sense to try to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> out of
the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who are too young to take the warnings seriously.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s
regulations do not make it harder for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to buy cigarettes. The advertising
regulations may make it harder for a new product to enter the market, or to
boost brand-switching. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> can still buy cigarettes. (I am sure,
however, that there are many in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> who would be prepared
to ban smoking because of the possibility of lung damage from secondhand
smoke--now that would be trying to create a childproof world.)

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Mikula</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bethesda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               He's No
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> of Rights
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA Smoke</ENAMEX>
Rings" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Turns <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yellow</ENAMEX>" complement each other on the same subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Brother Is</ENAMEX>
Watching. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "abysmal record on liberty," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>
calls it, is, indeed, a fatal twist of irony, incredible and troubling.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is willing to toss
away our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX>, and possibly Second amendments with a simple flick of
the pen. He seems motivated by a deep-seated longing to heal and protect, but
this is not a sufficient warrant for violating the privacy of an individual's
rights and trampling on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>.

            I'm weary
of the perennial bad excuse for cameras, censorship, and regulations: It's for
your own protection and safety. I understand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s utopian aspirations, but
no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> will ever find true peace and stability. There will always be a
small percentage who cannot govern their own lives and who abuse freedom, but
that shouldn't mean that we all have to pay the price by losing our
constitutional rights.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Marcus</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Meltdown
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Traub</ENAMEX>'s review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Glazer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Are All Multiculturalists Now</ENAMEX> , titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"I Was Wrong</ENAMEX>,"
really grabbed me. I grew up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, at a time when the concept of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> as a melting pot was widely preached in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and everyday
life. Later, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, we were told that the melting pot did not take dark
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>. But now that there is clear cultural and biological assimilation, I have
been surprised to see that large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> actually try to categorize
themselves by racial or ethnic labels.

            Like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glazer</ENAMEX>, I have questioned affirmative action and dreaded the creation of a
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caste</ENAMEX>/quota system. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glazer</ENAMEX>, I now believe that events and processes
are stronger than government policies and political mindsets. I find myself on
a similar journey of shifting concepts and renewed belief in the melting pot
but, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glazer</ENAMEX>, my journey is in process, and the questions loom much larger
than my answers.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
McMichael
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               Ratings
to Riches
            

            Hooray for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Domestic Goddess Dethroned</ENAMEX>," an assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX>'s self-made
downfall. While I wouldn't go so far as to praise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early years</TIMEX> of her show,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">succinctly</ENAMEX> tracked the devolution of what started out as a very good
idea. How ironic that a program once watched by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> and wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> alike
ultimately perished because its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> couldn't handle the move from being
poor to being wealthy herself.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Dussen</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
