
   
   
      
         
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plague Cheer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, wait a minute. Despite
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Cohen</ENAMEX> asserts in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">AIDS Isn't Over</ENAMEX>," nothing in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> article stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is over. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> full paragraphs
on the unknowables and imponderables of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. There is an explicit
statement early on that "in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense, obviously, it is not [over]," by which I
mean the fact of many, many more deaths from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> (including, eventually,
probably, my own); and a clear assertion that "nothing I am saying here is
meant to deny that fact, or to mitigate its awfulness." The quote he keeps
using as his smoking gun--"this ordeal as a whole may be over"--is wrested from
a fuller sentence, which reads, "Perhaps this is why so many of us find it hard
to accept that this ordeal as a whole may be over." It follows a section
devoted to the description of someone's gruesome death. Blithe optimism? Give
me a break. The very title of the piece--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When Plagues End</ENAMEX>"--is deliberately
and carefully conditional.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> is
obsessed with the idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>. This is understandable, since he has
devoted a good deal of his journalistic career to the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> will
only be cured by a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>. He may be right (although the obstacles to a
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> are enormous), but he shouldn't let his own agenda blind
him to a simple fact: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> may not be "cured," but it may be successfully
treated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. For those of us with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>, there's not a lot of
difference.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Cohen</ENAMEX>
Replies:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX> steers clear
of my main criticism of his article--that it overstates the hope that now
exists--and instead resorts to unfounded suggestions that I've ignored his
checked tone, taken his writing out of context, and--most absurdly--nit-picked
him because I am obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> and have an agenda.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>'s article, as its
subhead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, is an exploration of the "twilight of an epidemic" that
reflects repeatedly on why it is difficult for HIV-infected gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, in
particular, to consider the possibility that new drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regimens</ENAMEX> will allow them
to survive this plague. The ideas he examines, often with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> and delicacy,
have to do with things like past vs. future, loss of community, and excessive
skepticism. The passage he accuses me of having "wrested" out of context is
just such a musing. And he gives short shrift to another, more pertinent idea:
Perhaps many infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find it hard to accept that this ordeal as a whole
may be over because they have yet to see evidence that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> will extend
their lives beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX>. And the gruesome death he recounts prior to
this musing is not, as far as we can tell, about someone who responded well to
the new treatments only to die too young and too painfully. Rather, he
describes the death to set a marker in time, raising the possibility that such
horrible experiences now may be in the past.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> writes here
about the caveats his article contains, he is taking himself out of context.
The "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense" he is referring to about the epidemic not being over is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> at newly infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and those who can't access or afford the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Although he does describe attending a meeting where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> detail
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unknowns</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--which I state in my article
(listing, further, several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unknowns</ENAMEX> that he doesn't mention)--he does so
almost wearily: "There were caveats, of course," he writes. The dismissive tone
is critical to his entire argument, because if he squarely reflected on the
great uncertainty that now exists about the impact of the new treatments, he
would undermine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of an exploration of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End</ENAMEX>. His analysis would
seem, in a word, premature, and that is essentially my problem with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>'s claims
about my obsession and agenda, give me a break. True, I have written a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>, and I have a particular interest in the
subject. I've also written <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of column inches</NUMEX> about most every other
topic relating to the disease. And I have written, and continue to write, about
many things that have nothing at all to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. You could look it up.

            Finally,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> mixes up "cure" and "prevention." The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> I'm speaking of
are designed to prevent an infection and thereby stem an epidemic. If <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> do
extend the lives of infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for, say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>--and I hope they do and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> is wrong about his own fate--I, too, would use the word "cure."
But unfortunately, we have to sit and wait for studies that are underway to
finish before we can predict the future with something more statistically
powerful than hope.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lock</ENAMEX>
Is a Crock
            

            I just wanted to add
something to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denial</ENAMEX>," his amusing commentary on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' unseemly bout of whining, blaming, and rationalizing following
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s elections.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> other--rather
curious--explanation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> defeat in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> presidential race
was proffered by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s polling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. During an election
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-mortem</ENAMEX> (televised on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>), she suggested that it would have been very
difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> to win the presidency in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electoral College</ENAMEX> since,
according to her, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> went into this election with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some</NUMEX> electoral
votes already locked up, based on the results of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> election. As evidence
of this, she painstakingly detailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s electoral assets state by state,
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>. By the time she was finished, one could
only conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was predestined to win re-election.

            It was quite interesting to
hear this said, out of the blue, about a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. It
was a mere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>, I recall, that conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> were
crowing about the supposed "lock" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> had on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electoral College</ENAMEX>, based on its (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strongholds</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain West</ENAMEX>. This was supposed to guarantee <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential supremacy
forever--or at least until the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>" had slipped into the wells
of history.

            Well, a
mere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> uttered his last valedictory words, it would seem
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> did, in fact, have a chance at the presidency once
again.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Treumann</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Fight
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Night</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
            

            As much as
I get a cheap thrill from exploring the world of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> rivalry in your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> issue was beyond the pale. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanniski</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX>, and (particularly) Krohn &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackworth</ENAMEX> were all heavy on the feuding and light on the facts. I
probably agree with all your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' assessments; it's just that I'd hate to
see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> turn into a giant venting extravaganza.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hellman</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
