
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               One
Thumb Down
            

            You have
your nerve, touting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slate Explorer</ENAMEX> and making me go through the whole process
of registering before revealing that it's not available for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX>. This information belongs up top. Of course, if you're obtuse enough
not to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX>, I guess I shouldn't be surprised. Just remember:
If it weren't for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>, there wouldn't be any Windows for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> to run on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ingrates</ENAMEX>!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Down on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm</ENAMEX>
            

            This is in response to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Chapman</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smokey and the Bandits</ENAMEX>." Finally--a voice in the wilderness.
I have been trying to understand why I should cry for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, and
can't understand why others do. When slavery ended, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX> had either
to figure out how to harvest their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>-cheap labor, or find
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> to grow. Many opted to grow tobacco, and it looks like it's time
to switch again.

            I find it
interesting that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Bliley</ENAMEX>, can, with a
straight face, recommend subsidies for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> when he and others in his
party have vowed to get rid of "welfare as we know it." Tobacco subsidies are
just another form of welfare. I say give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">growers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, then make them
get a job like everybody else!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dina Coles Glen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            

               Shugerless Latte
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> received several
letters in response to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 8</TIMEX> absence of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>,"
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>, had fallen ill:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shuger</ENAMEX> withdrawals <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. My morning latte just isn't right without it.
Get well soon!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
Rose Pacific <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Diary of
an (Under-) Gradman
            

            The notion
of having college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> explore the "realities" of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX> in a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Bisen-Hersh</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Trachtenberg</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>) is very appealing--the problem arises in
the execution. Why did you choose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pompous, straight, white ultranerds for
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>? These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't the stuff of excitement, controversy,
provocation! Their particular narcissism renders them incapable of viewing any
sort of interesting scandal around them.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Schwartz</ENAMEX>
            

            
               High
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frat Content</ENAMEX>
            

            I just wanted to make a
comment on your "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diaries</ENAMEX>" of Ivy League <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bisen-Hersh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trachtenberg</ENAMEX>) that, in your words, "tell us what life at these top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is really like." First, when you pick <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are basically
similar in background and basically similar in every other way, you get two
diaries that--here comes a shocker!--sound similar. Therefore, how is two
better than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>? What kind of sample of real college life is that?

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, speaking from
experience of being at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivy</ENAMEX> and being in a fraternity, there are some things
that are really missing in their diaries. It's a crime to quote that
story about the fallen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, and then bring in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who would have no
clue about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> life! Sure, I find it interesting to read that some people
have fun playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boggle</ENAMEX> and touring the dorms together, but is this a good way
to find an answer to a question that uses "hotbed" and "sexual abandon" in the
same sentence?

            Next
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, fit your point--pick somebody in a fraternity or a sorority, or somebody
that would bring meaning to the anecdote you quoted. Be prepared to take the
good with the bad. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have a higher
average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX> than regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Or maybe that's not what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> wanted
everyone to hear. We wouldn't want everybody to know about our games of binge
drinking, sexual abandon, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boggle</ENAMEX>, too!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Webber</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weddings</ENAMEX> and an Assimilation
            

            There was a funny moment in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Liu</ENAMEX>'s responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX> in their "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on mixed marriage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX> declared himself unconcerned with
the very high rate of intermarriage among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>, and proposed that
the same easygoing attitude should work for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. And on the face of it, why
not? It is only when one considers numbers that the comparison becomes quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hilarious</ENAMEX>. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX>' concern that the (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">-million Jews</ENAMEX> in the
world might disappear through assimilation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX> replies with the generosity and
lack of worries of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> backed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Give me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a tenth</NUMEX> of that in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and I could also see it his way. Instead, in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> the depth
of the mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> runs at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 4</NUMEX> (embattled) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million</NUMEX>.

            Of course,
underlying this discussion is the deeper question of whether there is any value
in the preservation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> religion and culture. Those of us who believe
there is such a value are worried.

            
               --Sanda
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman Cleveland</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
