
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake</ENAMEX> the
Snake
            

            I'm sure
your political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, is smart and sophisticated and
all that. I'm sure he's wise to the ways of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX>. Nobody
will pull the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s eyes. But it's a bore to read someone who's
so confident in his own perspective that everything seems tired and transparent
to him. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch"</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On the Campaign Trail"</ENAMEX>) was a real
exception--he told us what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said, and he told us a little bit about how
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said was experienced by those who heard him. He made the scene
seem interesting, alive, and real. That's not my normal experience with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s columns. Anyway, if it's the start of a trend, it's a good trend,
and I think he ought to continue in this vein. When he's bored, we're bored.
When he makes an effort to look around and see and comment, we're interested
and rewarded.

            
               --Theo Padnos
            

            
               Beat the
Press
            

            In his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>"
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Did Clinton Harass Paula Jones</ENAMEX>?") and his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey, Wait a Minute</ENAMEX>"
column ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor Jr.</ENAMEX> argues that the
"press" has stifled coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' lawsuit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>, however, sheds no
new light on the subject. He tells us nothing substantive about this case that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> had not already
reported. Also, it's important to point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' suit is currently
winding its way through the justice system.

            Because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> reveals no new facts, I have to believe the press has done quite an
adequate job. And, because the case is pending, some patience is probably in
order. What's left to say? What does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> suggest? Should the press try the
case, as he, apparently, has already done? Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>, I'm confident the
press will keep me adequately and fairly informed as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> dispense
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> fairly in this matter. Get a better shtick, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>. Beating up on the
press is old and tiresome. Just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Moore</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Devine
Response
            

            I would like to clarify a
point I made in an "E-Mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>" that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. My e-mail
responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economic Culture Wars</ENAMEX>," a polemic against more "literary-minded"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James K. Galbraith</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> responded to my e-mail in his
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Who's the Real Economist?</ENAMEX>").

            The point I tried to make in
my e-mail was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> confuses mathematical rigor with science. I have no
criticism of the former (and use it myself), except to note that many important
issues cannot be quantified. Instead, I believe we need a version of the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">serenity prayer</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economists</ENAMEX> need the skills to do quantitative research, the
knowledge needed for qualitative research, and the wisdom to know when each is
appropriate and what its limits are.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>, on the other hand,
involves avoiding a dogmatic attachment to any method of analysis. It also
entails being open to reading and respecting ideas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> disagrees with. This
involves, among other things, avoiding criticizing someone's book without
reading it simply because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> has done with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Work of Nations</ENAMEX> .

            A scientific attitude also
involves eschewing the glorification of the self-appointed and self-promoting
academic pecking order of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Name</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. This kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glorification</ENAMEX> might be justified if economics were actually like physics, with
a clear ability to predict the behavior of our subject matter so that we could
objectively decide which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> were better than others. Having attended
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Name</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, I know that we can't take anybody's work for granted.
Some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> don't want to deal with empirical reality at
all.

            My
irritation with the adulation of Big Names does not arise from my lack of fame,
or from my working at a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> (which gives me freedom from "publish
or perish": I can write what and when I like, rather than having to "crank it
out"). On the contrary, it comes from my experience with many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who
have jumped from fad to fad, from rational expectations to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Keynesianism</ENAMEX> (a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">k</ENAMEX> a monetarism), without any kind of historical perspective, just an eye to
what the economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> are saying. It surprises me to see a Big Name
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> following this trend, and, further, using it
to discourage dissent within the profession.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Devineprofessor</ENAMEX>
of economicsLoyola <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marymount University</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>
Come
            

            Just a
small quibble with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review of Breaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waves</ENAMEX> ("Sex and
Longing") . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lars Von Trier</ENAMEX>'s last film to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zentropa</ENAMEX> , when (as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Links</ENAMEX>" section at the bottom of
the article correctly notes) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Von Trier</ENAMEX>'s last film to reach these shores was
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> , a film which, while made for television, was given a
theatrical release in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Go Home</ENAMEX>
            

            I want to report that,
somehow, your quality control slipped, and you let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Ferrigno</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Letter From</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>" ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss My Tan Line</ENAMEX>") slide into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrigno</ENAMEX>'s article
purports to be about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state becoming a northern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, but it reads more like a case of deadline desperation.

            I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yakama Indian</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Having lived here my entire life, I find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrigno</ENAMEX>'s premise
offensive and his point of view so lacking in humor, nuance, balance, and
perception, that, were I a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX>, I would drop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>! And he
makes a living writing?

            I don't
care that most of you on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> are not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and that your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sympathies</ENAMEX> may not be with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrigno</ENAMEX>. The simple truth is that if this article
were meant to be a column or an opinion piece, it should have been marked as
such and not presented as "hard journalism" or a report from the field.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
Tulee
            

         
      
   
