
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               Leftwaffe
            

            Regarding
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conintern</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>: Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> has been
forced out of the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> for his unflattering coverage of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> on the sinister intellectual conformity of the left?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CrittendenWomen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quarterly Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>
responds: I don't think so. There is PC on the left, no doubt, but this
episode is hardly an illustration of it. The idea that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who despised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> would have been made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of a leading conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unimaginable</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> of the right wouldn't have had to be fired. He
never would have been hired in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            
               Tax
Americana
            

            You waste
everyone's time by running pieces by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX> on the economy, taxes, and
the stock market. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Brief History of Taxes</ENAMEX>," the chart she runs with her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diatribe</ENAMEX> against supply-side economics is worthless, as even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> would
advise, because it accounts for neither the efficiency of the market in
discounting changes in tax law throughout the legislative process, nor the
volatility of monetary policy during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 30 years</TIMEX> of a floating dollar.
There are other minor variables at work, including differences that occur
because of taxes on income and taxes on wealth, but I would not trouble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
with those. Her attempt to correlate one variable--the date of passage of a tax
cut or increase--with GDP is not serious stuff. And, by the way, at the time it
passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, we told our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> tax increase would do no great
damage to the economy because the other variables were positive.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jude</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanniski Polyconomics Inc.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morristown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            
               Tax
Return
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Brief History of</ENAMEX>
Taxes" was indeed brief, though perhaps appropriately so, given the very
narrow focus of her argument. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> utterly failed to address is the fact
that regardless of their effects on aggregate consumption and investment, tax
hikes are bad--and tax cuts, good--for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. While it is quite
true, as she notes, that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> adhere to the questionable belief "that
tax cuts are ipso facto good (and tax hikes are ipso facto bad)"
for the economy and the financial markets, those same <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> also tend to
believe that wealth is inherently the property of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> who created
it.

            This is
not a subtle point, and it is certainly not one that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have ever been
shy about expressing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> ran his entire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX> presidential race promising a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-percent income tax cut. The accompanying "It's your money" slogan, while
unconvincing to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, is fundamentally true. It is also
essential to consider it when weighing the merits or ills of a proposed change
in tax rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX>' claims to their wealth and income must of course be
balanced by the need to finance governmental activities, no matter how few and
inconsequential they may be. For that reason, arguments for the complete
elimination of taxes would be absurd, a fact that almost everyone, regardless
of political affiliation, can recognize. Equally lacking in wisdom, however,
are analyses such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s, which only evaluate taxes' macroeconomic
consequences while ignoring completely the effects they have on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
Bissonette <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam King</ENAMEX>
            

            In his article "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chainsaw Capitalist</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> reveals his ignorance like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gown</ENAMEX> reveals one's bum. Consider this quote: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> pitches itself as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s selfless medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>, indifferent to the demands of the
marketplace."

            Regardless of the statement's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">validity</ENAMEX>, it shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> hasn't the faintest idea of what the marketplace
is. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marketplace</ENAMEX> is me, and you, and everyone else who wants medical care.
How can ignoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s medical wishes be considered a good thing?
"Selfless"? It would be the very height of selfishness and arrogance for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> to ignore the marketplace.

            In his next sentence, Plotz
says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX>, by contrast, is the marketplace." No. He can be at most
one 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> in the marketplace. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> then goes on to denigrate the
notion of efficiency, as if it were self-evidently bad rather than inarguably
good. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> also misuses the concept of the invisible hand, using it to mean
something quite apart from what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX> intended.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> tries to vilify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX>,
but anyone who understands economics sees that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> is actually a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>,
increasing the efficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and creating wealth. About the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> fired from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott Paper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> does the usual hand-wringing because he
has not learned to view the big picture: A society that can meet its tissue
needs with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX> fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is more efficient; it is a society that has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can now do something more productive. There are only so many
hands in the world to work, and--viewing things in strictly economic
terms--those fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are a freed resource, freed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>. (True, their
lives are temporarily screwed, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> do not exist to hand out
paychecks; they exist because they do something useful in an efficient manner.
Were it otherwise, we'd be knee-deep in unwanted buggy whips.)

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
printed an article dealing with principles and terms from chemistry, you would
pass it by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX>, wouldn't you? Why then do you let someone who has not the
barest acquaintance with economics spout nonsense?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Muse</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Doubting
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hamas</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> and foremost, I would
like to commend you on your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. You will go down in history as one of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and best attempts to use the Internet to spread intellectual debate
and well-written articles on politics and culture. The most impressive facet of
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> has been your ability to rise above other media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> and
provide voices for all political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and evenhanded coverage of all news
events.

            Sadly,
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" decides to editorialize by referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> as "scumbags." Aside from becoming part of the event instead of just
reporting on it, this reflected a poor style and vocabulary choice. Please
don't lower yourselves to tabloid language. You have been an important and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upstanding</ENAMEX> publication, and I would hate to lose you now.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holt</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
