
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Paste Test</ENAMEX>

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> considerations
to keep in mind when buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX>: clinical effectiveness and aesthetic
appeal. On the former, I talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. On
the latter, I and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> (my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, mostly) sampled more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> different toothpastes. First, the clinical categories.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fluoride: Clinical</ENAMEX>
effectiveness basically means "Does it have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX>?" If it does, it's
effective--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride strengthens tooth enamel</ENAMEX>. Some toothpastes boast than
others, but the difference is negligible. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> agree that if it's got
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX> and it's approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dental Association</ENAMEX>, you can't go
wrong with it. How regularly and how attentively you brush matters far more
than what you brush with. But while it's true that any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride toothpaste</ENAMEX> will
do a fine job, certain clinical distinctions may help you choose your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> claims are bogus, but others are for real.

            
               Tartar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>: For real! Tartar control toothpastes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crest Tartar Control</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Tartar Control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">With Micro-Cleaning Crystals</ENAMEX>) feature an ingredient
called tetrasodium pyrophosphate. This sponges up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">minerals</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX> that
would otherwise collect on your teeth and form tartar (hardened plaque). Tartar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">toothpastes</ENAMEX> can't remove tartar, but they can stave it off.

            

               Toothpastes for sensitive teeth: For
real--sort of. Toothpastes for sensitive teeth (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensodyne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crest Sensitivity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection</ENAMEX>) use potassium nitrate to block nerves connected to your teeth. This
works for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with receded gums. But if your sensitivity stems instead from
cavities, habitual tooth grinding, or a root canal problem (as it does for most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>), sorry--these products won't do a thing for you.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Baking</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">soda: Bogus</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Baking soda</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquafresh Baking Soda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Baking Soda</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peroxide</ENAMEX>) is a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste ingredient</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Baking soda</ENAMEX> does nothing
whatsoever for your teeth. However, its effervescence may leave your mouth
feeling fresh and clean. If this encourages you to brush more often, mazel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tov</ENAMEX> .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whitening: Entirely bogus</ENAMEX>! Whitening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toothpastes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mentadent Advanced Whitening</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Platinum Whitening</ENAMEX>,
Rembrandt, countless others) remove surface stains--but all toothpastes will do
this, even the nonwhitening kinds. No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> can whiten your teeth
permanently. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dentists</ENAMEX> can apply peroxide solutions to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bleach</ENAMEX> your teeth (just
as peroxide would bleach your hair), but the peroxide would have to stay on
your teeth for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several continuous hours</TIMEX> before it made any difference. Brushing
with whitening toothpastes does nothing, no matter how many times you have at
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topol</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smoker</ENAMEX>'s" toothpaste claims to remove stains caused by smoking.
Again, it is no more effective than any regular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> would be--it just
costs more. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>'s whitening pastes can cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $8</NUMEX> per tube--a horrible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rip-off</ENAMEX>.

            
               Triclosan: For real!
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triclosan</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-microbial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> currently available in a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate</ENAMEX> Total. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> I spoke with called Total "the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolutionary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>." Why? Triclosan clings to your teeth
even after you finish brushing and continues to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> says
you may feel a "residual slipperiness" after you brush with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total</ENAMEX>). Because it
alone contains triclosan, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Total</ENAMEX> is without question the most clinically
effective toothpaste on the market, for now. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">toothpastes</ENAMEX> will no doubt
add triclosan soon.

            Of
course, as noted above, any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride toothpaste</ENAMEX> will do an adequate job. For
this reason, you may wish to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVS</ENAMEX> brand tartar control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> (or a
similar generic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brand</ENAMEX>), which is fluoridated, has tartar control, and is every
bit as effective as every other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Total</ENAMEX>, yet costs
significantly less than its flashier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. Or you may wish to ignore all
the above advice and choose among the flashier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> for aesthetic
reasons, which are laid out below.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Consistency</ENAMEX>: This is determined foremost
by whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> is a "gel" or a "paste." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gels</ENAMEX> use silica as an
abrasive to help polish teeth. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pastes</ENAMEX> use calcium carbonate to the same end.
Simply a matter of preference for the brusher. For some reason nearly every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Barney, Oral-B Rugrats</ENAMEX>) is a viscous gel--especially
perplexing since thick gels are ineradicable when smeared across a sink top.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Consistency</ENAMEX> has a direct impact on ...

            
               Ease of
squeeze: Some brands offer smooth, even flow from the tube; others do not.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crest</ENAMEX> is the standard here, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate</ENAMEX> products tend toward runniness. The
outlier: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rembrandt Age Defying Adult Formula Toothpaste</ENAMEX> (don't ask about the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Age Defying</ENAMEX>" part). This product was so thick that it refused to come out of
its tube, even when squeezed with both hands at once. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> quickly
dubbed it "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>." Only stomping on the tube with a shod foot
produced any results, and those meager. One shudders to imagine an actual aged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> attempting to use this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX>.

            

               Packaging: The main choice here is screw
top or flip top. Flip tops make more sense, as you can open the tube and
squeeze it with one hand and you'll never drop a tiny toothpaste cap behind
your toilet. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> packaging design thinks out-of-the-tube entirely:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mentadent</ENAMEX>'s stand-up pump (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mentadent Advanced Whitening, Mentadent Crystal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mentadent</ENAMEX> pump is just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monolith</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> , if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monolith</ENAMEX> were white instead of black and emitted a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride toothpaste</ENAMEX> instead
of consciousness-altering rays. When you press down on top of the pump, two
separate substances emerge from two separate and concealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>. One tank
holds paste, the other gel, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">strands</ENAMEX> join on your brush in beautiful
harmony. The pump also offers superb ease of squeeze. To be clear: Mentadent
toothpastes are no better clinically than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brand</ENAMEX>--they're just cooler
looking.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX>: Most brands opt for classic titanium white or translucent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blue-green</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquafresh Baking Soda</ENAMEX> stands out with a barber pole stripe of jade
and crimson. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Baking Soda & Peroxide</ENAMEX> is a sickly, opaque green.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Barney</ENAMEX> (for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>) is neon pink.

            

               Taste: After sampling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 35</NUMEX>
different toothpastes, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and I came to some conclusions about
taste. A traditional minty zing is good. But it must have a real bite so your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mouth</ENAMEX> feels clean. Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rembrandt Natural and Rembrandt With Baking Soda:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">baking soda paste</ENAMEX> is not overpowering, but it bites just enough to let you
know it's there. The natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paste</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, lacks all bite, and your mouth
feels dirtier after you've brushed. The foaming action of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">baking soda</ENAMEX> in this
case makes all the difference. A severely biteless paste such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Platinum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Whitening Mild Mint</ENAMEX> can be retch-triggering. Some further
observations:

            Generally, "natural" pastes
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>'s of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maine Natural Toothpaste</ENAMEX>) taste awful, first because they lack bite
but also because they use "natural" flavoring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX> such as papaya
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt Natural</ENAMEX>). You may think you want to brush your teeth with papaya,
but you don't. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt Age Defying</ENAMEX>, when finally coaxed from its tube, tasted
like rancid cinnamon and smelled of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Gay</ENAMEX>--a miserable paste by any measure.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aquafresh Whitening Striped Gel</ENAMEX> is zesty and clean-feeling with good ease of
squeeze and little aftertaste--a solid entry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cool Mint</ENAMEX> Listerine Tartar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Gel</ENAMEX> is a minty and pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">concoction</ENAMEX>, unlike the mouthwash. Crest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gum-Care</ENAMEX> tastes repulsively buttery at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, then slightly bilious--its
lingering aftertaste makes your teeth feel chapped. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' toothpastes
all taste like bubble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>. Again, you may think you want to brush your teeth
with bubble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>, but unless you're under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, you don't.

            Our clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Total</ENAMEX>, got mixed reviews on taste. It could have used more bite, and it
tasted a bit medicinal. The clear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> on aesthetics in general: Mentadent
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Crystal Ice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> likened it to "brushing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altoids</ENAMEX>" and claimed it
cleared out nasal passages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">baking soda</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal Ice</ENAMEX> made my mouth foam
like a rabid <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>'s, leaving my teeth feeling reborn. Couple this with the
pump technology and the combination of gel and paste, and we have a hands down
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>.

            
               If you
missed the sidebar on differing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride concentrations</ENAMEX>, click .
            

         
      
   
