
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Authoritarian Dictationship</ENAMEX>
            

            Now that
you have published the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>" jottings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benazir Bhutto</ENAMEX>, regarded by many
Pakistanis as the most corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> that unfortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> has ever
seen, I wonder whose diary you will publish next. How about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu Sese Seko</ENAMEX>,
or perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Doc Duvalier</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim</ENAMEX>
Fernandes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Stroman
Polanski
            

            Thanks so
much to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> for pointing out the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and legacies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old Carolinians</ENAMEX>." As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> so ably demonstrates, that
great line from the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chinatown</ENAMEX> is absolutely on the mark:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Politicians</ENAMEX>, whores, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>--if they get old enough, they get
respectable." Of course, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> fit into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of those
categories ...

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               Battle
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sexes</ENAMEX>
            

            In
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gorilla</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warfare</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX> has misconstrued what <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> can teach us. It's
certainly a striking fact that male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> are twice the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>; but
looking from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, what should strike us is not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are
somewhat bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, but that they are nowhere near twice as big. What
evolution is trying to tell us here is that male aggression is much less
important for human beings than it is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s argument against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX> depends also on the assertion that what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in fact fight
about is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. That's debatable. At least as good an explanation is that men
fight about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebensraum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> is no doubt familiar with the wars of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzees</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gombe</ENAMEX>, which are much better interpreted as fights over
territory than fights over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>. As for things getting "more primitive, not
less" when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> go to war, this is also a fairly careless argument. Actual
combat could just as well make things better, not worse, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. It might be
easier to build solidarity when your life depends on it, rather than back home
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> might find it easier to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can fight if they
could see them doing it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rosenfelder Oak Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>
replies: Anyone who doubts that male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzees</ENAMEX> spend lots of time
fighting over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> should read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frans de Waal</ENAMEX>'s book Chimpanzee
Politics . Though the chimp <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Waal</ENAMEX> studied was not in a purely
natural setting, as were the chimps at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gombe</ENAMEX> studied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Goodall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Waal</ENAMEX>,
for that very reason, got a clearer look at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life within a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodall</ENAMEX> did. His exacting minute-by<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX> account of hostile encounters and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexual</ENAMEX> encounters leaves no doubt about what was ultimately at stake when males
fought (often coalitionally). And, actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodall</ENAMEX>'s own data, as synthesized
in her magnum <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">opus The Chimpanzees of Gombe</ENAMEX> , also support the idea that
males fight over access to fertile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>. This isn't to say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">territoriality</ENAMEX> couldn't also in theory be a cause of aggressive tendencies in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and/or chimps. But it is to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>--an inherently scarce
sexual resource, in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> terms--are in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> a big part of the
impetus for the evolution of aggressive tendencies in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>.

            
               Where
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys Are</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garance Franke-Ruta</ENAMEX>'s
response to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>'s "Watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Couples Go By</ENAMEX>" is amusing, but ridiculous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s
piece was simply light musings. How anyone could work up an angry, sweat-laden
combat attack over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s reverie, which I think is quite lovely, is beyond
me. And that part about "erotic confessionals" was too funny to be real! If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franke-Ruta</ENAMEX> actually believes for a sane moment that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafe</ENAMEX> reflections
are "erotic confessionals," if this is the frustration she experiences from
"Watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Couples Go By</ENAMEX>," then she had better not read anything at
all. And finally, the idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> could have spared her the injury of
having to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s piece had they listed it under the title of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>"
takes the prize for "most ludicrous statement thus far expressed in the history
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>." I suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franke-Ruta</ENAMEX> was compelled to read every
single line without really wanting to at all? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, blame it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>! Too
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male editors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grey San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>

            
               It's
Going to Be All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
            

            Being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afro</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reading Eric Liu</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Unbearable Being of Whiteness</ENAMEX>" was like finding a kindred
soul. It has been my feeling for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> that all the talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX> is in
fact just one word: assimilation.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James R. Hurd</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
