
   
   
      
         
            ddress your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Devil
Fish
            

            In response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Akst</ENAMEX>'s
piece "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passive</ENAMEX>
Aggressive"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Here at Morningstar</ENAMEX> we spend most of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> thinking about investment
strategies, and rarely does the word "evil" come to mind. Of course, there is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> in the mutual-fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. Fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' greed-inspired pursuit of
assets occasionally leads them to lie, cheat, and virtually steal from their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>, through deceptive advertising or outrageous fees and expenses.
But index funds rarely commit such sins--they are surely the choirboys of the
industry.

            Thus, I was surprised to see
index funds tarred as "evil" in your article. You allege that greedy index-fund
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> take advantage of noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> doing their own research and thereby
threaten to erode the quality of information and research that is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> of our efficient stock markets. In fact, this view is almost
completely opposite to the truth. The rise of index funds should be seen as
triumphant proof that our financial markets are robustly efficient. And it will
be impossible for index funds to destroy the efficiency of markets as long as
those markets remain free and ruled by greed.

            You beguile us with the
image of a pastoral commons in which index <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are selfish free riders
grazing on the fruits of hard-working financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. Having talked to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of mutual fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, I'd suggest that this is not the appropriate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> of the workings of the stock market. Instead, imagine a huge ocean of
information populated by vicious, hungry sharks. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> patrol the waters
looking for juicy tidbits to grow fat on. After they have had their fill of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prey</ENAMEX>, its carcass falls to the bottom of the sea. There bottom feeders wait
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">patiently</ENAMEX> to scavenge the remaining scraps. They don't get fat, but they have a
nice, easy life waiting for their dinner to fall to them. In this metaphor, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> are the active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> are the bottom feeders. The
final crucial detail that ensures that this world and our financial markets
will always function smoothly is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> can become bottom feeders, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> versa.

            If this were a true
biological world, competition between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> and the drive for survival
would ensure that there is equilibrium between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> and the bottom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feeders</ENAMEX>. If the lazy bottom feeders become too numerous, there won't be enough
carcasses floating down to the bottom. In this case, the ill-fed bottom feeders
will decide to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>, and will hunt their own kills. In the alternate
case, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> swarm the waters, there will be little reward to their
hunting, and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> will retire to the easy life of bottom
feeding.

            There is
a similar equilibrium in the financial world. Only, in the stock market, the
equilibrating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> is unfettered greed. Today, aided by an explosion in
information technology, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of active, aggressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> pouncing on every nugget of information, thereby making the markets
highly efficient. In this world, it makes eminent sense for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to
give up the hunt and be satisfied with the quiet life of indexing. It is true
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> are free-riding on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>. But don't cry for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>--they are just as selfish as the bottom feeders. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> are free to
hang up their fins any time and pursue the lazy life. And they surely will,
whenever it pays to do so. As the profits from active investing diminish, there
will automatically be fewer active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>. And whenever
the profits from an active strategy become evident, a feeding frenzy of sharks
will appear. It is this freedom that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have--to follow any strategy,
from fundamental analysis to astrology--combined with the powerful drive of
human greed, that guarantees that our financial markets will always be highly
efficient, and that indexing or any other investing strategy will never pose a
threat to market efficiency. As long as at least a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> patrol the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">waters</ENAMEX>, we will all be safe.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Porter</ENAMEX> mutual
fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, Morningstar

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Akst Me</ENAMEX>
No Questions
            

            Although his criticisms in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passive</ENAMEX>
Aggressive" are right on the mark, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Akst</ENAMEX> need have no fear of the
free-riding index <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who strive for mediocrity by investing passively.
If <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of new mutual fund money is now going into indexed funds, as
opposed to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, we can have some confidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> are
planting the seeds of their own destruction. As more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drop out of the
competition to outperform, the marginal research and trading value of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">decreasing</ENAMEX> number of active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> will become significant, and they will
begin to beat the market.

            Take the argument for passive
investing to its extreme: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suppose</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> all funds were invested
solely in index funds. By definition, that would be the last trade in the stock
market. That is, no one would be able to react to new information. Clearly,
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> would break from the pack as new information became public and
others were not reacting. Thus, the number of passive vs. active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> will
always fluctuate around an equilibrium.

            By the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, the "tragedy of the commons" is not a theoretical construct from a 1960s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">environmentalist</ENAMEX>. It was coined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 200 years ago</TIMEX> (I think perhaps by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricardo</ENAMEX>), to describe the pre-industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX>-tenure system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, wherein
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> would destructively graze their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX> on commonly held land.
Furthermore, the traditional response to the observation is not in favor of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX>, social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worrywarts</ENAMEX> who fret over issues such as
population growth," but rather supports the capitalist argument that land tends
to be used more efficiently under private ownership, in that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is
interested in supporting the long-term value of the property.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Robertson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wicked Niche</ENAMEX> of the East
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17</TIMEX>
column, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The East Is</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>," uses superficial research and ad hominem attacks to criticize
a recent article of mine on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade with emerging economies like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
Rather than join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> in the gutter, I will deal with his few substantive
points.

            First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> belittles
concerns about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s huge and growing merchandise trade deficits with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government figures I cited have kept <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of China</ENAMEX> separate. Combine them, he claims, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s big
global merchandise trade surplus shrinks to insignificance.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> does not
explain is how, if the macroeconomic forces he emphasizes truly explain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> flows, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> can be growing at roughly double-digit rates and running a
global surplus. In fact, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point he insists that it is an "arithmetical
necessity" for big capital <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to run trade deficits.
Evidently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politburo</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> needs some math lessons.

            Further, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s trade
balance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was my focus, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s global balance. And
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, combining the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> figures reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
deficit only from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39 billion to $35 billion</NUMEX>.

            Moreover, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> export
figures for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> are considered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to be understated by
at least <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX>--the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> textiles and apparel fraudulently
shipped to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Industry estimates place
the figure at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $10 billion</NUMEX>. But of course, what could matters like customs
fraud possibly have to do with trade policy?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> also criticizes my
expectation that emerging economies will continue developing as world-class
exporters but remain small consumer goods markets. After all, he argues,
although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that produce more than they consume must run trade
surpluses, these surpluses will guarantee high consumption because the
resulting national income increase "has to show up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX> ." Moreover,
he observes, most emerging economies are running global trade deficits--i.e.,
consuming even more than they produce--precisely because they import
considerable foreign capital.

            Yet many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> become
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importers</ENAMEX> but not major consumer markets. How? By concentrating their
imports in capital goods, intermediate goods, and industrial inputs--the very
products needed to maintain export-led growth. Such growth may indeed one day
create big consumer markets. But "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>" may be a long time coming.

            For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> in these
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have aims other than enriching domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. Indeed, many deny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> broad freedom to consume precisely because their top
priority is building national economic power--especially productive
capacity--over the long haul. As the examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> show,
for strategic reasons they are willing to interfere with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s vaunted
market-equilibrating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, by mandating high savings and
suppressing domestic consumption in other ways, and pushing exports. And when
they do consume, they often focus on purchases whose economic benefits do not
trickle down or abroad--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. Indeed, most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> and southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
is in the midst of a big, prolonged military buildup.

            Finally, numerous statistics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">belie Krugman</ENAMEX>'s claim that real wages inevitably rise with productivity. That's
certainly not the case in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Nor is it the case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
There, manufacturing productivity rose by an annual average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.6 percent</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1988 and 1993</TIMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>). But just before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> peso
collapse, real <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> wages stood <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 30 percent</NUMEX> below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> levels. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> main
reason: Some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>,
greatly increasing the labor surplus in a land where unemployment and
underemployment were estimated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> at a stunning
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1995</TIMEX>.

            Indeed, labor surpluses and
falling wages plague most low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east Asia</ENAMEX>. And even
there, anecdotal evidence indicates that once labor costs take off, so does
foreign investment--for much-lower-wage, labor-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s numbers
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> wages catching up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> wages ignore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big factor contributing to
that narrowing: a decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> wages. Although he calls this trend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panglossian</ENAMEX>, few other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will.

            I
anxiously await the bucket of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud Krugman</ENAMEX> is undoubtedly preparing to sling in
response.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Tonelson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Business and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Council Educational Foundation</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> replies: I'm sorry that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Tonelson</ENAMEX>'s offended dignity has
prevented him from actually taking on board the substantive arguments that I
made in my article. Let me try, however, to make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> points:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Tonelson seems to think
that the proposition that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which attracts large capital inflows must
also be running a trade deficit is merely my opinion. It isn't: It is a matter
of sheer accounting--it is, exactly as I said, an "arithmetical necessity." And
I believe that whatever asperity I may have shown in the column is justified by
the astonishing fact that he really doesn't understand that.

            The point--which I thought I
made clearly in the column, but then what do I know?--is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s trade
surplus, and actual rough balance on current account, shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
not, in fact, a net <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> of capital. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX> account plus current account
equals <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>; that is a fact, not a theory, whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politburo</ENAMEX> may say.) Any
attempt to make sense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s trade must include an explanation of how
the money brought in by foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> goes out again.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonelson</ENAMEX> accuses me of
"superficial research," then says that in his article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s trade balance
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was my focus, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s global balance." I have now
done a little more research, by rereading his review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Garten</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Ten</ENAMEX> , which was clearly cited as the source of my quotations ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15</TIMEX>, Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>). If there is any mention of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s trade balance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in there, I can't find it--in
fact, the article seems to say quite clearly that emerging economies will not
offer large markets to anyone. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonelson</ENAMEX> has some other article in
mind?

            Doing a bit more research, I
discover that in my own column I included a long sidebar which acknowledged
that, while the precise numbers are in dispute, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> certainly does run a
large bilateral surplus vis-à-vis the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and tried to discuss the
economic meaning of that surplus. But maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonelson</ENAMEX> had stopped reading by
then.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonelson</ENAMEX>'s letter makes a
big point of the likelihood that advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> will export mainly capital
equipment rather than consumer goods to the emerging economies. Why, exactly,
is this a problem? Is selling tractors and forklifts somehow a less sound
business than selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soft drinks</ENAMEX>? (What fools the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> are, selling us all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonelson</ENAMEX> denies
that productivity increases lead to higher wages, insisting that the dramatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tigers</ENAMEX> has been achieved through a fall in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> level. Funny: When I check
out the "real <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> compensation" number in the back of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Economic</ENAMEX>
Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> (Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">354</NUMEX>), a book which I assume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonelson</ENAMEX> has on
his desk, I find that it went up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 8 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1975 and 1995</TIMEX>.
We could go on at length about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> should have received even more,
or what adjustments one might make to that number to move it down (or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up</NUMEX>) a
bit, but by any calculation I can make, the overwhelming picture is one of
convergence between wages in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tigers</ENAMEX> and in the West through a process of
leveling up, not leveling down.

            I should
perhaps say that I have nothing personal against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Tonelson</ENAMEX>. I quoted him
only because I often find it hard to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that the views of the
faction he represents are as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> and naive as they really are. "Surely,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say, "they can't really believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> can attract massive
capital inflows and run big trade surpluses at the same time? They must have
some more sophisticated point in mind." The only answer to such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rationalizations</ENAMEX> is to catch somebody with his hand in the cookie jar. And
whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonelson</ENAMEX> may say, I caught him red-handed.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rape</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surowiecki</ENAMEX>'s article "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Redemption</ENAMEX>," he stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> was
"currently building the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117A Stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> and the thoroughly unnecessary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>." Given that the skies are filling up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurofighter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dassault</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rafale</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J-10</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAS Gripen</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MiG-29</ENAMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sukoi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Su-27</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>, all of which are comparable or superior to any
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>, how can the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> be "thoroughly unnecessary"? Those other planes
are being built by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> which are all pushing hard for foreign sales, so
it is not inconceivable that our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> might confront some of these
high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> in the future. The question is, will they do it with a
decades-old plane designed to fight the battles of the past, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> designed to
fight the battles of the future?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
Shibayama
            

            
               Don't
Shoot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX>
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Traub</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s Loneliest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal</ENAMEX>," he says: "By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Dinkins</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, this
kind of spending had made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ungovernable. The economy was dead, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> was in perpetual crisis, and crime was shooting through the roof.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> did nothing to reverse the trend."

            This is
an incredibly ignorant statement. Crime went down the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX>'
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>, and much of the current drop in crime can be attributed to the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of extra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> fought for in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> balanced
the budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all four years</TIMEX>, something that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> has not been able to
accomplish. The current economic turnaround started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX>' final
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> in office.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David White</ENAMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               A Shot in
the Arm
            

            Funny the
places you find vindication. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX> seems to be saying in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Property Is</ENAMEX>
Theft" that if an anti-theft device benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> other than the
property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, it should be encouraged. Research indicates that liberal
("shall-issue" concealed carry gun permit laws, not left-wing ideology)
firearms laws result in a reduction of crimes against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. Since citizens
legally carrying firearms make those areas safer, firearms restrictions are
counterproductive. Thank you for the encouragement.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niziol Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX> replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Niziol</ENAMEX> is correct in his facts but mistaken in his
reasoning. Recent research does indicate that liberal firearms laws
reduce crime against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. But it does not follow that liberal firearms laws
reduce crime against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who do not carry firearms . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therein</ENAMEX> lies a
critical distinction.

            Consider <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> hypotheses:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hypothesis 1</ENAMEX> says that when I buy a gun, I discourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from becoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and so reduce crime against my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. In that case, according to
the cost-benefit criterion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> like to employ, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> ownership
should be subsidized.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hypothesis 2</ENAMEX> says that when I
buy a gun, I prevent crimes against myself while having no effect on crimes
against my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who choose me as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> end up wasting their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who choose you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> are as successful as
ever. In that case, I have ample incentive to arm myself, and there is no
reason to encourage me with a subsidy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hypothesis 3</ENAMEX> says that when I
buy a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> gun, I protect myself from, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> worth of property loss, while
inflicting, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> worth of property loss on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>--because half the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who try unsuccessfully to rob me go on to rob someone else instead.
In that case--again, according to the usual cost-benefit criterion--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> is a
bad thing; it costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> and only reduces total crime by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX>. That's an
argument for discouraging gun ownership through taxation.

            I do not know which of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypotheses</ENAMEX> is closest to the truth and am not aware of any research that
settles that question. Therefore I do not know whether gun ownership should be
subsidized, taxed, or neither.

            What's
remarkable about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lojack</ENAMEX> research is that it does do a careful job of
distinguishing among the analogues of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hypotheses 1, 2, and 3</ENAMEX>. That takes a lot
of hard work and ingenuity. It will take harder work and more ingenuity before
we know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niziol</ENAMEX> has jumped to the right or the wrong conclusion.

            
               Brissing
Link
            

            I found
"So Are
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Neanderthals Still Jews?</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Paul Freund</ENAMEX> to be inappropriate
for a publication from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. While it may be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX> was attempting
satire in his review of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> origins over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 2,000 years</TIMEX>, it is
just a stonestep away from believing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX> himself believes many of the
things he chronicles. More importantly, his writing style lends credence to
these blatantly racist and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> writings. What purpose or higher
reasoning can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> use to justify such writing?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Goldstein</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">M.D. Chapel Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>

            
               Funny,
You Don't Look <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Neanderthal</ENAMEX>
            

            I just
finished reading "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">So Are the Neanderthals Still Jews?</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Paul Freund</ENAMEX>, and
found it to be in very poor taste. I will assume for argument's sake that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is not blatantly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>, but is only trying to outline the
theories put forward over the centuries which account for the survival of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the face of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of persecution. This type of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, even when well meant, just further <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> the fires of anti-Semitism
and is counter-productive to the ongoing development of peace and civilization
on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. Your decision to publish such an article dismays me. I would urge you
to remove this article from the Net and avoid this type of journalism in the
future.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Koppy</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Freund</ENAMEX> replies : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Goldstein</ENAMEX> thinks my style lends credence to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
being space <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>, horned devils, etc., while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Koppy</ENAMEX> says
my story impedes <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s peace and civilization. Thanks anyway, but exposure
(the story) and scorn (the style) are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> available antidotes to the heritage
of hatred and dehumanization I described, and which is arguably a bigger
problem than my story. The article's unfathomable purpose was, to quote it, "a
lesson in how the most inane ideas can have the most appalling
consequences."

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
