
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Unplug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Chapman</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unplug the DOE</ENAMEX>!"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Chapman</ENAMEX> recommends that an empty symbolic gesture drive policy. What's
more, he does it without apology or embarrassment.

            What may be provocative copy
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is actually outdated discourse. The perennial argument for
dismantling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX> doesn't succeed because it doesn't make
sense. No proposal has ever identified clear savings for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> from
eliminating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>--at least, none that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> the department
saved under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> (by undertaking contract reform, cutting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waste</ENAMEX>, privatizing, and streamlining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>).

            Of his various arguments for
redistributing our responsibilities, most disconcerting is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX>'s easy pass
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>'s nuclear-weapons responsibilities to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>. The decades-old
"check and balance" relationship between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> squares the needs
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are responsible for the safety, control, and stewardship of
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> with those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who decide whether to use the
weapons.

            Then-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX>
said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, "With the new technical challenges of providing stewardship of
the stockpile in the absence of underground testing, this is not a time to be
fundamentally restructuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of these activities." And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s energy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watkins</ENAMEX>, as saying, "I think it would be a mistake to give [weapons functions
to the] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>," and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> may not understand the
importance of rigorous--and expensive--nuclear-safety practices. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Watkins</ENAMEX>
described a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who wanted to stonewall public concerns about
environmental contamination and safety threats at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> by exercising the
government's sovereign-immunity defense against litigation. "And to hell with
nuclear safety," he added.

            So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> wants to give
weapons safety and cleanup to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living near our nuclear sites
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have seen progress both in openness and cleanup by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. I don't think they would want this change.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> goal is actually one we share: ensuring that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fully
understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s success in reducing the size of
government while increasing its effect. A better solution would be for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> to report the story. But that would be more difficult
than covering empty symbols.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmen</ENAMEX>
MacDougalldeputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant secretary</ENAMEX> for communicationsDepartment of
Energy
            

            

               Goddamnit!
            

            I remember seeing a piece by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years back</TIMEX> on the absurdity of punditry. You know, the
professional pundit, who is supposed to know whether (and how) we should have
intervened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, who should win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> for best cinematography this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, what revisions should be made to the method of GNP calculations, what
concessions the baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> should accept, and so on. Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> has
brought punditry to almost unimaginable new heights with its ongoing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX> There a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God?</ENAMEX>" dialogue between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Chapman</ENAMEX>. I suppose that
keeping up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sinai</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> predictions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> movements does give one
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> on this matter; but, it still seems to me, musings on this
subject (like those on solid-state physics, for example) should, if they are
going to be published, be assigned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who have had more than a
little training in the matter.

            One can, for example, read
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> to date without knowing what either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> means by the word
"God." We know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> believes in him (her? it? us?), and the other guy
does not; and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> has "always" had this belief, while the other guy
has lost his. But that's about it. Furthermore, while there have been no
definitions or real elucidations, the discussions seem mired in the concept of
a personal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>-type deity, as though the ability to prove or disprove the
existence of that sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> is in some way dispositive. I'm not sure if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> realize that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brahman</ENAMEX> has been around
considerably longer than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>'s cross-pollination of something like the
following: a powerful (yet devout) bearded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, a cool breeze on a clear summer
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> tune, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion King</ENAMEX>.

            Listen, I
really don't want to criticize. Many of us struggle with these issues for much
of our adult lives, and perhaps it's something we ought to do ... something
that's good for us and for the world. It's probably therapeutic for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">warriors</ENAMEX> to be taking time out from their inquiries into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Budget</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate</ENAMEX> to organize their thoughts on their place in the universe. And,
although I got a Ph.D. in philosophy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> and have thought and read
about these matters ever since, heaven (or whatever) knows I don't have too
many answers that I feel confident about. These matters are both very difficult
and (except for strict "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Raft</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddhists</ENAMEX>, who are interested only in the
relief of suffering, not in metaphysics) very important. I don't mind,
therefore, that your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> are interested, or that they aren't making
much headway. I just resist the idea of punditry in certain spheres. I mean, is
nothing holy?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Horn</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Give
Gates the Bill
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> ranks
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> in total giving on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>" list, but here is some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for thought:

            I heard on the radio that
Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $21 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. My calculations may be slipping a
zero here or there, but: If one divides <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27 million</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' contributions to
charity so far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>] by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21 billion</NUMEX>, and uses that percentage to prorate
what an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with a net worth of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> might give to charity, one
would come up with an annual contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$51.43</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about a dollar</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> at
the collection plate of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.

            Don't get me wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> is
entitled to do whatever he wants with his cash. But it is a little sad to see
that he has not taken a little more aggressive approach toward charitable
giving. His oft-stated goal of waiting until he retires to worry about giving
away his money is nice, but extremely shortsighted.

            A
well-placed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, especially when not burdened with the bureaucracy
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, could well cure <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, or otherwise profoundly alter
the lives of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, like many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, has been directly touched by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.) It's sad to think that the
epitaph on countless headstones over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few decades</TIMEX> will have this
postscript: "I might have lived a full life if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> had decided to retire just
a bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Trickle-Down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign-Finance Reform</ENAMEX>
            

            Why should the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> public
accept the yardstick <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JacobWeisberg</ENAMEX> offered us for "measuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
foreign-contributions scandal" in his defense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, "Does
Everybody <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do It?</ENAMEX>"? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> makes the myopic error of defining "everybody"
as the pustular ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> incestuously engaged in
doling out political favors to their campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. There is little
discerning power evident in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s relativist judging of the moral failings
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> campaigns against the most afflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> examples. There
are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who don't play the campaign-finance game despite the odds
stacked against them. Some are even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.

            The current shock and horror
over alleged large soft-money donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> by
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX>) in return for economic-
and military-policy considerations by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is amusing--as
if soft-money contributions made by domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are
somehow better, less sullied, more ethical. If such activity is considered
bribery when foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> engage in it, why is it any different when
domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> put our campaign system of legalized bribery to use? This
points to a moral duality in the current situation, which is troubling.

            Campaign-finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>
fixate too much on the demand side of this economic market. If we consider, for
a moment, that the primary aim behind reform is the reduction of
influence-peddling, then we can look at the present campaign system as a
political-influence market: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> making payments in return for policy favors.
No matter whether it is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> from a multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> or a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>
check from an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, a payment is made because someone feels certain
government policies benefit him or her. Most reforms attempt to deal with the
problem by placing limits on the demand side--that is, campaign-contribution
limits, campaign-expenditure limits, etc.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Invariably</ENAMEX>, contributors
find loopholes and skirt the limits--bending, even breaking, the laws. The
record tide of campaign expenditure during this election cycle can be viewed as
an index of the level of economic dependence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>--even foreign ones--on government policies. Is it any wonder that,
after the breakup of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, the economic marginal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
foreign policy has skyrocketed and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> are anteing up to the
larger pot the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has to offer? Demand-side proposals also run smack
up against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> guarantee of free speech, something some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fearfully</ENAMEX> consider abridging.

            
Addressing the supply side of the political-influence market may get us past
some of the pitfalls endemic to campaign-kickback reform. A supply-side
approach would focus on reducing the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to dole out favors.
Reduce the marginal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> of government influence peddling, and campaign
contributions will take care of themselves. Reduce the stakes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> will
leave the table.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Lipman</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
