
   
   
      
         
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>)
            

            
               Fact
Abuse
            

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey, Wait a Minute</ENAMEX>"
column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas J. Besharov</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob W. Dembosky</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child Abuse: Threat or</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Menace?</ENAMEX>") seriously misrepresents the methodology, findings, and
conclusions of the recently released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third National Incidence Study of Child</ENAMEX>
Abuse and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neglect</ENAMEX> (NIS-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIS-3</ENAMEX> project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and the supervisor
responsible for implementing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIS-3</ENAMEX> definitions, we want to set the record
straight. We address only some of the misinformation here.

            In light of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticisms</ENAMEX>, it is noteworthy that he participated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of Experts</ENAMEX>
convened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1991</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child Abuse and Neglect</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NIS-3</ENAMEX> sponsor) specifically to refine the NIS-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> design. Together with the rest
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conferees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX> recommended no changes in the NIS methodology and
definitions. Now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX> opines that the NIS methodology
and definitions are flawed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIS-3</ENAMEX> findings may run counter to his position,
but it is important for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dembosky</ENAMEX>, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, to get
the facts straight.

            First, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Besharov</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dembosky</ENAMEX> characterized the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4 million</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who joined the ranks
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maltreated</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1986 and 1993</TIMEX>, they summed up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIS-3</ENAMEX> estimates in
inappropriate ways to draw their conclusions. In doing so, they
overstated the percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who were harmed only by
emotional or educational maltreatment (actually <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9 percent</NUMEX>, not the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX>
they indicated) and they understated the percent of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who
were harmed by physical abuse, sexual abuse, or physical neglect (actually 37
percent, not the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> they implied). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dembosky</ENAMEX> also glossed
over how these percentages translate into numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX>
just mentioned refers to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over one-half million</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who
were harmed by physical abuse, sexual abuse, or physical neglect in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>--over
and above the number who were harmed by these forms of mistreatment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. An
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,249,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were harmed by these forms of maltreatment in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. Also, in discounting the rise in incidence found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIS-3</ENAMEX>, Besharov
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dembosky</ENAMEX> contend that "fatalities arising from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse have held
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> steady" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1986 and 1993</TIMEX>. But this is contradicted by the numbers
they themselves cite, which show that fatalities have risen by 
               20
percent during this period, from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,014 to 1,216</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX> and Dembosky
misrepresented the NIS methodology for classifying the severity of injury or
harm. (We wish we could ascribe this to misunderstanding, but we clarified this
issue for them before their article's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> and they published their
misinformation anyway.) In fact, the classification of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> as seriously
injured/harmed is relatively objective in that it does not rely on a blanket
judgment by a respondent. The criteria for defining serious harm or injury are
standardized; they are applied to the described injury itself, not to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">respondent</ENAMEX>'s judgment about that injury; and they have been consistent across
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> incidence studies. So the recent quadrupling of the number of
seriously injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> cannot be ascribed to some vague form of
"definitional creep."

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dembosky</ENAMEX>'s claim that increased sensitivity accounts for the rise in the number
of seriously injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> does not make sense in the context of the
patterns of NIS findings, which do provide evidence of progressively heightened
sensitivity for more subtle maltreatment cues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Respondents</ENAMEX>' sensitivity to
moderate injuries increased between the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NIS-1</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NIS-2</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>,
but did not change after that. Between the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NIS-2</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIS-3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>
showed increased awareness of endangerment (i.e., maltreatment events that did
not yet cause harm). Note that the significant increases found in the NIS-3
were discontinuous across the outcome spectrum, occurring in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
categories: serious injury/harm and endangerment, both of which essentially
quadrupled since the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NIS-2</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dembosky</ENAMEX> want to discount
both increments by appealing to the same process (enhanced sensitivity) then
they need to explain (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) why this process applied discontinuously in the NIS-3
and did not affect the intervening category of moderate injury or harm, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIS-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> managed to overlook <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-fourths</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who
had been seriously injured while at the same time evidencing greater
sensitivity in identifying moderately injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Seriously injured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of maltreatment are relatively unlikely to escape detection by the
study methodology, so the rise in incidence in this category cannot be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plausibly</ENAMEX> explained as due to heightened awareness. Considering all the
evidence, the most reasonable interpretation is that there has been a real
increase in the incidence of seriously injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than one-half</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were seriously injured by abuse or neglect in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX> and Dembosky
take issue with the documented drop of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX> in the rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child</ENAMEX>
Protective Services investigations by pointing out that the set of
uninvestigated cases includes educational neglect and emotional maltreatment.
But a careful reading of their discussion reveals that they do not address the
drop per se. Instead, their entire discussion emphasizes their "take" on the
relative inappropriateness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPS</ENAMEX> investigations for emotional and educational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">maltreatment</ENAMEX>. However, educational neglect and emotional maltreatment have
always been included in the incidence studies, and eliminating them from the
picture would not eradicate the significant drop in the overall rate of CPS
investigations from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NIS-2</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NIS-3</ENAMEX>. In fact, the percentages of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> whose maltreatment was investigated decreased significantly in all
categories except educational neglect--from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64 percent to 45 percent</NUMEX>
among physically abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent to 44 percent</NUMEX> among sexually
abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent to 35 percent</NUMEX> among physically neglected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent to 26 percent</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> seriously injured by
any maltreatment.

            Finally, contrary to what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besharov</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dembosky</ENAMEX> convey, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIS-3</ENAMEX> report does not "blithely call for
more" reporting. Nor did we "claim recklessly that too few cases are
investigated." Instead, we concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIS-3</ENAMEX> findings "emphasize the
need for better targeting, whether by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in referring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPS</ENAMEX>,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPS</ENAMEX> screening practices in connection with reports, or by both."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Sedlak</ENAMEX>, Ph.D.
            

            
               associate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services Research Area</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westat Inc.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Broadhurst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.L.A.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westat Inc.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Besharov Replies</ENAMEX>:
            

            It is difficult to respond
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedlak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadhurst</ENAMEX>'s letter. First, I have great respect for their past
work, and appreciate the constraints they faced in this project--as government
contractors in an underfunded study. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, words like "misrepresented" and
"misinformation" are, in the world of policy analysis, fighting words. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>,
their study is complicated, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX> can be thrown back and forth until the
eyes of the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> glaze over. Most important, my complaint is not so
much with the study as with the interpretation of its findings--and especially
with the spin given to it by political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services</ENAMEX>.

            Hence, I will deal with the
personal attacks in their letter and then go on to my larger policy--and
ethical--concerns about their response.

            In their letter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedlak</ENAMEX> and
Broadhurst correctly point out that I participated in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> that discussed the study's methodology. In fact, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child Abuse and Neglect</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1970s</TIMEX>, I helped design
the study in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place--long before either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sedlak</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadhurst</ENAMEX> were
involved. So, I know well the strengths--and weaknesses--of the study's
approach to the difficult task of counting illegal behaviors toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
that largely occur behind closed doors.

            They claim that, after the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> meeting, I "recommended no changes in the [incidence study's] methodology
and definitions." But they conveniently leave out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important facts. First,
at that meeting, I pointed out that the methodological changes that were
planned for the study all would have the effect of raising the count of
abused and neglected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> . In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedlak</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> described
(in a report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>) how they planned to "fine-tune" the study to "ensure that
categories of key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> who were most likely to encounter suspected
maltreatment cases in the [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> incidence study] are given higher probability
of being included in the [new study]." In other words, they proposed to change
the study's methodology so that more reports would be made to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westat</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, I
did urge that the study's conclusions be modified--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> before it was
released to the public. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7, 1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalala</ENAMEX> issued a press
release stating that "the number of abused and neglected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> rose sharply
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.4 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.9 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>." I tried to get a copy of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, but was informed that no one outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would be given a
copy until it was complete. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalala</ENAMEX> issued her press release
based on an uncompleted report.

            Like others, I tried to get
more information about the study from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westat</ENAMEX>, but was rebuffed. In fact, Sedlak
sent me a memorandum stating that "the continued contacts from your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on
the matter give the appearance of efforts to place me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in a
compromising position in relation to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCCAN</ENAMEX>. Please ensure that your
staff refrain from further contacts of this nature."

            Concerned, I wrote to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalala</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, stating: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Westat</ENAMEX> findings may be extremely
significant, but there is reason to doubt that they reflect an actual increase
in abuse and neglect." I went on to explain what the problems seemed to be, and
to offer my assistance in interpreting the study's results.

            In a bureaucratic
nonresponse, a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> replied by enclosing a defense of the study
prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedlak</ENAMEX> and stating, "I believe that the enclosed memo concerning
the study adequately addresses your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>."

            I mention this history,
rather than dueling with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedlak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadhurst's</ENAMEX> statistics, because I think
that it exemplifies their selective presentation of information.

            The last time Sedlak
conducted an incidence study, it had to be revised and reissued almost three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> because technical problems in the analysis inflated the estimated
number of abused and neglected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX>.

            This time around, the
problem seems to be more severe. The plain fact is that no attempt was made to
conduct the kind of second-level analysis that would have explored whether the
increases were real. (The data that they cite in their letter to contradict us,
by the way, were not presented in the original report and, in any event, are
too incomplete for these purposes.) I realize that one reason this essential
work was not performed was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was unwilling to pay for it. But
that is no excuse for announcing that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse and neglect nearly doubled"
without also cautioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> about the study's limitations. I hope that,
before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> pass, a revised report that does so will be issued.

            Moreover, I doubt that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> seriously believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse doubled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>. If it
had, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> would be in the midst of a child-abuse crisis. Decisive and
perhaps radical action would be required, not the puny list of previously
planned and budgeted activities that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalala</ENAMEX> described in her press release: A
demonstration program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23 million</NUMEX> in prevention grants, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to maternal and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-health programs, past initiatives to fund family
preservation programs and to oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-welfare block grants, and an
"unprecedented" level of technical assistance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> (again, though, not
an increase).

            But the real reason I write
is because of the broader problem created by exaggerating social ills. Cynics
might chalk up this latest report as yet another well-meaning effort to build
support for child-abuse programs. After all, goes the thinking, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> maltreatment is a big problem, they might be willing
to spend more money on treatment and prevention programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gelles</ENAMEX>, a
longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the field and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Book of David: How Preserving</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> Can Cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's</ENAMEX> Lives , says that he used to "go along" with
past exaggerations, but has come to appreciate the harm that they have
done.

            Exaggerating the severity of
cases is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> has called "defining deviancy up."
The more it seems that such serious maltreatment is common, the less likely are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to respond firmly. To put it bluntly, society can consider a tough
response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> serious cases a year--but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">560,000</NUMEX> is an entirely different
matter, politically and programmatically.

            I have
worked in this field for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 30 years</TIMEX>--first as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS National Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child Abuse and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neglect</ENAMEX>, and more recently as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>--and I know that child
abuse and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> neglect are profound national problems. But, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> after time I
have seen how such overstatements have made the problem seem too big to handle
or have distorted policy-making. I am afraid that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalala</ENAMEX>'s remarks will do the
same.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
Is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bearded Lady</ENAMEX>
            

            According to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>" posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 11</TIMEX>, "Gossip focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s new beard, the first
facial hair on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>."

            Well, I
know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Day O'Connor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Bader Ginsberg</ENAMEX> don't. And I'm pretty sure
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> don't. But doesn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> have a mustache?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            
               Mississippi
Yearning
            

            In his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diary</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Queenan</ENAMEX>
describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> at the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> he reads:
"Having persuaded themselves that they are living and working in rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>--which is where they all belong--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> always seems amazed to
find that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Boesky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Icahn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariah Carey</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Letterman</ENAMEX>
actually live in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> as them."

            These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> do not belong in "rural <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX>." No one here would put up with
their awful writing. When I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX> to work in the
publications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, I thought I would get
special treatment for being a wordsmith. Hell no. Telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around here
that you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> is like telling a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> that you are an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> and
expecting them to be impressed. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has a lot to be ashamed of, but not
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. Bad analogy, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queenan</ENAMEX>. Instead, condemn your weak local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>, which is where they all belong.

            
               -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bridgman</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
