
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Java
Jibe
            

            I was very disappointed to
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Shuman</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weak Java</ENAMEX>." The question of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> is an
interesting and complicated one, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuman</ENAMEX>'s analysis was alarmingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">one-sided</ENAMEX>.

            For instance, Shuman
discussed the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> is an interpreted language without bringing up the
fact that many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> included) have developed what are called
just-in-time compilers, which largely fix the slowness problem he discussed. On
the fly, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JIT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">compiler</ENAMEX> converts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> bytecodes, normally destined to be
interpreted, into machine codes, which can be run very quickly. Indeed, recent
estimates have suggested that, through the use of things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JIT</ENAMEX> compilers,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> will reach speeds of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 70 percent and 80 percent</NUMEX> of the speed of a
natively run <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> program. Not nearly as s-l-o-w as the article suggests.

            Shuman neglected to mention
the other big advantage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>, which is security. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ActiveX</ENAMEX> and some of
the other competing technologies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> applets can be run without fear of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">applet</ENAMEX> trashing your hard drive. A group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> demonstrated how a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">malicious ActiveX</ENAMEX> component can take over your copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quicken</ENAMEX> and make
financial transactions on your behalf.

            There is
a lot more to say on this issue, and I'm not going to try and outline all of
the important points. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuman</ENAMEX> should have. Or rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> should have
found someone more likely to give a more full and nuanced view of the
issue.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yaron M. Minsky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syracuse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>

            

               Refill
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX>'s "Weak
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Culture Wars</ENAMEX>"
are frightfully irresponsible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX>'s breezy article largely omits the
implications of the reliability, flexibility, and security provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> in
order to emphasize the cost of these benefits in execution speed. While a
strong case can be made that the advantages are well worth the cost, this by
itself does not reflect poorly on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. Nor does the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surowiecki</ENAMEX>'s
column to note its own thinly veiled role in the culture war surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX>
that it describes. However, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> chose to run these poorly constructed
articles is a clear instance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> editorial influence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> offer
attention that brings advertising revenue not for misleading propaganda like
this, but for information presented with the kind of journalistic integrity
that usually characterizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. If such a conflict of interest cannot be
handled gracefully, the subject is best avoided.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX> Gold New York
City

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottomless Mug</ENAMEX>
            

            Evangelistic movements being
what they are, I have no doubt you'll be swamped with letters responding to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Shuman</ENAMEX>'s criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> programming language (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Weak Java</ENAMEX>"). Here's
another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, though I'm no Java evangelical (I'd much rather program in
CommonLisp, thanks).

            The assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> as hard for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COBOL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> to learn as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> is sent the needle on my BS
detector into the red zone. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the nice things about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> is that the most
difficult parts of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX> (indirection and "pointer arithmetic," among other things)
have been left out of the language, while other convenience features
unavailable in C (such as memory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>) have been added to it. These
things make it much easier to learn than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Shuman</ENAMEX>'s harping on "s-l-o-w"
probably says more about the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s virtual machine than it
does about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> paradigm. (The virtual machine is the program that
"interprets" or, in some cases, compiles and runs the compact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> bytecodes
that make up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> program.)

            With the
one-two punch of items critical of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shuman</ENAMEX>'s piece and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surowiecki</ENAMEX>'s column, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Culture Wars</ENAMEX>," I have to close my eyes and clap for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinkerbell</ENAMEX> to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> remains independent and exercises untrammeled
judgment on what points of view to present on issues directly affecting its
parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Miklos East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norwalk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> reply: This
sampling of e-mail is civilized compared to the vituperative name-calling cast
down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who used the link on the article to e-mail him
directly. (But don't feel sorry for him, he asked for it.) At this moment,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">l-o-a-d-i-n-</ENAMEX>g his <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Java</ENAMEX> word processor and composing a response to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, which will run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.
            

            
               Milliken
It for All It's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Worth</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's Buying Whom?</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> defends himself against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who apparently accused him of
selling out to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> and multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> column
supporting trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The East Is in the Red"</ENAMEX>) by attacking me as a hireling of
protectionist interests directed by textile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Milliken</ENAMEX>. Since I
neither read his article on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> nor wrote him a letter, the logic that leads
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> to a gratuitous strike at me is unclear.

            What is clear, however, is
that he has either badly missed the mark by neglecting to do his homework, or
is engaged in a willful campaign of misrepresentation. While it is true, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> says, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Strategy Institute</ENAMEX> received early financial
support from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milliken</ENAMEX>, it is also the case, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> should have known, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX> ceased making contributions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over four years ago</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESI</ENAMEX>, over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX>'s objections, provided critical support to the passage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> and
the ratification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> and free-trade arrangements
concluded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uruguay Round</ENAMEX>. Thus, our support of free trade amounts to more
than pious, theoretical declamations from the groves of academe.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESI</ENAMEX> does not claim
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infallibility</ENAMEX> or even the absence of silly mistakes, but we are not for sale.
We make the best case we can based on the facts as we know them. Moreover, we
do not attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, only ideas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> says "the currency of academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> is creativity." Perhaps, but the ad hominem approach is usually the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mark</ENAMEX> of a weak argument.

            As for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Milliken</ENAMEX>, I don't always agree with him, but he is an honest and
honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> could learn a lot.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde V. Prestowitz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jr. Economic Strategy Institute</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Touché à</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">la Tonelson</ENAMEX>
            

            In his response to my
letter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 14</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> is so determined to nail me as an economic illiterate that he
loses sight of our original disagreements--and some of his own previous work.
The book review of mine that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> initially criticized in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The East Is in the Red</ENAMEX>"
cited "many reasons" for thinking that "consumer markets" in emerging countries
like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> "are likely to stay small for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, even if
formal trade barriers come down." I singled out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> such reasons: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>,
largely because most of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have huge foreign debts to pay off, and
therefore need to discourage consumption by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, they are
pursuing export-led growth strategies. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, if they don't keep wages and
purchasing power low, they will have trouble attracting the foreign investment
they require, both to service debt and to finance growth." I added that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
"has made it abundantly clear that it has no intention of becoming a major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">importer</ENAMEX>; it aims eventually to satisfy most of its own needs."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> responded in "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is in the Red</ENAMEX>" by observing that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> attracting enough foreign
investment "both to service debt and to finance growth" must be running trade
deficits. He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s record in particular belies my argument because
its roughly balanced global trade indicates that it is not a net capital
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">importer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> is, of course, right about the relationship between trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">balances</ENAMEX> and current-account balances, and about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s international
balances. But as I originally stated, numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> are responsible for
limiting the consumer imports of this disparate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Some, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most important emerging-market trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>), are struggling
with huge debt overhangs and therefore must restrict domestic consumption and
earn foreign exchange by focusing on exporting. Some believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> models of production and export-led development are superior to
consumption-led approaches to economic growth. Some are driven by memories of
domination by the West to seek substantial degrees of economic
self-sufficiency. And some are motivated by combinations of these
considerations.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, with major plans to
supply its own needs in industries such as motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, aerospace, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">semiconductors</ENAMEX>, is clearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> country striving for self-sufficiency. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> are also great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> of key aspects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> development
model. Indeed, the amassing of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $125 billion</NUMEX> in foreign-exchange reserves
has been central to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s success at pursuing export-led growth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
have accumulated these reserves by selling their own currency in order to
depress its value--which, of course, keeps export prices low and import prices
high. As a result, the already meager international purchasing power of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">rock</ENAMEX>-bottom wages is suppressed even further. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s claim that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have seen real living standards rise over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these last twenty</TIMEX>-odd
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, it is based on a poor choice of data--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s real <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX>
compensation figures. This series suffers from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> related problems. First, it
includes all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> to janitors. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it is an average. As
income inequality in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> rises--a problem <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> has written
about eloquently--any economy-wide average will of course deviate increasingly
from the median, which much more accurately describes the situation of the
typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>.

            The
typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s situation can be more accurately gauged by looking at indexes
focusing on median figures for production, nonsupervisory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>--who make up
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. Such series include the median <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> earnings
statistics published by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Labor Statistics</ENAMEX> and derived from the
Earnings Files of the Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population Survey</ENAMEX>. This series, and several
others, amply support my claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> living standards have been declining
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two decades</TIMEX>, and refute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s claim that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX>- and Third World
wages are converging "through a process of leveling up, not leveling down." Nor
do the results change significantly when nonwage benefits are factored in.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Tonelson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Business and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Council Educational Foundation</ENAMEX>

            

               Unsolicited Testimony
            

            I'm not
entirely certain that I have the correct e-mail spot simply to report how much
I enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. I humbly confess that when I first heard of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that
would be online only, I scoffed. Now, I am converted. I enjoy curling up with
Slate just as I do my more material <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, and there is nothing to
recycle or discard (guiltily) and no "newsprint fingertips." Thank you
especially for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"--lots of time saved there and a nice pithy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overview</ENAMEX>. Same for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Other Magazines</ENAMEX>." And, lewd poetry from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Herrick</ENAMEX>, yet. All in all, the best
of what's new in this cyberworld.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarke Phoenix</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
