
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               "Number
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9, Number 9, Number 9</ENAMEX> ..."
            

            Maybe it's because I'm a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dumb</ENAMEX>, narrow-minded conservative, but I count <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> reasons in the misnamed
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "Eight
Reasons Not to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cut the Capital-Gains Tax</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>.

            Too bad none of them are
very good reasons. In reference to No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, how do you get the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> figure?
Do <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> own their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, and think of selling
them from time to time? If so, then I'm more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> than I thought! The truth
is, the capital-gains tax affects a lot more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            Other
than that, I enjoyed the article.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John T. Tant</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>' Reply
            

            Kinsley
counts; it's his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX> who made the mistake.

            
               We've
Found <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reason No. 9</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> missed a pretty good reason in his "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eight Reasons</ENAMEX> Not to
Cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Capital-Gains Tax</ENAMEX>." Unless you can go back in time, cutting the tax
rate on existing capital gains cannot possibly increase investment in
productive resources. You cannot change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>' past investment decisions.
Those who claim to want a cut in the capital-gains tax rate because it will
increase investment and not because it is a handout to the rich could gain a
lot of credibility if they advocated reducing the rate only on future capital
gains.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Nelson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               It's My
Money
            

            I guess that one of the
things I liked about the blast at capital-gains tax cuts in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eight Reasons</ENAMEX> Not to
Cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Capital-Gains Tax</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s cheerful
admission that he has written it all before. I assume that he formed his
convictions as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, when he had no investments and didn't even know what
they were.

            I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">79</TIMEX>, and when I make
money out of the market, it is because I watch the ticker much of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>,
study documents, make guesses, and take risks--with money that I earned
myself. I could lose my shirt at any moment. I have had noticeable losses, and
the feeling of humiliation that goes with them.

            Kinsley
thinks it is OK for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to take a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> (give or take) of anything this
retired research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> labors to make through entrepreneurial risk-taking.
I don't.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaughn Davis</ENAMEX>
Bornet
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> Play
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>
            

            I am not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX>, nor do I
work for any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, but I have lived happily in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> for the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>, and there is very little that I recognize in the highly subjective
account "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Have Seen the Future</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> ...," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Easterbrook</ENAMEX>. He
is apparently unable to provide accurate factual information, and even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradicts</ENAMEX> himself.

            For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabena</ENAMEX> is very
far from being a state-sanctioned monopoly, as it is in competition with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> on all its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> except those with too little traffic to support a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>. If you want to find such a monopoly, you need look no further
than the rails, where the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> operates the world's fastest in
cooperation with similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Also, the
standard off-peak rate for local phone calls here is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than 2 U.S. cents</NUMEX> per
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>, which scarcely makes dial-up access to an ISP a "luxury."

            Although I
could flag numerous other fundamental errors, I think that these should be
enough to make my point that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easterbrook</ENAMEX>'s opinion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecoms</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>" is far from the truth.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan F.</ENAMEX>
Reekie
            

            
               Get Out
of Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cocoon</ENAMEX>
            

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurocrat</ENAMEX> in my cubicle
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX>, sitting on the ergonomic chair I "borrowed" from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> collapsed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, I was wondering who got those plush
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suites</ENAMEX> with leather chairs that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Easterbrook</ENAMEX> referred to in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Have Seen the</ENAMEX>
Future of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> ...." Suddenly I got it: He is referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ministers</ENAMEX>, a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>
get together to make decisions (mostly on proposals by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>).

            Just
because somebody can write and his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> gets an assignment abroad does
not mean they have insight on a whole continent. I do not think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Easterbrook</ENAMEX> had
to relocate to write that piece. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is distributed electronically and
is available to a wide international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, you should get less ethnocentric
views of the world. Couldn't you get contributions from outside your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cocoon</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Antonio Lopez</ENAMEX>
Sanchez
            

            
               Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>
            

            In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX> "Summary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judgment</ENAMEX>," when reviewing the reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladstone</ENAMEX> , you
understandably fell afoul of those tricky <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> titles of nobility. You
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX>," which is not correct. That would make him
the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Randolph Churchill</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Wimsey</ENAMEX>
(and not, thereby, actually a lord except in using that word in this courtesy
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX>).

            Instead, he is a life peer
with a barony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillhead</ENAMEX>, to distinguish him from some
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX>). So you can call him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Jenkins</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillhead</ENAMEX>" or "Lord
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX>" for short; or by his actual name, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX>," since he still uses
it; but not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX>." It is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Thatcher</ENAMEX>,"
not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>"; "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Callaghan</ENAMEX>" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Callaghan</ENAMEX>," not "Lord
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Callaghan</ENAMEX>"; and so on.

            This is
worth pointing out because most retired top-rank <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are in
this position, and an amazing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, even those for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , make this mistake. I'm sure most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who went
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX> only so they'd have a place to speechify after retiring from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commons</ENAMEX> would rather do without this, but it's part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> schtick, so
at the least we ought to get the names right.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bratman</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
