
   
   
      
         
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>)
            

            Click here
to see letters to our tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. You can send any technical questions to
slatetech@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and
all other mail to slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Foul
Ball
            

            I still
puzzle over <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> economics (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Diamonds</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rough</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Pastier</ENAMEX>). If <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> are such a good business deal,
why aren't they readily funded by private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> without major municipal
support? The funds are out there and available when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, and
venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> need <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few billion</NUMEX> to buy up some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>. My suspicion
is that the absence of private capital proves that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> are not a good deal
except for the select few on the inside who are subsidized by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
money.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
Cerny

            
               No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rain</ENAMEX>,
No Gain
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Pastier</ENAMEX>'s assertions (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Diamonds</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rough"</ENAMEX>) leaves me perplexed. He states that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> "has the driest
weather in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>." Is this the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> I know? Is this
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> described in a past issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , which featured
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> on the cover in a rain slicker? Have I missed something?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent</ENAMEX>
Wosepka

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sucker</ENAMEX>
Pitches
            

            Your story
on new ball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Diamonds</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rough</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Pastier</ENAMEX>) failed to mention their blatant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commercialism</ENAMEX> in the form of billboards and other intrusive enticements to buy
products totally unrelated to the game. Improvements in architecture, regaining
intimate space and scale and all the rest, won't disguise the ugliness of
advertising the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain retailer</ENAMEX> as a backdrop for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>

            
               Creaming
DeMuth
            

            I read
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee of Correspondence</ENAMEX>: Advice for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>," with some interest
and not a little amazement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris DeMuth</ENAMEX>'s contribution is an outstanding
illustration of the ideological dead weight carried by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s campaign so
far. The stable of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">think-tank hobby horses</ENAMEX> being promoted (school choice,
abortion, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile defenses</ENAMEX>) is as bloated as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeMuth</ENAMEX> decries.
Borrowing from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DeMuth</ENAMEX>, I ask, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Is Dole</ENAMEX> any less constrained than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
'by powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency groups</ENAMEX> within the [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" So far, the
answer is an unqualified "Yes!" These inside-the-Beltway issues and their
small, but vocal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> make this election <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s to lose.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
Bammerlin

            
               Click
Here to Snooze
            

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX> the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>
of Correspondence" has covered several topics. Each has been boring. The
root of the difficulty is most probably the format rather than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discussants</ENAMEX>.

            But the result is becoming
predictable.

            You have invented a piece of
writing that is created from conversation. This guarantees the outcome will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tiresome</ENAMEX> and seemingly self-indulgent. And hard to read--impossible to read. I
am interested in all the topics discussed so far, yet have been unable to read
through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a third</NUMEX> of any offering.

            I applaud
your willingness to experiment, and yes, all well-designed experiments are
successful. Please declare this experiment completed and move on.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ned</ENAMEX>
Fagan

            
               Left
Out
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX> is a senior
fellow at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise Institute</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee of</ENAMEX>
Correspondence: Advice for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bartley</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher DeMuth</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Keating</ENAMEX> is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Matalin</ENAMEX> was the deputy campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> '92 ticket.

            Maybe
fairness isn't an aim of your electro-rag, but how about an occasional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> who stands to the left of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Atilla the Helms</ENAMEX>?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
Paddock

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedestrian Crossing</ENAMEX>
            

            I have been very disappointed
by what I've seen of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> thus far. The economics articles, while a good idea,
have proven fairly trivial and even pedestrian. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>'s comments
on the national debt ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kwitcherbellyachin'"</ENAMEX>) were neither enlightening nor humorous,
leading me to wonder why you bothered running the piece.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> clearly seems to have
already taken a political slant to the right. Its content is proof enough.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s affiliation with a labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is hardly surprising ("The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>), even less so to one who supported his
position on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>. What is surprising is the temerity of running an article
titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Clintons and the Mob</ENAMEX>" when the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX>" in question has neither
been convicted of nor indicted for racketeering. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> only
establishes a connection between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coia</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> family; evidence of
organized criminal activities was weakly presented. This smacks of
irresponsible journalism.

            In another article, "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warlords of Democracy</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Goble</ENAMEX>, you offer a link to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
speech, at the end of which is a command to "go back." Dutifully following
instructions, I find myself in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> Web site endowed with the collected wisdom
of such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luminaries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX>.

            I
understand that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> is still developing. I certainly hope it
develops into a well-balanced, responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, but that is not the
direction I perceive.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Schultz</ENAMEX>

            
               War and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Remembrance</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goble</ENAMEX> is not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to discover that even the best forms of
government are prone to engage in war (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Warlords</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX>"). Nor is his analysis more penetrating than that of others
who have made the same discovery. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goble</ENAMEX>'s suffers by comparison to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.N. Waltz</ENAMEX>'s
in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> . Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goble</ENAMEX>'s point
is one that bears repeating, if only because it seems to be so easily
forgotten.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rendell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>

            
               C+ for
Democracy
            

            It's no surprise that
democracy isn't perfect (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Warlords</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Goble</ENAMEX>). It is essentially an averaging of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and like any average, it falls somewhere between the best and the
worst. The decisions a democracy arrives at won't be as good as those the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would have made, but neither will they be as bad as what
the worst would have done. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part is the most important side of the
equation.

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">benevolent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> would be the best form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, except for one
distressing fact. Nobody's figured out how to make sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> will
actually be benevolent before giving him the reins of power. And you generally
can't trade them in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> without a whole lot of bloodshed.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawkins</ENAMEX>

            
               Freedom
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fighters</ENAMEX>
            

            I was a bit surprised by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Goble</ENAMEX>'s position in his article titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Warlords</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX>." The term "peaceful democracy" is almost a contradiction in
terms. The justification of democracy is that it provides the greatest level of
freedom to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. There is an old saying, "You can have peace or you can
have freedom. But never count on having both at the same time." There will
always be threats to democracy and freedom from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want more power,
land, etc., and who are willing to use force to achieve their goals.

            
Democracies have always preferred peace to war. War is expensive and wasteful
in terms of human life as well as economics. If the alternative is to lose our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>, then we must be warlike to preserve it.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>
Biener

            
               Right
In
            

            I'm a far right, reactionary,
radical, mean-spirited, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-starving, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Limbaugh</ENAMEX>-loving ditto-head <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
(who for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commie</ENAMEX>, and was proved right). I'm also
a born-again <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and I'm studying apologetics, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawking</ENAMEX> and
other "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Hole</ENAMEX>" evolutionists. Thank God I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bluegrass</ENAMEX> picker too, so I
can take my banjo and go into another world when need be.

            Watching
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> used to make me see red. But I really do
try to look at all sides, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> is a great help. You have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> in
me.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean A. Bahr</ENAMEX>

            
               Feeling
Their Pain
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Chapman</ENAMEX> ("What's
Wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With 'Victims' Rights' "</ENAMEX>) expresses some practical concerns
regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights Amendment</ENAMEX>. However, there is great danger in the
amendment's subtext.

            There are several
justifications for taking a convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX>'s freedom away. The most
neglected rationale, but the one closest to our spiritual traditions, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rehabilitation</ENAMEX>. Other legitimate objectives include removing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX> from the
general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and setting an example to deter potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. The
impulse animating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights Amendment</ENAMEX>, however, is different. It
seeks to assuage the pain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> by allowing them to participate in the
suffering of those who hurt them.

            This cannot be called wrong.
How can one tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that they should not want to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who raped
and killed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> punished? Nevertheless, it is not a principle that
should be honored with a place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. It does not consider the
greater good of broad society; the amendment is a revenge wish, pure and
simple.

            The real
problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights Amendment</ENAMEX> is that it undermines the moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> of justice.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
Gadea

            
               Kill and
Ask Questions Later
            

            Reading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>'s piece about the prospects for human cooperation (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Interdependence Day</ENAMEX>"), I wonder how he might incorporate fear into
the theory of strategic bonding. It seems to me that the instinct for survival
plays as much a role in the trust or distrust among the races as genetics. I've
always felt that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> cause of racial strife is that on a primal,
instinctive level, we distrust something new or different from what we know. If
we encounter this new, different animal when we are alone, our instinct tells
us to run away. If we outnumber this alien being, our instinct tells us to kill
it and ask questions later (or, at the very least, discriminate against it and
keep it in a manageable place). Only by understanding the alien being, and
feeling unthreatened by its presence, will the instinct to control it be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neutralized</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX>
Kutzera

            
               Bad
Judgment Call
            

            I was surprised by "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull Street Journal</ENAMEX>." My reaction while reading it was to be
embarrassed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>, because the whole feature smells like a juvenile attempt
to slam a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> via the most unprofessional means. The kind of SLATE I was
coming to enjoy reading was one that would rip the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
apart using facts, ideas, and finely honed reasoning. There is no place in that
kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> for this kind of high-school parody of a competing
publication.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> is still new, so
perhaps this is the kind of thing that can be written off as inexperience.

            I'll keep
reading, but no longer will I assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> will always exercise good (or
even average) editorial judgment in its selection of features.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O'Neill</ENAMEX>

            
               Save Room
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dessert</ENAMEX>
            

            I was
rather annoyed to find that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and art reviews in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quel Drag</ENAMEX>!" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larissa MacFarquhar</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State of</ENAMEX>
Mind," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX>") cover minor events in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. I hope this isn't
a sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> will follow the lead of many of its print <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> by
licking every crumb from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s cultural plate while completely ignoring
major events that occur elsewhere.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Lauriston

            
               Facts
and Filters
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Volokh</ENAMEX> may
have created more confusion than he dispelled in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> ("Speech
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spillover"</ENAMEX>). Not only does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX> blur the constitutional issues raised
by legislation like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX>, but he also misinforms
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> about the function and effectiveness of software-content filters--facts
that are central to understanding the public debate about regulating content on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX>.

            There are many problems with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> discussion, but most seem to follow from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic
errors. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX> fails to note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has conditioned the
scope of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s authority to broadly regulate constitutionally
protected content (such as nonobscene sexual content) on the specific
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the medium distributing that content. At the risk of
oversimplifying, we may say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has allowed the government greater
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to regulate "indecent" content either when broadcast (e.g., radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">broadcasting</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pacifica</ENAMEX> case) or delivered in a manner
indistinguishable in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, at least--from broadcasting
(e.g., cable television in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Consortium</ENAMEX> case).

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX> conflates
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct (if overlapping) categories of content: "indecent," "sexually
explicit," and (by implication) "pornographic." In doing so, he reinforces a
common confusion about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX>--namely, that its reach
was limited only to pornographic material. But as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> noted, the terms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> criminalized a far broader range of
speech--speech that is "indecent" or "patently offensive"--much of which is not
"sexually explicit" as those words are normally understood. (Not all speech
that's indecent or patently offensive is about sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>
notwithstanding.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> also observed
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> (ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Writers Union</ENAMEX>) were easily distinguishable from the commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pornographers</ENAMEX> whose dial-a-porn services were at issue in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sable</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>). That's why it's particularly troubling to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX> cite <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sable</ENAMEX>, a case about regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>' access to
commercial pornography, in support of a more general claim that government
has broad power to regulate nonpornographic "indecent" or "sexually explicit"
content in the interest of protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice White</ENAMEX>, writing for the
court in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sable</ENAMEX>, does not go so far. Instead, he relies on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases that, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sable</ENAMEX>, involve pornography and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> never expressly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sable</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has constitutional authority to
regulate--regardless of the medium--the far broader category of speech called
"indecency.")

            These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic legal errors
give rise to other problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX>'s constitutional analysis. Most
notably, he suggests compulsory labeling of online content without mentioning
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> problem of "compelled speech" that clearly would arise, and
without discussing whether such compulsory labeling would be constitutional if
imposed on books and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Medium</ENAMEX>-specific analysis suggests it wouldn't
be, and factual record in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> seems to entail the same
conclusion about compulsory labeling on the Internet.)

            But perhaps the single most
disturbing error in his article has to do with the facts, not the law. In order
to support his thesis that technical solutions will never resolve what he sees
as a perennial "spillover" problem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX> attempts to raise doubts about the
effectiveness of selection/filtering software such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SurfWatch</ENAMEX>:

            
               The
SurfWatch solution is limited by the software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>' ability to keep up
with the latest 'dirty' places. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of Web sites are being added <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, and
you never know what will get posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> even on existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newsgroups</ENAMEX>. Some things will inevitably be missed.
            

            
               The
purely technological fix, then, is less restrictive than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>, but it's also
less effective.
            

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX> implies here
(that filters rely solely or primarily on a list of "dirty places") is wholly
false--not just about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SurfWatch</ENAMEX>, but about filtering software and filtering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paradigms</ENAMEX> generally. We know of no product that operates as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX> suggests
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SurfWatch</ENAMEX> does--while many such programs do include specific lists of
objectionable sites, this is not the primary approach any of these programs
rely on to filter content . This is true even though filtering paradigms may
differ among products: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SurfWatch</ENAMEX> uses multiple approaches, including keyword-
and pattern-matching algorithms; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> uses its "blocked site" list as a
supplement to its core filtering technologies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NewView</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Specs for Kids</ENAMEX>
program, in contrast, doesn't use a "blocking" strategy at all--instead it
reviews and rates sites (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">147,000</NUMEX> as of this writing), and admits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> only to
those pre-approved sites. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SurfWatch</ENAMEX>'s continuing success during a period in
which the total number of Web sites has boomed undercuts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX>'s
generalization about the effect of the boom on these filters' effectiveness.
This makes sense--block the word "sex" in a Web address, and it doesn't matter
if the number of Web addresses including the word "sex" has increased tenfold
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. And it's difficult to see how the effectiveness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Specs</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> approach can be diminished by the boom, even in theory.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX>'s analysis of
filters, together with his mandatory-labeling suggestion, also shows a lack of
awareness of the labeling infrastructure that software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> and the rest of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> industry are increasingly accepting as a standard--the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Platform</ENAMEX> for
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Content Selection</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICS</ENAMEX> was developed by a cross-industry working
group coordinated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web Consortium</ENAMEX>, and is described in the
paper "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PICS: Internet Access Controls Without Censorship</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Resnick</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Miller</ENAMEX>. This paper (to appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACM</ENAMEX> ) as
well as other material on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICS</ENAMEX> can be found on the Web.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICS</ENAMEX> is a set of conventions
that describe formats for labeling Internet content and methods for how labels
are distributed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICS</ENAMEX> does not dictate what the labels should say or how they
should be used. To quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resnick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICS</ENAMEX> is "analogous to specifying
where on a package a label should appear, and in what font it should be
printed, without specifying what it should say."

            The intent of this
flexibility is to support a wide variety of labeling systems and selection
methods. For instance, one might configure a Web browser to screen out material
that carries certain labels. This is the system imagined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX>, but it is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> approach. As an alternative, one might make accessible only those Web
pages that are labeled in a particular way, for example, Web pages that carry
the "seal of approval" of various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. This <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> approach,
functionally similar to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Specs for Kids</ENAMEX>, would address <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX>'s concern
about "keeping up" with new Web sites.

            And these are only the
simplest applications; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICS</ENAMEX> was expressly designed to be an open-ended system
that permits multiple labeling services and multiple ways of using labels;
unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICS</ENAMEX> can be used for purposes other than screening out sexual
or offensive content. In creating a standard for interoperability, the PICS
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">designers</ENAMEX> envisioned the growth of a competitive market in third-party rating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, where the pressures of competition will help assure that current and
future labels are timely and accurate. They also envisioned a competitive
market in selection software, leading to increasingly sophisticated techniques
for using those labels. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resnick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> write:

            
               Around
the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are considering restrictions on on-line content. Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> differ, contexts of use differ, and values differ, blanket
restrictions on distribution can never meet everyone's needs. Selection
software can meet diverse needs, by blocking reception, and labels are the raw
materials for implementing context-specific selection criteria. The
availability of large quantities of labels will also lead to new sorting,
searching, filtering, and organizing tools that help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> surf the Internet
more efficiently.
            

            The free-market evolutionary
approach may not be perfect, but it is counterintuitive to assume, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX>
apparently does, that saddling the system with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>-derived regulations could
make it more effective or efficient. If anything, such a regulation is likely
to have the opposite effect. Imposing a single, federally approved standard for
the kinds of constitutionally protected content that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can banish from
public forums in the name of protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> seems likelier to skew the
market. It would diminish the ability <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> now have to decide for themselves
which solution is most effective. (And the marketplace of ideas wouldn't
exactly be enhanced, either.)

            
Ironically, those who rely on either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX>'s constitutional "spillover"
analysis or his assessment of software filters may feel compelled to craft laws
that ensure we never escape from the "spillover" problem: laws that needlessly
pit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> rights against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s interest in protecting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. That would be a shame, since the technical solutions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dismisses</ENAMEX> carry the promise of avoiding his "spillover" problem altogether.
Thanks to these inexpensive and highly adaptable tools, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important social
interests--the protection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and the preservation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>
rights--need no longer be viewed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> sum game.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Godwinstaff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Frontier Foundation</ENAMEX>

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hal</ENAMEX>
of Technology

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volokh</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godwin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelson</ENAMEX> raise some
interesting legal points. I stand by my legal analysis, which I believe is
based on the most natural reading of the cases; I do not believe I am guilty of
any "basic legal errors" that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godwin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelson</ENAMEX> ascribe to me. I recognize,
though, that reasonable minds can differ on the questions involved here, much
as they generally can with regard to most genuinely contested legal
questions.

            My brief responses to their
points:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. As I mentioned in my
original article, it's true that one of the key
cases-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pacifica</ENAMEX> --contained language that limited it to the broadcasting
medium. But it seems to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sable Communications</ENAMEX> and the relevant
part (Part III) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Consortium</ENAMEX> allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to restrict
speech in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, so long as the restriction is the least restrictive
means of shielding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from improper material. The Internet would, I
think, be no exception.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. My article expressly
pointed out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>'s ban on indecency does indeed apply to more than just
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pornography</ENAMEX>. This is one of the things that troubles me about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>.

            Nonetheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court's decision in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Consortium</ENAMEX> seems to me to firmly stand for
the proposition that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has a compelling interest in shielding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from "indecent" speech: Speech that depicts or describes "sexual or
excretory activities or organs" in "patently offensive terms," whether the speech is pornographic or
not.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s decisions seem
to me to be equally applicable to commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> of indecency and
noncommercial ones. Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> can ultimately be persuaded to draw a
distinction between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>; it would, I think, be an uphill battle, but
perhaps a winnable one, and I wish free-speech hawks all the best on it. I
should note, though, that the recent federal court decision in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shea</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> (released after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godwin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelson</ENAMEX>'s letter was written) rejected such
a distinction--whether rightly or wrongly--in the closely related context of a
vagueness analysis.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> looks at a
rating requirement as a speech compulsion (you must self-rate any indecent
speech) or as a speech restriction (you may not say certain things unless you
self-rate them), a rating requirement is indeed a burden on speech; I don't
believe I suggested the
contrary. But such a burden might still be upheld if it's the least
restrictive means of shielding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. I think one can make a considerably
stronger case on this score for the constitutionality of the rating requirement
than of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> itself. As I mentioned in my original article, I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>
would probably be struck down, but my guess is that some form of self-rating
requirement would probably be upheld.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. As to the factual points
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godwin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelson</ENAMEX> raise, I refer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to my response to the letter from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Friedland</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SurfWatch</ENAMEX>. In that response, I agree that my discussion of
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SurfWatch</ENAMEX> does was an oversimplification--for which I apologize--but
explain why I believe it doesn't appreciably affect the legal analysis: The
other technological alternatives, in my view, will not constitute the "less
restrictive alternatives" needed to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> unconstitutional. (The
earlier
response does not discuss in detail the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, but I believe that the
points it raises are generally applicable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PICS</ENAMEX>.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Finally, as a policy
matter, I am no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>, or even of a rating requirement. My article
focused on whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> was constitutional, not on whether it was wise.
Given the choice, I'd much rather stick with private choice of privately
administered screening mechanisms.

            The heart of my argument,
though, is that none of these alternative mechanisms "carr[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ies</ENAMEX>] the promise of
avoiding [the] spillover problem altogether" (in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godwin's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelson</ENAMEX>'s words).
They doubtless decrease the problem. As I said in the article, they may
decrease it enough to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> unconstitutional: "The best guess seems to
be that the marginal benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> over the technological alternatives is
small enough, and the burden that the law creates is large enough, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>
will be overturned."

            But it
seems to me that the spillover will always be there, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will always
have to make the same "hard choice: sacrifice some shielding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in
order to protect grownups, or sacrifice some access by grownups in order to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">shield</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." Private screening mechanisms may make the choice somewhat
easier; but I'm not persuaded that they can eliminate it entirely.

            
               But We
Got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Price</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in the content
business? Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> hope to buy out the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the journalism field,
or is he trying to do something new here.

            I think the motto that comes
to mind is, "If you can't beat them, buy them." Congratulations, sellouts. You
have done nothing to advance the status quo. You had the opportunity to create
something unique, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> is the same old stuff.

            Your
crime is going for market share, rather than creating a new market. This is not
strange, coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. If only you had the slightest notion of how
demented the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> pushing the Internet is. Buy an upgrade for your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, before it's too late!

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>

            

               Digislate
            

            As a silicon-enhanced
knowledge serf suffering from chronic time-deficit disorder, I just don't seem
to find enough bandwidth in a day to properly digest enlightened journalism,
much less to enjoy a little poetry. But as I slavishly grind away at the
keyboard coding my assigned arcana, I often observe my neuronic (or is it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurotic</ENAMEX>?) operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> engaged in symmetric multitasking.

            Suppose all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>'s
articles featured the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> reading their visionary musings into digital
audio format. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> convenience of a paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that will take the digital
variety a while to match is portability. However the paper variety will never
be able to read itself to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX>.

            Fast-forwarding a bit to see
where this might lead, presume for a moment that the average automobile will
one day be equipped with a cellular-linked PC brain box (global positioning
system included, no extra charge). The proposed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HearSLATE</ENAMEX>" could then offer
discriminating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commuters</ENAMEX> and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> some intellectual refuge from
the endless tirade of mindless drivel currently broadcast by the common
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>.

            In blunt summary (I'm running
out of time), perhaps asking us (the unwashed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>) to shell out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> bucks a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> for the privilege of staring longer at this stinkin' monitor for an hour
or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, when we'd rather bail outta this rotten sweatshop before
the sun goes down, won't be as appealing an expenditure for our meager
discretionary income as say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> or a couple of baseball
game tickets. There's more free stuff available online to fill up the time when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> isn't around than the proxy-censor will ever let us read.

            Give us
some content-rich brainfood stereophonically fed through the audio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> while
our lower cortex is busy arranging electrons on the screen. And so you have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE 's</ENAMEX> suggested revenue-enhancement for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, and as for tomorrow, see
above--and let your imagination run wild.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dilbert</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
