
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mi NASA Es Su NASA</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mi NASA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Es Su NASA</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> seems to have
it wrong when he editorializes while reporting on coverage of cosmonaut Vasily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tsibliev</ENAMEX>'s press conference in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers": "Imagine a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> having the nerve to say such things!
You'll have to, because it's never happened, even when things went as awry as
they did with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX>."

            I guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuger</ENAMEX> doesn't
recall <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Young</ENAMEX> taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to task about flawed decision-making
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> accident. If he'll refresh his memory, he might recall
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>, speaking as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut corps</ENAMEX>, said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX> would refuse to fly until there were significant changes in the
decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.

            I guess
we're so used to our freedoms here that we quickly forget their use.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Andress</ENAMEX>
            

            
               We Got
NeXT
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Jobs</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Totalitarian Vision</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> is too hard on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX> when he
notes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s failure to build a business selling system software rather than
complete computer systems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> business model is an attractive one in
hindsight, but before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, every large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in the industry's
history--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Equipment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>, etc.--had prospered by
selling complete systems. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> was released, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
was dwarfed by both its hardware-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> of popular
applications. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> to understand that his tiny company
could own the link between those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the business, reducing PC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to commodity box-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> and forcing software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> to
compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> applications on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> turf. But as successful as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">system-</ENAMEX>software strategy has been for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, it isn't a panacea; see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s
experience with OS<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>' own experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NeXTStep</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterexamples</ENAMEX>.

            It is
interesting to note what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> gave up in order to pursue a software-only
strategy: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> systems still do not approach the
tight integration and polish of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX>. They don't even know
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> has inserted a floppy disk! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>' hubris was not that he wanted
to own the personal computer business, but that he wanted to sell a product
that was better than anything the industry could put together piecemeal.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews Hanover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don'ts</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Jobs</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Totalitarian Vision</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the finest examples of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> quarterbacking I've ever seen. He states, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>] wanted to make
the computers and the systems that ran them. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Had Apple</ENAMEX> allowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>, perhaps even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> to build hardware running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> OS,
it might very well have seen its software become the industry standard."

            Well,
yes. We all know that now. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, it was taken for granted that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of the computer also designed the operating system. I didn't know
anyone with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> system in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>, but I knew plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">64s</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI 99-4As</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IIs</ENAMEX>, computers by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tandy</ENAMEX>, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timex</ENAMEX>--all
with distinct and incompatible operating systems. This was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the
industry when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> was born. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> realized it would be more efficient
if all computers, regardless of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, ran the same system (which is why
he's the richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>). As obvious as this insight seems <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
though, it wasn't in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX> didn't realize it, my computer nerd
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and I didn't realize it and, I suspect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> didn't realize
it either.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarborough Chicago</ENAMEX>

            
               High
Infidelity
            

            The
premise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "Adultery
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boredom</ENAMEX>" is simply wrong. The allegations against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> are not the contemporary equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX>'s
videotaped escapades on the appropriately named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monkey Business</ENAMEX> . Do you
remember the grainy video of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart</ENAMEX>--stop motion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>, circle
around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rice</ENAMEX>, drinking, fun--that was broadcast for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> on local and national
news programs? Have you seen any such videos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>? In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of public opinion there is no parallel between video and
a bare allegation--something often forgotten by zealous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s conclusion that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are apathetic about infidelity
may be true, but it is totally unsupported by his argument. If anything, the
column merely supports the conclusion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is more careful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Weisberg</ENAMEX> in branding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">scarlet</ENAMEX> letter.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Van Cleef</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               Where
There's Smoke There's Hire
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> is certainly
correct, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Tobacco Whores</ENAMEX>," to condemn the shameless
immorality of liberal ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who have sold their services to the
tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but he fails to properly identify why their actions are
wrong.

            Defending the freedom of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to make dumb decisions is not morally wrong. Whether it is sky diving,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eating Big Macs</ENAMEX>, smoking, or engaging in promiscuous sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be free
to take risks with their own lives. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> of the nanny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> may respond
that society bears some of the costs of these behaviors, but that is the fault
of the health, welfare, and other government programs that protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from
the consequences of foolish behavior.

            No, there
is nothing at all wrong with defending tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. What is immoral,
instead, is taking lots of money to lobby for something you do not believe in.
This is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX>, and all the others deserve the scorn
of principled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of all persuasions.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell The Heritage</ENAMEX> FoundationWashington

            
               True
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Polar Politics</ENAMEX>"
makes us Alaskans out to be a pretty sorry lot. We would "log, mine, and drill
every corner" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. We are an odd collection of "adventurers, loners,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>," as illustrated by a sex crime described in lurid detail. On top of
that, we get huge gobs of money from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> but are not sufficiently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grateful</ENAMEX>.

            We do have our share of
"loners and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>," but most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskans</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and jobs, go to churches
or synagogues, and are the same as the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> except for having to
dress warmer. We have chosen to live in a beautiful place where some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s most scenic areas have been closed to mining and oil development
forever. But thanks to advances in mining and petroleum technology, other areas
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> can be safely developed, leaving only a minuscule "footprint" on
the environment.

            As for federal spending in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, keep in mind that you will get skewed statistics on a per capita basis
when you are dealing with a small "capita." The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is the
outright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of most of the land in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> and has financial responsibilities
the same as any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX>. Add to that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>'s strategic position in a
world where the threat comes increasingly from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, and you can see that the
money spent here on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is hardly a boondoggle dreamed up by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>. In addition, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> spends a large amount of money on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>. It would certainly save money not to deliver mail to
scores of isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> that can only be reached by air, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">natives</ENAMEX> hardly intend to apologize for living in their ancestral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.

            Sensible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">environmentalism</ENAMEX> deserves everyone's support, and gets it up here.
Environmentalism as a secular religion, though, is another matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alaskans</ENAMEX> will never satisfy those who believe that the only good development is
no development. Those with a more rational view, however, have been and will be
accommodated.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX>
Berkowitz <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anchorage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
