
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               The Case
Against the Case Against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Against Microsoft</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Case Against the Case</ENAMEX>
Against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Rule</ENAMEX> wrote: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ore</ENAMEX> convenient, seamless access to
the Internet from the desktop will help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to use the Internet. It is hard
to see any anti-competitive danger that justifies denying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> these
benefits."

            I
completely disagree with the implication and reasoning here. It is the purpose
of antitrust law to look to the future. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is giving away Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX> now, but who thinks they would have acted this way if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> had
not existed? Would <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> have added such rich features if they were not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emulating Netscape</ENAMEX>? I think that industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> know the answer is no. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> can eliminate their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>'s viability by flooding the market
with a free product, the long-term result for the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will be a loss.
The whole point of this area of law is to examine such patterns. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX>'s idea
were right, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, which, for example, flood the
chip market with underpriced products, would simply be acting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>'s
interest, even if they are seeking a stranglehold on the market. The challenge
of antitrust law is to grapple with such questions.

            -- Rhett
Savage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>

            
               PC OS
BS
            

            I found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Rule</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Case Against the Case</ENAMEX>
Against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>" to be an insulting farce. There are numerous misleading
statements that, to me, demonstrate a merely superficial understanding of the
situation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s rise to prominence as being a result of
an economic phenomenon known as "network externalities." I believe that
although he understands the economic phenomenon, he completely ignores how
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> relates to it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> dominates the PC
operating system market. The next paradigm shift was supposed to be the
emergence of the Internet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is leveraging the power it has in the PC
OS market in order to minimize the damage to its core business (the Windows
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">software</ENAMEX>). How is this possible? Well, browsers are not full-fledged operating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>. They were never intended to be the software that gives fundamental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directions</ENAMEX> to a PC, and I doubt that they ever will be. They still run as
another layer on top of the PC OS, the most dominant of which is Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>.
Rule mentions that browser software is already--or in the near future will
be--competing with the OS market, and he interprets that to mean that the OS
and the browser are the same in a functional sense.

            That is false ! The
browser software circumvents OS considerations by having a common interface no
matter what OS you're using. That was the beauty of it (and the nightmare in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' mind, because you don't have to be running Windows software to run
it). You could be using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEC</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sparc Workstation</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>, or a PC, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> is still Netscape. It works the same and is compatible with Netscape
running on another system. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is trying to do is latch a separate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">functionality</ENAMEX> (Internet functionality) onto its existing OS, and claim it is a
modification of the OS. How intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can buy that argument is beyond
me. As far as I understood it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> didn't run on my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>. Windows didn't run
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sparc</ENAMEX>. Yet now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS IE</ENAMEX> will run on my non-PC computer? Do the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> products
sound even vaguely similar? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Rule</ENAMEX>, you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> for buying that argument.
It is this very basic misunderstanding that allows you to delve into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>-speak arguments as to why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> is just a maligned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>.

            Through a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decade</ENAMEX> of good luck and leveraging its lead in the PC OS market, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has
unfairly eliminated competition. The only real test that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has faced
in recent memory is due to the emergence of the Internet, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is once
again trying to eliminate this threat unfairly. Shame on you for defending this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unfairness</ENAMEX>.

            -- Venkatesh
Abboy
            

            
               Shrink
Rap
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larissa MacFarquhar</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diagnosis: Totally</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sane</ENAMEX>," on criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> , does a nice job of answering
frequently leveled charges. However, she did neglect to mention a more
interesting controversy within the mental-health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> regarding the nature
of diagnosis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> is a categorical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>--either ya got it or ya
don't. However, many mental-health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> argue that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dimensional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model makes</ENAMEX> more sense and would more closely mirror the
real world. Of course, such a diagnostic system may prove to be more unwieldy
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> and to annoy insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (who hold frightening sway over all
health-care endeavors), and it is politically unlikely that such a dramatic
shift will occur any time in the near future.

            I must also take exception
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacFarquhar</ENAMEX>'s use of the term "disease" in referring to mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX>.
By definition, a disease is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that has a known etiology, and as
she noted early in her article, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> avoids such issues, choosing to
focus almost exclusively on description. Mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> should not be
considered "diseases," though many may have some biological underpinnings.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laypersons</ENAMEX> should realize that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> and its diagnostic categories are
a human construction, created in order to describe the variety of human
emotional and mental disturbances. Such a system provides mental-health
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>--who, in addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX>, include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>, social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and a number of other disciplines--with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a common language by which
they may communicate with one another and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a logical starting point for
therapeutic intervention. Without some guiding framework (even a framework
troubled by more political maneuvering than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacFarquhar</ENAMEX> reported),
mental-health work would be an intellectual wilderness.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tabacchi</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
