
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Don't
Believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hype</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cullen Murphy</ENAMEX> is so good
that it really stands out when he blows it, as he does in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too Much of a Good</ENAMEX>
Thing." Hype derives from hyperbole , and when it came into
use in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, it was used, in much the way overhyped is used <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
to refer to something praised far in excess of its value (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Sergeant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX> has been hyped as a masterpiece, but the fact is, most of the songs
on it aren't of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> rank").

            Once the provenance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hype</ENAMEX> has been established, you can discard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>'s elaborate apparatus
for explaining overhyped . That ghastly neologism is just the latest
example of the peculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tendency toward tautological idioms. Similar
excrescences include: preplanning and its business familiar, advance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX> (when the heck else are you going to plan something--after the
fact?); and my own special hate, self-confessed (if someone else is
doing your confessing for you, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, it ain't a confession). Yes, yes, I
understand that self-confessed follows the path laid down by perfectly
acceptable terms like self-professed and self-avowed ; I still
hate it.

            Well, I'm
glad that's straightened out.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>
Collingwood <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Cullen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris Collingwood</ENAMEX>'s letter is one of many I have received that
would derive hype from hyperbole rather than more circuitously
from the hype derived from hypodermic , and thus from the idea of
stimulation associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. I stand my ground, though. Yes, at first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glance</ENAMEX>, this alternative derivation would seem to make sense, because hype
sort of sounds like hyperbole and sort of means hyperbole . It
would also seem to make sense that frosh would be derived from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">freshman</ENAMEX> , since it sort of sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> and sort of means
freshman . But it isn't.
            

            Hype in the sense of
excessive or false publicity goes back much further than the 1960s
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collingwood's</ENAMEX> suggested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> of origin)--to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least the 1920s</TIMEX> (per the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX> ), which is the same time that hype is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attested</ENAMEX> to as a verb and noun associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, and the word is
explicitly linked to hypodermic . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Slang</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barnhart Dictionary of New English</ENAMEX> , and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House Historical Dictionary of American Slang</ENAMEX> all make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypodermic</ENAMEX> connection. None of them makes a hyperbole connection.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Political Dictionary</ENAMEX> writes: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Investing a</ENAMEX>
minor occurrence with false importance is called 'hype' or 'media hype,' from
the euphoric kick one gets from an injection of a narcotic with a hypodermic
needle."
            

            
               I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.E. Lighter</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> Historical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of American Slang</ENAMEX>
(whose volume containing "H" words has just been published), about the
possibility that hype was derived from hyperbole . His immediate
response was, "I very much doubt that." He went on to note that "hyperbole
comes from a rather elevated level of diction for the kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
begin using the word hype ." He did observe that the existence of the
word hyperbole could well be offering hype a certain
reinforcement. "Once a word comes into circulation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lighter</ENAMEX> said, "its
survival is based in part on all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> it brings to
mind."
            

            

               ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frosh</ENAMEX> , by the way, seems to have come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> for "frog"--it
was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> nickname for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of an entering class of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jingoistic Java Juggernaut</ENAMEX>
            

            I am very disappointed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Shuman</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weak Java</ENAMEX>." If you want to look like a propaganda organ of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, about the best thing you could do would be to publish an article
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a very hotly contested industry issue, take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s side, and support
your point with misinformation and untruths.

            The most egregious example
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuman</ENAMEX>'s statement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>'s plan to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> faster is to make "Java
into an operating system." This is entirely and totally wrong, and anyone
paying any attention to what's going on with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> would know this. I am really
appalled.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is
certainly free to come out on any side of any issue, but when it comes to an
issue in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has a huge financial stake, I think the least we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> can ask is that you take care to learn the basic facts of the matter
and check that what's in the article is at least remotely plausible.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weinreb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuman</ENAMEX> replies: This letter is one of the nicer ones I have received in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two weeks</TIMEX>. I had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> goals for my article: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, to explain what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> is;
and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, to debunk the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> hype. I can only gather by the voluminous
responses to my article that I was successful in touching a few nerves. I would
like to quote myself on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> seem to have overlooked: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) "I work
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>" and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> is cool."
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> off, to all you
speed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX> who claim <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> will soon be as fast as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/C++</ENAMEX> and who rightly point
to some of the work on making <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX> much faster: You are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-right. There is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal of effort afoot to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> faster (just-in-time compilation,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX>-code generation, etc.). However <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> will never be as fast as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">straight C/C++</ENAMEX>; there are too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX> features of the language (garbage
collection, array-and-string bounds checking, dynamically loaded classes) for
it to ever be as fast as raw <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/C++</ENAMEX>. Yes, I agree that the differences will
shrink, but they will still be with us. Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> will never work well
on more memory-constrained systems because of the large overhead of these
features. I apologize for having the wrong ratio in how slow current Java
implementations are. It is indeed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> times as slow as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> code,
not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> times slower as I stated.
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>:
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have pointed out how great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> is; I agree! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> makes code
easier to write, but at a cost--and that cost will always be with us.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> should rightly be compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Visual Basic</ENAMEX> and other tools meant for rapid
development of applications. It should not be compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/C++</ENAMEX>, however.
This is the comparison most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Java</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> make; therefore, it was the comparison
I chose to highlight. I have not found any examples of truly complicated robust
applications written in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX>. The only thing that came close was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corel</ENAMEX>'s office
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suite</ENAMEX>, and it was w-a<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-y t-o-o s-l-o-w.</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Monologue
            

            I was
under the impression that the purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s dialogues was to allow two
well-informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with opposing views to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duke</ENAMEX> out a topic at length. Why,
then, in your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Promise Keepers "Dialogue</ENAMEX>," have you chosen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX> to
face off on the burning question "Are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> totally wonderful, or
only mostly wonderful?" The last time I checked, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate voters</ENAMEX>
were taking the position that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> are not a healthy phenomenon.
Maybe their side should be represented in the discussion.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dexter Emmaus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>

            
               I Ain't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonna Work on Marlboro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm</ENAMEX> No More
            

            In
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smokey and the Bandits</ENAMEX>," I agree with most of the points, but it
seems to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Chapman</ENAMEX> ignores the fundamental dilemma of the tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>. If he's living on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 acres</NUMEX> surrounded by other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, just
how does he change his <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX>? He needs more land. He can only buy it from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, thereby putting them out of business. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way or another many
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> are forced out of their livelihood.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Allen Mountain</ENAMEX>
View, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religious Extremists</ENAMEX>
            

            
Congratulations to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> on "Extreme
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prejudice</ENAMEX>," a terrific piece on the lunacy associated with "extreme"
activities. The inordinate attention granted to these activities by the
advertising-driven media is merely another symptom of the triumph of form over
substance that characterizes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> in this nonsense
have lost their ability to enjoy physical activities just for fun and the
satisfaction derived from a good, hard workout. They feed their resultant
emptiness with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">manic</TIMEX>, life-threatening, competitive pursuits that become
substitutes for their sense of self worth. These sorts of things once seemed to
be restricted to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dorks</ENAMEX> going through midlife
crises. Now it seems that the disease has cut a swath through a much broader
sector of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, and no longer requires testosterone poisoning as a
condition of entry.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Proulx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Media</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Media</ENAMEX> 0
            

            All of a
sudden the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> bore me to tears. They sit
on my nightstand until I chuck them. I just figured out that it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
fault. Every issue is interesting; I read every article. Your links are
wonderful. Most of my bookmarks are Slate links that I would never have thought
to look for otherwise. Thank you.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingrid Peters</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
