
   
   
      
         
            I <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have Seen the Millennium, and It Works</ENAMEX>.

            Since plans for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium Dome</ENAMEX> began to take shape <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, condemnation has poured in from
all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>. Left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are appalled at the waste of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> that
could have gone toward housing and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health Service</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX>
object to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s attempt to present <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> as a modern,
multicultural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> instead of a tradition-bound, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. With the help
of constant attacks from all sides, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>'s approval rating fell to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
percent in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recent poll--lower than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>'s, or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>'s. The
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> who don't heap scorn on it are those who complain they're
too tired of the topic to talk about it.

            On the
chance that something so despised might deserve defending, I put on a hard hat
and rubber boots and went to look at the construction site in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>, just
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. (Because the world's clocks are fixed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>
Mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>, this is the spot where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> can be argued to officially
debut.) As I <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> suspected, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> is better than advertised. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>,
it is stunning. As the site of the main international event of the Year <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>,
it may or may not succeed. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> has at least a chance to follow in the
path of its illustrious <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> ancestors, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal Palace</ENAMEX> exhibition of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1851</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>. Those events, too, were derided in
advance as wasteful and stupid. But they are remembered now as monumental
expressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> identity and historical moment.

            As a feat of architecture, engineering, and urban renewal,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> is already close to being a success. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> government
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> conceived of the project, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> was officially opposed before it took
power, so until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, no one knew what would happen. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> decided to
make the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> a kind of signature for "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Labor</ENAMEX>," there were just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
to plan and build one of the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> on earth--on a contaminated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gasworks</ENAMEX> site. Before construction could begin, the ground below literally had
to be washed to remove cyanide and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arsenic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Engineers</ENAMEX> then went about raising a
room of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nearly a million square feet</NUMEX>. This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> so huge that,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Day</ENAMEX>, the retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> who gave me a tour, weather
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> would form inside if not for the high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiberglass</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teflon</ENAMEX> double
skin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day</ENAMEX> suggests that winter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> will want to bring overcoats and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brandy</ENAMEX>
flasks, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is simply too big to heat (though I suspect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brits</ENAMEX> like it that way).

            Even if
the exhibition fails to draw the hoped-for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, it will be
responsible for turning <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of acres</NUMEX> of industrial wasteland into a lovely
spot on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX> linked to the rest of the metropolis by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underground</ENAMEX>.
This follows the urban planning ideas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rogers</ENAMEX>, who is responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX> believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
like many of the world's great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, is being undone by traffic and unplanned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sprawl</ENAMEX>. He argues in a recent book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cities</ENAMEX> for a Small <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet</ENAMEX> , that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> is to reduce car traffic; develop new neighborhoods for
mixed use; and convert the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s greatest natural asset, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX> riverbank,
into public space. If successful, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> will make the case for pursuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>' grander vision--turning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames Embankment</ENAMEX>, now a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> along the
river, into a grand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>.

            
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>' best-known <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, the Pompidou
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> is drawn in brilliant color, which jumps out against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> drab like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brightly frosted cake</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>'s
other hallmark, of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lloyd's</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> is the leading
example, is for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to show how it works, exposing its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX>,
ventilation pipes, and structural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girders</ENAMEX>. You can see, at a glance from the
outside, how the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome stands</ENAMEX> up. Its huge tent is sustained by brilliant yellow
tent poles, nearly <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 feet</NUMEX> high and stitched together with steel cables. From
the overlooking hill of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenwich Royal Observatory</ENAMEX>, the structure looks
like a whimsical sea <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> that crawled out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> fault of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>' other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> is that they don't age well--many of the better known
ones have an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '80s</TIMEX>, "new wave" look. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> has the advantage of
being temporary. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX> exhibition will last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and though the
structure may be converted to another use, it's only supposed to last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            The tent
is beautiful empty--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hockney</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>, was recently quoted proposing
that it be left that way. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> may privately
share that wish. Almost every decision about how to fill the space has aroused
controversy. The most ridiculed proposal is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Body</ENAMEX>," a gargantuan naked human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can walk through, observing the operation of the internal organs as in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome Person</ENAMEX> unsexed on the exterior seems overly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prudish</ENAMEX>. But the alternative of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brobdingnagian</ENAMEX> genitalia and python-size pubic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hairs</ENAMEX> could be hard to stomach, even after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report.

            The greatest challenge may be the least futuristic part of
the exhibition--the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Identity</ENAMEX>" section, for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> has
yet to announce any kind of plan. In deciding what to put here, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> will be
describing itself to the world. In previous great exhibitions, this was a less
complicated issue. At the dawn of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1851</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
was an imperial power with a unitary culture. A great exhibition was a chance
to dazzle with what it could make and build, beginning with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and iron
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal Palace</ENAMEX> itself, a marvel of early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> engineering. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>
Festival of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> (organized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> now in
charge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Millennium Dome</ENAMEX>) still represented a culturally homogenous,
industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It displayed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-made things, heralding
the emergence from wartime rationing into postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumerism</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> is increasingly an immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> with an emerging postindustrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. It depends far more on the export of services and its culture than it
does on its goods. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has invested its prestige in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>
because it sees it as an opportunity to convey this new social and economic
reality.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Mandelson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in charge of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> project, was lampooned for traveling to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> in search of ideas. But an excess of popular appeal is less likely
than an overinfusion of centrist political ideology. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> loves to say that he
sees <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> as a dynamic, forward-looking, and multicultural society.
Laborites talk unblushingly about "re-branding" the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Labor</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dome</ENAMEX> is a great marketing opportunity. Which makes it, in a way, an authentic
expression of the spirit of the age.

         
      
   
