
   
   
      
         
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wharton</ENAMEX>@mount.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
henjam@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>; listserv@deadauthorsguild.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cc:</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>--or,
better, don't

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cher</ENAMEX>

               Maître ,

            Saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wings of the Dove</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> & was very impressed. So that was what it was all about! Your
writing has no bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EW</ENAMEX>, but I must admit to finding some of the
later novels a bit, shall we say, murky . Large & charming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cineplex Odeon</ENAMEX>--the young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldorf Astors</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balfour</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ld & Lady Elcho</ENAMEX>,
Dcess of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Essex</ENAMEX>, &c. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&c</ENAMEX>. All seemed delighted but for
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teddy</ENAMEX>, who ran screaming from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> reel--his
nerves, no doubt. Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonham Carter</ENAMEX> was splendid . She ought to play
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily Barth</ENAMEX> if The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Mirth</ENAMEX> ever makes it out of turnaround. Is it
true they're giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Merchant</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX> treatment to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Bowl</ENAMEX> ?
Can't say I ever made it quite to the end of that one either.

            Have you
looked over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Library</ENAMEX> list yet? As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scribner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, neither of us is
likely to find much favor in a list of books sold by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cerf</ENAMEX>. Still, I fear
that to the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> we must represent the literary equivalent of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">tufted</ENAMEX> furniture and gas chandeliers. Ulysses , alas, is No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Have you
driven into this fog? It's a turgid welter of pornography (the rudest schoolboy
kind) & uninformed & unimportant drivel. The ingredients of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> do not
make soup without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>'s intervention. The same goes for Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerouac</ENAMEX>.

            Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devoted Edith</ENAMEX>

            ******

            
               From:
henjam@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wharton</ENAMEX>@mount.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>; listserv@deadauthorsguild.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cc:</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100</ENAMEX>
romans
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dearest Edith</ENAMEX>,

            The drab unblinking question
that presents itself is that "compilation" to which you refer, whose arrival,
though unwelcome, is in no way resistible. Of the part that is mine to pass
over in silence is perhaps the course both of humility and of humilité .
That the number of my own works chosen should be trois is a matter for
neither protestation nor ingratitude. Yet that such an ordering hardly induces
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the aforementioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">trois</ENAMEX> such satisfaction as might be
hoped to accrue to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> looking down with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympian</ENAMEX> detachment from beyond the
vale of longevity is a statement the validity of which cannot be called readily
into question. It is unlikely to fail to play upon the suspicions of such a one
that the composition of his most highly esteemed should be that most lately
converted into a wan cinematic confection of fretsome abbreviation. Neither,
however, could a figure such as he neglect the observation that the personage
with whom the former is now abstractly in conversation was accorded the merit
of only dues livres , and that those due were accorded a position
more terrestrial, which is to say well below those of the former on the "list."
Such a "point," once made, could not resist the tendency to instill feelings of
"envy" and ressentiment on the part of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> perhaps better
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compensated</ENAMEX> and perhaps more "popular," but in the view of the critical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>--if any such fitful and discredited light may still be conceived
as being within our sphere--not really as good as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>. Thus it is an
expression of both discretion and a great humble reverence for the feelings of
others to leave such a "point" unmade and unwinced at.

            Though it
may be additionally unpenworthy, there is another "point" that heavily impels
making . It is that of all the volumes, some eminent, some too much
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">esteemed</ENAMEX> in the trail of "fashion," there is one included that so transgresses
the hesitational boundary of propriety as to induce a feeling of stammering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dyspepsia</ENAMEX>. Attention is called to the uncouth Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>, whose effluviations are
so juvenalianly unspeakable that I cannot bear to utter their "title." This
work , it cannot be refrained from being pointed out, has as its chief
topic that exercise that in our own great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">palmy day</TIMEX> was considered least worthy
of writerly elucidation. That this basely erotic occupation that was to our own
contemporaries so unsupportable should form the core of the work in
question might be thought to constitute a disqualification. To such vulgarian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depths</ENAMEX> does this "fascination" descend that there is in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place depicted an
act of rank unsalubrious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> between him and a comestible whose
ingestion by familial others is ineluctably and tenebrously foreordained. I
speak here of the "liver" scene. For a work whose "climax" depends on feelings
of the most passionate revulsion to be esteemed ahead of your own labors, so
far superior as to be undeserving of inclusion in the same tormented sentence,
is, my dearest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith</ENAMEX>, an insult insufferable to all whose reverence for
literature anglais is to be warranted. To commiserate against so great
and gaping an injustice presents itself as a course of action perhaps less
unwise than others.

            Yours faithfully fond,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Henri</ENAMEX>

            ******

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gatsby</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigy</ENAMEX>.net

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wharton</ENAMEX>@mount.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cc:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ernie</ENAMEX>@erols.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>; listserv@deadauthorsguild.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: What did I
win?

            Dear Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wharton</ENAMEX>,

            This is
the first I've heard about a prize. Pardon me for asking, but is there by any
chance some money attached to it? Also, please forgive me for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>color
stories I told at <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bordello</ENAMEX> went a little far, I think. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelda</ENAMEX> and I may have had a few too many
before stopping by.

            Mirthfully, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>

            ******

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ernie</ENAMEX>@erols.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gatsby</ENAMEX>@<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigy</ENAMEX>.net

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cc:</ENAMEX>
faulk@snopes.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noedu</ENAMEX>; listserv@deadauthorsguild.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Re: Listing</ENAMEX>
slightly

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Scott</ENAMEX>,

            I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Key West</ENAMEX> when I got
a copy of your message. I have a place down there in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Key West</ENAMEX>. It's a small
place but a good place. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and when it rains the
cats all come inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> is named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hem</ENAMEX>. There are some
smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, too, with names like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherwood</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dos</ENAMEX>." The big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat</ENAMEX> is bigger than the others and also braver and probably a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. But
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know any better think the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are pretty cute.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> I'll put them in a bag and drown them in the river for their own
good.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> drink
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, but we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink rum</ENAMEX>. It's not very good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX>, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX>
is the drink to drink so we drink it. Sometimes we mix the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rum</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> and
sometimes we don't mix it with anything, depending on how thirsty we are. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rum</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>, but not if you're thirsty. If you're thirsty, you
want <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, but never <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>. Here's 400 bucks. You can pay me when you
see me, unless I see you first.

            Hell, you
were saying something about a list. I couldn't quite make out what you were
saying, but I knew it was about a list. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>, a list is a fine thing if you're
young, and you're high up on it. But when you're a little older and not so high
up you see that the list is just a list and that's all it is.

            Yours always--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernesto</ENAMEX>

            ******

            
               From:
faulk@snopes.<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">noedu To: ernie@erols</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com Cc: gatsby@hotmail.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>;
listserv@deadauthorsguild.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org Re:</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ernest</ENAMEX>,

            Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can be cured
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, drink, gambling, biting his nails, and picking his nose, but not of
making lists. I'm not giving it another moment's thought on account of I'm too
busy writing my novels, and if somebody wants to read one of them instead of
sipping a whisky highball and kicking back in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adirondack</ENAMEX> chair or an
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-dollar swivel chair or a pig iron porch swing covered in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty-cent</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montgomery Ward</ENAMEX> paint from a paintcan he keeps on a ledge in the fallingdown
barn where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been begetting quadroons and octaroons and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sixteentharoons</ENAMEX> and thirtysecondaroons since the time before they thought to
write it down, that's nobody's business but his own. I've got only one
complaint for you to please pass along to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. My handwriting may not
be all handwriting should be, especially after lunch, but even a county court
judge drunk at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> ought to be able to read a title straight. So please tell
those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> it's not Light in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> but Fightin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> ,
for godsakes.

            Let's get
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soused</ENAMEX> again sometime soon,

            Yours, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>

            P.S. Mailer is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX>
on a tight budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Styron</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> on no budget at all.

            ******

            
               From:
mailer@daemon.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> To: faulk@snopes.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">noedu Cc</ENAMEX>:
listserv@deadauthorsguild.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insult</ENAMEX> as e-mail; the e-mail as
insult

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> had always thought
highly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX>. Once, when he was younger, he had read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s
As I Lay Dying cover to cover. Privately, he had found it a bit
confusing. Why was the mother a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>? But he knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought it was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fine</ENAMEX> novel, and he resented that he hadn't written it himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> was a
Southerner, probably a racist, and hard to understand. Mailer was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish New</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>, beloved by black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and a comparatively easy read (not to mention
a fine lay). Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX> thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> were a lot alike. Both
were great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>--between them they had written many of the best <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
novels of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. Both drank, heavily at times; liked to
get paid for what they wrote; and had contempt for lesser talents. Mailer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thought Faulkner</ENAMEX> thought highly of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> as well--maybe as highly as Mailer
did himself.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> had sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>
every book he had ever written, all with flattering inscriptions, and never
received so much as a thank-you. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX> suspected that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> had read them
all and wished he had written them himself. Possibly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> had never so
much as looked at them. He had heard somewhere that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> had died. Still,
Mailer was irked. He felt that it had all been a big literary game. Mailer was
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> literature, but he privately wondered whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">posterity</ENAMEX> might not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jakes</ENAMEX> a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>, sources
close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX> tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX>.

            So to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> on
a budget by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> angry. It made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mailer</ENAMEX> very, very angry. So
angry did Mailer become that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX> took the big picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> that hangs
over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX>'s desk and smashed it into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> pieces. After he did that,
there were just pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> hanging there. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> recognized that this
reaction was not very mature, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX> had bigger things to worry about than
minding his literary manners. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> didn't understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were treating
him like a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, either. Just recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> had published his
autobiography and a book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> had the inspired idea to combine
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> in one book. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Faulkner</ENAMEX> never had an idea that good, or if
he did, no one could understand it.

            Mailer
thought to himself that next time he saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>, he would probably sock him
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the kisser. No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX> thought, the next time he ran into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> at a
swanky literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, he would return <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s insult with his usual witty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insouciance</ENAMEX>. Mailer hated those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, but he hardly ever missed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. "Your
books stink," Mailer imagined himself saying. "Mailer can't understand a word
of them."

            ******

            
               From:
dharmabum@nirvana.net To: mailer@daemon.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>;
listserv@deadauthorsguild.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org Cc:</ENAMEX> beats@evillage.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com Re</ENAMEX>: On the
list

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX>,

            Easy on the benzedrine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
Me, I was just pleased to be on that list with famouswriters like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul Bowles</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Golding</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX> was on there too. It made me think
about the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> and I went to see him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>.

            I came in by Greyhoundbus
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>. It was an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Greyhoudbus</ENAMEX> with runaways and oldfolk and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greyhoundbusdriver</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greyhoundbusdriver</ENAMEX>'s cap not saying much of
anything but just driving the bus toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> didn't have the busfare so
he hotwired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, not to steal it, but just to ride ride ride for the thrill
of it like some magnificent highflying parkpigeon. Along the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> had
married or maybe just kidnapped a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX>-extracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenosha</ENAMEX>
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inga</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inga</ENAMEX> had blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curls</ENAMEX> and beefy arms like a stevedore and was
excited about seeing the bigcity but said she wanted to go home and was going
to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> if he didn't take her. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> should have been worried about
Inga being jailbait but at that point he was pretty focused on medieval
literature, and kept on reciting passages from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaucer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Cid</ENAMEX> and
talking about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giotto</ENAMEX> was a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>, nokidding.

            We were crashing at a cold
water flat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South</ENAMEX> side with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chihuahuas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chihuahuas</ENAMEX> had been shaved real close to the skin, so there
wasn't much to them, just a lot of pointy ears and dogyapping. They must have
been pretty cold in those <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> and when they were hungry they'd claw at
your shins. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> wanted to invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marylou</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie Engels</ENAMEX> over
for a sexorgy but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> was out of chihuahuafood, so before we could do
that, we had to get something for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> to eat.

            As soon as we stepped outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, a cruiser spotted us and tailed after us at a slow
crawl down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> had ditched his freebuick, but apparently we looked
like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hipsters</ENAMEX> who had pulled off a jewelry heist downtown. They didn't
stop us on suspicion, but just kept tailing us at a distance which made us
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twitchy</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inga</ENAMEX> kept saying she was going to turn us in for being hopheads
and whiteslavers and a lot of other stuff I couldn't understand because it was
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX>. We knew they were cops because they had copuniforms and were
driving a copcar. So we stopped in a dark dingy old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side tavern</ENAMEX> to think
over our plans and have some coldbeers.

            When we
came out of there, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inga</ENAMEX> had split and we realized we were on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> Street.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> Street shoots out West for an amazing distance, which is where we were
headed, so we hijacked a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>-whipped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>, wham, and made
straight for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joliet</ENAMEX>. As we were riding through the sweetsmelling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> looked up from the book he was reading, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les aventures de la</ENAMEX>
dialectique , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Merleau-Ponty</ENAMEX>, which he had lifted from the
philosophy section of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kroch's & Brentano's in the Loop</ENAMEX>. He turned to me and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> who was wearing a lettucepicking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> and a red
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bandanna</ENAMEX> tied around his mouth and said, "Oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, we completely forgot to go
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>." And now we're all on the same list of goodbooks. I'm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sohappy</ENAMEX>.

            As ever, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>

            ******

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">virginia</ENAMEX>@bloomsbury.net To: dharmabum@nirvana.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">net Cc</ENAMEX>:
bloomsburygroup@bloomsbury.net; listerv@deadauthorsguild.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: Who's
afraid of V <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>?

            My dear Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerouac</ENAMEX>,

            Yes, of course I too am
pleased to be on the list. All these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last several decades</TIMEX> I have been
overwhelmed with feelings of horror & despair; annihilation; nothingness;
barrenness & void. One could say that I have been in a poor mood. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lighthouse</ENAMEX> to place fifteenth provides a moment of cheer, for it proves
that someone has indeed read to the end of it.

            But a moment of cheer quickly
passes. What after all is a list? A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> books; perhaps seventy-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>;
perhaps only fifty. The end of each arrives, and soon another book is
published, a book is reviewed, more books appear. List succeeds list. Lists
turn into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>. Some of these books are borrowed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>. These
books seethe with plots; with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>; with life & suspense. In other
books, little occurs. A group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> goes somewhere; or does not go
somewhere; or contemplates going somewhere but delays the decision about
whether to go. The words fly past; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> words; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred</NUMEX> words; one
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand five hundred</NUMEX> words; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> words. The words turn into pages: one
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> pages; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> pages; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> pages; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> pages. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alphabet</ENAMEX> is recounted. B follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. D</ENAMEX> is preceded by C; then comes E; then F;
then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>; then H; then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. If L</ENAMEX> could be reached, that would be something. But L
is very hard to attain; very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the whole of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> ever attain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX>
Not many even get so far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX> And what of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>, and the murky letters which
follow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>, which include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>? Who can even speak of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>, which shimmers at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> end of the alphabet, scarcely visible from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> When I think of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>, an
image comes into my head that I am powerless to resist: it is the cross section
of a mackerel.

            Please
forgive my digression--what else can one call it, except perhaps
"maundering"--which has made me forget entirely what I had been about to tell
you! It is nothing of importance! Perhaps something about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vanessa</ENAMEX>; or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lytton</ENAMEX>;
or Vita; or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Ottoline</ENAMEX>; or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX>, who as I write pursues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duncan</ENAMEX> around the
garden with lust in his heart & a croquet mallet. Such gossip pales beside
this "maundering," this reverie for which I am intensely thankful; for nothing
so solaces me, calms me in the perplexity of life, and miraculously raises its
burdens, as this sublime power, this divine talent for writing endlessly about
hardly anything at all, & one should no more interrupt it, while it lasts
than one should break the crockery in one's home and leave the shards lying on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen floor</ENAMEX> for no reason. Though yes, I have done that at times as
well.

            Write if you
find work, V

         
      
   
