
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Gaul-ic
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bread</ENAMEX>
            

            I thoroughly enjoyed reading
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unmitigated</ENAMEX>
Gauls," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> thinking, but I
would quibble with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point.

            Krugman
mentions in passing that a unified (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>) market and a common currency
"will do almost nothing to create jobs." In fact, one way or the other EMU
matters a lot for jobs. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> stick to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMU</ENAMEX>'s monetary and fiscal
rules the policy stance will be on the tight side, i.e., cyclical unemployment
will go up, or at least will not fall. If, in addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> reduce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rigidities</ENAMEX> (particularly in the labor market), the initial consequence will be
a rise in unemployment, followed by an improvement with a delay of a couple of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>, for example). Should
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> ignore EMU rules and take it easy once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMU</ENAMEX> has started, cyclical
unemployment may fall initially, but at some stage higher inflation and a
depreciating euro would force a course correction, and unemployment would rise
again.

            -- Gunther
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thumann London</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> replies: A common currency per se has got nothing much to do with
employment; the rules of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maastricht</ENAMEX>, which bear a dubious relationship to the
actual requirements of such a currency, are another matter.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>
Banal-ytica
            

            Although "Why Do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bother?</ENAMEX>" by the anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Analytica</ENAMEX> was just chock-full of
silly blather about globalization, I was particularly struck by the vacuousness
of this sentence: "The liberalization of trade also effectively prevents
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> from erecting protective barriers to boost the domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>."

            "The
liberalization of trade," by definition, is precisely the lack of protective
barriers like tariffs and import quotas. Although I'm sure it's true that a
lack of protective barriers leads inexorably to a lack of protective barriers,
this is hardly a profound insight. At least I can be thankful that I'm reading
this for free in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, rather than paying big bucks for the wisdom of these
international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Susin Berkeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schneider Retort</ENAMEX>
            

            Please tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Goldberg</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News You Can't</ENAMEX>
Use") to log off. He's obviously spending too much time online. That's the
only explanation I have for his weak attempt at reviewing/satirizing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX>-news wars. Did this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> ever watch more than a minute or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the
programs he panned? If he had, he certainly would have noticed that the program
I anchor and edit on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Channel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Schneider Report</ENAMEX> , is a
serious news program. We feature extensive coverage of the major issues each
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, and devote more time to international news than any of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. You can look it up. Or, better yet, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>, you
could watch!

            By the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, if not showing up in gossip columns or fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> makes me, or my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, "distinctly unfamous," I'll wear that title proudly. I'm just a guy
with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years</TIMEX> of TV news experience, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of them anchoring network programs like
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekend Today</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Morning America</ENAMEX> news. Who the hell
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Goldberg</ENAMEX>, anyway?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike SchneiderThe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schneider Report Fox News ChannelNew York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Prose and
Cons
            

            In "The
Conintern," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> implies there is a rigid conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>
that squelches dissent in "movement" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> under punishment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expulsion</ENAMEX>. He must be reading different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> and attending different
"movement" gatherings than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX> My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and I at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Competitive Enterprise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> have criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> in the pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Times , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , and Human Events for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
Yet we are still invited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> meetings and his
frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> has been scathing in its attacks on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, yet it has yet to be ostracized. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page complains about "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Kasich</ENAMEX>" and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> deal, yet no one is seeking to write <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bartley</ENAMEX> out of the
movement.

            And the
idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> is an enforcer of the party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX>--the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> who
splits with the conservative mainstream on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, campaign-finance reform, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jude Wanniski</ENAMEX>--is absurd. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX> is a fine investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, but he is
no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s imagined conservative politburo.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adler Competitive Enterprise InstituteWashington</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lima</ENAMEX>
'Zines
            

            It's
amusing to see what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> considers front-page news, but it would be
truly eye-opening to learn what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>' or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lima</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>'s concerns are. I
hope you will consider widening the scope of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Brooke</ENAMEX>
Mandel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Schlock
to the System
            

            Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> for his
humorous, balanced, and concise "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> working against him. I take issue with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point
in the article--the issue of antecedents.

            Plotz rightly lists <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> as a primary enabler of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> is doing now. An even better case
can be made, however, for the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.G</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder Junkies</ENAMEX>
as an influence/antecedent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.G</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allin</ENAMEX> created the same kind of talentless,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgusting</ENAMEX>, yet strangely compelling schlock that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> puts out, and combined
it with a stage show that would make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Cooper</ENAMEX> squeamish. The difference
here is image <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allin</ENAMEX> had huge contempt for fame. He avoided the
conventional spotlight all he could. He died of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin overdose</ENAMEX> in relative
obscurity.

            Until
recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX> had worked in obscurity as well, with just a slightly
larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> following than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.G</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allin</ENAMEX>. It was only when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> acquiesced to
the hype machine created by his record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> that he started getting rich and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> started getting angry.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armstrong Denver</ENAMEX>

            
               Rate
Crimes
            

            In your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attack Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> for telling a national radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that lower taxes
mean "less time at work and more free time" when supply-siders have for years
been saying that "cutting taxes would spur more , not less work effort,
thereby speeding economic growth." In criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, you state,
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>]conomic theory tells us, lower taxes do have contradictory effects--they
prompt us to work harder, because we net more from each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hour</NUMEX> of labor, and to
goof off because higher total take-home pay means we can satisfy our needs more
easily."

            In fact,
economic theory says no such thing. You have confused lower taxes with lower
tax rates . Lower tax rates have conflicting effects on the work
effort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> for the reasons you stated. Some tax cuts, however, do
not raise the reward for work and therefore do not increase work effort. The
best example of this is the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>-per-child tax credit--the centerpiece of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> tax package. Clearly, this tax cut does not "net more from each hour
of labor." Rather it is like winning the lottery--it makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> better off (or wealthier) and, therefore, reduces the need to work. In
this regard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is correct. Economic theory predicts that the centerpiece
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> tax cut will mean less time at work, which in turn means a
further reduction in tax revenues. This may be good "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" politics but I
believe it is bad economic policy.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart Cincinnati</ENAMEX>

            
               Throw the
Book at Him
            

            With regard to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Personal Trade</ENAMEX>
Deficit," I commend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Landsburg</ENAMEX>'s use of personal experience with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> bookstore in the next <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to effectively explain the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of trade.

            In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, however, he passes judgment--a more ambitious undertaking. Further
browsing, perhaps in a different section of the bookstore, may be in order. His
conclusions:

            "[F]oolishly excessive trade
surpluses are a greater danger than foolishly excessive trade
deficits . That's because excessive trade deficits are self-limiting: If
you run a trade deficit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, bankruptcy will eventually force you to
stop. But excessive trade surpluses can go on forever. A perpetual trade
surplus is likely to mean you're either working too hard or consuming too
little; either way, you're not getting enough enjoyment out of life."

            Really? Bankruptcy is not
harmless; the debt is transferred to others (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>,
the rest of society), and the damage can (and often does) multiply beyond the
original "foolishness." The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">crash of 1929</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> that followed is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> dramatic example of such a domino effect.

            The real
kicker is the last line. Enjoyment of life is reduced when one produces more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> consumes? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX> really has wandered over from the economics
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> to the philosophy section of his bookstore, and thought about this, I'd
like to hear his reasons.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Noble Winchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
