
   
   
      
         
            

            
               If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ego</ENAMEX>,
Then I Go
            

            Very
frustrating to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Husarska</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>." Obviously an experienced foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, Husarska
has chosen to dedicate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first two days</TIMEX> of her diary to the technical
frustrations of being an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and the impact or
nonimpact of her piece. Such self-absorption seems very selfish when what I
want to hear about is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and its condition on the eve of the elections. If
Husarska keeps this up, her diary might as well have been written from a
shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>. Love your mag, but can you do something to restrain
the egomania of your diarists?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Light in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bosnia</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> must be credited for a journalistic coup. The international community
is whistling in the dark about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Husarska</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diary"</ENAMEX> counters the hype
and myopic optimism surrounding the elections there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bravo</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ned</ENAMEX>
Fagan
            

            
               Mustang
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey</ENAMEX> had a proposal that I think would be much more effective than the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> suggested by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor Jr.</ENAMEX> in "The Norplant
Option." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey</ENAMEX> suggested we offer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mustang</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convertible</ENAMEX> in exchange for sterilization. He did
offer a few stipulations, but the important part was sterilization, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">removable</ENAMEX> contraceptive devices. Of course, he was after more than a reduction
in welfare costs. While I agree postponing childbearing is a laudable goal, we
have larger problems to solve regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelley</ENAMEX>
Stallings
            

            
               Publish
or Perish
            

            Perhaps
because I work in the newspaper industry, where we publish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> regardless, I
find your seemingly frequent vacations troubling. But, OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are
different. I had been prepared all along to pony up the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> or whatever it
is to subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> when you begin charging. But now I'm worried, because
I don't know what I'll be getting for my <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadley</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
Origin of Specious
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Horgan</ENAMEX>'s review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dawkins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Climbing Mount Impossible</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mystery of</ENAMEX>
Life") is interesting. However, he makes some specious claims. He argues,
"After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of searching, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have found no conclusive evidence that
life exists elsewhere in the universe." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> wouldn't be able to find
such evidence in the nearby star systems that we have searched thus far; and
the tools we use for detection have limited capabilities.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Horgan</ENAMEX>
also writes, "In spite of the immensely powerful tools of modern biotechnology,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> still cannot make matter animate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>." Surely few
biotechnologists are so arrogant as to claim life-creating power. Besides, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of laboratory research falls somewhat short of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> natural processes need.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Living
Single
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bravo,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Wasserstein</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party of One</ENAMEX>"), for telling it like it is! Why haven't political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> picked up on the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singles</ENAMEX> are discriminated against by both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have long denigrated alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lifestyles</ENAMEX>. Now
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> talk about singleness as if it is an alternative lifestyle.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Costello</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
