
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               Illiteracy 
               Test
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Cares if Johnny Can't</ENAMEX>
Read?" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larissa MacFarquhar</ENAMEX> is a truly stupid article, whose only point
is that there is a big difference between basic reading and highbrow reading.
But this is not a crucial distinction for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> concerned about literacy in
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. There has been a palpable decline in literacy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 30 years</TIMEX>. Even the average university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> both knows less and, by
common-sense measures, is less intelligent than his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>. And
even if IQ has not declined on a mass scale (and I suspect that it has), there
is a point at which lack of curiosity and sheer ignorance are indistinguishable
from a deficiency of intelligence. This article was a good example of
supposedly skeptical and revisionist garbage.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey</ENAMEX>
Scodel
            

            
               Lying
Illiterates
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Cares if Johnny Can't</ENAMEX>
Read?" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larissa MacFarquhar</ENAMEX> is so off base that it is difficult to fathom
that she really believes what she is saying. I am the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the Literacy
Council of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, and I know that the functional illiteracy rate
in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52 percent</NUMEX>.

            Her data
is obviously faulty. It is nonsense to ask an illiterate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> if he's reading
a book. Of course he's going to say "yes." The last thing an illiterate person
wants to advertise is the fact that he can't read. Our culture is filled with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hide their illiteracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Restaurants</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoney's</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny</ENAMEX>'s feature pictures of their entrees on the menu so those who can't read
can still order their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know who wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huckleberry Finn</ENAMEX>
and other books because they have learned from television and the movies.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmidt</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Lay Off
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX>
            

            Thanks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> for giving me the link to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s Web site in his
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Ambassador From Shangri-La</ENAMEX>." But other than that, it was a
complete and utter waste of my time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> is merely
cashing in on the West's romance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> spirituality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> is
the only world religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who acts the way many feel a world religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> should--speaking inclusively to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about his faith instead of trying
to ban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from the priesthood and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> from humanity in
general. Maybe he is a feel-good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimist</ENAMEX> or maybe the answers are really
simpler than our unnecessarily complex world would like to believe, but either
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> is one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world whom I can
legitimately not feel cynical about. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> has dismally failed to
change my mind.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cotton</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX>
the Mooch
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s article
"I Like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>" is based on an extremely dangerous and faulty premise: All income
belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and the portion we are allowed to keep is some sort
of present. The flaw is best expressed when she refers to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> as
"windfall week." As we all know, the money in a tax refund is money that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taxpayer</ENAMEX> earned and was kept by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to a year</TIMEX> without
interest. Windfall? Incredible.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s comments about "tax
shelters" are similarly puzzling. Can she possibly mean that we should pay more
in taxes than the law requires? She then goes on to extol the virtues of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beloved IRS</ENAMEX>, distracting us from the actual percentage of our income that is
being taken.

            As for her
discussion of the graduated tax and the flat-tax proposal, she blithely opines
that taxing higher-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> is OK because the dollars are "less
precious," but she knows that we are talking about percentages of their total
income, not a fixed amount. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s articles are usually insightful,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> informed, and the viewpoints balanced, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s article
possesses none of these virtues.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Cleef</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Amen to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
            

            I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s argument in "I Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>." The present tax system is pretty fair, and is
certainly more democratic than a flat tax. The system of exemptions and
deductions, although perhaps a little complicated, really means that one's tax
obligations are custom tailored to one's specific circumstances. Paradoxically,
the more we try to simplify the code, and the more "one size fits all" we try
to make it, the less conforming to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> needs the system becomes.

            The problem is, we are
always trying to have it both ways. We want all the breaks, and we want a
simple system. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> approaches, unfortunately, are mutually exclusive. If we
go to a flat tax and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find out that they're paying more than others
they perceive as less deserving, they are going to scream like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuck pigs</ENAMEX>. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are unhappy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>--thanks to contentious, self-serving news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who
are more bent on garnering attention through controversy than they are through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enlightenment</ENAMEX>--they are going to be miserable when they realize what they have
done to themselves.

            My only
complaint with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> is that they seem to be lagging in the computer area, a
problem I attribute to the politicization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s top management. We get a
new top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, and then it's a whole new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ballgame</ENAMEX>--again and again. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> ought to be like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>, above party, serving terms that transcend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incoming</ENAMEX> and outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collingwood Harris</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Taxing
Ambition
            

            I beg to differ with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Like</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>." As a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX>, recently married, I was one of
those <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> that you spoke of who didn't get money back. But even if I
had, this should not be viewed as a source of income or bonus. How about the
fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has held that money over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>,
preventing you from collecting interest or circulating it throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. There is no positive outlook in having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> hold on to your
money so you can get a bonus check at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>.

            Moreover, your definition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> is concerning. You feel that you can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who values a dollar more based
on community standards. However, we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that was built
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">individualism</TIMEX>. Taxes do not empower the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, they empower the
government and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker people</ENAMEX> by taking their extra income to fund
government-program flops.

            What
continues to baffle me about progressive taxing is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> care so much what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, or I pay in taxes. We should trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>
who turn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> and make our economy stronger, improve our overall
standard of living, and even provide jobs. These are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that drive our
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. The more money you take out of their hands the more money you take out
of the economy. Our current method only penalizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for making more money.
We have turned monetary success into a crime. It is no wonder our society is
floundering around and the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Generation X.</ENAMEX>

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
Stanich
            

            
               Put
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dworkin</ENAMEX>'s Argument out of Its Misery
            

            In the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on
assisted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suicide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Dworkin</ENAMEX> holds that neither a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> aborting "her" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> nor
a "terminally ill patient killing himself" involves either "important interests
of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" or an action "horribly against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s own interests." I
disagree.

            The definition of humanity
is not intrinsically questionable. For some, it is clear: From conception until
death, human life is sacred. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dworkin</ENAMEX> reduces the ontological status of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> to an issue of ownership by calling it "her" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>, using an assumption
central to the validation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master-slave</ENAMEX> relationship. He implies that
killing is justified when it releases a willing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> from pain, a maxim that
could lead to a justification of slaying the innocent to avoid any other
painful social or personal dilemma.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dworkin</ENAMEX>
wishes to replace the moral teleology of law with obeisance to cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prejudices</ENAMEX>, informing us that unjust acts may be countenanced when popular
ideology asserts them to be "personal" and hence putatively free of legal
restraint. But the better part of Western thought has always affirmed that the
principles of law are ineluctably related to the principles of good.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Long</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teacher</ENAMEX>'s
Pet
            

            I want to thank you for
bringing the insights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Landsburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. I'm a high-school economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>; their
perspectives have enriched my understanding and challenged my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. They
have made all of us really think, which should be the highest motive of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>. Clearly, you have chosen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the best.

            I especially appreciate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX>'s accessibility. I have been able to carry on an e-mail
dialogue with him regarding his ideas expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and his book, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armchair Economist</ENAMEX> . Through me, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have participated in this
dialogue. They think that's exciting, and so do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>

            By
providing this service, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> has demonstrably increased my effectiveness in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> by engaging my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in a conversation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>. So I thank you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> sponsors and ask that you
continue the good work.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nelson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
