
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Auteur
Amateur
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX>'
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Island of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost Auteurs</ENAMEX>" suffers from deficiencies that his just verdict on the latest
film cannot alleviate. In praising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Frankenheimer</ENAMEX>'s earlier works, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> is
much too gripped by a childish auteuristic fascination with the technical
aspects of what are very minor works. And his appraisal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and acting is
shockingly amateurish. It is amusing that he could mistake <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brando</ENAMEX>'s ludicrous
and perfunctory posturing as some controlled experiment in caricature and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parody</ENAMEX>, but the homoerotic slavering over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Val Kilmer</ENAMEX> is infantile and
unbecoming of anyone who is supposed to make informed aesthetic judgments. One
would think a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> would hire a film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> who has
something other than breezy pop-cultural enthusiasms to offer.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Khan</ENAMEX>

            

               Pointless
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>?
Could <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Hulbert</ENAMEX>'s review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Didion</ENAMEX>'s latest novel ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Thing We</ENAMEX>
Expected") be any more convoluted? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulbert</ENAMEX> takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> to task for writing
stories that go nowhere. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulbert</ENAMEX> likes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>'s new work.
Unfortunately, her review reads like any one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>'s earlier novels, dense
on prose, short on directness. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulbert</ENAMEX> has a point to make, she missed
making it. I think I'll buy the book and take my chances.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
Hopper

            
               Property
Rights
            

            The premise of "The Norplant
Option," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor Jr.</ENAMEX>, reminds me of the plan my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">township</ENAMEX> put into
effect in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'70s</TIMEX> to protect and preserve prime farmland by purchasing the
development rights.

            This concept was picked up in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polluters</ENAMEX> who reduce their toxic output beyond requirements
can sell the right to molest the environment to others less willing or less
able to control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor</ENAMEX> proposes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> on welfare be paid to use an implanted device to prevent pregnancy.
In effect, he suggests the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> purchase reproductive rights, at least
for a limited time.

            Since wage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slavery</ENAMEX> is a well-established phenomenon, and getting better established by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, a little nonreproduction bribery sounds pretty mainstream. Our loyal
opposition on the right used to tell us that "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can do anything with his
property." (Land-use regulation is a plot by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commies</ENAMEX>.) Isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s body her
most personal property? Can't she do with it what she will?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Silver

            
               Sexual
Experimentation
            

            I believe we would probably
be justified in experimenting with the initiative outlined in "The Norplant
Option," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor Jr.</ENAMEX>, in a limited and controlled way. At the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, I am struck by what I find to be considerable conceptual confusion as
well as an absence of fundamental analysis based on solid biology and
sociology.

            The initiative is, in fact,
an intrusion by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>. True, the government
already makes or withholds payments based on a number of individual conditions,
including the birth of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, etc. However, there is a quantum leap in
intrusion levels when payments are made based on something that is put under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s skin.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coercion</ENAMEX> is inevitable. The
argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> will get paid more rather than less for something
is disingenuous: They will be paid less than would otherwise be the case if
they refuse to submit, a point that no doubt will be made by many program
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX>.

            More fundamentally, the
debate seems to ignore the biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> at work. While underclass
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> may consciously have no interest other than in fooling around, their
underlying reproductive strategy is a wide dissemination of genes to numerous
offspring in the statistical hope that a few will make it. The proposed
initiative equals an attempt to "buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out" of their biological destiny.
Some may reject it ; some others may, in effect, make a successful transition
to a higher-class reproductive strategy and become "like us." Still others may
be "neutered," with their vital energies being redirected in potentially
dangerous directions.

            Having
said this, and given that there presumably are no panaceas, it might be
appropriate to proceed with caution and let different proposals compete in the
market of real life.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Kailor

            
               Us and
Them, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rights and Wrongs</ENAMEX>
            

            I was disappointed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
chose to publish "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Norplant Option</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor Jr.</ENAMEX> Why are we so
interested in interfering with the sexual and reproductive rights of Them,
those other than Us? If we turn the tables, and ask ourselves what laws we
would choose to enact to curtail our sexual and reproductive rights, it becomes
immediately clear how offensive and obtrusive such laws are to the rights of
Them. What law would I be willing to sign against myself to curtail my sexual
and reproductive freedoms? If I were certified insane, I might want the
government to assign a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian</ENAMEX> who would act to protect my reproductive
rights, as I would not have the mental faculties do so myself. Otherwise, I
cannot imagine any situation in which I would choose to have some
self-righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>, a k a our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, sticking his nose into my
business by telling me if, when, and how I can have sex or reproduce.

            The fact
that these sexual and reproductive intrusions are typically proposed by white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should raise a red flag for anyone listening to such
nonsense. One moment these self-righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would force a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to bear a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. The next moment these same self-righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would force a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. Either way, I cannot think of a more intrusive act--short of
hanging.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
Adcock

            

               Duh
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley, you really are brain-dead to propose eliminating the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
Amendment to solve the welfare problem ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Jobs</ENAMEX> at
Now Wages"). You should consider this truism: "For every complex problem
there is a simple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX>, and it is always wrong."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>

            
               Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers for Slavery</ENAMEX>
            

            I was disappointed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s "modest proposal" to reform the welfare system by
re-establishing slavery ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Jobs</ENAMEX> at
Now Wages") did not mention the book from which it was likely inspired,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilaire Belloc</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Servile State</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>).

            
Unfortunately, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> might consider the article merely humorous, describing
an impossible proposition, where in fact, the basics of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Servile</ENAMEX>
State (concentrated ownership and status-based laws governing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> relations) have been long established, and the need for
slavery in the light of the increasingly degraded condition of the welfare
class becomes more evident. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX> has been part of organized human society
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should not assume that it has breathed its last.
Despite its obvious drawbacks, I doubt it is the worst way to organize society,
and it may be better than our present narcissistic fashion.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
Sponsler

            
               Apples
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oranges</ENAMEX>
            

            Please
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inform Robert Wright</ENAMEX> that he is indeed confused (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Styles of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polygamy</ENAMEX>"). There is a difference between adultery and divorce. I was
flabbergasted that he could compare the morality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and imply they are the same. Divorce is caused by many things, including
adultery, but to imply there is no difference between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is just
unbelievable.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>
Kimzey

            
               Blue
Notes
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Steingarten</ENAMEX>'s article
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> aversions ("The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omnivore</ENAMEX>") reminds me of a perplexing phenomenon I have observed during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few years</TIMEX>. I am talking about the apparent growth in the popularity of
blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.

            A study conducted at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX> (where the maraschino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cherry</ENAMEX> was invented) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 25 years ago</TIMEX>
found that blue was almost universally disliked as a food color.

            Recently, however, something
seems to have changed. I have seen many blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> on the market: blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jell-O</ENAMEX>,
blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juicelike drinks</ENAMEX>, blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>, and blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>.

            Mr.
Steingarten, are we seeing a trend here? Assuming the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> study was
correct, what has changed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> of the eating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to cause
blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to become acceptable? Do you think its rise in popularity parallels
that of blue lipstick and blue nail polish? Are we talking about postmodern
food here? Or punk <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
Curry

            
               To the
Left ...
            

            Still
heavy on the left-wing status quo. Not even any token "balance." Kind of like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> promise. Nothing really new or different here either. You can get the
same info in any of the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. Thoughtful and insightful? I don't
think so. I guess you can still fool some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> some of the time.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
Hoke

            
               ... And
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right</ENAMEX>
            

            Despite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurances</ENAMEX> that your corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> would never influence editorial content,
you are presenting such a right-wing, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> position (don't believe it?
Check out all the adjectives used in supposedly "evenhanded" stories) that your
true colors (mainly yellow) are apparent.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Tarnowski</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
