
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Last week
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX> documented former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Robert B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s fabrications in his much-touted memoir, Locked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich to Rauch</ENAMEX>'s accusations. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch Reich</ENAMEX>'s response.
            

             

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> the
controversy continues:
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reich</ENAMEX>
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> controversy captures the meaning of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> in the new world of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webzines</ENAMEX>. I don't particularly care about
either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, nor do I find the substance of the controversy particularly
gripping: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> going after each other like a couple
of school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>--big deal. What did matter to me was being
able to access the gestalt of the experience. Sounds like psychobabble, but it
means I liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX>'s original piece, felt and understood <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s arguments in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reply to Rauch</ENAMEX>, and was able to incorporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX>'s counter-arguments, all in
what seemed like a comprehensive whole occurring at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one moment</TIMEX> in time. Sort of
like playing a good point in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX>--lots of interchange and then a precise
conclusion, quick and satisfying. It doesn't happen the same way in print
journalism.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walters Toronto</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX> to
Judgment
            

            Thank you for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rauch/Reich/Rauch</ENAMEX> dialogue. I found the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX> counter particularly compelling
since it mirrored exactly my reaction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> reply. What struck me most,
however, was how this little folk tale of inaccurate reporting of events
illustrates a dilemma of modern life.

            From my
occasional role in affairs reported in the media I have drawn the general
conclusion that very little reporting is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> accurate. Whether the
inaccuracies are intentional, mere failures to understand, or just
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oversimplifications</ENAMEX> in order to dumb down the message or meet space or time
limitations matters not. My rule of thumb is that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> "right" is way
above average. How, therefore, am I ever to recognize the (minimum) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>
"wrong" in most articles? It is this question which, for me, limits media
credibility more than any other.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
Ruswick
            

            
               Tales
From the Trans-Crypt
            

            This from a former chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate Committee</ENAMEX>:

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX> wrote
wrong. Recording <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> never challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX>'s changes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obsequious</ENAMEX> staff
often offer trimmed and tabulated transcripts, the better to butter their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>.

            In contrast to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>,
I can tell you that the official record of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> proceeding is
what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> says it is. Hired recording <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> make typed transcripts
of what their stenographer thinks the tape recorder, supplemented by written
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, captured. This "draft transcript" goes back to whomever the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman designates</ENAMEX> for corrections. Tradition mandates that changes are
assumed to be technical corrections--to set the record straight, to translate
garbled portions, or to sort who said what when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> speaks at
once.

            
Corrections can be complete rewrites, however. Sometimes the corrections are
accurate, sometimes awful. Angry, sarcastic, or tongue-in-cheek responses are
most likely to be struck from the record. Poor grammar, misspoken words, and
confrontational moments between important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> also regularly hit the
cutting-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>. Even the most ethical staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> gets to the typed
transcript draft <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> after the event and is dependent upon his or her
own memory to edit the record. The connection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stenographer</ENAMEX>'s wire has
been known to fail suddenly at sensational senatorial clashes. Finally, members
of the press have also erroneously visualized goings-on, especially when
writing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours later</TIMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.L.S. Kropf Tahoe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>
replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX> (and privileged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>) do sometimes modify
hearing transcripts, but not in this case: I checked the hearing transcript
against a videotape.

            
               The
Village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> full of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gotham</ENAMEX>'s hippest logicians couldn't construct a better example of the
begging-the-question fallacy than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX>'s lead to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Was</ENAMEX>
Beautiful." To wit: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Village</ENAMEX> is no more the "center of bohemia"
than Colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> farming community.

            Whom did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollander</ENAMEX> see
decked out in pastels? Well, there's a large young professional demographic in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Village</ENAMEX> (you'd be surprised how few genuine bohemians can come up with
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> a month for a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150-square-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>), there's a sizable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, and I wouldn't be surprised if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a few</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollander</ENAMEX>'s
"bohemians" were toting cameras and wearing bulging nylon fanny packs.

            Still and all, there is
plenty of black being worn in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Village</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollander</ENAMEX> simply picked an odd
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for her fact-finding stroll. The throngs of black-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> who
flock to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Village</ENAMEX> in the summertime to use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, panhandle, sleep in
abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink malt liquor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tompkins Square Park</ENAMEX>--it's sort
of like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>--have yet to arrive. However, many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Villagers</ENAMEX> most
likely to go about in black--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parsons</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pratt</ENAMEX>--are gone
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, squatting with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.

            It's too
bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollander</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are late. She might have gotten a kick
out of them without having to significantly revise her argument. They are
almost all white. As a rule they stick to a punk-rock look: studded black
leather jackets over plaid flannels and old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad Brains</ENAMEX> T-shirts, black jeans
(torn black tights or fishnets for the ladies), safety pins through the ears
and nostrils, and heavy eyeliner. They lurk outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
begging change from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passers-by</ENAMEX>, flashing curled lips and hangdog stares, as
precious in their own way as any amateur anthropologist taking her first
cautious steps east of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Avenue</ENAMEX> in breathless anticipation of a walk on the
wild side.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Mazmanian</ENAMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Double
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vision</ENAMEX>
            

            I
thoroughly enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Sante</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Master of All He Surveys</ENAMEX>" review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Visions</ENAMEX> program. I did want to point out, however, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's site is not the only place on the Web where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> can read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' words on the subject. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS/WNET</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Visions</ENAMEX> piece also includes a major exhibition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 300</NUMEX> pieces
of artwork, accompanied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' detailed commentary (drawn from the
transcript of the program). We include links to other articles by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, and
will be posting the transcript of a live chat conducted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3, 1997</TIMEX>. All in
all, a great stop for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughesophile</ENAMEX> and the devotee of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art and
culture.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mendlow</ENAMEX> associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Visions Web PieceNew York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Bullish
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pippen</ENAMEX> in the '90s
            

            Having just read "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boycott Nike</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>'s treatise on the evils of shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and their
athlete "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchmen</ENAMEX>," it becomes clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> has failed to do his homework,
at least with regard to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scottie Pippen</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> calls Pippen
"reprehensible" for his failure to enter a playoff game in which the final shot
was not designed for him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firstly</ENAMEX>--not that this makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pippen</ENAMEX>'s decision any
better--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pippen</ENAMEX> felt that he, ostensibly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX>' best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> at the time,
should be on the floor as an option for the last shot, not inbounding the ball.
He would most likely draw a double <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, freeing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammate</ENAMEX> for the final shot,
thereby giving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> a better chance to win. His behavior was indeed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immature</ENAMEX> and boorish. Is it not enough, however, that he publicly apologized to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>?

            Unlike many self-centered
and pampered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottie Pippen</ENAMEX> is recognized by his peers
and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> as one of the more giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to disadvantaged youth.
Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pippen</ENAMEX> does not call the media to follow him around with camera
crews every time he finds an opportunity to give back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. Is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> aware that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve a couple of years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pippen</ENAMEX> delivered over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500 winter</TIMEX> jackets to inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cabrini Greens</ENAMEX>, or
that he was very upset when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> wrote a story about it? Is he
aware that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pippen Foundation</ENAMEX> supports reading programs for disadvantaged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>? Does he know of all the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pippen Parks</ENAMEX>" underwritten by Pippen
in his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> to provide safe play environments for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>?

            On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> occasion it
has been suggested to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pippen</ENAMEX> that he issue press releases to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Wrights of the world understand who he really is and the values for which he
stands. His response has always been that it does not matter what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think;
that he knows, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> know, and that's what matters.

            Scottie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pippen</ENAMEX>'s problem is that he is a very private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--one who has learned and
grown as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. To suggest that he made a mistake by not entering a game
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> is fair. To suggest that he is "reprehensible" is absurd.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Flack</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
