
   
   
      
         
            

            
               A Bunch
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot Air</ENAMEX>
            

            There are a couple of
problems with the statistics cited in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Killer Air</ENAMEX>
Bags."

            First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> overestimates
the cost of air bags. Because each consumer only pays for the air bags in his
or her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, the cost of each life saved is no more than the cost to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. The total cost of an air bag is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>--this breaks down to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$166.67</NUMEX> per year on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> lease. Air bags lower insurance rates; hence,
there may be savings on the above figure. And anyway, that figure would seem to
be a rather small price to pay for additional safety.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the article states
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1,136</NUMEX> lives have been saved by air bags, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">650,000</NUMEX> air bags have
been deployed since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. However, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,136</NUMEX> figure is based only on accidents
in which death might have occurred if air bags had not been installed. It does
not take into account the number of accidents in which the injuries might have
been more serious if air bags had not been installed. It also doesn't reflect
the number of lives saved that might have been lost due to accident-related
complications.

            Restraint
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> aren't perfect, but they do offer another level of protection. Being
aware that there may be a problem with air bags will help us minimize that
problem in the future--small comfort, I know, to those who have already lost
loved ones.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Solomon</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Homo</ENAMEX>
Economicus Absurdus
            

            So, the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2.97 seconds</TIMEX> it
takes to put on your seat belt is just too long a period to make economic
sense.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX> study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> cites in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Killer Air Bags</ENAMEX>" calls, at least implicitly, for us to assign a
value to our time, and to use that to determine the value of the total time we
spend buckling up. There are (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> problems with this approach:

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> lies in the
assumption that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all three-second</TIMEX> periods are worth the same. All time was not
created equal. A <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-second</TIMEX> period before getting in the shower is worth far
less than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three seconds</TIMEX> taken from the middle of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s wedding.
Buckling up always occurs between activities--we are accustomed to treating
that time between activities as a buffer period during which several small
tasks are addressed and uncertainties are guarded against. So the time, in
practice, will not be missed.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, related problem
is that the value of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of time is partially determined by the duration of
the total period in which that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> falls. Put simply, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 uninterrupted minutes</TIMEX>
are worth far more than 400 individually occurring <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-second</TIMEX> periods. And
you don't get to cash in your buckle-up episodes like casino chips.

            But, as the last problem
I'll outline suggests, neither of the previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> objections matters. It only
makes sense to worry about the time it takes to put on a seat belt if it
actually results in a delay in our progress. Does it? Many of us put on our
seat belts while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is in motion. Others do so while warming up their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. The rest of us can live on the edge until the first red light--when we
can buckle up in obscene leisure.

            Aside
from the problems with these basic assumptions, I was duly awed and intimidated
by the complexity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s analysis.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Fano</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Swollen
Insensitivity
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> of "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture of</ENAMEX>
Impotence," by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>, should know that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impotence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of America</ENAMEX> is neither a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> nor a business, as was inferred by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">See Slate</ENAMEX>'s correction, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Readme</ENAMEX>."] In fact, it is the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonprofit</ENAMEX>, nonvested health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> that provides impotence education. It
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55</TIMEX> nationwide <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impotents Anonymous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, which were not founded by
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> states. Our helpline (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800-669-1603</ENAMEX>) provides
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">factual</ENAMEX> and unbiased information.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 50 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are involved in relationships where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is impotent.

            Exciting developments in
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">impotence</ENAMEX> treatments offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> renewed
hope for a better quality of life.

            It is
unfortunate that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> elected to treat this topic with a flippant
disregard for the emotional stress associated with impotence. The accompanying
illustration, combined with the overall tone of the article, demonstrates a
petty insensitivity to the emotional anguish of aging. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impotence</ENAMEX> is no joke. In
an article about the loss of sexual virility among older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, we find a lack of
compassion among younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkerpresident &</ENAMEX> chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> executiveImpotence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Erection</ENAMEX>
Injection, Yes
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture of</ENAMEX>
Impotence," by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>, was humorous, but also glib and smug.
Injection therapy has truly benefited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            I would describe the process
like this:

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is engaged in
foreplay, or anticipates being so engaged soon. He excuses himself briefly,
wipes the side of his phallus with a small alcohol wipe, and uses an
auto-injector to painlessly inject a small amount of medication. Over the next
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five to 15 minutes</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> produces heaviness in, and engorgement of, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penis</ENAMEX>. With stimulation (visual, manual, oral, fantasy), this engorgement
becomes a normal erection, with which he can satisfy his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and
himself.

            Having treated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many hundreds</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with this technique, I must say that it is safe, effective, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dependable</ENAMEX>. Moreover, it costs much less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> per use (closer to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $5</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>). Satisfying sexual relations have helped to keep many couples
together.

            Why do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> drop out? Poor teaching, poor motivation, lack of opportunity, and, very
rarely, a failure of the treatment itself. Although this glib and witty piece
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> suggests this is some sort of snake-oil therapy, it certainly is
not!

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Varady</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.D.Florida Center for Impotence</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Active
Faith
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX>'s response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX> is riddled with reductive thinking
and cheap rhetorical tricks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> doesn't realize that revelation is not a
set of propositions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> accepts, but an encounter in which one is moved beyond
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oneself</ENAMEX>. It's analogous to an encounter with a work of beauty. Neither the
beauty of the artwork nor the truth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripture</ENAMEX>'s word can be proved using
some supposedly neutral line of reasoning. Instead, both are given to human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>, and each calls for a choice.

            But the real question is not
what faith means, but what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> means by "illogical" and "without evidence."
What exactly would count as "evidence" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX>? Clearly, many find it very
reasonable to believe that God exists, despite their adolescent need to have it
proved to them, as if metaphysics and mathematics were the same discipline. For
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there is evidence, but not proof persuasive enough to meet the
mythological standards of neutral rationality, a standard that no philosopher
in his right mind would defend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Is there a rational basis for thinking
that God exists? Yes, but the answer depends on what counts as "evidence," and
what one means by "rational."

            Finally, a
note on God's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. We can, of course, continue to ask why there is evil in
the world. But, at some point, we also have to face the fact that this is the
world we live in, a world where evil often seems to triumph, and death appears
to have the last word. In this context, the cross not only inscribes God's
concern, but also proclaims, with the resurrection, God's ultimate victory, a
victory for which we can ardently work and hope.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
Kieke-Sciglitano
            

         
      
   
