
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fightin</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>?
            

            I have to take issue with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>'s piece "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Potatoes</ENAMEX>."

            I agree with his criticism
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> law mandating the teaching of the famine as a historical
example of genocide. As a sometime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, I see this sort of legislation as
the worst kind of politically-motivated government meddling in education. It is
also clear that the motivation behind such legislation is a reaction to
"multiculturalism" and the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> brutality toward non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>. The resulting tit-for-tat is perhaps the best possible
argument for refraining from even well-intentioned political efforts to shape
the public-school curriculum. I object, however, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX>'s characterization of
both the famine and the current vogue of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> identification with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history and culture. His understanding of the famine and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
government's role in it--at least as demonstrated in this piece--is shallow, at
best.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> economic policy
aggravated a desperate situation. That <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> should have been exported
while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> starved--for little other purpose but to hold down the price
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> market--was as morally repugnant to contemporary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> as it is to modern ones. Many contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>
advocated intervention to thwart the famine. Their voices went unheeded by the
likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peel, Russell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trevelyan</ENAMEX>, and the ideology of laissez-faire
political economy meshed with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Irish</ENAMEX> bigotry to produce catastrophic
results for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>.

            Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX>'s
apparent ignorance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history goes deeper still. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> government
was responsible for the underlying conditions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> agricultural economy
that made the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> so vulnerable to the blight. The dispossession of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, which took place in successive waves over several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>, relegated them to the most marginally cultivable pieces of land. A
cash-crop market system supplanted the traditional locally based subsistence
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, and placed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in a position of dependence on a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX>.
When that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> failed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> in succession, they had no viable
alternative to starvation or (if they could afford it) emigration.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>-imposed legal disabilities also hobbled the efforts of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> to redress ill-treatment by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landowners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX>.
Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> makes no mention of the deliberate withholding of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> market to prop up prices for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foer</ENAMEX> points out, other
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> experienced blights of the potato <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> from the same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fungus</ENAMEX>,
but none suffered the human devastation that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> did. The historic policies
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> crown, and later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, turned a crop failure
into one of modern history's most tragic episodes. To argue, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> does--that
the notion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> bears a substantial measure of
responsibility for the humanitarian crisis of the famine is merely an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
"folk tradition"--is as absurd as arguing that the blight itself was introduced
deliberately in a genocidal conspiracy.

            As for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX>'s criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> identification with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> culture as part of
a so-called "Diaspora chic," he is unfair to those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> descent
who do not romanticize terrorism, support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> or the IRA, join
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Order of Hibernians</ENAMEX>, or celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick</ENAMEX>'s
day by getting obnoxiously drunk and excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who happen to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gay</ENAMEX>. That there are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who do these things in no way devalues the
efforts of others to connect with their past. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> tend to have a
superficial understanding of their own history, and to focus on the positive
aspects of their culture to the exclusion of less admirable parts, this only
proves that they are human, and as prone to historical myopia as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglophiles</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Afrocentrists</ENAMEX>. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who is unapologetically proud of both parts
of my hyphenated identity, I find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX>'s piece less offensive than tendentious
and historically ill-informed.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gorman</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Feeding
Hunger
            

            The article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can We Really Feed</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World?</ENAMEX>" only scratches the surface of this issue by focusing on the
murky areas of politics, raw power, and corruption.

            A more in-depth view would
recognize that when the basic framework of a society disintegrates, external
food supplies may just lead to additional reproduction, and thus more
widespread starvation. Desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have lost all hope for themselves
are biologically driven to propel possibly surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> into the next
generation.

            This in turn is just one of
the issues posed by the relationships between technologically advanced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">societies</ENAMEX> (TAS) and technologically primitive societies (TPS). Should "we" (who
is "we"?) let nature run its course and let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> eradicate the TPS
culture or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> themselves? Or should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> take it upon
themselves to "elevate" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPS</ENAMEX> to their level? Or should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAS</ENAMEX> build and
patrol walls around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPS</ENAMEX> to keep adventurers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> from preying
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPS</ENAMEX>? Should the TAS withhold medical technology from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPS</ENAMEX> to preserve
their balanced ecosystem?

            Clearly I
have no answers, but a suggestion: Look at the global picture and step down
from ideological and judgmental postures onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> of common sense and
compassion.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Kailor
            

            
               Buns of
Steel
            

            As Low
Concept as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rumble</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>" may be, I take issue with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s
choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballet dancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baryshnikov</ENAMEX> to unfavorably compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude Van</ENAMEX>
Damme with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Seagal</ENAMEX>. Now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 50</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baryshnikov</ENAMEX> may no longer make a
career of jumping higher than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>'s grasping hands might reach, but he is
still dancing professionally. Which means, just like our grunting action
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, the mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Misha</ENAMEX> still has buns of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
