
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               "The
Name's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomer Bond</ENAMEX>."
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arrogance</ENAMEX> and ignorance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underpin Edward Luttwak</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The CIA Is Déclassé</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> looks beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> and
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and their "targets" hail from around the globe. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
Bubba may prefer a cold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX> and softball over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bondian</ENAMEX> play in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moritz</ENAMEX>, I defy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luttwak</ENAMEX> to demonstrate how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can reliably use
such experiences as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter holidays</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s slopes as screens for future
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> in gathering information on dangers such as nuclear- or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemical</ENAMEX>-proliferation threats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Asia</ENAMEX>. Leave charming
the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>.

            Spare us laments about the
decline of Ivy League credentialism in government service. We have the world's
broadest-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> of higher education, and those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>-college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> work
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> because they are smart and well educated.

            Young
caffeine- and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormons</ENAMEX> just happen to be--because of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>'s
missionary zeal--one of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veins</ENAMEX> of talent with foreign
experience and skill in languages. Odd as it may sound, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> probably knows a lot more about the world than his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>. As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> problems,
they seem to stem more from lack of accountability than from the basic nature
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O'Reilly</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Party
Hack
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hack Attacks</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, was uncomfortably close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> party line.

            I was particularly bothered
by a subtle attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> as vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ActiveX</ENAMEX>. The article says several times that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> approach is "slower." It later says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> is unsuitable for
high-performance video games because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>'s slowness. This is deceptive.
Technology has been commercially demonstrated that runs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> programs at very
high speed (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asymmetrix</ENAMEX>). It simply isn't linked up to Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape Navigator/Communicator</ENAMEX> yet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> byte-code verifier imposes
some performance cost, but there's no reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX> code cannot be byte-code
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">verified</ENAMEX> once, then translated to efficient machine code, and then stored on
your hard drive along with all your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>-bought applications.

            The security approach of Java
does restrict what an unsigned applet can do, and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> are fair.
But the criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> on performance grounds, as if the performance
problems were inherent in the security model, is not fair and is not
accurate.

            And because the question of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ActiveX</ENAMEX> is a very hot topic in the industry now, with lots of money
riding on it, it's impossible not to wonder whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s influence on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> had something to do with this unfairness.

            Of course
I don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> ordered you to slander Java! But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> presumably
hangs around with a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">JavaSoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and is
likely to absorb their point of view, as I'm sure I would in the same
circumstances. The ultimate effect is that this article treads close to the
danger zone.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Weinreb</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Barnes</ENAMEX>
replies: You're right, of course, that I tend to understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
view more clearly, just as you obviously do the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">JavaSoft</ENAMEX> view. As with any
religious war, no one is neutral except the atheists. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> is a great and very
useful language, but all the upcoming performance-improvement technologies in
the world won't help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> using <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s browsers, as you yourself admit.
Therefore I stand by the caveats I described.

            
               Key
Points
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hack Attacks</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, was generally excellent, but I have a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX>.

            Secret-key cryptography
("single-key," in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>' terminology) is not bad for two-way interactions. In
fact, it's routinely used for that purpose. But it's difficult to get the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> secret key to the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>) in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.
Public-key key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> gets the secret key to its destination safely, avoiding
the chicken-and-egg problem of having to share a secret key already in order to
share another key secretly. Afterward, secret-key cryptography is normally used
for efficiency reasons.

            The reduced version of a
long document is known as a "digest," not a signature. It is a widely held but
mistaken belief that a digital signature is the public-key
decryption/private-key encryption of a document's digest. That's how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSA</ENAMEX>, the
most popular signature algorithm, works, because it happens to be both a
signature algorithm and a public-key encryption algorithm.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> also might have
mentioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> solution to the problem of the corruptible system <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>:
"secret sharing." It is possible to divide up secrets (such as passwords) among
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such that only a subset of them of a certain size (a majority,
for instance) can recover the original. That way, a single corrupt authority
can't hurt you.

            The last
part of the article might have underplayed the security threats to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. It's
true that nothing serious has really happened yet, but very little of value (to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker</ENAMEX>) is in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s computers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. That may change fast; if desktop
banking (including check writing) becomes widespread, for example, then the
incentive for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> to use their discoveries for something other than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embarrassing Microsoft</ENAMEX> or causing general mischief increases dramatically.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simon</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Barnes</ENAMEX>
replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simon</ENAMEX>'s technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nits</ENAMEX> are well taken. However, while I agree
that security is a serious issue, I reiterate that the hysterics with which
security stories are played out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are generally overblown.

            
               Breaking
the Waves
            

            I enjoyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee of</ENAMEX>
Correspondence discussion "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cycles, Waves, and Endings in History</ENAMEX>," and I agree with those who
say that the generational conflict is driving electoral politics and
policy-making. Someone should interpret moves like cutting welfare as yet
another symptom of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boom me-firstism.

            And while
I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Fukuyama</ENAMEX>'s optimism for democracy, it's important to note
that anti-democratic movements have gained new strength in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>, and in some cases have gained power through
the same systems they want to destroy. The future of democracy through
technological change is anything but assured. Postindustrial, extreme-right
movements know where to find the Web, too.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Hunter</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Is That
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">D Cup You're Wearing, or Are You Just Glad to See Me</ENAMEX>?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bra Story</ENAMEX>,"
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX>, was a great contribution to the recent surge in chronicling
the history of the unleashing of the female form in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. Her appreciation of the em-bra'd breast manages to be both appropriate
and evocative, if not titillating.

            It may be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> more
before the male version of this trend plays itself out thoroughly enough to
merit similar discussion. Some future male <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> appearing onstage in his
bullet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> will signal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pinnacle</ENAMEX>, I suppose. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decades</TIMEX> have
already seen the liberation of the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jewels</ENAMEX>.

            The heterosexual world has
embraced gay iconic sexuality consistently at a lag of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years or so</TIMEX>. From
1950s fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX>'s crotch bulge in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Male catalog in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GQ</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marky Mark</ENAMEX> in his
Calvins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, the penis has gone from unspeakable to unavoidable.
And just take a look at the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jockey</ENAMEX> underwear packaging if you need to
confirm that circumcision is still being practiced in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>.

            The
sociological implications are huge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Penis</ENAMEX> envy is spreading. And surely there's
a link between naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on billboards, hard-core porn in the home video
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>, and anything that can be attributed to largely male decision
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>--from corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mergers</ENAMEX> to the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Rothery
            

            
               The Odds
on God
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Wittes</ENAMEX>' article
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cracking God</ENAMEX>'s
Code" must have been intended for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April Fool's Day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wittes</ENAMEX> apparently
believes that the discovery of statistically unlikely "secret codes" in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> proves the existence of God. Even if we accept the dubious premise that
the existence of God can be proven scientifically, it is extremely naive to say
that the occurrence of an unlikely event would do the trick.

            I don't
know which is more depressing: the fact that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s faith is so weak
they seek scientific approval of their beliefs, or the fact that they believe a
supposedly all-knowing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">all-powerful</ENAMEX> God would choose to reveal himself through
some inconsequential abnormality.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bohan</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Criminal</ENAMEX>
Procedures
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Dershowitz</ENAMEX> argues in a
recent book review titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Crime and Truth</ENAMEX>" that powerful procedural safeguards for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> allow some guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go free, but that these procedures are
justified to prevent miscarriages of justice and to deter misconduct among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.

            He misses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> essential
points. First, these rules harden public attitudes toward everyone accused of a
crime. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, they feed into the corrosive cynicism within the justice system.
Since procedural niceties seem arbitrary and irrelevant to fact-finding, there
is little motivation to enforce the rules, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> often find ways of
bending rules that they regard as arbitrary and silly. For example, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dershowitz</ENAMEX> himself has written, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> pretend to believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> who lie about
illegal searches.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>,
the most glaring injustice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is not the wrongful conviction of the
innocent. It is the remarkably cruel treatment of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are actually
guilty. When a troubled and illiterate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> can receive life
imprisonment for committing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> muggings, it seems laughably irrelevant to
focus on courtroom procedures.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Sleepers
            

            As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 and 11 months</TIMEX>), I enjoyed reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Go Ahead--Sleep With Your Kids</ENAMEX>." I urge him to get back in touch
and tell us if he winds up with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 7-year-old</TIMEX> in bed with him
(now, that's what I call birth control).

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Murphy</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
