
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX>
            

            I am
furious! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wood</ENAMEX> revealed the plot and ending of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX>
in his review (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Gone With the Wind"</ENAMEX>). That's the last time I read a book review in

                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. From a review, I want an impression of the book and
an opinion, not all the details of the plot! If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> uses a plot with a
surprise ending, he probably wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to be surprised. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX> should not
have done this; you should never have published his review. Can you change it
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> before you reveal the plot to other innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> like me?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Acton</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Not
Innocent
            

            In
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 24</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> made a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rookie</ENAMEX> mistake for saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX> was "innocent" of bombing charges
instead of "not guilty." Not so fast. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> has a very good reason.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> stylebook, the manual for how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> should address varying concerns, one should "use innocent ,
rather than not guilty , in describing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>'s plea or a jury
verdict, to guard against the word not being dropped inadvertently." Now
many other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have their own styles, even when it comes to "innocent"
vs. "not guilty." But the technical difference is secondary to possible libel
concerns.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince</ENAMEX>
Tuss
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
