
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruity</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Multiply</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Be Fruitful and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Multiply</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>, makes no sense. He argues that
refraining from having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> may impoverish those who would have been your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>. But that wouldn't be the case if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of
those potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> also refrained from reproducing. Also, there are over
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on earth, surely more than enough to provide everyone with
"potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>." And one does not tend to encounter small acts of kindness
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> in overcrowded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Ryan</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Make
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love, Make War</ENAMEX>
            

            The article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Be Fruitful and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Multiply</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>, explores a key area in the search for
new directions in economics: the connection to biology. Unfortunately, it is
likely to sow considerable confusion by suggesting that an individual could or
should add value to humankind through additional reproduction.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reproduction</ENAMEX> is not guided by a moral imperative toward humanity as a whole but
by a competitive struggle to pass on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. This includes the effort to give
one's progeny the power to pass genes even further-- hence, family names,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mansions</ENAMEX>, and monuments. But as the species grows to fill its biological space,
nature itself provides limiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> like single lifestyles, wars, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">famines</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Kailor</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX> replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Ryan</ENAMEX> thinks that among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX>, he has more than enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Good for him. Surely he's aware that
there are others less fortunate. Among all his many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, is there none, for
example, who has had difficulty finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who will make a suitable
marriage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kailor</ENAMEX> says that reproduction is not guided by a moral imperative toward
humanity. That was exactly my point. If they were guided by moral imperatives,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> than they do. In the absence of those moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imperatives</ENAMEX>, there's a case for subsidizing reproduction.

            

               FashionSense <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>
            

            I was greatly encouraged to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Goff</ENAMEX>'s proposal of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> fashion-upgrade strategy, titled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dressing Up the Nerds</ENAMEX>." The development of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> FashionSense
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX> is long overdue, and I for one would like to offer my services as a
volunteer beta tester.

            I agree that your initial
ramp-up strategy of having everyone wear more black is an excellent starting
point. It will be especially helpful to inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">FashionSense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, many
of whom are likely to encounter usability issues related to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX>-coordination decision-making process. You may want to clarify, however,
that polar fleece is not a recognized attribute of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FashionSense</ENAMEX> in any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX>.

            As you move through your
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> product cycle, you may also want to consider some of the following
additional features or revisions:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> employee
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> is at a premium and offsites are quite expensive, you may wish to consider
having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barneys</ENAMEX> perform weekly on-site seminars instead. Preferably these would
be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 9</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX> to accommodate everyday activities such as
feature cutting, server breakdowns, office moves, cross-divisional re-orgs, and
the like. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Right</TIMEX> before ship dates, these seminars could be held <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 11 p.m.</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> to provide additional convenience for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> attempting to
finish their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> tasks.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) You might want to add
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birkenstocks</ENAMEX> to your list of footwear banned between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial</ENAMEX>
Day. Wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birkenstocks</ENAMEX> with dresses should be prohibited at all times.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small VR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glasses</ENAMEX>/headsets
would make both a chic, high-tech alternative to sunglasses and provide users
with something additional to do during discussions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SQL</ENAMEX> server and
ODBC-connection failures.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Increased revenue
potential may also be realized by leveraging existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Money</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX> to create direct-debit relationships between approved fashion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vendors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' stock accounts.

            Thank you
for your attention to these suggestions. I look forward to further status
reports of this product's development and am certain that you will do a fine
job in your implementation.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>
Carnahan
            

            
               Toot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liu</ENAMEX>
            

            I was impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX>'s article on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feng Shui America</ENAMEX>." With the
current demonization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>, it was refreshing to find an informed
Asian-American voice here.

            After
having lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, I was shocked upon my recent arrival
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> influences are being bandied about, there is clearly a
backlash against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>, especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. Also, all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin Americans</ENAMEX>) are effectively lumped into one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> by
mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. It's as blinding as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> cultures are all alike. I welcome more of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> has offered:
thought-provoking and unsung viewpoints.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
Ingkavet
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
