
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Right
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wrong Neck</ENAMEX>
            

            In
"If At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
You Don't Secede," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Heard</ENAMEX> should have used the term "redneck" instead
of "right-wing." It is unfair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> a bunch of wackos in with those who are
just politically conservative. The new "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>" are
gun-brandishing "rednecks" with an attitude. I grew up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state of Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and have seen others of the same type. As a conservative, I
think we need to revise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the general posturing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BATF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, but I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will pay for misuse of authority eventually, and I
think there are other ways to fix our problems without stupidity injected into
the debate. Those "rednecks" don't represent my part of the political
spectrum.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pastor Lew Everett</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Maysey III</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kooks</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cranks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loons</ENAMEX>.
            

            I was offended by the
language employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Heard</ENAMEX> in "If At First You Don't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secede</ENAMEX>," his portrait of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Texas</ENAMEX>
movement. With an insouciant and supercilious tone, he employed descriptors
such as "trailer-trash," "redneck," "codger," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"nut</ENAMEX>," "fringe," and the rest of
that all-too-familiar list.

            The
undereducated, lower-middle-class white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> comprise the only
identifiable class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that can still be insulted with
impunity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s politically correct society. What if, instead of white
folk, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heard</ENAMEX> had attended a gathering of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>,
or even ordinary-grade media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>? He would never have used analogous terms
to describe them.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito Perdue</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cops</ENAMEX> as
Robbers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akhil Reed Amar</ENAMEX> made a
disturbing comment in his dialogue with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Dershowitz</ENAMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth and Crime</ENAMEX>." In
criticizing the ability of the exclusionary rule to reverse a conviction, he
wrote: "The wrong done was the search, not the conviction. Yet the exclusionary
rule in effect rewards B with just such a windfall by sparing him from the
conviction."

            Amar
fails to grasp the purpose of the reversal. It is not a reward for the criminal
but a punishment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. It is very important in our imperfect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> system that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> do not get the idea that the
ends justify the means. As it stands now, police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, especially in urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, present more illegally obtained evidence than legally obtained evidence.
They justify their actions with the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> whose civil
rights they routinely violate are involved in criminal activity, and therefore
have no rights. However, this indicates that law enforcement is convicting
before trying and is ignoring the fact that in performing illegal searches,
they themselves are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. I would encourage a reinterpretation of the
exclusionary principle to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> where they belong, but only if
the cops and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> are severely punished for their crimes as well.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
Hoofnagle
            

            
               Book
Revue
            

            It was clear in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Z.</ENAMEX>" that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirn</ENAMEX> had made up his mind about the book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason & Dixon</ENAMEX> before he
picked it up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirn</ENAMEX> doesn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX> and doesn't like the kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novel Pynchon</ENAMEX> writes. Nor does he have anything interesting to say about why he
doesn't like them.

            You might as well pick
somebody to review a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> retrospective who never liked all that Cubist
stuff in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place (too hard to look at), or have somebody who thinks
rock music is just screeching write about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alanis Morissette</ENAMEX>. The reviewer ought
to consider whether the work succeeds on its own terms.

            To say
nothing of how, somehow, it's not only OK but cool to say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, I didn't even
read the book in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place," as if we could really infer the book is
unreadable from that. This, I guess, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s self-chosen role, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> for
those who can't really be bothered to try. How " <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'90s</TIMEX>."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Lowry</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
