
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               What's
Not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>?
            

            With regard to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Doctor</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX> is either mean, foolish, or both. Most of us
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">literate America</ENAMEX> know better than to buy, read, or in any other way attend
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> memoirs. Such books are produced at a network-movie-of-the-week
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pace</ENAMEX> (I doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> had time to unpack before his book appeared), and are meant
to polish up whatever glossy finish the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> thinks he or she had left upon
crossing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>. It doesn't hurt when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> talk up otherwise
unremarkable volumes (positively or negatively). Workaday facts, routines, the
same old office <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, or the unvarnished truth are precisely not the
matter of these books.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX> naively (or cruelly)
and sanctimoniously skewers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> for doing exactly what is expected of him.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>, in his response, is only too happy to put on a display of witty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woundedness</ENAMEX>. Rauch strikes back, gleeful in his further discovery of docudramatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distortion</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s backhanded self-aggrandizement.

            On net
(no pun intended), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reich</ENAMEX> sells a few more novels ... I mean, "books," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX>
rests easy, knowing he has done his part.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook Evanston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>

            
               Kesey
Does It
            

            I side
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Robert Reich, Quote Doctor"</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX> attacks the
difference in details with a small-mindedness that misses the larger picture
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> was painting. That picture still seems pretty accurate to me. As I read
the transcript of the disputed congressional hearing, and then read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s
account of it, I could see how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s account could be essentially accurate.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> may have actually done a better job of painting a picture of the emotions
present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>--emotions the transcripts failed to capture. (Although,
even in the transcripts, you could see some definite hostility and sarcasm,
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX> seemed to pointedly miss.) As a working professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, I
like accurate quotes. But space should be allowed for a memoir that may not be
as accurate, in the smallest sense, as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> said in
One <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest</ENAMEX> , "It's the truth, even if it didn't
happen."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Norfolk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               We Got
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beats</ENAMEX>
            

            While reading "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Ginsberg</ENAMEX>'s
Secret," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Berman</ENAMEX>, regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>'s confession of altering a poem
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Podhoretz</ENAMEX> had submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Review</ENAMEX> , I was struck by a
dark thought: What if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Ginsberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Podhoretz</ENAMEX> were the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>?
Weren't both of them noted for taking long sabbaticals? They were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, and
therefore in a position to arrange their own schedules, correct? And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginsberg</ENAMEX>
was noted for unleashing many of his more notable works in marathon sessions
under the influence of controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Podhoretz</ENAMEX>'s work diverged
so far from the liberal mainstream that one could argue it could only have
emerged using similar means.

            I think
it behooves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, in its effort to take over the public-opinion industry, to
make a thorough effort to uncover the truth behind this unnatural connection.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s choice for this groundbreaking piece? That should be obvious: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stadler Beltsville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               Apply
Liberally
            

            I was
enjoying reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Lehrman</ENAMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on revisionist
feminism until I came across the statement that "feminism--like
that is an accurate description of Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrman</ENAMEX>'s view of feminism, but it is
ludicrous to apply that description to liberalism. Modern liberalism, sad to
say, has strayed far from the libertarian philosophy of classical liberalism.
It is the left, after all, that continues to defend income-redistribution
programs regardless of the evidence on their failure. It is the left that
continues to resist an end to government-imposed racial and sexual
discrimination. It is the left that props up our loophole-ridden tax system by
opposing reforms, such as the flat tax, that are based on treating all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> equally. Those of us battling for freedom long for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liberalism</ENAMEX> was based on equality of opportunity instead of equality of result.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That day</TIMEX>, unfortunately, ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell The Heritage</ENAMEX> FoundationWashington

            
               In His
Element
            

            After reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review of The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Element</ENAMEX>, I had decided not to waste my time
seeing such an illogical mess. But then I read a rave review in a major paper,
which seemed to agree on every point about the movie's plot save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reviewer</ENAMEX> thought it was intentionally funny, instead of unintentionally dumb.
So I went to see it, wondering which of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> had so totally
missed the point. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> into the film I--and everyone else in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX>--was laughing uproariously . The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Element</ENAMEX> is one of the
funniest, most visually stunning satires in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>!

            The problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> is summed up in this observation: "A good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> is spent getting the
couple past the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. It's as if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luke Skywalker</ENAMEX> had to wait around
for his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">billet</ENAMEX> to be stamped before he could fly off to destroy the
Death <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX>." This is actually an accurate description. Imagine various rabid
mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>--and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>--trying desperately to fool an irritated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX> into believing they're legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> on the last flight out
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort hotel</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ultimate Weapon of the Universe</ENAMEX> has been left in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Now have them all try to be the same legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX>, who
has already boarded. Add in some slapstick, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> getting catapulted
into a massive mountain of garbage. How could anyone see this and take it
seriously?

            Now that his column is a
regular feature, perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX> can amuse us with reviews of some older
movies:

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> expects us to
believe not only that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Kelly</ENAMEX> would dance in the rain while using an
umbrella as if it were a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX>, but also that a symphony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX>, conveniently
hidden from view and under some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX>, just happens to be playing a tune
while he does so."

            Or perhaps:

            "In an astonishingly
illogical script, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> expects us to believe, among other stupidities,
that a nose flattened by a steamroller would be flexible and bloodless, and
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen Beetle</ENAMEX> would start up after being neglected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1,000 years</TIMEX>.
Even minimal research should have informed him that no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead-acid</ENAMEX> battery could
sustain a charge for more than a fraction of that time."

            I look
forward to reading his future nitpickings; I just hope that somewhere along the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> he develops a sense of humor.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwarcz Sharpsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> Are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>, Too
            

            I just
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">finished Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>'s "Watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Couples Go By</ENAMEX>." How can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> be so literate,
so open-minded, and so commonsensical, and be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>? Surely
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sets of phrases have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> overlap?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
Kornheiser
            

            
               Tutti
Faludi
            

            Thank you, both for proving
the necessity of the feminist enterprise and for providing a powerful
commentary on the sad position of contemporary feminism by publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s awful fancies ("Watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Couples Go By"</ENAMEX>) in the same cyberspace as that
spat between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Lehrman</ENAMEX> ("Revisionist
Feminism").

            In a magazine which was
written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>, I was less
surprised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s musings than by your publishing any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at all. I do
feel, however, that his article might more appropriately have been placed under
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>" heading, allowing those of us who don't want to read erotic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confessionals</ENAMEX> to have neatly avoided it.

            My real quarrel, however, is
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s contention that "I have written these views entirely from the
point of view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. That is only natural for me." Well sure, but only if
it is biologically predetermined that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are incapable of understanding
perspectives different from their own. My sense, based on reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stendhal</ENAMEX>'s
On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> and a number of extraordinarily psychologically astute literary
works by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, is that such a narrow perspective is most assuredly less natural
than acquired. And it is acquired by the perpetuation of precisely the sort of
one-sided public conversation as is found at your site.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Lehrman</ENAMEX>, indeed, seems
of a feather with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>. She, too, believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s understandings
are naturally (biologically) bounded by their own limited experiences and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bodies</ENAMEX>, and that feminism must therefore focus only on that narrow swath
dictated by such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. The most frightening thing to me about all this talk
of nature and biology is that what is really being naturalized is the
marginality of female voices. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> must naturally write only of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> only of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, then feminism and femininity become the only natural
subjects for women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. Hence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX> on fashion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Lehrman</ENAMEX> on feminism, and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>" entry by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>.

            And the
rest of politics, art, and culture? Ceded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, naturally.

            
               --Garance
Franke-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ruta New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey, Hey</ENAMEX>,
Paula
            

            I disagree strongly with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s assertion in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>
Out" that, by employing renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX> to defend him
against sexual harassment charges, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has lent credence to those
charges.

            "By hiring an obscure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> contends, "or by letting his regular lawyer
handle the case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would have sent a compelling signal that [the] story
was a fantasy." Perhaps. But that strategy might best have served the president
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of public opinion, rather than in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of law. And it would
certainly not have served him adequately in the present political climate. Keep
in mind that this isn't the simple case of a wronged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> quietly making
allegations against a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, has
allowed herself to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> in a much larger and well-known political
battle--that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> bent on destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s reputation and
career. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reactionaries</ENAMEX> who have shoved
her story onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s front pages hope not only to cripple the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s ability to control the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, but weaken his
support among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women voters</ENAMEX>, who backed him overwhelmingly for re-election and
will be equally instrumental in promoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
has a plateful of historic tasks ahead of him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next four years</TIMEX>. He can
ill afford the politically motivated distractions posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> and others.
He'd have been foolhardy not to trust his defense in this case to an
experienced big gun such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Kingston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pierce Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
