
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>, Listing

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Orwell</ENAMEX>, of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, now stands accused of being an informant for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> secret
service. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press has been filled with articles
asking whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX> was a hypocrite for naming
names.

            
Revelations about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s "secret list" have been trickling out for some
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Shelden</ENAMEX> published an excellent biography that revealed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> kept a notebook listing the names of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he took to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Foreign Office</ENAMEX> disclosed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> had shared some of the names in his notebook with a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War-era</ENAMEX> outfit
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Research Department</ENAMEX>. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> last
month of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s complete works, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> volumes, we have a more complete story
of what he did, despite the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Office</ENAMEX> has yet to release the
actual list of names <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> submitted.

            Surprisingly, little of the story has been reported in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. The only prominent mention was a confused quasi-defense that
appeared on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Naftali</ENAMEX>, asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s list showed and
criticizes him for showing poor sense. The apparent point of the piece was not
to challenge his reputation but rather to argue that those who named names
did only what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> had done in a time of difficult choices. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Orwell defenders</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> have emphasized that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1949</TIMEX>, when he shared his list, he was on
his deathbed. Some have suggested he was coaxed into cooperating by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he
was in love with.

            None of
these excuses is necessary. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> did was not the pardonable act of a
dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. It was the moral act of an ethical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--right not only in the
context of the times but also in retrospect. The behavior he is now being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excoriated for</ENAMEX> was not Orwellian, in the sense of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> 's world of
inverted truth--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>-like, meaning that it was in keeping with a career
based on political courage and intellectual integrity.

            
To understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> did what he did, it's
necessary to reconstruct a bit of history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s hatred of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> communism
dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> he volunteered to go fight in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Civil War</ENAMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX>, he was a witness to, and nearly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX> purge
of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> on the left. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> not
controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>--such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POUM</ENAMEX>, for which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> fought--were being
jailed and murdered. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> tried to spill the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> about what was
happening behind the lines, he was prevented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who, though not CP
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, viewed criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> as intolerable. These included
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kingsley Martin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Statesman</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Gollancz</ENAMEX>,
who had published <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s early books. Homage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catalonia</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>),
which may be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s finest work, was finally published by the tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secker & Warburg</ENAMEX> and sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 700</NUMEX> copies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> faced the same experience
when he finished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Farm</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. Because of its
criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warburg</ENAMEX> would touch it.

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> ended, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> became preoccupied with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s power grab in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> and the way those whom he saw as dishonest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West</ENAMEX> were abetting it. With his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rees</ENAMEX>, he played a game of trying
to figure out who was what in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>-traveling constellation. In his
notebook, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> listed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX> names--with remarks about who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were, who
he guessed might be "some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>," who a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> or "crypto,"
and who merely "stupid," "dishonest," or "naïve." He missed the mark a few
times--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Steinbeck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orson Welles</ENAMEX> didn't fellow-travel very far. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> was often not just correct but also uncanny. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Smollett</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who headed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Department of the British Ministry of</ENAMEX>
Information during the war and whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> described as "almost certainly an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> of some kind," was later revealed to be, in fact, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Complete Works</ENAMEX> , believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smollett</ENAMEX> was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who talked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Cape</ENAMEX>, a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dropping Animal Farm</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> kept his private list up-to-date. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Upton Sinclair</ENAMEX>, a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, turned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Stalinist</ENAMEX> after the
war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> crossed him out.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> was not just a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> who spoke from
the sidelines. He was someone who believed in choosing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> and taking action,
even when the alternatives were imperfect. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, he was busy arguing that it
was necessary to choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in the emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.
He criticized the editorial page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> , where he wrote a
regular column, for failing to take a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> position, even though the
paper was anti-Communist. It was in the midst of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Crisis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> received a hospital visit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celia Paget</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Stalinist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Koestler</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelden</ENAMEX> recounts in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koestler</ENAMEX> had fixed Paget up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> suddenly died
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> was enough taken with her to propose marriage, rather abruptly.
Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paget</ENAMEX> refused him, they became good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

            After going to work for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRD</ENAMEX>, a department roughly analogous to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Information Agency</ENAMEX>, she asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> for help in countering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> propaganda around the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Orwell</ENAMEX>
declined the offer of a commission to write a pamphlet, in part because he was
too ill--he was suffering from tuberculosis and would be dead in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX>.
But he was happy to recommend others suited to the task, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz</ENAMEX>
Borkenau, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-Communist</ENAMEX> who wrote the best book other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Civil War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> also told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paget</ENAMEX> that there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRD</ENAMEX> should
avoid. He asked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rees</ENAMEX> to bring the notebook he kept at home to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sanitarium</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cotswolds</ENAMEX> where he was dying. From his list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX> names--not
all of which have been revealed, because some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are still
alive--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> chose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of whom he said he was fairly sure. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 
               Times published excerpts from the larger list of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">135,</ENAMEX>
even including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> had crossed off, leaving the impression that he
had submitted them all for blacklisting. The names <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> submitted are almost
certainly those marked with a red asterisk on his longer list and do not
include such familiar ones as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Spender or Michael Redgrave</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Orwell</ENAMEX>
asked that his list remain secret not because there was anything shameful about
it, but because he feared it was libelous. Where he could say the same thing
publicly, he did. Many of those on his list are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> wrote against in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> and in his "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Letter</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">for Partisan Review</ENAMEX> . There
is no analogy to the behavior of those like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX>, who named names before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Un-American Activities Committee</ENAMEX>. Kazan betrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in order to
protect himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> lost their jobs and had their lives ruined as a result.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. And they weren't his personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, they
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he believed to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of liberty. Nor were their civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liberties</ENAMEX> infringed as a result. The only consequence of appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s
list is that you weren't likely to be asked for help by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> Foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>.

            
               Did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>'s list demonstrate he was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> and anti-homosexual? If you
missed the link to the sidebar, click .
            

         
      
   
