
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMarshall Plan</ENAMEX>
            

            In his book review "How the West
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Won</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Walker</ENAMEX> makes an awkward attempt to criticize the West for its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air</ENAMEX> of superiority after victory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. Although he doesn't want to
blame <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> for fomenting and maintaining the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> or for
failing to seize supposed golden opportunities to make a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>, he
doesn't want to let them off the hook either.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> buttresses his case
with one of the poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> imaginable: Vyacheslav <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Molotov</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> cites his rants against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cultural influence
and its "economic enslavement" of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, all of which are just an echo of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> line against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marshall Plan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> didn't want any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> around
to influence anybody or to see anything, and as his puppet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Molotov</ENAMEX> chirped
along. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> repeats his words as if they were prophetic.

            As far as I can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> has no liking for these revolting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, nor for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> they
represented, which was the most disastrous social experiment in history.
Rather, he wants to complain about the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americanization of Europe</ENAMEX>: the
fast foods, the consumerism, the fake entertainment, the destruction of native
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cultures</ENAMEX>, the profiteering, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>.

            Agreed:
It is horrible. But I do not agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> was about that. To blame
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marshall Plan</ENAMEX> for the transmission of mindless high-tech adventure films
into every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is akin to blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s belief in free
speech for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and porn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> quite had those things in mind.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Kern</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Back in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arms</ENAMEX>
            

            As a fellow failed
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferberizer</ENAMEX>," I enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>'s most recent column, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Go Ahead--Sleep With</ENAMEX>
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>." But I found it curious that he ignored a relevant phenomenon
that he described so clearly in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Moral Animal</ENAMEX> : the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-offspring
conflict over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weaning</TIMEX>. This conflict is inevitable in mammalian life because
offspring seek to monopolize maternal resources as long as possible, but their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> seek to divide resources between all present and future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>.

            Sounds a little like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s
"Ferberizing" experiences to me. To be fair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> is talking about sleeping
with a newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX>, before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age</TIMEX> when weaning would naturally become an
issue. However, from my own experience, a newborn becomes a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-month-old</TIMEX> and
then an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-month-old</TIMEX> rather quickly. Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> were no less vocal in
their objections to being kicked out of our bed at those ages than when they
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>.

            Also, the resulting obstacle
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' sex life is not the incidental side effect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright</ENAMEX>
suggests. Rather it may serve to delay the conception of a rival for maternal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>--both directly (by literally coming between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indirectly</ENAMEX> (by tending to prolong breast-feeding and, therefore, to suppress
ovulation for a longer period).

            In the
end, I agree that principles of evolutionary psychology tend to support the
argument for sleeping with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX>. But those same principles also suggest
that if you choose to do so, you won't avoid the noisy battle of wills with
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>--you'll merely postpone it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Weaver</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
Family <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Lies Together, Thrives Together</ENAMEX>
            

            I was gratified to read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>'s article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Go Ahead--Sleep With Your Kids</ENAMEX>," but I think it missed the
larger point. With modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s emphasis on independence and individualism,
you might say that the early separation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> is sending a forceful
message to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that they are going to have to learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtue</ENAMEX> of self-reliance. Societies in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> sleep with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> bring
up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to be cooperative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of their social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Though I
appreciate the personal freedoms I enjoy as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>, I think our culture is
overly fearful of the dependent nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and so we try to force them
(prematurely) to be the atomized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> that industrial society
demands.

            Another
influence on this debate is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudian</ENAMEX> trend of seeing all family
relationships as sexually charged. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> implies in passing, there is a
feeling that sleeping with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is vaguely incestuous. However, incest
tends to occur among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that are distant, not ones that are intimate.
Everyday contact, in fact, seems to take away the glamour.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Reeves</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
