
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uncritical Critics</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> took the
unprecedented step <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> of refusing to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> see The
Avengers before it was released. The widespread assumption was that the
studio knew the movie was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> but was hoping to salvage a good opening
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> found out. But by locking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> out, knowing this
would be widely publicized, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> was essentially announcing to the
world that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Avengers</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. It's as futile as a restaurant
publicly refusing to allow a health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> inspection.

            Maybe it
was a big bluff. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> was trying to propitiate the film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>--a largely disgruntled and demoralized bunch. By publicly sacrificing
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avengers</ENAMEX> , a sure flop in any case, studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> flattered the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> by pretending to be deeply afraid of them. They also bolstered an
important delusion: that a movie as awful as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Avengers</ENAMEX> is the
exception and not the rule. Singling out The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avengers</ENAMEX> as terrible
implies that the other current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> releases-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon 4</ENAMEX> ,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Negotiator , and A Perfect Murder</ENAMEX>-- are not equally worthless.
Reviewers too have a stake in keeping up the pretense that most films are worth
reviewing. Were they to acknowledge that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of what comes out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is eyewash, there wouldn't be much left for most of them to do.

            You might argue that movies aren't so bad nowadays. But
that would only prove that you haven't spent much time at the multiplex this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. Here are the big <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> releases from the other major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>: The
X-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Files ; Small Soldiers ; Armageddon ; Six Days</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nights ; Something About Mary ; Ever After ; The Mask of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zorro ; Dr. Dolittle ; Mulan</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> ;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BASEketball ; Disturbing Behavior ; Madeline</ENAMEX> ; Out of
Sight ; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">H20 ; Saving Private Ryan ; The Parent</ENAMEX>
Trap ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Snake Eyes</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subtract Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> , which was
a virtuoso piece of moviemaking despite its hack storytelling, and subtract <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others that qualify as harmless fun. What you have left is a run of
formula films and glorified video games pitched to the adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.
It's not necessary to see these films to know how dismal they are, because they
are reiterations of other bad films. To be sure, there were plenty of crummy
genre films in the golden age of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>. And good ones still break through from
time to time. But it would be seriously perverse to maintain that mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> is a robust popular art form.

            The sorry
condition of popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> leaves film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in a quandary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>
argued in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> that they face a choice
of being either hucksters or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cranks</ENAMEX>. Either they declare that pablum is
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious</ENAMEX>, or they sink into chronic dyspepsia. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denby</ENAMEX> is right in
saying that these are the twin poles, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> actually fall somewhere
on the continuum between them. Relatively few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are either blurb-whores
or kvetching sourpusses. Most are simply battle-fatigued and judgment-impaired,
trapped in what has become a journalistic dead end, an untenable profession.
(My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
               's own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> whose oeuvre rises to a level beyond all pigeonholing, and he is
therefore omitted from the following analysis.)

            
Let's consider the fringes <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. In addition
to Denby at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, the legion of honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cranks</ENAMEX> includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX> of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> . These are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of widely divergent disposition. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denby</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">high-minded</ENAMEX> and dour, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane</ENAMEX> biting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kauffmann</ENAMEX> gentle and wise. But all take
basically the same approach to their job. As far as possible, they ignore
brain-rot movies and focus on independent and foreign films. At the
uncompromising extreme are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. Hoberman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Reader</ENAMEX> , who ignore the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> wasteland
almost entirely. They concentrate on obscure films, which may be wonderful but
which hardly anyone has an opportunity to see.

            Reviewing
only <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Taste of Cherry and Pi</ENAMEX> is not a viable alternative for
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. Even relatively successful independent films have no distribution
beyond big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, and if you want to see foreign films nowadays, you have to
go to festivals. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> arts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, not to mention TV and radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, understandably want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> to write about movies advertised
in their pages, movies that also happen to be the only ones average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
likely to see. The worst hucksters are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> who spend their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
on previewing junkets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. They fly <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class, stay
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons</ENAMEX>, and get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> a day for incidentals. In return, they
provide the blurbs quoted in advance newspaper ads ("An ending that will knock
your socks off"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucson Gazette</ENAMEX> ). The junketeers deliver these squibs,
which seldom appear in actual reviews, to the studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicists</ENAMEX>. In some cases,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">publicists</ENAMEX> write the blurbs themselves and find "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>" to accept
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attribution</ENAMEX>.

            Most movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> occupy a middle ground between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quixote and the Yellow Kid</ENAMEX>. Typically, they fell in love with movies when
movies were better and are trying not to notice that their love object has
shriveled into hagdom. They're not overtly corrupt, but their standards are in
a condition of collapse. They appraise poor films as good and fair films as
great. When something flawed but interesting such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> or The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Truman Show</ENAMEX> breaks through, they overpraise it in an cringe-making way.
Into this category go <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Siskel</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> , who recently
gave a rave to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armageddon</ENAMEX> ; his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sneak Previews</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>
(who calls <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Negotiator</ENAMEX> "a thriller that really hums along"); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Ansen of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Maslin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , intelligent though she is, seems headed
down this slope when she enthuses about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon 4</ENAMEX> or prostrates
herself before the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>.

            I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> theories about why
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are so uncritical--one aesthetic, the other economic. The
aesthetic explanation is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> see so many bad movies that their taste
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deteriorates</ENAMEX>. If you are forced to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> sitting through
Godzilla , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armageddon</ENAMEX> comes as a relief. The economic explanation
is that movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are really part of the movie industry. They exist to
encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to see movies in general, even if they must discourage them
from seeing some in particular. In all but a few places, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewer</ENAMEX> who
consistently pans blockbusters is likely to run into trouble with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>. Movie ads are a major source of revenue for papers and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and
TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> don't want some "elitist" reviewer
threatening that money. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> can tell you stories about the pressure on
them to be upbeat and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sontag</ENAMEX> argued in an article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> that the
decline of film quality is a demand-driven problem. What's killing cinema as an
art form is the demise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> with a taste for serious and challenging
films. If she's right, there may not be much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> can do. But it would be
nice to see them rage a little against the degradation of the medium they're
supposed to love. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to protest would be to follow the "crank" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in
acknowledging that movies such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Impact and Small Soldiers</ENAMEX>
don't require evaluation. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that wants to serve its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> well can
provide <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a paragraph-long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">capsule</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zagat</ENAMEX> -style <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> rating
instead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> should address the larger question of why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> thinks so
little of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> doesn't want The
Avengers reviewed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> should be only too happy to oblige.

         
      
   
