
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Arts Index</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> , high culture is flourishing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The evidence? In a
front-page story published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> noted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microbrews</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX> and that you can now get a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cappuccino</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alpena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>

            Though it
might shock my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, I'm not sure that better <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> measure of a civilization. But if we don't count <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starbucks</ENAMEX>, how do we
know that the arts are flourishing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>? There's some support for the
notion in a recent survey of public participation in the arts published by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>. According to numbers extrapolated from a poll,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
participate in the arts in some way. A full <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34.9 percent</NUMEX> of us went to an art
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15.6 percent</NUMEX> attended classical music concerts. From these
numbers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> has derived a figure of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">88 million</NUMEX> classical music concerts
attended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">225 million</NUMEX> art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> visits in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">163 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> points out that its <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1992</ENAMEX> numbers aren't
comparable to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> ones. Weirdly, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> survey was appended to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Crime Victimization Survey</ENAMEX>. (Has anyone in your household been mugged
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 12 months</TIMEX>? Have you been to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riverdance</ENAMEX> ?) The bleak
context may have led to underreporting. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> poll, by contrast, was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">free-standing</ENAMEX>, but one can see how it might register false positives. An NEA
survey that asks whether you like to go to the theater, opera, ballet, etc.,
subtly begs for affirmative answers. And in fact, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> increase
indicated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> is much greater than the numbers tabulated by various
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">arts-</ENAMEX>service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>--which in some cases report a decline where the NEA
sees growth.

            But the chief limitation of
using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> numbers as a proxy for the health of high culture is that it's a
demand-side picture--it captures consumption rather than production. It tells
us nothing about the quality or quantity of high culture being created in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. And in fact, the new study's upbeat tone cuts directly
against the conclusions of a report issued by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">NEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chair Jane Alexander</ENAMEX>
on her way out. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Canvas</ENAMEX> study, published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, argues that arts
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> are elitist, complacent, and largely hostile to popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>, the arts were sick. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, they're
thriving.

            Of course,
numbers can never resolve the inherently subjective question of cultural
health. For a consensus about whether a lot of masterpieces were painted or
written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, check back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years</TIMEX>. But it may be possible to come up
with a more rounded portrait of relative cultural well-being--one that takes
into account how well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> are doing as well as how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butts</ENAMEX> are in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">auditorium</ENAMEX> seats.

            To that end, I hereby initiate the 
                  Slate
                Arts
Index. This is a measure based on statistics culled from various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> that
give a clue about the health of different art forms. Here's how it works. The
baseline is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> points, composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> separate categories. It breaks down as
follows: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> points for literature, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> for music, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> for the fine arts, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> for film, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> for dance. On the basis of the numbers I've
gathered, it's hard to say how well any art form--or culture as a whole--is
doing. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, we should be able to say whether they're doing better or
worse. If the music score rises to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>, that would suggest a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>
improvement. A total tally of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">92</TIMEX> would mean an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> decline in the health
of high culture overall.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Literature</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> points)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> points--number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>
that literary books were on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> best-seller list

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">295</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> points--number of
full-length poetry titles published

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">942</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> points--number of Penguin
classics sold

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.95 million</NUMEX>)

            The only
book question on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> survey is "Have you read any literature in the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>?" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> said yes. The 
                  Slate
                literature index
derives from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more compelling factors. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>
new works of literature spent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> best-seller list in the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">295</NUMEX>, as it turns out, out of a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">780</NUMEX>. What is literature? Rather
than attempting to gauge quality, I have included all books that have literary
aspirations or are regarded as literature by most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX> , yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Partner , no. Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX>, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Hiaasen</ENAMEX>,
no. As opposed to the commonly cited figure of total book sales, this number is
a reasonable stand-in for the question of how many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are reading
nonpulp new novels. I've reserved the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> points for poetry and classic
literature. Our proxy for verse is a fairly crude one--the number of books of
poetry published. For classics, I'm using sales from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, since
Penguin keeps most of the world's great literature in print.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
points)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> points--number of opera
performances

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-97</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,397</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> points--number of opera
premieres

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-98</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> points--number of trips to
the symphony

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-97</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">31.9 million</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> points--number of new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orchestral</ENAMEX> works commissioned and performed

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-98</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">211</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> points--jazz sales as a
share of the recorded music market

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.8 percent</NUMEX>)

            The logic
here is that while the first number gives a sense of the availability of opera
as whole, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> gives a sense of whether new work is being added to
the standard repertoire. Both statistics come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera America</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> numbers, provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Symphony Orchestra League</ENAMEX>, do the same
thing with orchestral music. It would be nice to include chamber music, but
there are simply no useful statistics. Lastly, while I wasn't able to find any
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">reliable</ENAMEX> numbers on jazz performance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recording Industry Association of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> keeps track of jazz CD sales relative to other kinds of music.

            
               Fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> points)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> points--attendance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">149</NUMEX>
art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">42.7 million</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> points--number of people
employed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>, sculptors, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> printmakers

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">251,000</NUMEX>)

            Art
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> attendance is a reasonable proxy for how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are experiencing
art. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Association of Art Museum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> reports a much smaller
increase in visits than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>. Based on the constant number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> that
responded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1993 and 1996</TIMEX>, attendance rose from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37.1 million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41.3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> (for a slightly smaller sample <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>). As
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay attention to art, it's becoming easier to get by as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.
The other useful figure is the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. According
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">251,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> made their livings as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>,
sculptors, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">222,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.

            
               Theater
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> points)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> points--attendance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11.98 million</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> points--number of
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>)

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater Communications Group</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, keeps figures for
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Repertory Theater</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guthrie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steppenwolf</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">197</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>
surveyed in a forthcoming TCG study, attendance was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17.25 million</NUMEX>. However, in
the interest of having an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples-to-apples</ENAMEX> comparison in the future, I'm using
the smaller sample of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> tracked over time. In these, aggregate
attendance is up slightly over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX>--from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11.79 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11.98 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. This does not include <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> musicals, but then,
we're looking at high culture. Our other measure is the total number of
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>, also according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCG</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
points)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> points--box office
receipts for independent films as a share of total

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.8 percent</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> points--foreign film
receipts as a share of total

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.1 percent</NUMEX>)

            According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exhibitor Relations</ENAMEX>, which provides numbers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> , box office
receipts from independent films were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$239 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, out of a total of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.3 billion</NUMEX> for all films. Foreign film receipts were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$68.8 million</NUMEX>. The first
number is likely to be higher for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>--the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-to-date</TIMEX> figure is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$210</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, while the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> looks to be much lower--there being no Full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty</ENAMEX> import hit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. I'm using percentages rather than dollar
amounts so that I don't have to adjust for inflation in future. These numbers
reflect consensus trends--foreign films are barely alive, while independent
ones are flourishing.

            
               Dance (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
points)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> points--average attendance
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> largest ballet companies

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,997</NUMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> points--contract <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ballet</ENAMEX> and modern companies

            (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>)

            Dance indicators have been
falling since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Munger</ENAMEX> began keeping systematic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dance/USA</ENAMEX>. This contradicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> report, a discrepancy possibly explained by
a rise in attendance at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> performances. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> useful measures of
dance strength. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the average attendance per performance at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ballet companies</ENAMEX>, which has declined from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2,400</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,997</NUMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. The other is the average number of contract <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> at major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--which includes modern as well as ballet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. That figure was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>--up from a low of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. In other words, the dance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> has
been declining, while professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> are finding slightly more work. This
suggests philanthropy at work.

            I couldn't come up with a
plausible indicator for architecture. Nor have I devised one for criticism,
which, perhaps self-servingly, I consider to be an important component of
cultural health. Lastly, the 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts Index</ENAMEX> doesn't try to
measure--as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> survey does--how many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are actively participating
in the arts as amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>. What the

                  Slate
                index does do is establish a baseline. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next fall</TIMEX>, we should
be able to come back and say something meaningful about what kind of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arts</ENAMEX> have had. For what it's worth, I'm predicting we'll hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
