
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Geriatric
Gist
            

            Was your
primer of pop music, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Jenkins</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>," meant as a joke? I mean, really, are you
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KIDDING</ENAMEX>? Who do you think your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>?

            
               --Emily
White
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Un</ENAMEX>-coolio
            

            Why, exactly, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
publishing a primer on pop music (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Jenkins</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist"</ENAMEX>)? Is pop music a
largely undocumented phenomenon? Certainly not. We wouldn't call it "pop" if it
wasn't popular. Surely your intended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are keen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> of the world,
much like you try to present yourselves. Why, then, does pop need explaining?
You publish articles on economics, opera, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> musicals, and lexicography
without cheeky "background" pieces. It's as if you're explaining this facet of
low culture to your high-culture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>: "Let's explicate the silly art forms
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite readership</ENAMEX>."

            
Hopefully, your coming music criticism won't be so pedantic or derisive--or so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simplistic</ENAMEX> and misguided: To imply that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coolio</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gangsta's Paradise</ENAMEX>" is
celebrating violence is to admit that you haven't actually listened to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
Auburn
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s
Nakedness
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lost Fig Leaf</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s explication of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican revolution</ENAMEX>'s collapse, ignores the two
main reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will win re-election. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cynically
undermined the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> effort--tentative and modest as it was--to take care
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> nettle. His action on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> will remain a model of
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sandbagging</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and the rest of
the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> were successfully demonized. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saint</ENAMEX> and no statesman, but his early conduct as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> showed promise. He
managed to push along more of the Contract With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> than most thought he
would. He did shoot himself in the foot (e.g., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> One faux pas), but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have preferred to knife him in the back. All that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-inspired cynicism will, in the long run, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> more contempt among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> than familiarity ever did.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Peterson</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ear-</ENAMEX>itation
            

            So just
what the hell was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme"</ENAMEX> column about? Ear irrigation? Say it ain't so!
Since none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> told you, I will: Don't publish it. It is not:
interesting, funny, or newsworthy. It is: disgusting, childish, and
unnecessary. I MAY decide to pay for the witty articles and intelligent social
commentary in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> when you start charging. I promise I will NOT pay for this
kind of silliness--and I sincerely hope other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> won't, either.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
Riehm
            

            
               Willing
Executioners
            

            There is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> angle I would like to add to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> have played an active role in terrorizing and killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of another
once-stateless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenians</ENAMEX>. It is chilling to read the many firsthand
accounts of the massacres of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenians</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX> and during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Armenian</ENAMEX>
Genocide of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> were willing and extraordinarily cruel tools of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turks</ENAMEX>: another example of how nobody cares what happens to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> once it is
defined as the "other." Now it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> who are defined as the "other" by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
Cerny
            

         
      
   
