
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               Punditariat
            

            In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Readme</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
rejects my coinage of the word "punditocracy " in favor of "commentariat,"
coined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Greenfield</ENAMEX>. He says punditocracy is "clumsy," while commentariat
is "much wittier." He is in good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, but it is a hopeless battle, and he
should relent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> complained in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> that the word was "too intellectual." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> knew better
than to fight the tides of history and included the word in his political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX>, lest that weighty tome prove useless to future generations. I am
also include it. I am sorry to have to inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> of this, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> are where etymological decisions get made. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
charged only with the momentous decision of choosing whether to name new
software programs "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX>-Point-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX>" or "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>-Point-Oh."

            So while
I admire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX> battle on behalf of his witty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s sorry-ass word, I think he should stick to moral causes still worth
fighting. For instance, I hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> is being unfairly harassed by the
can't-stand-to-see-anybody-be-successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Alterman</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX>
of Innocence
            

            While I actually agree with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s main points in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 27</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Readme</ENAMEX>," one aside
disturbed me. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX> wrote, "Often in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> ... the press has brushed aside
the question of what exactly is wrong with the explanation that the situation
creates the perception of impropriety." Uhm, wasn't it none other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , who originated this line of
reasoning when castigating the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> (and later <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>) administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who had a nasty tendency to do sleazy things but avoid technical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illegality</ENAMEX>--and thus proclaim themselves "innocent"?

            While that
line of reasoning can be taken too far--and has in the most recent case with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> plots--I do believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> was right to say
that high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> should observe standards of propriety which surpass the
merely legal. I don't know why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> seems to
disagree.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer Budapest</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
replies: I'm clean. I maintained throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that "appearances"
was a dodge for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">malefactors</ENAMEX> alike. I doubt you could find a single
example of my ever having used it myself.
            

            
               Talk of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>
            

            I have enjoyed participating
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackathlon</ENAMEX>,"
but the criteria are ambiguous. The nature of the events suggests that we are
to vote on who best imitates a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial or a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Town</ENAMEX>" piece. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Gladwell</ENAMEX>'s exegesis, however,
suggests that we are to vote for the most impressive display of empty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtuosity</ENAMEX>. (Actually, I think his definition of a hack is incorrect; a hack is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who's paid by the word or line, not one to whom the rules of journalism
don't apply.)

            So, do we vote for
virtuosity in imitation or virtuosity in itself? If the former, then all the
contestants have missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> event. There is a formula for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>" pieces. First, the focus of the event (as
defined by the headline of the press release) would never be the focus of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>. It is therefore unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Karan</ENAMEX> (or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>)
would have been quoted. It is much more likely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> would
have talked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caterer</ENAMEX> or a disgruntled unknown sitting in the corner.
Also, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> would include details of clothing
unless it were to make some larger, allegorical point about the subject.

            Confusion
and uncertainty have never kept me from voting before, however.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               Camus
Snafu
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suicide</ENAMEX>
Watch," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atul Gawande</ENAMEX> makes a very poor effort. He may claim to know
something about science and policy, but he is bumbling out of his depth when it
comes to matters of philosophy.

            I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gawande</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capt. Button</ENAMEX>'s alleged suicide was a strange event indeed. However, after
ruling out addiction or mental illness, by what logic does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gawande</ENAMEX> assume that
Button--and all others who commit suicide--are not thinking rationally? Wasn't
it Camus who wrote that "the only reasonable decision a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can make is whether
or not to commit suicide"? This letter does not permit me the space to develop
a definition of rationality, to examine its compatibility with the decision to
end one's life, or to explain why it's so important that we must always be
strictly rational in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. However, I would expect exactly that from
Gawande before accepting his somewhat outlandish claim. In fact, the way
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gawande</ENAMEX> explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Button</ENAMEX>'s situation, his decision seems quite reasonable:
Assuming you have no a priori moral or religious objection to suicide and do
not greatly fear death, death seems like a rational (if not recommended)
alternative when faced with likely court-martial, professional ruin, a possible
jail term, and a very public dishonor brought upon oneself and one's
family.

            Perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gawande</ENAMEX>'s own prejudices are showing when he simply assumes that the elderly or
terminally ill, in wishing to escape from constant pain or degeneration through
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suicide</ENAMEX>, are--if not actually addicted or mentally ill--then "obviously"
irrational. Perhaps the need for rationality does not enter into the
assisted-suicide debate simply because it is taken for granted by all parties.
In the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have flirted with voluntary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euthanasia</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> must
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s (why does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gawande</ENAMEX> assume they are all
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>"?) decision is not made under the influence of addiction, mental
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gawande</ENAMEX>'s dreaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX> of "irrationality."

            -- Chet
Pager <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>

            
               Atul
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gawande</ENAMEX> replies: Though I didn't say all who commit suicide are irrational, I
did argue nearly all are. By what logic? Well, for starters, I noted that
studies show that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 90 percent</NUMEX> of suicides suffer from mental illness or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> abuse. In addition, I pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> find that an
additional group kill themselves on impulse.
            

            
               I
wasn't trying to use the word "rational" in any fancy sense. When I say most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who die by their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX> are irrational, I mean that their thinking is
usually clouded. Generally, mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> impair their thinking. If
not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are often simply caught up in circumstances and exaggerated fears,
as it appears Button was. I've seen such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> myself. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> I saw rashly
swallowed a bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> after a fight with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>. Later she thanked
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for saving her from what she called a "stupid thing to do." Is it
possible to kill yourself while thinking clearly? Yes, but it is far rarer than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pager</ENAMEX> would like to believe. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Button</ENAMEX>'s case, it's particularly doubtful given
his tendencies toward dumb, impulsive action revealed in his records.
            

            
               Playing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Percentages</ENAMEX>
            

            Regarding the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Kennedy</ENAMEX>:

            Though I
admire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX>' new book <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> , I was more
than slightly disturbed by the facile understatement from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> when
they pointed out (in reference to residential choices among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>): "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 18</NUMEX>
percent said they would move if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> came to live in great numbers. Much
other reliable polling--summarized in our book--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paints</ENAMEX> an equally reassuring
picture." We should all be aware of our diction. "Only" <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18 percent</NUMEX> is huge.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly 1</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> would relocate if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> became their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purely</ENAMEX>
on racial grounds, not class.) And other sources paint an "equally reassuring
picture"? Is this fact a "reassuring" one? Any number greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> is too
big.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               Roof
Goof
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "Signs and
Wonders" incorrectly traces the lineage of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Raising the Roof</ENAMEX>." I think you
will find that it is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> that gave birth to this sports gesture. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">musical The Pajama Game</ENAMEX> , the big dance number, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Once a Year Day</ENAMEX>," has
the lyrics "Everyone's entitled to be wild, be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, be a goof, raise the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roof</ENAMEX>," at which point the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX> raises a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX>-skyward
pump."

            I am sure
that this is not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that the theatrics of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> have crossed
over to the sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart</ENAMEX>
            

            Ecclesmachan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Deriving</ENAMEX>
High-Fiving
            

            Contrary
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "Signs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonders</ENAMEX>," credit for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> High-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> should go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1968</ENAMEX> classic The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Producers</ENAMEX> . Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX> did
not execute the maneuver, but directed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Shawn</ENAMEX>, as a flowery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> role of the fictitious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springtime</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> , to
complete the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> High-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who was giving a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> salute,
to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX> responded, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heil, Baby</ENAMEX>!" and slapped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s outstretched
right hand in the exact same manner that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, yea <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>, have done
since.

            -- L.C.
Renbaum <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Terminatour II</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judgment Day</ENAMEX>
            

            It is as
incorrect for you, as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, to refer to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
Party"--in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Is (Not Quite) Your Life</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>--as it would be
for an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to refer to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbour</ENAMEX>." Both are proper nouns
and should be spelled accordingly. In other words, you could legitimately state
that "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour Party</ENAMEX> represents the interests of organized labor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX>"
To modify the names of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to fit a localized spelling
style is to show disrespect to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of those names, and condescension to
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendell Wokingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>

            
               I Don't
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Writing Headlines, I Like Having Written Headlines</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> received several replies to a request in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme</ENAMEX>" 
               for
attribution of a quotation:
            

            When I
was a sophomore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 45 years ago</TIMEX>, I was told by my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> that "I
don't like writing, I like having written" was said by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Louis Stevenson</ENAMEX>.
I was an impressionable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lad</ENAMEX> and have believed that ever since. I have also
passed on the remark and the attribution to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. You may be hearing from some of them.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns Vestal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
