
   
   
      
         
            Paying for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX>

            If there is any art form
that cannot pay its own way, it is opera. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 18</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Friedrich Handel</ENAMEX> struggled to keep a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> going in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, opera has been sustainable only with the help of subsidies--whether
from aristocrats, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, or corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">benefactors</ENAMEX>. Even with tickets
priced <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $125</NUMEX> and higher at the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, box
office revenues make up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the cost of the show. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, tickets can cost twice as much and contribute an
even smaller share of operating budgets. I'll get to the question of why opera
costs so much in a minute. But for the moment, assume that the problem is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incorrigible</ENAMEX>. If you want to live in a society in which opera continues to
exist, you have to decide who should pay for it.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the instinctive reply is "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." But even in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with long histories of public subsidy
for culture, government support has recently drawn public fire. While opera is
the most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX> of the fine arts, it is also the most elitist. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, according to a just-published survey of participation in the arts,
fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> of the public claims to have attended an opera in the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably exaggerate about this, just as they do when asked how
often they have sex). Around the world, opera is synonymous with snobbery. Its
reputation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> was not helped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> when a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>
described the homeless in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> as "the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you step on when you
come out of the opera." Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snobs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say, let rich
snobs pay for it.

            That's essentially the system we have here. Wealthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> make up the gap between box office revenues and
operating expenses--amounting to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$223 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>. But the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do
not publicly subsidize opera (or the other arts) is, in fact, erroneous. We do
support them, quite generously, not through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>
but with a law that says contributions to charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are
tax-deductible. Studies say that a dollar contributed to opera costs the
government <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 40 and 45 cents</NUMEX> in foregone revenue. In other words, opera
benefits from the public purse to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $100 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--more
than the entire proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> budget of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>. (Why don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who
want to eliminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> ever make the point that there is a multibillion
dollar arts subsidy embedded in the tax code? Click for the answer.) The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$62</NUMEX>
million privately donated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> cost
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX>. This is less than the direct subsidy
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99 billion lire</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 million</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Scala</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>
or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87 million</NUMEX> deutsche mark (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52 million</NUMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>
Staatsoper, but is slightly more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Opera</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> gets.

            Opera
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> constantly lament the lack of direct government
support for the arts. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, faced with a new climate of
budgetary austerity (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are having to trim their deficits to join the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Monetary System</ENAMEX>) wonder how their cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> can attract
the private money that seems to flow so freely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. With opera
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> on each side of the ocean admiring the other's support system, we must
ask: Which method of subsidizing opera is preferable?

            
But first, back to the cost question. Why does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX> endemically require subsidies? The short answer is that while there's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, there are multiple performances all taking place at the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. An opera is a symphony concert, a choral recital, a play, a ballet, a
mural, and a fashion show all at once. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who work to put on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these spectacles--building the set, brushing down the wigs, turning the
crank that lowers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Giovanni</ENAMEX> down into hell--is incredible. It can take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, all of whom eat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times what normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> eat. Then there
are the supernumeraries--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spear carriers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>, etc. What would opera do
without supernumeraries? What would all those supernumeraries do without
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
who work in the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> opera <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> tend to be well paid, but not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ridiculously</ENAMEX> so. In her wonderfully gossipy new book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilia Bartoli</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella & Company</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manuela Hoelterhoff</ENAMEX> digs out some
hard-to-come-by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>. Top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,000</NUMEX> a performance, for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between nine and 12</TIMEX> performances. If you factor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> of unpaid
rehearsal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placido Domingo</ENAMEX> gets less for singing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> General <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Volpe</ENAMEX> is well paid, but not absurdly so, for
someone who runs a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 million</NUMEX>-a-year business and has to deal with
malingering divas instead of deferential corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice presidents</ENAMEX>.

            Those hoping to reduce costs run smack up against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baumol</ENAMEX>'s
Law, named for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Baumol</ENAMEX>, who first elaborated it in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>
book titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Performing Arts: The Economic Dilemma</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Baumol's Law</ENAMEX> says
that in certain sectors, productivity cannot increase. It takes the same number
of musicians the same amount of time to perform The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barber</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as it did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1816</TIMEX>. (In fact, thanks to union contracts, it actually takes
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>--you pay an orchestra big enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX> even when you
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX>.) In order for the wages of the skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> who
perform an opera to keep pace with those in other sectors of the economy, where
productivity does improve, the cost must inflate. In short, there's no
alternative to subsidy.

            Given this
state of affairs, whose system of subsidy is better? The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> model has the
advantage of being forthright: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> declares that it wants more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puccini</ENAMEX> than the market provides on its own, and it writes a check to pay for
it. Though this means that there is political oversight of artistic decisions
in theory, this structure yields considerable creative freedom in practice. But
because a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is paying most of the bill, there's less pressure to
please the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. This can encourage complacency, artistic mediocrity,
welfare dependency, and the rest--which may be why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> say the best American
operas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are now of higher quality and consistency than the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">continental</ENAMEX> ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Scorca</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera America</ENAMEX>, says that the
more he learns about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> system, the less envious of it he is.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> opera <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can't sustain the mostly empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> Scorca says he
witnessed on a recent trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. And the kind of catastrophic financial
mismanagement that has resulted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Royal Opera</ENAMEX> closing down for the
coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> is less likely when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> have to raise the money
themselves.

            
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, pleasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is
doubly important--not just because the box office take contributes a higher
percentage of overall revenues but also because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contributors</ENAMEX>, too. This incentive system keeps opera <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> lean and
hungry--and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> opera <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> filled near capacity. The need to win private
support may encourage a higher degree of artistic conservatism--too many
performances of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> pleasers like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tosca</ENAMEX> instead of works by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX>--and an overreliance on big-name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstars</ENAMEX>.
But it has the advantage of seeming fairer to culturephobes. The same
government benefit--a tax deduction for all charitable contributions--flows to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Opera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>, in
proportion to their generosity and enthusiasm. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> gets more music than the
free market would provide, and more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>.

            On
balance, I think our system of paying for opera is more rational. But then, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reading Hoelterhoff</ENAMEX>'s book will remind you, the words "opera" and "rational"
seldom belong in the same sentence.

            
               If you missed the link
on why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who want to eliminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> don't make the point that
there is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multibillion dollar</NUMEX> arts subsidy embedded in the tax code, click
.
            

         
      
   
