
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pondering Jew</ENAMEX>
            

            In his
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>"
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Liu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX> writes, "For any serious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, 'being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>'
isn't an ethnic or 'ethnocultural' identity at all, it's a religion." I believe
this to be a demonstrably false premise. Of all the major religions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX> is
the only one which insists upon a genetic test, i.e., that anyone whose mother
is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> is automatically a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, and for some sects that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of the
presumptive must be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Undeniably</ENAMEX>, membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has
been, in large part, defined by one's genes. Thus, it seems to me that the deep
concern about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of world <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewry</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost a fear that
one's gene pool might disappear, and has very little to do with religion. That
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">atheistic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> very often have the same fear lends credence to this point. The
history of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> certainly justifies this fear, but the
fact that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX> accepts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX>' false premise shows how confused many are on
this subject.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Thom</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Snide
Order
            

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> is going to
include snide comments in parentheses in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>,"
shouldn't that be reflected in the name of the section? For example: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers (and our snide comments)." I love the comments, and they expose the
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s frequent indulgence in propaganda under the pretext of reporting
news. But if part of your summarizing is commenting on the occasional lapse in
the journalistic ethics of those you are summarizing, then isn't it unethical
of 
                  Slate
                not to mention that your summaries are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">editorialized</ENAMEX>?

            I have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of

                  Slate
                since its inception, and I usually find the articles and
other pieces:

            highly informative

            well thought-out and
articulated

            very funny

            highly pretentious

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more of the above.

            Keep up
the good work.

            -- Rangarathnam
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gopu Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            
               The
Strange Case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Foster</ENAMEX> book ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Strange Case of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ruddy</ENAMEX>") is very revealing--namely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> wrote the review
without reading the book. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laughable</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamont Eugene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>

            
               Die
'Soft
            

            Whenever
you write an article about your parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that has a financial
stake in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, I think you should have the courtesy to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) keep your
comments neutral and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) make an explicit reference to the connection. I find it
a bit strange that you seem so comfortable pronouncing dismissively on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s legal battles.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graeme</ENAMEX>
McIntyre
            

            
               The
Thumb of all Fears
            

            In his "E-Mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> wrote, "Just remember: If it weren't for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>, there wouldn't
be any Windows for 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> to run on.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ingrates</ENAMEX>!"

            I believe
it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> who pioneered the concept and developed the technology. I don't
hear too many acknowledgments from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>. The accolades go to those
who make the technology accessible.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Leung</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Bursting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biobabble Bubble</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>'s critique of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bionomics</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Power</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biobabble</ENAMEX>") may be justified. In my humble opinion, however, it does a
disservice to the advancement of economic science, which I believe should move
away from excessive focus on the concepts of scarcity, trade, and money that
the founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> worked with. Instead, recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> as a biological
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entity</ENAMEX>, and recognize economic processes and phenomena as those resulting from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s interaction with the environment.

            This would lead, for
instance, to closer attention to relationships between savings and investment
and the human life cycle (rather than abstract analysis on the incentives to
defer current consumption). It would also look at many artifacts such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mansions</ENAMEX>, cathedrals, etc., as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in the competitive propagation of genes
to future generations through better nesting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> identification, etc.

            This kind
of analysis is probably much more called for than evolution. There is a lot
more to learn about current economic phenomena before exploring evolution,
which in a biological context is long-term. Also, it is likely this kind of
analysis will not support the same free-market agenda that bionomics pursues,
but then the purpose of sound science is the search for the truth, not the
support of a pre-defined agenda.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Kailor</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
