
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX>'s 2 Percent Solution
            

            Like his previous columns,
"Tax the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knickers Off Your Grandchildren</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>, took a simplistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mathematical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> with little connection to reality, extended it to absurd
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lengths</ENAMEX>, and stated that the conclusions are the only reasonable social policy.
He truly embodies the worst stereotypes of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> and radical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>.

            "If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> per capita income
manages to grow in real terms at a plausible <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> per year, then in just
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">400 years</TIMEX>, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> will enjoy a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> income of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>," he writes. Using this logic, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1597</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> should have let their economic policies be dictated by their
estimations of what would happen here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. In addition, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX> didn't
say is that no society in human history has ever sustained very rapid economic
growth for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX> goes on to berate
and insult those who disagree, using phrases like "their pathological concern
for future generations" and "an epidemic of hysteria," ending the piece with
the diagnosis of "a mild air of intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>" for those of us who
don't subscribe to his beliefs.

            In addition to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">simplistic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and the sheer arrogance of his prose, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX> spews
anti-conservationist nonsense that demonstrates a total ignorance of history.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a dozen</NUMEX> examples of man-made ecological disasters that led
to famine and widespread devastation, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a couple of</NUMEX> major
civilizations that collapsed under the weight of ecological mismanagement. I'd
bet that each famine-wracked region in history had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Landsburg</ENAMEX> who had been predicting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> economic growth for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> and
ridiculing anyone who tried to consider the consequences of their actions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One-third</ENAMEX>
of our government budget now goes to pay the interest on the debt that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> ran up just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX>. Most of that money went into
short-lived schemes that no longer have measurable benefits (if they ever did
to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>), yet the interest on that debt will dominate government
spending for the foreseeable future. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX> would have us do is pay
this interest by borrowing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more each year</TIMEX>, and continue to do so indefinitely,
or until the inevitable collapse, which he presumes would take over 400 years
to happen. His silly little savings-account example does nothing to hide the
staggering stupidity of that policy.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Schwarcz
            

            
               Tax the
Trees
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax the Knickers Off</ENAMEX>
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Grandchildren</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>, seems less like a
well-reasoned editorial on economics than a weak rationalization for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shortsightedness</ENAMEX>. He begins by suggesting that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> could
achieve growth rates reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of decades</TIMEX>, our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> would eventually be earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> a day. But it seems
misleading, verging on irresponsible, to compare the economies of the most
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> on earth to a Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> recently infused with the
newfound growth of capitalism. It's akin to saying that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX>
showed the same growth as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raptors</ENAMEX>, they'd eventually be winning more games
than they're playing.

            Based on this faulty
assumption, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX> then goes on to make the assertion that since our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are going to be so rich, they won't mind being reduced to seeing
things like trees only in photographs, and they "might prefer inheriting the
proceeds of economic development to inheriting the redwoods," anyway. But this
seems to be bred from the same kind of "intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>" he
attributes to those who would disagree with him: If economic growth is
dependent on cutting down <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, what happens when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> are gone, as he
himself concedes will eventually happen? And if we can continue at this superb
rate of growth after there are no more trees to cut, couldn't we continue with
this rate of growth by stopping the cutting now?

            He sees this "pathological
concern for future generations" carrying over to the deficit as well, and has a
similar defense of our spend-happy ways and insatiable need to consume: Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are going to be a bunch of spoiled, rich little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brats</ENAMEX>,
undeserving of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> we've been giving them.

            What if
our economy doesn't grow at the rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>'s, or even <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, but stagnates, or, God forbid, goes down despite all the cutting of taxes
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and racking up of deficits? Then, I suppose those of us who support
income redistribution wouldn't look so hypocritical and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> would
have big debts, higher taxes, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>--and be poor.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan Otto</ENAMEX>
Krider
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg Replies</ENAMEX>:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwarcz</ENAMEX> thinks that the
residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> did the right thing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1597</TIMEX> when they chose not to
worry too much about how their consumption would affect their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. He's right; it would be absurd for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
century conditions to eat less well so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
century conditions could afford an even more extravagant lifestyle.

            Replace the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th and 24 th</NUMEX> , and
you'll see that he's making the same point I am.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarcz</ENAMEX>'s statement about
rapid economic growth never lasting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a century</TIMEX> is incorrect. The world
has enjoyed rapid economic growth for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 200 years</TIMEX>; worldwide per capita
income is now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times what it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1800</TIMEX>. That growth is fueled by
technological progress, and technological progress is, if anything,
accelerating.

            On a completely separate
issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarcz</ENAMEX> confuses the effects of government spending with the effects of
government debt. Government spending consumes resources. It consumes an equal
amount of resources regardless of whether it is paid for by debt or by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taxation</ENAMEX>.

            He has in fact made the
standard freshman-economics error of viewing the interest on the debt as a
cost, without accounting for the offsetting benefit: By keeping current taxes
lower than they would otherwise be, the debt allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to have higher
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> and therefore to earn additional interest. That benefit offsets
the cost. This is not a matter of sophisticated economic theory; it is a matter
of simple arithmetic. Not even the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has the power to override
the laws of arithmetic.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krider</ENAMEX> is absolutely correct
that achieving and maintaining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> growth rates for the next 400 years
is unlikely. But that's an observation about an essentially parenthetical
remark. The thrust of my argument--and the numbers that I used in the
mathematical hyperlink--assumed a plausible growth rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>.

            Finally,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krider</ENAMEX> worries that the economy might not grow at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>, in which
case policies based on that forecast will have been mistaken. Sure. It's also
true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> might get destroyed by an asteroid in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>, in
which case all our sacrificing for future generations will look like a big
mistake. It would be silly to say that we should consume everything we've got
just because an asteroid might destroy us, and equally silly to say that
we should engage in an orgy of conservation just because economic growth
might slow to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. We make the best estimates we can and plan
accordingly.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
Donations
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>'s "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatch</ENAMEX>
Act" adopted the conventional response toward this affair: to find a way to
sweep this unseemly activity under a rug.

            The current cycle of shock
and horror about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> sleepovers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Bedroom</ENAMEX> in return for
large contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> is amusing. I remember
this same response when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Conference</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Boehner</ENAMEX>,
was caught passing out checks from tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor. Howls
of iconoclasm and protests against tainting the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> with Tammany
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall</ENAMEX> vote-buying rang then and ring now.

            The corrective response
offered by most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> to both of these events is the exact opposite of what it
should be. Rather than prohibit the solicitation of campaign contributions at
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hatch Act</ENAMEX> should be amended to designate these "hallowed
places" as the only <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> at which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> may solicit or accept a campaign
contribution. It ought to require that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> rotunda be the only
place at which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> may accept large contributions, and
that the floors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> be the only places an
individual or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> may give a large contribution to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            The law ought to also
stipulate the check(s) must be presented in a small, white canvas sack with a
large "$" sign on it. The burgeoning surveillance possibilities of microchip
technology ought to be applied toward a public good. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> at each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> should attach a tag with a microchip to each sack
that emits information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>, the recipient, and the amount of
the contribution. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> could run a stock ticker ribbon at the bottom of
the screen conveying information on the current "trades."

            Attempts
at prohibition or limiting this activity have shown the proclivity of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to simply move it underground to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> resorts
in order to skirt responsibility for its appearance. By forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to
conduct their fund raising at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> of the peoples' business, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
will have to accept responsibility for the appearance and fact of the tie
between influence and money instead of maintaining the fiction of a
separation.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Lipman</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The Check
Stops Here
            

            In reading the revealing
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hatch Act</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major issue seems to jump
out at me. We have heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> say that he has violated no
law, and that may be true, within the narrow letter of these laws. The issue
that bothers me is that, as the supposed paragon of virtue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party, why does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> apparently go to the very limit of the definition to
condone his actions?

            If it is unlawful for any
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>, save the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, and confirmed
appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, to engage in fund raising from a government building, why
do our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> choose to walk the very thin edge of legality in their political
activities?

            What
happened to the concept of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> being a shining example to the people
expected to follow? Are all now to presume that any activity we choose to
engage in is fine as long as we can find a narrow definition that appears to
exclude us from the responsibility of our actions?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
