
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               Penalizing the Prez
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s piece
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Case</ENAMEX> for Community Service for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>" advances an excellent
analysis of the political requirements for an acceptable punishment to
accompany censure, if indeed censure is chosen in lieu of impeachment. The key
point is that there must be a humbling element, without complete humiliation,
and that a purely financial penalty such as a fine would not be enough.

            One approach worth
considering is the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s post-presidential privileges. I am
thinking particularly of the post-presidential pension and office expense
allowances. Beyond any actual financial loss (which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could probably
recoup with a high-paying post-presidential job) there is likely to be a
perceived element of strong moral rebuke associated with the forfeiture of
retirement benefits. Perceived analogies would be to "rogue cops" who are not
prosecuted but must resign from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and lose their pension (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least</NUMEX> on
television). Loss of office expense allowances would carry an implicit message
that, while we don't want to force you out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, we really don't want to
hold you out as an honored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-president</ENAMEX>. Indeed, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> did not
suffer these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> penalties.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essence</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would not be forced to resign or leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, he would
suffer a penalty that is often associated in the public mind with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who
are required to resign to avoid being removed or criminally prosecuted. The
penalty, in effect, would be bad spin.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald B.</ENAMEX>
Susswein <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               Lip
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s piece "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Case</ENAMEX> for Community Service for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>": There's only one
kind of service he understands, and he has to have someone else do that!

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boals Lancaster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>

            
               Trapped
in Monicagate
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> writes in
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" entry: "And there's no question whether

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> want more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. Their e-mail says no no, but
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse clicks</ENAMEX> say yes yes." This is not a contradiction. Rather, it is an
extension of a well-known game theory model called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Prisoner</ENAMEX>'s
Dilemma."

            Take the following example:
Suppose the world consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. If both know nothing about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, then both are happy. If both have information about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, then both
are unhappy. If one has information about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, then that one is happy, but
the other one is very unhappy, since he or she is at a disadvantage. Now,
assume that information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is published. Unless the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
an agreement not to read anything about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, both defend against extreme
unhappiness by reading the info, settling for moderate unhappiness. Expand this
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and it's obvious that no agreement can hold,
especially when some of them actually do want the information.

            Our
situation is comparable to the situation 
                  Slate
                now faces about
whether to print damning information about the hypocritical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. If you
don't print it, someone else might beat you to it, and you'll have to talk
about it anyway. Does this mean that you will be happier when the information
comes out?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               Working
Relationships
            

            Considering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
defense in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politicians and Privacy</ENAMEX>" dialogue, I would add that although
I do not find invasions of privacy acceptable, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do wish to know something

            Biographical criticism is
important, not only for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> reasons that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX> expressed in his initial
argument, especially the point on hypocrisy, but for historical reasons. We
have no problem accepting biographical criteria for literature. In fact, there
is an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of criticism devoted to the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and
work. Why shouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' lives be open to examination in the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>?

            For
historical reasons, attention should be paid to the private life of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> or to the idea of the "work" as an expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s
inner being. If it turns out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> is a fraud or a hypocrite, we
should be able to know this--as long as the methods of revealing such knowledge
do not invade the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s privacy in an unfair or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>-like way.

            -- Jacque
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Paris</ENAMEX>

            
               Nuts to
Us
            

            As one
with family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> whose lives are literally threatened by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> in their
environment, I fail to find the humor in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nuttiness</ENAMEX>" on the subject
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. If you think this is amusing, think how much fun you could have with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paraplegics</ENAMEX> or muscular dystrophy issues--much bigger universe, many more
sniggering opportunities. A sad, adolescent performance you should be ashamed
of.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenny Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               Nuts to
Everyone
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Peanuts</ENAMEX> are a wonderful
source of nutrition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, for some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99 percent</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, not to
mention the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut products</ENAMEX> are easy to keep, very popular, and
generally inexpensive!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
must be responsible for determining, as early as possible, which
allergic reactions will be a part of their lives. It is absurd to rely
upon any "controlling legal authority" to do that for you!

            Peanuts
and their products are astoundingly good for us, as is the industry that keeps
them before us. Killing either on the basis of gene pool considerations for
fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of the population would be criminal.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hammond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Killer Nut</ENAMEX>
            

            Peanuts
can kill and have killed. This is not a laughing matter.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William C. Siroty</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.D. Board Certified</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allergy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ImmunologyMason</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>

            
               Really,
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>!
            

            I do not read "Dear
Prudence" as a rule. However, this morning I dipped into the column to see
if I was missing anything, and I found a letter citing a previous Prudie
column, saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> finds the appellation 'Ms.' ridiculous and crosses it
out whenever possible, believing that single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are 'Miss' and married ones
are 'Mrs.' (The nice thing about divorce is that then you get to choose between
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forms of address.)"

            Does
Prudie mean to imply that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are not equal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in this society and that
therefore it is important to know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s marital status immediately, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are allowed to remain judged for who and what they are, regardless of their
marital status? I find this inane and the title "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX>" an excellent solution to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s entry into equality in the workplace and society. I do not think it is
anyone's business whether or not I am married (I am) and have kept my "maiden"
name as many married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> now do. I am sorry to say that the Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>
column remains one I will not visit in the future and, I suspect, one that does
not have the highest ratings among the 
                  Slate
                offerings.

            -- Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtis London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
