
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Battle
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>
            

            A comment on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s
assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>'s "surely regulate [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">volleyball</TIMEX> net]
placement on beaches" ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volleyball</ENAMEX>"): As a devotee of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Mission Beach</ENAMEX>, I can attest to the growing popularity of beach
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volleyball</ENAMEX>. However, there appear to be no rules for the erection of private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nets</ENAMEX>. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> needs, it seems, are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-inch-by-4-inch</NUMEX> posts, a shovel or
post-hole digger, a net, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fluorescent</ENAMEX> orange plastic rope (to mark court
boundaries), and a ball. The problem is that, quite often, players emerge early
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> from their seashore abodes, put up a net, and then return to bed,
thus denying large sections of beach to nonplayers. I suppose that as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> proliferate, those who come to the beach to bathe in either sun or surf
will be pushed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>'s edge, and that conflict will result. Government
will then rear its ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, issue regulations, and the beach will be calmer
but more regimented. Meanwhile, anarchy reigns.

            Perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volleyball</ENAMEX> is an apt metaphor for politics, after all.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Newton</ENAMEX>

            
               Backward
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myhrvold</ENAMEX> got it wrong in "Insufficient
Funds." It isn't the content or the lack of advertising that endangers
Internet publishing. It is the old-fashioned thinking that is inbred into print
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>--and it doesn't work in the new medium (thank goodness it doesn't).
Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, you're riding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> backward as you try to build a
bridge into the past.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montgomery</ENAMEX>

            

               Apocalypse Now?
            

            I found
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Myhrvold</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Insufficient Funds</ENAMEX>" interesting, but I hope the hidden
message wasn't that you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are planning to bail out. I really find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> an
interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, informative and thought-provoking. Will you continue,
or is the end near?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan</ENAMEX>
Kossen

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> reply:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is here for the duration.
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monumental Mistake</ENAMEX>
            

            I'm
writing to complain about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Utah National Monument</ENAMEX> item in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The</ENAMEX>
Spin"--specifically about the claim that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> depend on
mining-industry revenue." The total percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s school budget supplied
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Trust Lands</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 2 percent</NUMEX>. The percentage that comes from
mining revenue is somewhat less than that. This hardly counts as dependence.
You have fallen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> to the propaganda of anti-wilderness sagebrush
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walker</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
