
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               The
Large <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Curd Giveth and the Small Curd Taketh Away</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> couldn't have
been more wrong when, in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX> column, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporate-Welfare NIMBYs</ENAMEX>," he implies, with no supporting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">documentation</ENAMEX>, that I am selective in my commitment to deficit reduction and
eliminating corporate welfare.

            Weisberg correctly notes I
am a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-sponsor</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 206</NUMEX>, a bill to establish an independent
commission to review and recommend termination of corporate-welfare subsidies.
However, he is incorrect when he states, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> sentences later, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feingold</ENAMEX>, who
is up for re-election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, carries a different tune when it comes to aid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> also poses a
rhetorical question in his column, asking if my commitment to reducing
corporate welfare "would ... include, say, federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy</ENAMEX> supports and marketing
orders for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> industry, which somehow escaped being scaled back in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1996 Farm Bill</ENAMEX>?"

            I voted against the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
Farm Bill, in large measure because it did so little to eliminate market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distortions</ENAMEX> and bring needed reform to the antiquated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milk Marketing Order</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, or MMO, to make it more reflective of supply and demand. The current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, instituted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, distorts the market, discriminates against the
dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Midwest</ENAMEX> by providing higher prices (called "distance
differentials") to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> who live far from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eau Claire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>, (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> from
which these "distance differentials" are calculated) and puts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> at an artificial competitive disadvantage. The current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMO</ENAMEX> system
survives because it is defended by powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> who are its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>.

            I have, in fact, worked hard
to create dairy-policy reform, including introducing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bills in the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Congress</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. 52</NUMEX>, which would eliminate the distance
differential in dairy pricing, and S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">322</NUMEX>, which would repeal the creation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy cartel</ENAMEX> created <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that
allows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to fix higher prices for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> in their
region.

            I have often stated that if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> cannot be reformed, it should be eliminated, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> have probably been more active than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in any other part of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in calling for deregulation of this system.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s assertion that
"federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy</ENAMEX> supports ... somehow escaped being scaled back in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> Farm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill"</ENAMEX> is also incorrect. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy</ENAMEX> supports have, in fact, been cut
dramatically. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, the price support was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13.10</NUMEX> per hundredweight (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 11</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gallons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>), and the program cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2.6 billion</NUMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>,
the price support had been reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.10</NUMEX> per hundredweight, and, while the
myth persists that the dairy program costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX>, the facts are that, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> operated at no cost to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. Moreover, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> Farm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> completely eliminates the dairy price support by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1999</TIMEX>. The
dairy industry is the only commodity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to have its support terminated by
the most recent Farm Bill. Some other commodities, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> and feed
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX>, were provided with hefty annual guaranteed government subsidies in that
same legislation.

            So exactly what is the
corporate welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> is talking about?

            Deficit
reduction and balancing the federal budget are serious, complex, and demanding
tasks, and the policy implications of our efforts reach across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, even
around the world. These efforts are not advanced by unsupported suggestions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hypocrisy</ENAMEX>, such as are contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s column.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell D.</ENAMEX>
Feingold
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg Replies</ENAMEX>
            

            Read Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feingold</ENAMEX>'s letter carefully. He does not say he wants to end corporate welfare
for dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>. He says he wants <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> to get a better deal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feingold</ENAMEX> wants to "reform," not eliminate, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milk Marketing Order</ENAMEX> system,
though he acknowledges that it constitutes a "cartel" designed to keep dairy
prices high. Sounds a lot like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIMBYism</ENAMEX> to me. I should add that I would have
been in a better position to reflect the subtleties in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Feingold</ENAMEX>'s position if
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press office</ENAMEX> had returned repeated calls asking about it.

            

               Revolted
            

            I was
revolted by the reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet Ramsay</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thank Heaven for Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larissa MacFarquhar</ENAMEX>. I felt that you were trying to capitalize
on the savage bestiality committed on a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> by whoever strangled her,
as well as the abuse committed by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, who put her on display in a
manner no 6-year-old should be forced to endure. When will publications such as
yours manage to develop some sense of human moral responsibility?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "Eight
Reasons Not to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cut the Capital-Gains Tax</ENAMEX>" truly proves the adage that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> cannot stand success.

            Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s analogy, if
we observe that we have too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bakers</ENAMEX> and not enough butchers, it is
reasonable to suggest that we ought to reduce the tax on butchers. Our rates of
saving and investment are staggeringly low, in both historical and
contemporaneous contexts. There is ample reason to believe that increasing the
rates of saving and investment would be beneficial to the economy. Hence,
reducing disincentives to save and invest (e.g., the capital-gains tax) seems
to make sense.

            The evidence that a
capital-gains tax would pay for itself is a bit stronger than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> would
care to admit. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to do something with the money
they have made as a result of realized capital gains. Either they will spend
it, in which case local sales-tax receipts will increase, or they will move it
into some other form of investment, which will be taxed in turn. Having the
government take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly one-third</NUMEX> of the amount of your investment earnings is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> too much.

            The
purpose of tax policy should be to generate income for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, so that
it can perform its necessary and essential functions, with the least distortion
and effect on the overall economy as possible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> seeks to remedy, through
the coercive power of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, those circumstances and conditions in society
that he finds troubling. I would respectfully suggest that this makes him much
more of a socialist than his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen J.</ENAMEX>
Konig
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Master</ENAMEX> of
Deceit
            

            It astonishes me that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX>, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psycho Dramas</ENAMEX>," her review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Tanenhaus</ENAMEX> biography of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker Chambers</ENAMEX>, acknowledges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> was right about everything, but
still maintains the old liberal condescension for this perennially maligned
figure. She recognizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Witness</ENAMEX> is "one of the great
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autobiographies</ENAMEX>," even a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">masterpiece</ENAMEX>," yet still regards it as
"torrential" and "lurid." She notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chambers</ENAMEX>' "susceptibility to ridicule and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parody</ENAMEX>," and concludes that "he was a pulp-fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dostoyevsky</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> he
admired above all others."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX> writes as if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>
was not really involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> conspiracy inside this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but
somehow fictionalized it. She implies that he was ridiculous for admiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dostoyevsky</ENAMEX>. Finally, and worst of all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX> prides herself for being able
to "believe ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chambers</ENAMEX>' testimony against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> without accepting his
interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet-American</ENAMEX> confrontation." She faults the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanenhaus</ENAMEX>, for sharing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX>'s viewpoint and not doubting
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>' more or less total culpability for the long disaster we call the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>." She recommends that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanenhaus</ENAMEX> should read some revisionist works
that challenge such an assumption.

            But what is her assumption?
That there was a chance for meaningful cooperation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictatorship</ENAMEX>? That its recruitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX>, a top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> present at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yalta</ENAMEX> conference (which set the conditions for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> by selling out
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>) and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> (which granted
independent votes to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> subject <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>), was an
exception, or a trifle? That the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> were really grand old
troopers with a different vision of the future?

            She should
take time from reading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">revisionist works</ENAMEX> to look at the revelations of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VENONA</ENAMEX> files, those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of intercepted telegrams from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that reveal the tip of an enormous iceberg of espionage and subversion.
She characterizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dostoyevskian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, "trying to break what he
saw as the 'invincible ignorance' of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> blinded to the 'crisis of
history' by its prosperity and misguided generous-mindedness." Here she is
right: The ignorance does indeed appear to be invincible.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kern</ENAMEX>
            

            
               In
Defense of Alexis
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s article
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Swingers</ENAMEX>" was both inaccurate and unfair when it comes
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Herman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of labor.

            Let's start with a simple,
central factual error in the first substantive paragraph about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis</ENAMEX>: "After
she left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>, she set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to advise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> on how to
comply with those [affirmative-action] regulations." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baloney</ENAMEX>. That was not why
she set up her business. She set up her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to provide advice to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>,
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, and nonprofits on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of aspects of labor and marketing
issues.

            She started this business to
see if she could make some money by making the workplace work better. This was
what she was trained to do, and what she was accomplished at. Remember, this
was at the dawn of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> era. We of the policy-wonk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> were all
a-titter about the theory of federalism, public-private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> pablum was
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> beginning to gurgle from the mouth of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, and every
program to help black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get jobs with federal help was being axed. So Alexis
hit the road, trying to help localities figure out how to get the most out of
what was left and trying to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> make more progress on hiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and marketing to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>. Her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, most lucrative, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">longest-standing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procter & Gamble</ENAMEX>--a contact she had made before
she ever entered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            But wait--that's not the
half of the misleading errors in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s paragraph. His accusation by
innuendo when it comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> needs to be spelled out. He implies
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis</ENAMEX> funneled money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> when she was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>, in exchange for
being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s largess when she went to the private sector.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> further implies that there's something wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation</ENAMEX>
Push negotiating agreements with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that included monitoring
arrangements.

            Most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> did
not involve any relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation</ENAMEX> Push. But some contracts did, and
here is how they worked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> and others spotted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX> that
there were no white-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority employees</ENAMEX> in lots of major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and
no black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX> in major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise businesses</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> realized they
had to do better or face marketplace consequences, so they set out to hire more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. They then turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis</ENAMEX> for help--sometimes at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestion</ENAMEX>, sometimes because other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had recommended her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. Her
work ended up delivering radical reductions in turnover, and that made them
more money, provided revenue for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis</ENAMEX>' business, and opened doors for women
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>.

            Now we get to the
"appearance of impropriety" card. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Market Square</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis</ENAMEX>, as a private
businessperson, provides valuable help to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX>. He gives her an
ownership stake. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> agrees nothing is illegal, but he elliptically
implies there's a problem. He implies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman</ENAMEX> later helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>--even though there is no evidence of it. He then adds in a passing shot
at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>--as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon</ENAMEX> needs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis</ENAMEX>' help.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis</ENAMEX> should be and is
proud of her career before and after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>. Apparently with
little or no knowledge of it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> chose to believe the smug, cynical
view--odd that he didn't bother to check with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. He may dislike
anyone who goes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to business and back, but to make it sound like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis</ENAMEX> is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> for likely wrongdoing is unsupportable.

            This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> of
real experience making progress on the critical problem of diversity in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workplace</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> and others are making her sound as if she's been a
product of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, all the time. That is unfair and harms her ability
to help us all later. When she talks about teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the "culture of work,"
she isn't speaking dry corporate prose, nor is she speaking the
fashion-sensitive policy prose. She's speaking with some actual experience.

            Alexis
deserves full and fair reporting and an open hearing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> committee
needs to do its job and get these issues into a forum where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> can
respond, rather than leeching them through repeated, incorrect media stories.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> needs to do his and get a full picture of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> before he chooses
to dismiss her life's work as a trip through the revolving door.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Steitz</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
