
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>)
            

            
               Green
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cheese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>
("The Dismal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientist</ENAMEX>") has done me the honor of another attack, this time for an
alleged vulgarization of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX>.

            The odd thing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
and I actually agree, more or less, on the policy question. I favor a low
interest rate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> doesn't say quite as much. But he does concede that it is
OK, intellectually speaking, to quarrel with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s judgment. This
may be the closest I'll get to having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s explicit endorsement on this
important issue, and I'll take it with pleasure.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> and I also agree that
the way to get lower interest rates is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> to cut them.
This is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Tietmayer</ENAMEX> always calls, with severe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disapproval</ENAMEX>, "the easy way out." I definitely favor the easy way out when it is
available.

            Our argument begins with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> had some contrary and different view. Krugman
seems to be saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> overlooked the importance of monetary policy to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of the interest rate. He writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> held a "liquidity
preference" theory of the interest rate, according to which, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s
version, markets for money and bonds determined the interest rate, with
monetary policy playing no visible role.

            This misrepresents <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>,
who understood central-bank powers extremely well. Among other things, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>
had wielded those powers himself, for all practical purposes, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. Later</ENAMEX>, he was a vociferous opponent of tight
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> monetary policy during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>.

            Liquidity preference, though
important in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>, is not a full theory of the interest rate. It is only a
theory of the "demand for money"--of the choice between holding illiquid bonds
and liquid cash. In order to get from money demand to a full theory of the
interest rate, you need a theory of money supply. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> was well aware of
this, and his view of the supply situation was more or less the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s
or mine. The central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> supplies the liquidity (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">money</NUMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>
demand. The terms on which it does so, combined with the demand conditions,
together determine the interest rate.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keynes</ENAMEX> therefore understood
perfectly well that a low interest-rate policy requires an accommodating
central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> increase their demand for money, then either interest
rates must rise, cutting investment, or transactions must fall, cutting output
and employment--unless the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> acts. The problem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> wrote, was
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> desire the moon"--a perfectly safe place to store their wealth.
The solution, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>' own metaphor, is to persuade them that "green cheese"
is nearly as good, and to have a green-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>--a central
bank--conveniently at hand.

            Now, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>'
interest-rate theory is not so easily written off, perhaps we should also look
again at that paradox of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX>. That argument which holds that the attempt to
raise saving will end up lowering national income, because consumption will
fall, and with it profits, output, and employment. Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> also right when
he warned against excessive saving?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> shrinks from this view.
He wants to maintain the tidy and comfortable belief, beloved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victorians</ENAMEX> of
all epochs, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX> is always a virtue. I know that he also strongly favors
a reduction in the federal budget deficit, precisely because that represents a
rise in so-called "national savings." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> agrees that such a rise in national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> might have some tendency to depress the economy, along lines of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multiplier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. But since--according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> can
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> output and unemployment, he believes that this tendency is easily
offset by cuts in interest rates to hold employment steady.

            This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> error,
in my view. It is one thing to assume that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> could in
principle always lower interest rates enough to offset the depressing effects
of tax increases and spending cuts. But, in fact, there is no assurance that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have any actual intention of behaving in this way,
nor any persuasive evidence that they have done so in the past. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s
statement that this is "simple" and "reasonable" does not make it right.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> seems to regard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologue</ENAMEX> who actually does control the unemployment rate
according to the dictates of some economic theory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> himself has
repeatedly denied this, and I believe him. I think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> is a nimble
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, no more nor less. That being so, the main reason we have high
interest rates is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> favoring them are more powerful than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> opposed. This, I believe, is the deplorable truth.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1993</TIMEX>, recall,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> took drastic action to raise "national saving" by cutting the expected
future budget deficits in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> then raised interest
rates, beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1994</TIMEX>, an action rationalized by entirely spurious
fears of inflation. The raising of interest rates went on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX>, was
never fully reversed, and actually raised federal spending on interest payments
by enough to wipe out a large part of the deficit reductions.

            That <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> experience proved
that one cannot rely on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> to offset the workings of the
paradox of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX>. That being so, excess saving is a danger, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>
warned. Analytically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>' theory is right and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s revision of it is
based on a false premise. And the way to get lower interest rates and more
investment and durable consumption spending and lower unemployment, all of
which I favor, is not to increase thriftiness or to cut deficits. The essential
thing is to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> to bring interest rates down.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> and do I agree on one
other thing. It is very hard to improve on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>, and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should read
him. When they do so, they will find that parable of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>'s cruse--a
marvelous tidbit on the rewards of vigorous consumption spending as opposed to
parsimony, niggardliness, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX>. But, speaking of vulgarity, they ought to
know that this is not from some "old folk tale," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> writes. The source
is actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible: 1 Kings 17:16</ENAMEX>. "And the barrel of meal wasted not,
neither did the cruse of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> fail."

            You'd
think a good Keynesian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> would know that.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James K. GalbraithLBJ</ENAMEX>
School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public AffairsThe University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Moneybags
            

            What a great job of compiling
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropists</ENAMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate 60"</ENAMEX>! However,
there are a couple of things I wanted addressed: Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Mellon</ENAMEX> is missing
from the list? And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Annenberg</ENAMEX>? Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafik Hariri</ENAMEX>
donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University School of Management</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for
its new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. That is a big donation from a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>.

            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">113</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Slifka</ENAMEX>, does
not belong to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> and investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slifka</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bostonian</ENAMEX> who owns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Petroleum Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>.

            Hope you
can correct the errors.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> Lo
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann Castle</ENAMEX>'s reply:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the important lessons I've learned since we started the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> project is
to be open to change, especially in an entrepreneurial effort like this one.
Another equally important message is that no matter how carefully we try to
craft categories of giving, human behavior refuses to be comprehensively
categorized. I find that reassuring.

            We didn't include the Hariri
gift because it came from a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>. There were several very large
ones made both in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. We
may consider changing that guideline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, or we may do a feature on gifts
from non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> here and abroad.

            We also decided to list gifts
only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> the actual gift was announced, not when payments were made on
previously announced pledges. This accounts for a number of missing foundation
gifts. I did not do a mailing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> (or to anyone,
for that matter) to compile the list; I've changed that procedure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. I
relied on what I could find in public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, and sometimes foundation gifts
are not as well-publicized. We were quite open about this in the Introduction to the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate 60</ENAMEX>."

            As for the background on
Slifka, I took that information straight from a news story. I have learned that
I need to verify everything and that even the most reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are
occasionally wrong.

            We will
stick with our decision to list gifts as they are announced, and won't list
gifts made to create or add to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>. Again, we may address this
type of giving in a separate feature. We will only list gifts from a private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> to an actual grantee. We are always looking for ideas of how to make
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate 60</ENAMEX>" even more useful than it has proved to be so far.

            
               In
Defense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Suburbs</ENAMEX>
            

            Attention really should be
drawn to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>'s incredible article on suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Suburbs Have</ENAMEX>
Won." If I was forced to pick <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>) favorite bit, I think I
would have to go with the equation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Starbucks</ENAMEX> coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> with
sophistication--perhaps the single most novel, irreverent idea I've ever read
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. (Not that I wouldn't be mighty tempted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s pining for "a
Merchant-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>-type movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>," mind you.) You, of course, are free to dive
in and pick your own favorite strand of drivel.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> then goes on to
explain that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> has no suburbs that are "truly hip." He doesn't favor us
with a definition of "truly hip," but he is kind enough to drop some clues:
"[A] truly hip <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> (no, that's not oxymoronic--go visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Lake Hills</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Topanga</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>), where there would be leaflets stapled
to the telephone poles and vegetarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and rave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, is completely
out of the question in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>." Never having been to either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Lake Hills</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Topanga</ENAMEX>, I can only go on the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> gives us to grasp what makes a
place "truly hip," but let me go ahead and see if I don't have the whole
picture--uh, upper-class, white, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with dreadlocks, tattoos,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nascent heroin</ENAMEX> addictions playing in bad rock bands named after legendary
1970s TV sitcoms? Bookstores with lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noam Chomsky</ENAMEX>? Loud, irony-free
discussions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irony</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burrito</ENAMEX> delivery? Am I in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX>? Close? Well, gee,
I guess if that's "truly hip," then suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> does come up sorely.

            What can I tell you? The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> suburbs are largely the product of the migration of white-ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> (and now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX>) from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who were (or are), by and large, at most one
generation removed from poverty. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who were (or are), as they say, shaped
by that experience. If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> by the standards of middle-
and upper-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASP</ENAMEX> bohemians from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle America</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Starbucks</ENAMEX> coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vegetarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>), yeah, they're going to come up short.

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s claim to fame
is that he wrote a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">408</NUMEX>-page book explaining to prep-school-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>
that many black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> used to live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, this refusal to address basic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sociology</ENAMEX> is glaring. There are a lot of awful things to be said about suburban
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> is clearly not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to make the case for or against
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> he simply does not understand. And, of course, it isn't
all bad.

            Take, for instance, oh,
food. The food here is really good. Really, really good. Turns out the rest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> isn't full of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakeries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pizzerias</ENAMEX>. And <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> and
delicatessens that cut giant chunks of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> with scary slicing machines. Not to
mention the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of fine, relatively inexpensive ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. I
realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> is partial to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>, homogenized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, but some of us are
still content to eat in independently owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. I guess we're just not
as "sophisticated."

            Then there's the matter of
our cultural influence, which is huge (and by no means entirely benign), even
if its full magnitude isn't always appreciated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nassau County</ENAMEX>
alone has given the world <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> comedians, who for better or worse, probably shape the
cutting edge of our national culture more than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>; and all the truly hip suburbs with "a patina of
sophistication" combined.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s
silly, misinformed article completely ignores issues of class and ethnicity
while presenting the giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain stores</ENAMEX> of mall <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borders, Starbucks</ENAMEX>)
and the passing trends of middle America upper-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> (leaflets on
telephone poles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglophile</ENAMEX> raves) as some sort of ideal. His problem with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suburbs of New York</ENAMEX> would seem to be that they have too much <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and not
enough <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX>. All in all--just a really dumb piece.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Langnas
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Lake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hills Is Not Hip</ENAMEX>
            

            I can't think of a more
sophisticated way to begin, so I'll just blurt it out: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Lake Hills</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>,
is in no way, shape, or form a hip suburb, no matter what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Lemann</ENAMEX> says in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Suburbs Have</ENAMEX>
Won." I'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Lake Hills</ENAMEX>. I left my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> behind when I
moved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>, but I still visit frequently, and I have to tell you,
there's not a vegetarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in sight. A notice for a rave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> would
send an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of cell-phone-waving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> into the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>'s office
and church <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX> demanding action. (After, of course, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> learned
what a rave party was.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Lake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hills</ENAMEX> is a pretty place, lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, stone, and gorgeous views of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albertson</ENAMEX>'s supermarket is great fun to shop in--good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>,
fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">herbs</ENAMEX>, and reasonably good focaccia <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>. But in all that lovely,
expensive real estate, there's no edge, no irony, no one dressed in black,
even. It's certainly no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>. Which, I suspect, is why my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> still
live there. It's also why I don't.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fresh-Brewed Influence</ENAMEX>
            

            The one
issue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James J. Cramer</ENAMEX> avoids in his article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Had Coffee With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>" is the fact that had he not given money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he would not have had the opportunity to sit next
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and discuss his stock-option idea. It's not what he may or may
not have been "shaken down" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, but what he paid for the price of
admission. Access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should be for all. Why are someone's ideas
more important than <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> because they gave money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or his
party?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Strupek</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Train in
Vain
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>'s What It Means to Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Other L-Word"</ENAMEX>),
he states, "But if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can't reroute the freight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> in a better
direction, it's hard to see how it can derail it." As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>, I feel
qualified to point out that rerouting requires new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> and a switch (not to
mention a new destination) before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> arrives. Derailing can be done with
a few common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> or tools (remove a short section of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rail</ENAMEX>), or a tow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strap</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> (simply pull the rail out of line <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few inches</NUMEX>).

            In truth, most government
"programs" actually accomplish the opposite of the goals they are intended to
achieve. Thus, welfare has created a group of permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX>, gun control
has increased gun-related crime, and the war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> has created an immensely
profitable drug trade. Weisberg incorrectly states the nonaggression principle
as "no one can use force against anyone else." The proper statement is, "No one
may initiate force against another." The difference is obvious when considering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX>.

            Also, in writing about
Libertarianism: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Primer</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boaz</ENAMEX>, he states that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boaz</ENAMEX>'s model
for this is the Internet" and asserts that "[h]e neglects, of course, the fact
that the Internet began life as a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> project." Granted, the
Internet's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DARPANET</ENAMEX>. This may be one of the (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no more than six</NUMEX>)
cases where a government project went right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DARPANET</ENAMEX> was intentionally
designed as a decentralized network in order to (as much as possible) ensure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">survivability</ENAMEX> in the event of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War III</ENAMEX>. The current Internet, still
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decentralized</ENAMEX>, has become a worldwide threat to authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, due
to the free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of ideas it allows. This explains the recent spate of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governmental</ENAMEX> (and intergovernmental) attacks on the Net.

            In all,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> displays an abysmal ignorance of what libertarianism is, and what
libertarian goals mean to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>." I suggest that he be limited to
reviewing official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> pronouncements in the future. This may be the
only <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> in which he can operate comfortably.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> Warner
            

            
               A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian Quilt</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> has it all
wrong in his review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>'s What It Means to Be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> . He takes the position that he can state and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> "What is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">libertarian?</ENAMEX>"--as though there were only "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type" of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">libertarian</ENAMEX>.

            That's no more true than
saying there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> standard by which you can call yourself a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protestant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, black, white, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, or any other philosophy or
race.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s view of what it takes to be a libertarian and survive, and hope to
have any impact and success in the current political arena, is far different
and more appropriate than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s view. Follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> and you'll be in the
sticks by yourself and getting nowhere.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Cornell</ENAMEX>
            

            
               No More
Hot <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dogs</ENAMEX>
            

            In "The Accidental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theorist</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> demonstrates his penchant for naive economic
analogies, ranging all the way back to the classical argument for free trade
that involved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>-producing economies. The fact that he recognizes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will fault him on the oversimplification of his economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">representations</ENAMEX> doesn't get him off the hook. The problem with these analogies,
and the reason they are not immediately disposed of, is that, like Afrocentrist
historical revisionism, they are so riddled with problems that one hardly knows
where to begin.

            Perhaps we could begin by
noting that the service jobs replacing manufacturing jobs (i.e., selling hot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> instead of making hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>) rarely pull the wages of the manufacturing
jobs. In his earlier work he accepts models that don't even make allowance for
the mechanisms of capitalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s disdain for evidence is alarming; I can
well hear him telling the hungry to simply eat more hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>.

            Krugman
asserts his argument through use of psychology, not economic reasoning. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Namely,</ENAMEX>
if you don't accept my argument then you are a smug, high-minded sophisticate.
He is willing to disregard the growing income inequity in this country
(illustrated in my article), among other issues, and practically admits that
changes in his playful thought experiments would come only after cataclysmic
evidence demonstrates otherwise (i.e., when they are useless). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> serves
only himself and business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> (now with its new
spin-doctoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>) that pamper him.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
Imboden
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

             

         
      
   
