
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Utilitarian Burial</ENAMEX>
            

            In your
"Egghead"
column, it is stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Bentham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> was preserved according to
his wishes. Unfortunately, as so often happens, his last wishes were not
fulfilled in accordance with his will. His wish was to have his clothed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeleton</ENAMEX> displayed, not a dressed, mummified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX>. I attach herewith the
.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bjorkland Toronto</ENAMEX>

            
               True
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Grits</ENAMEX>
            

            In his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Wattenberg</ENAMEX> refers to something slicing
through something else "like a laser through <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX>."

            The
metaphor is initially appealing, but on further examination it demands
clarification from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engineer Wattenberg</ENAMEX>. A laser strikes one as a particularly
infelicitous tool for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX>-slicing. Awkwardness aside (we're not talking laser
pen-pointers here; do we take the laser to the breakfast table or the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX> to
the laser?), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> practical difficulties arise: As the slicing begins,
some considerable quantity of steam should be produced, shielding the subject
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX> from our slicing instrument. Moreover, sliced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX> show a disconcerting
tendency toward self-healing. I'm reminded of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX>
following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX> into the (temporarily) parted <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX>. Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX>
stay sliced? I think not.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lundell Half Moon Bay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Why
Couldn't He Be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kam Ho</ENAMEX>? Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chin Fong</ENAMEX>?
            

            From "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 23</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amidst</ENAMEX> all this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Lord</ENAMEX> and his hair died. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obits</ENAMEX> fail to
clear up an abiding mystery: Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kam Fong</ENAMEX> play 'Chin <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ho</ENAMEX>'? Why couldn't he
just be 'Kam <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fong'?</ENAMEX>"

            Sorry,
but this is pretty offensive. Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuger</ENAMEX> ever have said: "Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> play 'Sol <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX>'? Why couldn't he just be 'Irving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" or
"Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Luigi Santini play 'Giuseppi Romano'</ENAMEX>? Why couldn't he just be 'Luigi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santini</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> needs an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. Can't you pay somebody else to stay up all
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to keep a lid on his, er, excesses?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Krist</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Greed
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goeth Before a Fall</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Griffin</ENAMEX> writes in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hollywood Strikes Back</ENAMEX>" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> extended an olive
branch to former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ovitz</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> declined to accept it. She then
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> might be someone whose pride exceeds his greed.

            This is an
absurd statement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> didn't engineer a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90-million</NUMEX> severance package because
he was proud of leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> or his brainchild, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creative Artists Agency</ENAMEX>. And
now that he has more money than God (or, at least, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oral Roberts</ENAMEX>), he doesn't
need <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner</ENAMEX>'s friendship. He can open a studio on his own and thumb his nose at
everyone else.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Hamburg West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hills</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               The
Troubles
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Luck of the Irish</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> makes statements that are flat-out false, and omits many
issues that are at the real root of the problems.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>
always notifies ahead of time when a bomb will be set off in a civilian
area. There is an established code just for that. He omitted this fact. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surowiecki</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish Catholics</ENAMEX> a minority he should point out that they
make up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. But <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish Catholics</ENAMEX>
have been accepted into the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            Further, there was no
mention of the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert "Basher</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bates</ENAMEX>, who took part in dozens
of murders of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>, has spent less time in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Doherty</ENAMEX>, who
was convicted of one killing. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bates</ENAMEX>' method was to beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hammers</ENAMEX> and then dismember them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butcher</ENAMEX> knives.)

            Finally, the founding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> promised to help free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4, 1778</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Franklin</ENAMEX> assured the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>, who made up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, that he
was "charged to assure you that means will be found by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental Congress</ENAMEX>
to establish your freedom." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17, 1781</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX> is
the time for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to help secure her independence."

            Had
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> kept its word, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surowiecki</ENAMEX> wouldn't have anything to lie about.

            -- M.G.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCormick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glen Oaks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
