
   
   
      
         
            E-Mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editors</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>)
            

            
               An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affair</ENAMEX>
to Not Remember
            

            In
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adultery and Boredom</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> cites a poll in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s affair would not affect
their vote. Another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> said the affair made them less likely to vote for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>. So, are the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> more likely to vote for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> because of his affair? If so, it could mean that male adulterers are
now a voting bloc that must be courted!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Raley San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>

            
               Radical
Chic
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Berman</ENAMEX> seems to suggest
in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Refractory</ENAMEX>
Ones" that the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX> is somehow analogous to the trial of
Sacco-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vanzetti</ENAMEX>, in that a misunderstood radical faction was descended upon by a
bigoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> that then executed the sacrificial lambs. While the comparison
between the modern-day "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patriot</ENAMEX> movement" to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> belongs and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">turn-of-the-century</ENAMEX> anarchist movement is worth making, the contrasts, rather
than similarities, are what stand out. For starters, there has been no public
outcry to ban or do away with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX>, as there was with the anarchists.
Certainly, there has been no public self-examination to consider the
implications of the movement. Rather, the opposite has occurred. The mass media
in general have covered the rise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> only spottily, rushing to
report the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> incidents the movement inspires and doing little to examine
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. When, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> disaster, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> asked
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to deal with the "voices of hate" that inspire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> to
action, there was no attempt to actually do so. Rather, every talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> on
the radio, it seemed, scurried to proclaim his or her innocence: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Not me</ENAMEX>! I
didn't do it!"

            The truth is, there are many
of us whose gasoline rhetoric has fueled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX>' bonfires of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>.
And we still have not stopped throwing it about with glee. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patriot</ENAMEX> movement is at the opposite end of the political spectrum. With its
roots in white supremacy and McCarthyism, the movement really represents the
rise of a genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-bred fascism--which, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berman</ENAMEX> points out, is
precisely what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">anarchists</ENAMEX> had organized to combat. I'd wager that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacco</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanzetti</ENAMEX> would be disgusted to be included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>. Finally,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanzetti</ENAMEX> probably were innocent of the murder of a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> has practically confessed to killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">168</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and maiming
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> more. And while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> have generally cheered his
route to the executioner, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at large has been strangely mute on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>'s fate. They seem to have been much more preoccupied with a certain
black <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>'s murder trial.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX>'s
main point is worth making: Executions exist not for the actual pursuit of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> but rather for wreaking vengeance. However, he should consider the fact
that this very mentality--an eye for an eye--is a large part of what drives the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, and as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> himself has recently suggested, this is what
drove him to fill a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX> truck with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> that he then set off. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacco</ENAMEX> and
Vanzetti may have been sacrificial lambs, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> appears to be reaping the
fruits of his own belief system. It may be a sickening view, but there is
something appropriately symmetrical about it.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neiwert Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               Poll
Position
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saletan</ENAMEX>'s comments in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Centrists</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressives</ENAMEX>" are more definitive than most other
observations about patently obvious things in society. But they don't change
the obsession idea-mongers and contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have with polling. As a
matter of fact, instead of focusing on polling's farcical contributions to an
enlightened society, he conveys the notion that polling is/would be credible
without the manipulations (subtle or otherwise). The universal credibility
problem with polling is that wordsmithing and mathematics don't mix, and never
will.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLuca</ENAMEX> Upper
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>

            
               Nothing
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commons</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Akst</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passive Aggressive</ENAMEX>," on
the evils of index investing, threatens to mislead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and policy wonks. There is no commons problem in index
investing. It is true that markets are efficient because securities research,
and that index <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> invest without doing research (or paying others to do
research). But as more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> invest without doing research--i.e., as markets
become less efficient--then the returns to research will increase and money
will shift away from indexing. In the commons problem, there is no reason not
to overgraze if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> is overgrazing as well. In a securities market,
if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> overgraze (i.e., engage in index investing at times when the
market is relatively inefficient), you can fleece them.

            This index-investing
question is a subset of what seemed to be a paradox in the efficient-market
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypothesis</ENAMEX> (securities research is both necessary for market efficiency and a
waste of money) that was worked out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 years ago</TIMEX> in a paper by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanford J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grossman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph E. Stiglitz</ENAMEX>, "On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impossibility</ENAMEX> of Informationally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Efficient Markets</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Am</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Econ</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rev. 393, 405</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>), and in more
accessible form in a law review article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Efficient Markets</ENAMEX>, Costly
Information, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities Research</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 NYU L. Rev. 761</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>).

            I bet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> would agree.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Law SchoolNew York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

             

         
      
   
