
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Net
Worth
            

            I
disagree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Barnes</ENAMEX>' conclusions in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search Me</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>'s dream, enabling quick and fairly easy access to a wealth of
information. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> doing research on the Web quickly learns to acquire
the proper tools for the job and, with a little imagination, can find almost
anything. I use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">initiates</ENAMEX> searches on many search engines
simultaneously and rarely fails to locate what I'm after. Also, even when a
little "search refinement" needs to be done, it is much more time efficient
than going to a library, searching there, and then bringing the information
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Most importantly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is not just about information. It is about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>. Through e-mail, one can interrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and seek out better
information.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Thornburg</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
Knot
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boaz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Privatize</ENAMEX>
Marriage" adds more confusion to a muddled debate. We need
clarification.

            Marriage is already a private
contract, and nothing keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from making their own very special
stipulations as part of a marriage contract. But the nation-state currently
functions as the enforcer of contracts, making certain rules and formalities a
practical necessity. In the absence of common rules and enforcement, people
would have to resolve conflicts on their own, which can become messy and
chaotic.

            Also, the
marriage contract includes provision of certain social services between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, the absence of which would result in excessive burdens on society.
Nothing should keep <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or more</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from signing cohabitation contracts
committing to certain mutual obligations, but whether and to what extent
community privileges should be extended to such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> is another matter.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Kailor
            

            
               An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institution</ENAMEX> by Any Other Name ...
            

            "Privatize
Marriage" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boaz</ENAMEX> disregards the importance of semantics. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gays</ENAMEX>
"demand" recognition and respect. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> enough. But they would get farther in
their agendas if they would give a little respect to conventional marriage by
letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heterosexual people</ENAMEX> keep the word marriage to themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gays</ENAMEX> should
come up with a word for their own committed relationships. Then, they would
attract more support for gaining recognition for the same kinds of legalities
that help married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Polese</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Voluntary
Spending
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trumpet Voluntary</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> misses something essential when he argues that potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteers</ENAMEX>, and in particular well-off ones, might do better to donate their
money than to actually volunteer. Someone who donates their time becomes more,
not less, likely to give money on top of that.

            Also,
increasing volunteerism has goals other than encouraging more financial
support. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> is divided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. It is possible, by choosing the right
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suburb</ENAMEX>, for middle- to upper-middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to live their lives in very
little contact with the most severe problems of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. If these people
were more directly involved, they would undoubtedly feel more connected to the
problems around them. The effect is both monetary, in that it encourages
donations, and political, in that it changes and challenges the indifference to
the poor that seems so painfully common on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political stage.

            -- Yaron
Minsky
            

            
               Blanking
Out
            

            Since I was looking forward
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s coverage of what is sure to be one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s most intelligent
movies, I found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grosse Pointe Blank</ENAMEX> , titled
"Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>," doubly disappointing. Her belabored references to '80s teen movies
serve no purpose, save to further showcase what seems to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr</ENAMEX>'s suppressed
"thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s" crush on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX>. Her actual criticisms of the film were
buried in a pointless parade of her insider knowledge of the scene behind the
movie--far worse than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX>'s emphasis on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Evanston</ENAMEX> in interviews.

            She
whines that it wasn't "developed." But the symbolism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>'s profession was
clear, and the ideas were consistent. Without having read any interviews or
reviews, I immediately grasped the film's stance on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. It gave a
funny, precise critique, without being bitter. And the movie did not exclude
those of us who did not know the real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> behind it. On the
contrary, for those of us who grew up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, it spoke with a fresh, real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> that's distressingly rare. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review, on the other hand, was
annoyingly insular and bitter.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Chihara</ENAMEX>
            

            
               A Flat
Tax on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net Worth</ENAMEX>
            

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on the
capital-gains tax between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John C. Goodman</ENAMEX>
points out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the problems in taxing income: It's hard to make it simple
and fair. That's why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX> likes the simplicity of the flat tax on income.
But that isn't fair either. There is a growing disparity between rich and poor,
but what an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> earns in any given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> may not indicate true
wealth.

            In place of the income tax, a
flat tax on net worth should be considered. First, net worth is easy to define:
assets (such as cash, real estate, and securities) minus liabilities (or debts)
equals net worth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> would be turned into an agency
whose mission would be simplified: determining the existence and value of
assets. While that is no easy task, we ought not forget that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> currently
performs this very function in administering the estate and gift tax.

            An important feature of a
flat tax on net worth is that the tax rate would be considerably lower than
that advertised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>. That is so even if the goal is to collect
the same amount of money that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> now takes in from the
individual income tax--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$588 billion</NUMEX>. But the single most compelling argument
for the imposition of a flat tax on net worth is this: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> wouldn't pay any tax at all.

            The major
arguments against the imposition of a wealth tax will be by those who argue
that it will inhibit savings and result in capital flight. But the experiences
of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> suggest that this is not true. The richest
will pay much more in taxes, but most of the rest of us will pay less. Some
will pay nothing at all. That's as it should be.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>
Ulrich
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
