
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slender Reed</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creed</ENAMEX>," only got it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> right. He is correct to identify the glibness,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guile</ENAMEX>, and style with which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> manipulates mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>, but he doesn't
point out that this masks a dark, self-serving ambition. Elevating such people
to "gifted" status puts a nice face on their hypocrisy and does very little to
improve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s expectations of its politics or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. So I only wish
that while delegitimizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">d√</ENAMEX>©cor, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> could have called
a spade a spade.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. DeLuca</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Illogical
Rigor
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Shall Inherit the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Earth?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX> continues to astound by insisting that logical
rigor requires binary choices. Once more he's taken an issue which he modeled
as a silly yes-or-no question, extended the consequences of this answer to
ridiculous lengths, and smugly pronounced the conclusions as the only logical
result. He posits that "the unconceived are like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> being held in a sort
of limbo, unable to break through into the world of the living." So life no
longer begins even at conception, as some would have it. Rather, the process is
like a giant heavenly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>-ball machine, where the bored and listless unborn
souls wait to be selected. From this dubious proposition, he deduces that we
are morally obliged to have more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> than we really want.

            Then he
uses his trademark rhetorical trick, the false absolute choice: "If we have no
obligations to those imprisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>--then it seems there can be no moral
objection to our trashing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, to the point where there will be no future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>." The truth that his assumptions try to mask is that even if you
don't assume that all potential unborn, unconceived <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> have "rights," there
is still a certainty that there will be many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> conceived and raised, and
there is no contradiction in considering their future to be important.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Schwarcz
            

            
               First
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comes Time, Then Comes Money</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
money-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-time argument in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trumpet Voluntary</ENAMEX>" all adds up nice and neatly--provided
one's time and one's money aren't intimately linked. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to spend
money on things they feel connected to. If the hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> doesn't care
about the cause, she will write fewer and smaller checks. But if she's willing
to "sacrifice" more of her time, she'll "sacrifice" more of her money.

            
Ultimately, volunteer work benefits us at least as much as those we serve. It
can bring balance and fulfillment to our lives, while providing real leadership
to some who may need motivation more than money. And, for the sake of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ledger</ENAMEX>, it benefits the bottom line as well. Get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to invest their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and the funding will follow.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Sulentic</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
