
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               
                  Mal
Appétit
               
            

            As the
managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, all I can say is, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si</ENAMEX>, you've
been holding out on us." Entertaining as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let Si Get This</ENAMEX>"
was, it bears no relation to my experiences at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>.
Either those of us who work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> outposts aren't in on the perks,
or your research was a tad out-of-date.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria von BielBon</ENAMEX>
Appétit magazineLos Angeles

            
               Negative
Action
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blacks</ENAMEX>
Only," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> appears to be all over the map. On the one hand, he
correctly diagnoses the central problem with affirmative action, which is that
it causes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>) to be favored at the expense of another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>). Yet at the same time that he admits this is unfair, he proposes
that we retain it.

            How to justify, then, the
fact that a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who has never practiced discrimination, and who never
had anything to do with the subjugation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, should be placed at a
disadvantage in relation to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less</NUMEX>-qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>? "Why should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> who did
not themselves discriminate against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> be punished for what their or
someone else's ancestors did? The answer is that it shouldn't be thought of as
punishment."

            This is
Orwellian logic at its best; it is reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> propaganda at its
worst. Despite the fact that, on its face, it is punishment, we shouldn't think
of it that way. Excuse me? Perhaps, extending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s philosophy a bit
further, we should simply declare that there is perfect equality between blacks
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> in society, even though there isn't. Why should we ignore the fact
that there is inequality between races in society? The answer is that it should
not be thought of as inequality. Seems to work for me!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Konig Roanoke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irrational Exuberance</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take This Simple</ENAMEX>
Test," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX> goes into quite some mathematical detail about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s so-called irrationality. But there's no need for woolly notions of
"regret" to explain why someone would rather have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> than a shot at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, but would rather have a shot at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> than a slightly better shot
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>.

            It's very simple, really--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> isn't worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $1 million</NUMEX>. If I receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>,
I'm rich. If I receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>, I'm rich. So the first choice should be read
as being between the certainty of being rich and a possibility of being rich.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> choice is a simple mathematical choice--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX> points out,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> is a lot more welcome than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110,000</NUMEX>.

            I'm sure
that if you asked the same questions, but divided all the amounts by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX>,
your answers would be very different.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix Salmon</ENAMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Landsburg</ENAMEX> responds: I am deluged with e-mail from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who
want help understanding my column "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take This Simple Test</ENAMEX>." In the course of
responding, I've found a much better way to explain the paradox.

            In the
original column, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snip</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snurr</ENAMEX> asked you to choose among
various gifts. Let's put those questions aside. Instead, here are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> simpler
questions:

            
               A. I'm
going to give you a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> gift. Do you prefer:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX>
There's an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">89-percent</NUMEX> chance I won't give you anything for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. There's
an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> chance I'll give you a choice of gifts. If I give you a choice of
gifts, do you prefer:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX>
There's an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">89-percent</NUMEX> chance I'll give you a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. There's an
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> chance I'll give you a choice of gifts. If I give you a choice of
gifts do you prefer:
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX>.

            I define a rational person
to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who gives the same answer to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> questions. Some rational
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> to geese, some prefer geese to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX>, but no rational
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> switches answers in going from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question to the next.

            Now replace "a duck" with
"<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>" and replace "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX>" with "a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/11</NUMEX> shot at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>." Then
Questions A, B, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> are identical to the questions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snip</ENAMEX>,
in that order. So a rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should give the same answers to the
questions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snip</ENAMEX>.

            (To see that these questions
are exactly the same as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Snip-Snap-Snurr</ENAMEX> questions, keep in mind that an
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11-percent</NUMEX> chance of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a 10/11</NUMEX> shot at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> is the same thing as a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-percent</NUMEX> chance at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX>
that, contrary to the expectations of several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, none of this has
anything to do with the fact that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> is "worth" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 5</NUMEX> times <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>; replace the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> with any other amount whatsoever and the
argument still holds.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Practice Post-Structuralism</ENAMEX>
            

            One glaring weakness of
"deconstruction" (a method of literary criticism long favored by the academic
ivory-tower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>) is that it often searches for meaning in a comparison where,
in reality, there is none. However useful in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rarefied halls</ENAMEX> of academia, it
is conspicuously ineffective in the real world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>'s comparison of
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>" ad campaign with that being conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Climate Information Project</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> Go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>") is no more than an interesting
academic exercise and a cynical misrepresentation of both the facts of the
global-climate debate and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Manufacturers</ENAMEX>.

            It is wrong to characterize
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Map</ENAMEX> ad campaign as a "use" of populism by big business. The ad
campaign is simply one way in which we are attempting to educate the public on
the effects a treaty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> would have on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who make
things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, the overwhelming majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. To lump these small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, many of which are
family-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, in with the artificial
moniker of "big business" (itself a populist tool of the left) is a disservice
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> whose efforts form the backbone of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-quarter</NUMEX> of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. These small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> would, by the very nature of their size,
feel the devastating impact that mandated carbon-based emission reductions
would have on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy to a greater degree than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAM</ENAMEX> are united in opposition to a treaty mandating emission
reductions because such a treaty would take a bite out of the budget of every
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in the form of, among other things, higher costs at the gas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pump</ENAMEX>, more expensive home heating, and lost jobs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> cannot see
its competitiveness and prosperity erode for the benefit of developing nations
that, for whatever reason, will not be required to abide by the strict
impositions of a global-climate treaty. That is a fact that bears repeating
over and over, until reason wins out over the scare tactics being employed by
environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> (and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>) in the furtherance of
their own agendas.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
