
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avant-Garde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Derriè²</ENAMEX>¥

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Weisberg</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Walking
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoHo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX>, you are received by an enormous
inflatable dominatrix lying on her back. She wears fishnet stockings and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teddy</ENAMEX> festooned with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> doll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> and holds a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX>. In other respects, the
image is that of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> kewpie doll--powdered face, braids, tassels, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">silk</ENAMEX> gown. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">irregularly</ENAMEX> shaped dirigible on which the photograph of this
amalgamated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is superimposed is connected to foot pumps. From the balcony
at entrance level, you can step down on these pumps, blowing air into the
sculpture below.

            
               Hydra

               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monument</ENAMEX>) is a self-portrait by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Bul</ENAMEX>, one of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hugo Boss Prize</ENAMEX>--a biennial competition for cutting-edge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> sponsored by the German menswear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> that takes place at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoHo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> is the most in-your-face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Her
previous works include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abortion</ENAMEX> , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> performance piece in which she
hung upside down and naked from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> ceiling, talking about her abortion
and reciting song lyrics. In another series, , she exhibited rotting fish
decorated with beads and sequins, supposedly to "create a biting satire on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s servitude in a male-dominated culture," according to the exhibition
catalog.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>'s approach and preoccupations are characteristic not
only of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX> prize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX> but of contemporary conceptual art in general.
Her work is theory driven and eschews traditional technique. It is based on the
manipulation of pre-existing images rather than the coinage of new ones. By
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appropriating</ENAMEX> and commenting on them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, like the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>
show, aims at a critique of the dominant culture. The key buzzword echoing
through the catalog is "otherness," a term borrowed from formerly trendy French
literary criticism. Minus the obscurantism, the idea is that cultural
difference--racial, sexual, and national (though never religious)--is the
fundamental and brutal truth of modern existence.

            Elsewhere on the left,
this view is at least subject to argument and criticism. Only in the art world
is radical multiculturalism an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">unquestionable</ENAMEX> dogma. There is not even a flash
of recognition of the irony that this philosophy manifests itself in a big
international art show where brings together <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> of every race,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationality</ENAMEX>, and sexual orientation to proclaim that they are despised and
ignored. But whatever the merits of essentialism as an outlook on life, its art
world <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX>, as displayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX> exhibition, are flavorless and
repetitive. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, what you have learned is that in contemporary art, "the
other" is always pretty much the same.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> has essentially ruled out conventional forms
such as painting, drawing, print-making, or sculpture, preferring art that is
"process-oriented" to art that is static. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> of the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX>
present video installations. The wonderfully named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pipilotti Rist</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> who
used to be in a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, makes--in the guise of commenting on racy music
videos--what are essentially dull racy music videos. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> submission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>
prize is an installation titled , an underwater sequence set to her own version
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Isaak</ENAMEX>'s song "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Wicked Games</ENAMEX>," which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rist</ENAMEX> sings and then shrieks.
Projected in mirror image on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> screens joined at right angles, it turns
images of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> cavorting underwater along with various objects such as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese grater</ENAMEX> and a TV set into a kind of giant vaginascope. Of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
represented, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rist</ENAMEX> is the only one who approximates a sense of humor, and it's a
fairly distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">approximation</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levity</ENAMEX> is not part of
the repertoire of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorna Simpson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> has
previously exhibited photographs of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> accompanied by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of cryptic
text. For example, a print of in a dilapidated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, one in sunglasses
with a drink, the other peering across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, bears the legend "forecasting
visibility from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>." According to the catalog, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s pictures of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women staring blankly</ENAMEX> underscore that they are "unheard in a racist,
patriarchal society." Lately, she has moved into film. Her entry in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>
prize competition is a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine minute</TIMEX> black-and-white piece titled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recollection</ENAMEX> , in which several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> conduct disjointed conversations on
the theme of forgetfulness.

            Arguably the most banal work in the show comes from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Gordon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glaswegian</ENAMEX> previously known for
having one of his forefingers tattooed completely black and taking , and
another in which he slowed down the film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psycho</ENAMEX> to a speed at which it
took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> to watch. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordon</ENAMEX> contribution is a piece of insipid text
titled , lettered in white on a blue wall. Statements such as "hot is cold"
form a kind of word palindrome that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenny Holzer</ENAMEX> seem deep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX>'s
other work is archival footage projected on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> free-standing video screens.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hysterical</ENAMEX> uses film from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> putting a
masked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> through some sort of psychological treatment.

            More inventive than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang Yong Ping</ENAMEX>, who was caught abroad during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> uprising and now lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> is also interested in
the conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> cultures but seems less enraged on the
topic than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>. His previous work has involved putting books through a washing
machine cycle and collecting live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, such as scorpions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX>, and setting them to battle in enclosures filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> art
objects. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">installation</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX> prize, the largest work in the show,
is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Saint Learns From the Spider to Weave a Cobweb</ENAMEX> . It's a
lattice of copper pipes from which hang a chair and a dozen mesh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cages</ENAMEX>. Inside
each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> is a hairy, live tarantula. The title refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taoist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ge Hong</ENAMEX>,
who wrote that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are superior to human beings." Reminiscent of the
room-filling iron <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spiders</ENAMEX> cast by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Bourgeois</ENAMEX>, it conveys the feeling of
being trapped in a philosophical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX>--and in so doing perfectly captures the
spirit of the exhibition as whole.

            Because the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> prize to be announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29</TIMEX> is for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s whole oeuvre and not the work submitted for the show, I
would award it, if forced to choose, to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kentridge</ENAMEX>, who is
known for powerful , many with anti-apartheid themes. Unfortunately, following
the vogue of conceptualism, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentridge</ENAMEX> has entered a film in the show, , which
uses animation of sketches much cruder than the ones he usually does
interspersed with documentary footage from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the apartheid era</TIMEX>. Set against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">solipsistic</ENAMEX> identity politics of the rest of the show, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentridge</ENAMEX>'s old-school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agitprop</ENAMEX> is nearly refreshing.

            It is perhaps unsurprising
that a prize endowed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Boss</ENAMEX> should end up being less about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> than
about fashion. What makes the exhibition truly dreary, however, is the pretense
that it's daring, when really it's an exercise in intellectual conformity. All
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde artists</ENAMEX> included are actually academic, both in the sense of
deriving their ideas about cultural difference from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and
in the sense that they follow the dictates of others about what art should be.
Subtract the shock value, and what you have here is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salon</ENAMEX> painting of the
1990s.

            
               If you
missed the link about the irony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Boss</ENAMEX>' sponsorship of the prize, click
.
            

         
      
   
