
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               I Kept
My <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise</ENAMEX>, Don't Keep Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distance</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue" on the Promise Keepers</ENAMEX>, between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marci McDonald</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stodghill</ENAMEX>.

            Could you
really not find a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who has a problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX>? Not
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with any qualms, or even complicated questions about a right-wing-funded
mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who want to wear the pants at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>? Next time, instead of hiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to pooh-pooh
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feminists</ENAMEX>, how about one bored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who actually believes
that equality for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is a meaningful concept. Although you wouldn't know it
from the PK publicity <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>, there are quite a few of us out here.

            -- Katha Pollitt New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Gimme
Shelter
            

            The "examples" included in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McIntyre</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax Shelters: The Video Game</ENAMEX>" incorporate some highly dubious
rate-of-return calculations. Anybody with a fundamental understanding of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> can tell you that return analysis in the absence of accompanying risk
analysis is incomplete. That's why investing in stocks (usually) pays better
than buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> bills--one outcome includes an element of unpredictability, while
the other is relatively certain.

            McIntyre, however, presents
examples in which leveraged buying of equities generates large rates of return,
and then proceeds to throw those numbers into his analysis without any
discussion of the leverage and resultant risk involved. That's preposterous--he
may as well have used an example with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> in gambling winnings from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX>.
The point is that it's the degree of leverage, not the tax shelters, generating
the large and highly volatile rates of return in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McIntyre's</ENAMEX> examples.

            In reality, it's practically
impossible to buy entirely on margin anyway, which is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McIntyre</ENAMEX> is
describing--you'd need to deposit additional funds with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX>, which
would then be included in any rate-of-return calculation. I don't dispute the
fact that tax shelters affect rates of return, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McIntyre</ENAMEX>'s decision to use
an implausible example in order to come up with some big return numbers
(ooh--evil tax shelters!) reveals his own strong bias toward income
redistribution.

            

               
                  Slate
                could have put someone with a reasonable grasp of
elementary finance and a balanced viewpoint in charge of writing a tax piece.
Too bad it chose to use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">McIntyre</ENAMEX> instead.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph Osha New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Noble
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nobels</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Porter</ENAMEX>, in his article
"Ph.D., <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thyself</ENAMEX>," draws his main conclusion by misunderstanding a basic tenet of
economic theory. His article describes profit maximization as if it were the
central behavioral assumption of economics. It isn't. Utility <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maximization</ENAMEX> is.
While they sound similar, the two principles are extremely different. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profit</ENAMEX>
Maximizer maximizes the amount of money it has. A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Utility Maximizer</ENAMEX> wants to
acquire many things, including cash, but also such things as trips to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">beach</ENAMEX>, time to watch TV, adorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX>, and (probably most important in
this case) professional prestige.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Porter</ENAMEX>
tries to both make the point that profit maximization doesn't explain all human
behavior (of course it doesn't, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> thinks it does), and that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> were not greedy enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX>'s own tastes.
Things would be simpler if only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scholes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merton</ENAMEX> had been in it for
the money: "plain old greed should be adequate to explain nearly everything in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>, because finance is about making money." OK. But associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>
studying financial markets aren't in them, only theorizing about them. Their
choice of career should have been the first sign that they have interest in
things other than money. In which case, aiming for a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> is the kind of
behavior any good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> would expect.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shill</ENAMEX>?
            

            No doubt I
am not alone in wondering if anyone from 
                  Slate
               's ownership talked
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> before releasing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>," which covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s
antitrust actions aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. Have we a conflict of interest here? How
much of the evidence against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> (anecdotal or otherwise) that is
reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> won't make it into any of the stories in

                  Slate
               ? Is online self-censorship any different from the
old-fashioned print variety? How will we know if these suspicions are
unfounded?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barde Berkeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nattering Naders</ENAMEX> of Negativity
            

            There must be something
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soothing</ENAMEX> and redemptive about publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Microsoft Menace</ENAMEX>"
shortly after getting slammed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">InfoWeek</ENAMEX> for slamming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>. Just wish
it didn't remind me of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">radio</ENAMEX>'s recurrent flirtation with conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> reconsiders its funding.

            That's
the problem with perceptions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> seemingly sponsor-serving article, and any
number of future self-flagellations are written off by a cynical, jaded public.
Where do these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get their diet of opinion, anyway?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolette Pemberton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nader</ENAMEX>
Redux
            

            In the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Links</ENAMEX>" section
following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>'s piece ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Microsoft Menace"</ENAMEX>) on why he is concerned about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s business practices, you mention how one might meet "other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bashers</ENAMEX>" at his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13-14</TIMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. I find this not-so-subtle
characterization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> as just another "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> basher" off base.

            Whether you agree with him or
not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> has been a constant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer for more than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> now, well before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> came into existence. While some would love
to attribute his current courageous (albeit quixotic) stance as some kind of
personal vendetta against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, the diversity of his actions in the past
make it plain that his concerns lie with the anti-competitive and monopolistic
practices of this or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and not with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> itself (or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>).

            I believe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> has very good reasons why we should all be concerned about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
attempts to corner the future of computing, and to belittle him with the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> basher" label is inappropriate.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter Benson</ENAMEX>
Robbinsdale, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>

            
               Yet More
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nader</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> does engage in
some anti-competitive practices, such as not allowing resellers to disclose
contract terms, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> is doing a fair job of policing
such activity. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> bashers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Love</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>
("The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
Menace") just don't get it. Any honest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> must ask a fundamental
question: What if the software business is a natural monopoly?

            A natural monopoly means
that due to the nature of the product and market, the industry will be
dominated by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. Roll the clock back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> and start over. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>
may dominate the market with OS<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> OS; even a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novell</ENAMEX> or
a Unix <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> could come out on top. But any honest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> must ask the
question: Is the market structured so that one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is likely to have a huge
market share? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX> tells us most likely, yes.

            On the supply side, for any
application, software--unlike industrial goods--is subject to "increasing
returns." This simply means that the costs of producing an application always
go down as the number sold goes up. Intuitively, consider a market of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> evenly shared between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word, WordPerfect</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmiPro</ENAMEX>. Each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> must spread out its costs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmiPro</ENAMEX> dropped out of the
market, then Word and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> could spread their costs out over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>,
and if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> dropped out, then Word can spread its costs out over all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. This result obtains because the cost of producing another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of
software is, for all practical purposes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. This doesn't necessarily mean
that costs will go down--the extra costs may be taken up by hiring more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">programmers</ENAMEX>, doing basic research, or even (gasp) in extra profits. But the
point is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> can get a large market share without engaging in any
wrongful behavior. Indeed its actions are generally consistent with consumers
doing better.

            On the demand side, software
is subject to "positive network externalities." This means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> get an
extra benefit when others are using the same software. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, I used
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmiPro</ENAMEX> because I liked the interface and features better, but I eventually gave
it up and switched to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS Word</ENAMEX>. Why? Because all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> were using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>
Word, and messily converting files back and forth just never worked that well.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that there is something illegitimate about this type of cost,
but remember, this is a real cost. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, we may not be better off with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> word processor that uses a single file format. But then again, we may
be, and it would seem the marketplace has rendered some sort of decision.

            These
considerations should give pause to those attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. Taking down
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> may simply mean exchanging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> with another. The only
other intellectually honest approach is to advocate wholesale government
regulation, a strategy that most agree would be a spectacular failure (and is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whole 'nother</ENAMEX> story).

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian McDaniel</ENAMEX>
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Journal of Law and Technology</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
