
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Get Me
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
            

            There are several odd things
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanda Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s letter ("E-Mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16</TIMEX>), but the most striking is her
reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> as "the mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." If, as she has said, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, how many are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and how many in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> were born there?
The area is the mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> who were there
before and during the invasion by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. If they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embattled</ENAMEX>, it is like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> in the West, with the invaders surrounded in
their forts by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> to whom the region belonged. We now know that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> were right and that the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> were the invading white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>.

            However,
the main questions are mixed marriage and religion. To even speak of "mixed
marriage" reveals a certain racism. There is no such thing as a "mixed
marriage," because there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> human race. A mixed marriage would be with
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>, or some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. And as for religions, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our day</TIMEX> and
age they should be forgotten except as interesting historical artifacts. The
sooner we are done with all these superstitions, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>, the better
off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> will be. Why do some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still think we should follow the
ignorant ideas of mostly illiterate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheepherders</ENAMEX> who lived <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> or more years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joss Randall</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Your
Point is Moooooooooooot
            

            In the article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamburger Hyper</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mastio</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson Foods</ENAMEX> is not at fault in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli spaz</ENAMEX>. And
while I would agree that the whole incident was overplayed, after finishing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> I'm left to conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastio</ENAMEX> is blaming ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>?!

            Actually, I suppose he is
suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranchers</ENAMEX> are to blame, since it is during their
stewardship that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> are contracted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mastio</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX> are infected. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mastio</ENAMEX>, "the real problem"
is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> to begin with, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> are fed too
close to slaughter time, causing their stomachs to burst during slaughter.

            Blaming this problem on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">farmer</ENAMEX> is nothing less than biting the hand that feeds. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> infects
much <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 2 percent to 4 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX>. So withholding infected
cattle is much easier said than done. But, more importantly, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX>
contamination occurs when fecal matter comes in contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>.
Consequently, the cause of the contamination must occur at slaughter time, not
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>.

            I do agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastio</ENAMEX>'s
general premise that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> is not fundamentally to blame. The fault lies with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s appetite for abundant and inexpensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in general,
much more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, have lost the connection between
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and health. We eat without thought to the consequences and expect the
medical industry to drop us a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> for our ills, many of which are the result
of poor nutrition.

            We have industrialized our
food systems, and continue to do so, something which classic economics says is
not possible, since economies of scale do not easily apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> production.
Yet we seem to desire cheap and anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. Rather than our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> being
handled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>, it passes through the processing and distribution
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, being handled, packed, unpacked, rehandled, packed again, transported,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unpacked</ENAMEX> and displayed, and on and on. It is a good system for dealing with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deodorant</ENAMEX>, but it is simply not a good system for dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.

            The
answer, as pointed out in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> article Mastio mentions, is
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to rely more on locally produced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, and to be willing to
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and pay more for high quality, safe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bump Madison</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wis.</ENAMEX>

            

               Resistance is Feudal
            

            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax Evasion</ENAMEX>": Of course there is a case against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>--it is a
feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> that has been continued despite the fact that we are no
longer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> and thus ought not to be forced to pay for the
privilege of working for a living. That was the lot of serfs, who were nearly
owned by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX> and whose land was owned by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX>.

            What we
ought to do to fund the proper functions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is to charge contract
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees. These would be plenty to support a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that operates
within its proper scope. The fact that you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> find all this bizarre is not
different from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> finding private ownership of television or telephone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> bizarre <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tibor R.</ENAMEX>
Machan
            

            
               What's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black and White</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Read All Over</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Kennedy</ENAMEX> was very
smooth and subtle as he laid waste to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Glass Is Not Half</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX>." I particularly liked the way he worked the book through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pessimist/optimist grinder.</ENAMEX>

            I was amused that the
Thernstroms start off with a few statistics to initiate their optimism in their
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>. This annoyed my liberal heart just enough to want to hear more from
them.

            I would
appreciate at some juncture that they drop the high-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>-and-gloves Victorianism
and come clean as to their political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliances</ENAMEX>. In a world of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> ,
it is so obvious and boring to have interlocutors priss around their hidden
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">agendas</ENAMEX>, weave intellectually dishonest tapestries, and lob decontextualized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">softballs</ENAMEX> back and forth.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Sholar</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
