
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Champagne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Champion</ENAMEX>
            

            In fixing his attentions
solely on an extreme close-up in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>," I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> may have overlooked the larger tableau. True,
if this "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant-y</ENAMEX>" type's acid remarks toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> were due to having
been caught wearing his pants in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant-y</ENAMEX>" fashion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s portrayal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Spencer</ENAMEX> as just another hypocritical, bratty royal would have
resonance.

            But that's not the case
here. Had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> pulled his focus back a bit, he may have noticed that at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time Spencer</ENAMEX> made his remarks, he was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. More importantly, there was
a funeral going on. And, rotten luck, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Loved One</ENAMEX> just happened to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. Given the setting, one could posit that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s invective
was not concerned so much with the convoluted interplay of the press with his
past peccadilloes, but rather was more driven by the unavoidable necessity of
having to plant his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in the earth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later that day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Plausible,</ENAMEX>
wouldn't you say?

            Lacking
the sophistry of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s editorial credentials, my interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>'s remarks is fairly basic. What I heard him say was: If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parasite</ENAMEX> lives, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> dies, it really can't be described as a symbiotic
relationship.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bower Dallas</ENAMEX>

            
               The
Missionary Position
            

            In your
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> titled "The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week/</TIMEX>The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>," the caption under the picture of Mother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa</ENAMEX> says,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Angel</ENAMEX>." Is this a sick joke or, I hope, a typo, because it is offensive
and wrong. With this one slip you lost complete respect and reliability by me,
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. You'd better check this out because I'm sure I'm not the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> who noticed it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shefferly Detroit</ENAMEX>

            
               Hear,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX>!
            

            I find
myself in disagreement with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hear Me</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Barnes</ENAMEX>, about the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s
VoiceType software. Although I am a poor typist, I find that I am able to type
a document much more quickly and accurately than the above-named software can
perform. Although I speak with an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> accent, my pronunciation can be
modified to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American English</ENAMEX>. Whatever I dictate is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-percent misinterpreted
by the program. The correction modification seems to have no effect. My
software definitely does not learn by its mistakes!

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw Ramona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Barnes</ENAMEX> replies:
"The product I reviewed was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM ViaVoice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VoiceType</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of voice-recognition software."
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
