
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Abuse
Redux
            

            I agree with the overarching
point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas J. Besharov</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob W. Dembosky</ENAMEX>'s article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child Abuse: Threat or</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Menace?</ENAMEX>" I am sorry that they were not given more space to flesh out the
details and evidence that support their position. I do believe that the
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIS-3</ENAMEX>) for purely political purposes--to demonize welfare reform and draw
attention away from the fact that it (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>) has no plan to
rectify the crisis that afflicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-welfare system.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Community professionals</ENAMEX> now
see more abuse and neglect because they are trained to see more. Clearly,
child-welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> want--and need--to point to bigger numbers in order
to bid for what they perceive to be diminished resources. However, there are
survey data (that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Daro</ENAMEX> and I collect) and data on homicide that
indicate strongly that it is very unlikely that there is any kind of major
increase in the rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> maltreatment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            As to whether an effort
should be mounted to get a better analysis of the report--well, the social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> in me always wants more honest data analysis. On the other hand, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, myself included, find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIS</ENAMEX> studies of such limited value
that we rarely use the data or even reference the studies beyond a cursory
mention that they have been conducted.

            On
balance, though, I think that as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is going to fall back on
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NIS-3</ENAMEX> to support anything they plan to do--and to block programs they don't
want--it is wise to push for a more honest accounting of the study.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Gellesdirector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Violence Research</ENAMEX>
ProgramKingston, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> Commune
            

            I was stunned to read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss</ENAMEX>
My <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tan Line</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Ferrigno</ENAMEX>'s insulting article about the migration of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>.

            I hate to break it to
Ferrigno, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s renaissance is not attributable to an influx of
aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> has had--and continues to have--a high quality
of life; its popularity has very little to do with economics, and a lot to do
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the surrounding environment--the beauty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>. Here, you can watch the sun's orange light reflect off snowcapped
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Rainier</ENAMEX>, or walk past <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that have been around for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
It is the threat that all this will be destroyed by commercialism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> that
worries the citizenry. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> (and others) emigrated to move away from
image and toward <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, when you walk through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pike</ENAMEX> Place
Market, there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, just local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.

            Since my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> is much too valuable to waste (I've got a little kayaking to do), I have a
request for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. I read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> because the articles are
stimulating. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrigno</ENAMEX>'s article was crap. It lacked intelligence,
introspection, and humor--it was crass, worthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmopolitan</ENAMEX> or
Star . I do have a sense of humor, but can only appreciate a joke when it
starts with a grain of truth.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cruz</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Eat My
Flannel
            

            Well, it appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrigno</ENAMEX> (see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss My Tan Line</ENAMEX>") has done well at touting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX>
presence here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. But, if he had bothered to read any history books,
he'd have discovered that a new set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> was born out of the
massive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> layoffs of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were trying their hands at anything to make a buck.

            If he'd like to assert that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> are responsible for the growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrigno</ENAMEX> had also
better take responsibility for the lack of growth-planning, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastside</ENAMEX> sprawl
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angelesifcation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puget Sound</ENAMEX>), and the lack of transportation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX>--all of which envelop the region. Maybe that's why this lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resident</ENAMEX> has decided to move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>.

            Ferrigno
has written the most pompous bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS</ENAMEX> that I've read in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Brownlow
            

            
               Grade
Deflation
            

            I was surprised and saddened
to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David M. Mastio</ENAMEX>'s article, "Give This Subsidy a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-," appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. While I
understand and support the publishing of "controversial" opinions, his take on
student loans was naive, at best.

            First, although having a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> eligible for a student loan, no prospective college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> is
dumb enough to think that the money from a loan would even approach the costs
of raising a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. This eligibility requirement does not encourage
student-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, but provides those who already have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> an opportunity to
escape the life of poverty that most teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> experience.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> takes
issue with the regulation that stipulates automatic eligibility for a student
loan after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 23</TIMEX> regardless of parental financial status. I agree that this
eligibility factor is a bad one, but for entirely different reasons. Where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">author</ENAMEX> suggests that parental financial status be offered as grounds to deny
loans to those over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>, I feel that the exact opposite should be done. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> reach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 18</TIMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should no longer be obliged to
support them financially. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> becomes an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> in
the eyes of the law, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should have the right to decide whether or not
they will continue to support their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s fears of abuse
seem pretty far-fetched--these are loans, not gifts, and will be paid back.
While default rates for student loans are high, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defaulters</ENAMEX> are not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> trying to milk the system Would you choose to pay
interest on money you already have?

            Additionally, to suggest
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who is in need of a loan should not be allowed to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
because state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are cheaper is disgustingly elitist. After all, we are
talking about loans that will be paid back. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> may cost a fair deal
more than a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community college</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> grad <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> with an education
that almost guarantees him or her a job that will equip him or her to both pay
off the loan and pay more in taxes.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, while making a somewhat convincing argument to those unfamiliar with
the realities of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, clearly has had little real-world experience
with student loans. His fears make sense in the world of words, but they are
not justified by the reality young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> face <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kahn</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dismal Ideologue</ENAMEX>
            

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economic Culture Wars":</ENAMEX>
I'm sorry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> (if I may be so bold with an old college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> of mine who's
now famous), but this article is a bunch of nonsense.

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX>, the difference
between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sets of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> himself, vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuttner</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>, etc.) is that the latter are literary, and the former, mathematical. In
the interests of simplicity, I will call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s school
"mainstream-neoclassical," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuttner</ENAMEX>, etc., the "liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>."

            I'm not on either of the two
competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. But on this issue, I would side with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that Krugman
trashes: I've never seem them use fancy lit-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">crit</NUMEX>-shit words and literary "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big</ENAMEX>
Names," except casually. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> who get into that kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postmodernism</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deidre</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald McCloskey</ENAMEX>--and some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marxists</ENAMEX>), but
they do not include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Galbraith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kuttner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Tyson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>, the targets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s imperious ire.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> seems to cast himself
as a white blood corpuscle defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of economics against the invading
pathogens of the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>.

            This kind of
establishmentarian guarding of the gates actually goes against the scientific
pretensions of economics--and its progress as a field. To see this, we have to
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> made a mistake to choose lit crit as a model for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>.

            Instead of lit crit, I would
point to very difficult fields in academia: sociology, political science,
psychology, and anthropology. They are difficult, since they deal with
difficult subjects: the complex interactions amongst those ornery creatures
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." That they cannot simply "assume away" the complications (as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> usually do) makes these subjects inherently more difficult than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physics</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dogmatism</ENAMEX> shuts out
critical thinking, preventing adaptation to new eras and events. Of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> can easily fail as a science while surviving or prospering as an
ideology. Enforced homogeneity of thought--including allegiance to mathematics
über alles --fits perfectly with the vision of economics as an
ideology.

            As a final
word on the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> vs. the mainstream-neoclassicals: The former
always cite an important historical precedent, still relevant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Back in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1930s</NUMEX>, the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in economics was one (very similar to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
toadies for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.M.F.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>) that used impeccable deductive logic to
show that mass unemployment was impossible, or temporary, or unimportant. But
along came an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> who used a somewhat vague, literary, empiricist style
to propose an alternative vision. This was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> has
his way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyneses</ENAMEX> of the future will be rejected as being outside the pale
of legitimate economics, beneath contempt.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of economicsLoyola <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marymount University</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
