
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pique</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX>
            

            Having
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>'s essay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July Esquire</ENAMEX> , I am aware of his penchant
for the witless smear. But for him to claim in his latest "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramesh Ponnuru</ENAMEX> ... sounds like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wannabe</ENAMEX>" is a truly low blow. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, I don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
underwear drawers to get my stories. Nor do I try to pass off rumors as fact. I
make a point of checking facts before criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in print. Finally, I'm
not in the habit of being photographed surrounded by kindling and tied to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>. But I suppose these are minor differences that shouldn't get in the way
of the truly important things. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> is still welcome at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> 's next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            -- Ramesh
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PonnuruNational Review</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> Is
the Word
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Franklin</ENAMEX>'s complete
misunderstanding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socratic</ENAMEX> method in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trials of Socrates</ENAMEX>"
leads him to the right conclusions for all the wrong reasons. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin</ENAMEX> writes
under the impression that, as the law is a practical art and not a science, the
Socratic method is improper. This is absurd. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socratic</ENAMEX> method is effective
only in seeking resolution to nonscientific matters: morality, justice, ethics.
Thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socratic</ENAMEX> method is extremely effective for the training of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.

            The problem is that law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> fail to practice the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socratic</ENAMEX> method. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX> never engaged more than
a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in a dialogue. Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> question-and-answer teaching is as
Socratic as slam dancing is balletic. Contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s claims, a true
Socratic method would require a student-to-faculty ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5-to-1</NUMEX> and a higher
quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
is ultimately correct; radical reforms are needed. Nevertheless, the answers
involve embracing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socratic</ENAMEX> method (it is impossible to think of anything
more radical than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-year</TIMEX> law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>),
not demeaning it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Daniel Gatti</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midvale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>

            

               Hemlock
            

            In
reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Franklin</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trials</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX>," which is subtitled, "It's worse than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexist</ENAMEX>. It's idiotic," I ask you: Isn't sexism idiotic? To what are we
comparing idiocy? A considerably audible "tsk, tsk" I send you, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer Paducah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passive</ENAMEX>
Voice
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passive Aggressive</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Akst</ENAMEX> is wrong to think that index investing is an example of the tragedy
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commons</ENAMEX>. Akst reasons as follows: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) When markets are efficient it is in
everyone's self-interest to passively invest in index funds; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) When everyone
passively invests in index funds, markets will no longer be efficient; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
Therefore, index investing leads to inefficient markets. The flaw in the
reasoning is that it is not in an individual's self-interest to invest in an
index fund if everyone else is doing so.

            Suppose that everyone invests
in an index fund. Since no one does any research, shares in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> will sell
for the same price as shares in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imafraud Gold Mining Co.</ENAMEX>--hence the evil of
index investing according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akst</ENAMEX>. But, should this situation ever occur,
anyone who does even an iota of research could make a killing by buying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock at a ridiculously low price. More generally, as the amount of
index investing increases, the return to market research increases. We need not
lose sleep, therefore, about any lack of market research.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akst</ENAMEX> is
perhaps confused by the following <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> truths: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) If everyone researches the
market, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> should passively index invest; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) If everyone passively
index invests, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> should research the market. The paradox is solved
by realizing that everyone need not follow the same strategy. Index investing
makes sense for those of us who don't have the time or inclination to closely
monitor our investments. Researching the market makes sense if you are good at
it and you are willing to do it full time. Index <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
to keep the market tolerably efficient. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> rely on index <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to
leave enough opportunity for them to make money based on their research. In
either case, no tragedy occurs.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Tabarrok Ball</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muncie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Akst</ENAMEX>
responds: It's possible that, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> has suggested in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>,"
if indexing goes far enough, the marginal returns to research will become so
great that research will pay, the market will be made efficient, and everyone
will live happily ever after. It's also possible that this will not happen. In
a world of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>, I can certainly discover, through my research, that XYZ
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX> is a great deal at a given price, but in such a world, who will pay me
the price I think I deserve? Certainly not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>. Indexing probably has
already made the stock market less efficient, simply because a growing
proportion of the money invested is now indifferent to ratios of price to
performance and other measures of value, not to mention expectations of growth.
Bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are already being subsidized in this way, and to the extent that
the larger economy is any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commons</ENAMEX>, indexing is undermining it.

            
               Girls
Just <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wanna Have Funds</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Girl, Bad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girl</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graef Crystal</ENAMEX> has some very convoluted logic at the end of his
piece. He writes: "We need a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women CEOs</ENAMEX>, and not merely because of
considerations of fairness. Those extra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will expand the supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>
and help to drive down, or at least moderate, the currently obscene levels of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> pay. I only hope those new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women CEOs</ENAMEX> are like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Sandler</ENAMEX>, rather than
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Wachner</ENAMEX>."

            How will more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women CEOs</ENAMEX>
"moderate the current levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> pay," when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> he cites in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> represent both extremes? His assumption is that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women CEOs</ENAMEX> will
manage alike. Can't we get past the gender stereotypes and just evaluate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>? Maybe he meant that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> will dilute pay, but he
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in his piece that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> wants to squeeze out more money from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">compensation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, he/she will.

            And isn't this issue more
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s culture than the gender makeup of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>? In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>
are paid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 10</NUMEX> times more than the lowest-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, it's capitalism mixed with greed run amok.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX>'s
illogical argument reflects poorly on his journalistic abilities and the
magazine.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               Dish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>
            

            I share <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>'s
disappointment in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">207 Channels</ENAMEX>" at the lack of quality programming on small
satellite dishes, but it was strangely satisfying to learn that a leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> was so thoroughly ripped off in the purchase of his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX>. Next time
any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> behave rationally, they should be forced
to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s article.

            Firstly, it's ridiculous to
spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120</NUMEX> (or any amount) on a service contract for one of these devices. Most
service contracts are scams, and this sort of solid-state consumer-electronics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gadget</ENAMEX> certainly doesn't warrant one. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350</NUMEX> to install <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these
things in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> is just plain gouging (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>, I'm guessing, is only
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). I did <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> with a drill, a
screwdriver, and a pair of pliers. And, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s "professionally"
installed dish, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> worked perfectly right away.

            But I too
wish there were more worthwhile things to watch--say, an enlightening
discussion of microeconomic theory by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield Arroyo Grande</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> responds: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Broomfield</ENAMEX> thinks it was not rational for me to have my
TV satellite dish installed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and to buy a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> service
warranty. Whether it is rational for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to make the decision I made
depends on a number of factors, including: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the physical conditions in which
the device is to be installed; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s manual dexterity; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the
alternative uses of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s time; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s risk aversion; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s tolerance for hassle; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s income; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>)
the prospective marginal tax on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s estate.

            
Considering these factors, I think that my decision was rational for me; it
might not have been rational for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX>. I am not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> who believes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> always make rational decisions, but I believe that they often
do.

            
               Chain
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fable</ENAMEX>
            

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, I wrote an article
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Jude</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> letter. I am an unwitting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on the subject--until recently I was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">th person</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> phone book, and so received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> copies of it. I started
collecting them in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bound In Chains</ENAMEX>"
says, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> estimates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> has circled the globe
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least nine</NUMEX> times." It is a curious claim. Firstly, because with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> worth of
stamps and a pen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> I could make it circle the globe another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> times all by
myself. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>, because a reading of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Jude</ENAMEX> letter reveals this
sentence: "It has been around the world <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> times."

            The
recipient of the letter is asked to make copies and send them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, who
are instructed to do the same. Eventually, the letter becomes illegible and has
to be retyped and re-photocopied. As errors are introduced and propagated, it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evolves</ENAMEX>. Names change--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> mentioned in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> copy of the letter is named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlo Daddit</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlo Laditt</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Paddit</ENAMEX>, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> his name had
mutated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grodotit</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would expect that by now the letter would have mutated
almost beyond recognition. But curiously, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> the names revert to
their original spellings. I have recent copies that are almost identical to
ones I received <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years ago</TIMEX>. Obviously, there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that
continues to publish the original letter. But who?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Aaron</ENAMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Ruffled
Feathers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> makes some
good points in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Stock Market Chicken-Counting Orgy</ENAMEX>," but relates the
arithmetic to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillions of dollars</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is a notable part of the world, there are quite a few of us who don't
live there, and we consider ourselves to have economic activity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock
market doesn't live in isolation. My investment in it breaks down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> equations, as I'm not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and didn't earn my money
there. My investments are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qualcomm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globalstar</ENAMEX>. These are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that
plan to get a lot of money from places other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, indicating
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock market includes production worldwide. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX> needs to
have a more expansive view of the world to decide whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-counted.

            Another of his points was the
variation in valuation year by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. He is quite right to question it. The fact
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, myself included, have a very rough idea of what a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is
worth, and plus or minus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> is as accurate as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can guess, though
we do our best. But on top of that, he asks what's new. Well, there is a
realization that there is a never-before-in-human-history amalgamation of human
activity and astronomical growth in creativity, with each development
propelling us faster. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the big ones, now widely recognized, is the
computer revolution. Look at his own business, publishing. I read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> for
zero marginal cost. It would have cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>.

            We are entering the golden
age of humanity, and to be a little sci-fi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can now imagine there really
might be a new form of life heaving into sight: a hybrid of organic [us] with
human-created technology. The wild blue yonder is the limit. There is no
limit.

            Watch the
Dow soar to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. And beyond. Don't forget another sneaky little
matter that is much more prosaic than human imagination and the amalgamation of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Money printing. We are not richer because of money printing,
but it does cause stock market valuations to soar. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> torture
themselves because they think there should be concomitant inflation, but they
are now starting to see that the inflation that would normally exist as a
result of such enthusiastic money printing is not happening because technology
has reduced costs and improved productivity dramatically. Basically, the money
printers are nicking off with much of the productivity improvements. It is just
another tax, though a very sneaky and well-hidden <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. In the good old German
money printing, inflation did soar. But you don't see it this time. And
won't.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX>
Winn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Auckland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
