
   
   
      
         
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hinducentric View</ENAMEX> of the World
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Humanity: Get Over Yourself</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Myhrvold</ENAMEX> was interesting to read,
but I suggest the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> did not complete his homework. Aryabhatt, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">astronomer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX>, pointed out before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copernicus</ENAMEX> did that the solar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is heliocentric, not geocentric.

            -- Debjyoti
Das

            
               Earth to
Myhrvold
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan Myhrvold</ENAMEX> needs to
reread his scientific history (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Mars</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Humanity: Get Over Yourself"</ENAMEX>). How can he seriously think of discussing
the conflict between humanity's pretensions and scientific progress (especially
in the field of biology) and not make a single mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Darwin</ENAMEX>'s
Theory of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Evolution</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myhrvold</ENAMEX> also indulges in
absurd generalizations about the scientific community. His contention that
"mainstream opinion in biology--until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>--orbited around the essential
mystery of life on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> just as surely as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ptolemaic</ENAMEX> view was lodged in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firmament</ENAMEX>" is simply not true. Has he ever heard of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Experiment</ENAMEX>,
which demonstrates how easily and quickly organic molecules (including amino
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acids</ENAMEX>) could have been synthesized in the tumultuous environment of a newly
formed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>? As for the lack of scientific speculation about forms of alien
life, why is it the result of a "taboo"? Could it be that the general
scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> finds such speculation ultimately pointless in the absence
of real data? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> has done a wonderful job of confounding "speculation" on
forms of life so far; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myhrvold</ENAMEX> is, in effect, taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to task for not
letting their imaginations run riot.

            
Scientific thought is hardly the rigid and dogmatic collection of prejudice
that this article implies. It is certainly true that "research over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> has changed the scientific view of life." But research over the 120 years
before that has changed the view of life as well (and arguably in a more
radical fashion!). Research over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 20 years</TIMEX> undoubtedly will bring
further changes to "the scientific view of life" (whatever that may mean).
Myhrvold may not realize it, but he is simply restating what "mainstream
opinion in biology" has believed for quite some time now.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
Cleaveland

            
               The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
Percent Question
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s article titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Biggest Tax Increase in History</ENAMEX>" repeats, without
challenging, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Molinari</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> takes in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of the
GDP in taxes. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> data in the "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Economic</ENAMEX>
Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>," total federal, state, and local revenues amounted to
just <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31.5 percent</NUMEX> of the GDP in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">calendar year 1994</TIMEX>. Who knows where the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
percent figure came from? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> common mistake is to count federal grants-in-aid
as state and local taxes, but that's double counting, since they're already
paid for by federal taxes. Even that mistake wouldn't get you to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
percent.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
Bakija

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color Me</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gray</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shearer</ENAMEX> refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Deavers</ENAMEX> as the éminence 
               cerise of the
convention "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>." As a registered pedant, I cannot refrain from posing this
political trivia question: Who was the original éminence 
               grise on
whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s word play is based? If this is too easy, consider this bonus
question: Who was the éminence 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rouge</ENAMEX> ? Hint: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>, mutatis
mutandis, would be a natural candidate for the title of "éminence
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blanche</ENAMEX> ."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glen</ENAMEX>
Tomkins

            

               Bootleg
            

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> is an old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quarterback</ENAMEX>, I would liken the grip the "new" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> thought has on reality
to the football feeling here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama/Auburn</ENAMEX> game time. It's
the "let's throw out the records because this is a different game" mentality
("The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Supply-Side Virus Strikes Again</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>). While that may be fine
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, it sure is a bizarre way to run a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The record does count
when it comes to jobs, taxes, and feeding your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> use up their eligibility. It seems the supply-side virus
allows the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to keep playing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX>, never forcing them to
graduate.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
Pennington

            
               Supply
Snide
            

            I'm surprised that any time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of supply-side economics refer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for
support, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> don't mention the exponential growth of the budget
deficit during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX> ("The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Supply-Side Virus Strikes Again</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>).

            How can
anybody defend the supply-side theory by citing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>? In discussions of the
supply-side experience during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> era, I rarely hear anyone speak up
about the deficit spending that accompanied the tax cuts.

            --Kam
Thakker

         
      
   
