
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Queer
Numbers
            

            A few points to additionally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bolster Walter Olson</ENAMEX>'s excellent "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gays</ENAMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>":

            As the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fact Sheet</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>," put out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California at Davis</ENAMEX>, points out, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
District <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchmeyer</ENAMEX> concluded in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> decision that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> had perjured
himself to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buchmeyer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> hardly seems to be a source on
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtue"</ENAMEX> himself, should be relying.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticizes Cameron</ENAMEX>'s findings that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> experience "shockingly high rates of
violent death." There may actually be a grain of truth to this conclusion, but
it is not the kind that does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron or Bennett</ENAMEX> any good. Over the last several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, incidents of gay-bashing have gone up across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. There is no
doubt that this is due, at least in part, to the increasingly poisonous
rhetoric of homophobic hatemongers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue Readers</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>
            

            Thanks for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gays</ENAMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>," a clear and timely example of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> will manipulate the most far-fetched data on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX>
to serve their bigoted interests. Sadly, even mainstream media <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">routinely parrot</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gay</ENAMEX>-newspaper studies as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of all gay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Yet no reputable
news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> or political pundit would dare get away with using, say,
Vogue- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> surveys to make a point about all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
attitudes. It's refreshing to see 
                  Slate
                doing simple math as
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> snooze and bigots take advantage of them.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant</ENAMEX>
Lukenbill
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
