
   
   
      
         
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reviewers Reviewed" Reviewed</ENAMEX>
            

            Your
regular column "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment" bears the subtitle "Reviewers reviewed</ENAMEX>"
but, in fact, it does not resemble the "review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>" that used to run
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spy</ENAMEX> as much as it resembles a "review revue" (a title previously used
by the paper I work for, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stranger</ENAMEX> , when we condensed reviews from
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> , and
others into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-word blurbs to run in a table atop our film listings). The
summaries read as rather uncritical, so you're not really reviewing them. Don't
you think?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
Fredrickson
            

            
               Where Do
You Want to Go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>?
            

            The
inaugural "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webhead"</ENAMEX> column (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Push Me, Pull You</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Barnes</ENAMEX>), while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">informative</ENAMEX>, is nothing more than an extraordinarily long advertisement for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. So much for the vaunted independence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> from its benevolent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Kersten</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Generation Screwed</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s stated
refusal to participate "in the deadening conformity of the culture [of]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberspace</ENAMEX>" takes an unusual form in his article "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>: From Ponzi
Scheme to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Game</ENAMEX>." Perhaps I'm the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> out here who thinks
Generation<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-X</ENAMEX> bashing has lost its sheen of originality, but that's just what
Kinsley indulges in with his reference to the "particular generational
self-pity" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gen-Xers</ENAMEX>.

            Hell, if my ire at forced
participation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> program is self-pity, then sign me
up--particularly if that might somehow allow me to get out.

            I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions for the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. First, is it a mandate[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d</ENAMEX>] savings
program? OK, fine--simply provide me with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> reports on the yield of the
fund and the value of my share in it. (It's totally unlikely that the
government could invest as successfully as I could with my own money, but never
mind that.)

            Or, is it a transfer payment
to the less-fortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fine</ENAMEX>, then simply means test it. (I'd prefer to
help poor old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> by contributing to charities of my choice, but never
mind.)

            However, as it stands, my
hard-earned cash is simply being handed directly over to retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, many
of whom are much better off than I am--and I'm never going to see dollar one of
a payout from this so-called "investment." What the hell is that?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is a Ponzi
scheme, but it's even worse: It's a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DISsavings</ENAMEX> plan--and it is
robbery. Forget privatization and other attempts to "save" the program.
Mandated retirement savings was a bad idea that has seen a disastrous and
immoral implementation. Let me out of the cursed scam now, and I'll forfeit
every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> I've contributed thus far.

            I'll even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wink</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Generation-X</ENAMEX> bashing.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Fuchs</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Selfish</ENAMEX>
Prohibitionists
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Politics of the</ENAMEX>
Drug <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson Morley</ENAMEX> doesn't tell the whole story of the absolute
failure of prohibition. I didn't find his conclusions surprising, but here are
the brutal facts of modern prohibition:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Drug arrests are at record
levels and rising. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1.5 million</NUMEX> drug arrests in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. This
figure is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent</NUMEX> higher than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX> higher than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has continued the hysteria.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Marijuana arrests by state
and local law enforcement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> totaled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">588,963</NUMEX>. This is the highest level of
pot arrests ever recorded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, and represents an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18 percent</NUMEX> increase
above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1994</NUMEX> arrests. The total number of pot arrests under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who
supposedly "didn't inhale" is an astounding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,450,751</NUMEX>!

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Of these arrests, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 86</NUMEX>
percent were for simple possession, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 14 percent</NUMEX> were for
sale/manufacture. One pot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> is now arrested <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every 54 seconds</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, yet adolescent-use rates are still rising!

            I'm not sure what more even
needs to be said in this case. Saying, "It's not working" seems to induce the
"OK, Let's Spend (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax</ENAMEX>) Even More" response. "Let's Spend (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax</ENAMEX>) Even
More" is indeed a popular argument, and it's well funded by the diverse
industries spawned by the hysteria. Corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> don't exist only in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>, and they are far from being the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of
prohibition.

            These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all very much fear the world of personal freedom I propose. Their
arguments usually have to do with the morality of letting others make their own
(occasionally stupid) choices, without government intervention. Deep down,
though, most of them aren't thinking about other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
