
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               No
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luddites</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pawns</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Kasparov</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX>
match, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> characterizes a perceived backlash against technology as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX> thinking." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX> hardly sees any threats to humanity
arising from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX>'s battle for greatest chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX>.
afford to see the world in such simplified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luddite</ENAMEX> terms.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX> embraces
technological innovation. In addition to giving us lifesaving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> and
better products, science and technology are improving our ability to live in an
economically robust <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> using environmentally sound business practices. We
depend on scientific methods and technology to assess the changing conditions
of our planet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> and technology are the tools that provide us with
methods such as bioremediation for cleaning up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> spills, and data on the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who breathe polluted air.

            What does
merit our suspicion is a blind faith in the ability of machines and chemicals
to make up for the destruction of the natural environment that ensures
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humankind</ENAMEX> has the clean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, air, and abundant resources we need to
survive.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Werbach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra ClubSan Francisco</ENAMEX>

            
               A Shade
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gray</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pay Scales in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black and White</ENAMEX>" ignores the simple fact that racism is nonrational.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managers</ENAMEX> do not say to themselves, "I am going to ignore the qualifications of
this black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> even though it will hurt my bottom line." Rather, a racist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> does not even see those qualifications.

            Landsburg
would do well to remember that, while mathematics is a wonderfully consistent,
logical system of symbols, those very characteristics greatly limit its
usefulness in describing the decisions we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> make on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis. A
computer may have beat a human at chess, but we have yet to make a computer
that is capable of even the most basic human emotions that guide us.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terry Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vital Middle</ENAMEX>
            

            I found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landsburg</ENAMEX>'s piece "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pay Scales in Black and White</ENAMEX>" extremely unconvincing. Saying that
discrimination is not widespread in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> because it wouldn't be in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s best interest is like saying that waste in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must
not exist because it would be politically embarrassing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>
don't make hiring, promotion, and salary decisions for the vast majority of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. These decisions are made by middle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, who are free to indulge their prejudices, regardless of a
calculation of what's best for the corporate bottom line.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
Ciccarello <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kirkland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            
               Outer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Economics</ENAMEX>
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pay Scales in Black</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>'s back-of-the-envelope "proof" that
discrimination doesn't exist (in any serious form) runs up against the hard
fact that research shows it to exist. This is another example of abstract
economic theory ignoring reality. After all, such calculations would prove that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> never prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, that they
never goof off on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and that they never waste money in general,
because all these things would reduce their market performance.

            It is a
shame that at this stage you would cite <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> . It has been, by
now, thoroughly discredited by a panel of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psychological</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> and by several studies that reanalyzed the very same National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longitudinal Survey of Youth</ENAMEX> data that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> did--studies by,
among others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Winship</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> led by myself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of psychologists
you mention who endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX> of a
now-anachronistic subfield in psychology, and are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude S. Fischer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Vacuum
Cleaning
            

            While I do not presume to
speak for all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, I am sure that the vast
majority of us are not endeared to an otherwise excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webzine</ENAMEX> that insists
on printing quasi-intellectual racist nonsense from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>, such
as his latest article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pay Scales in Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>."

            Landsburg attempts, by
economic sleight of hand, to argue that racism does not exist in corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> because it would not be in its bottom-line interest for it to do so. By
making racism into some financial decision on the part of rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
is not only wrong, but insulting. This sort of scientific objectivism is one of
the major failures of applying the scientific method to economics. He sees the
problem in a vacuum, instead of attempting to look at the entire picture.

            The
majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> can't afford the same lifestyles and education as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> because they have not been allowed the opportunities in the past to take
advantage of good jobs and good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> must remember that they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, not physicists (although they stole all of their mathematics
from physics), that the representative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> does not exist in the real world,
and that they must adjust their analysis accordingly. I do not mean that racism
must be assumed and then disproved, although the track record of corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> would almost make this allowable, but that assumptions must be
thoroughly examined for all implications before even the first result is
paraded about like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>'s new clothes.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Christopher</ENAMEX>
Appling
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landsburg</ENAMEX> replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Terry</ENAMEX> has missed the point completely. Of
course racism is nonrational. The point is that nonrational behavior
becomes less likely as it becomes more expensive. So to determine the
likelihood of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> discrimination, it's certainly relevant to figure out
how expensive it is. If the answer were "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of corporate profits,"
irrational racism would be pretty plausible. Because the answer is "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150 percent</NUMEX>
of corporate profits," the plausibility falls dramatically.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Ciccarello</ENAMEX> has a more
interesting observation, which is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who make hiring decisions in
large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> might not have the interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> or the shareholders
foremost in their minds. The question then is whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> would be likely to take action to improve the performance of
middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. And again, the answer depends on how expensive it is to
ignore such improvements. Nobody is claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> operate
rationally or efficiently all the time. The claim is that irrational and
inefficient behavior is more likely to disappear when it is very expensive--and
in this case it is very expensive.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude S. Fischer</ENAMEX>'s bald
assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> discrimination has been shown to be a significant
factor in explaining black/white wage differentials is false. I note that he
gives no citations.

            In the same deceptive spirit,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischer</ENAMEX> claims that a similar calculation would indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> never
prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, or that they never goof off on the golf
course--even though he makes no attempt to supply that calculation. I do not
believe he can do so. There is no doubt that nepotism and golfing are costly,
but to suggest that they are costly at anything like the level of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150 percent</NUMEX>
of corporate profits is just ridiculous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> also to my citing
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> , despite the fact that I did not cite it with
approval.

            Finally,
while I'm reluctant to respond to anybody who thinks that the laws of
arithmetic can be "quasi-intellectual racist nonsense," I note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appling</ENAMEX> switches sides in the middle of his letter. By citing differences in
educational opportunity he offers an alternative to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>-discrimination
theory of racial wage differentials. That's just what I was calling for in my
column.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
Look <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX> in Profile
            

            As a security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, I would like to respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Simonyi</ENAMEX>'s "I Fit the
Profile."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is a wonderful
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. All over the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are subjected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to the most appalling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humiliations</ENAMEX>--their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> and possessions searched, their livelihoods
threatened, their very safety jeopardized--by obnoxious, petty, corrupt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of brutal, repressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regimes</ENAMEX>. Worst of all, they must suffer
in silence, knowing that a callous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> cares little about their miserable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fates</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is different: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here</ENAMEX>, even a pampered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">multimillionaire</ENAMEX> can
gripe about having his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luggage</ENAMEX> inspected at an airport, confident of a
sympathetic hearing. When it comes to righteous outrage, this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is truly
blessed.

            I suspect
that it was the randomness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simonyi</ENAMEX>'s search and not its sinister
"profile" implications that really bothered him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Profiles</ENAMEX>, after all, don't
usually target wealthy software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, whereas random checks can't
distinguish a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simonyi</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simon Redmond</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            
               Hacking
Away
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s attempts to discredit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hackworth</ENAMEX> mentioned in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Medal Detector</ENAMEX>" item in
"Readme" will
not impress those of us who form our opinions on defense affairs from sources
other than military publicists and their media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hack</ENAMEX>'s
crime is making a noise in behalf of the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working soldier</ENAMEX>, and
criticizing the complacent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, defense
contractors, and their media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sycophants</ENAMEX> who are all feathering their own nests
at the expense of those who will risk their lives on our behalf. As far as
decorations are concerned, one Medal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor</ENAMEX> is conferred for one act of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bravery</ENAMEX>. Respect is due but it does not outrank a lifetime of proven courageous
service. If you want to help preserve <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military integrity I suggest you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">investigate Hack</ENAMEX>'s charges instead of shooting (at) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.D. Grissom</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Survey
Says
            

            I wish to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dicker</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Sante</ENAMEX>'s assertions in his piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>' New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee TV Art</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wagon</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Master of All He Surveys</ENAMEX>." First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Puryear</ENAMEX> has been covered
all over the place and so the question of whether his copy is "hot" is one that
depends entirely on an assessment of where the art world is, exactly, and who's
copy is cold. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, I really don't think we have to worry about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>
steering clear of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton Kramer</ENAMEX>'s opposition to postmodernism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, though
he likes not much of what he has seen lately, at least does not jerk his knees
in response to all new cultural production.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
DeBord
            

            
               Draining
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pool</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s argument in his capital-gains "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" that the tax does not affect the capital pool--is false.
The assertion is that whether the transaction takes place or not, the amount of
capital held between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> remains constant. True, and utterly
meaningless. A market-driven <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">economy</ENAMEX> runs on transactions, not cash held in
buried coffee cans. It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of value between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> which
provides the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> (profit) for growth. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX> sees a constant balance of
capital between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seller</ENAMEX>, I see a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that was not sold, a
transaction that did not take place. When that transaction fails to take place,
a host of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> fails to benefit from it. Each of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardeners</ENAMEX>, will then not spend the income that they
did not earn when the transaction failed to take place.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Betz</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
