
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               A Need
for Speed
            

            If we're going to have a
debate, let's at least get the facts right. For starters, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Speed Trap</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>
misspelled my name. I'll get over it. More important, he is just as careless in
depicting the arguments of those of us who think the economy is now capable of
decent growth without reigniting inflation.

            My essay ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy: What it Really Means"</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> was much more
balanced and modest in its claims than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> suggests. I invite

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to reread my piece rather than accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s
caricature of it, then decide for themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> has
generally been right about the performance of the economy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>--and
right in urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> not to raise interest rates. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> had
raised rates in order to hold growth down to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5 percent</NUMEX> over the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> seems to prefer, we would have given up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 billion</NUMEX> in
economic output. The unemployment rate would have been at least a half
percentage point higher, putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 750,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of work.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> was a
wonderful year--strong growth, declining inflation, declining unemployment,
rising productivity, and rising real wages. Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>.

            Links:

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Cycle</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> cover story, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31, 1997</TIMEX>)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Long Can</ENAMEX>
This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last?</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> cover story, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19, 1997</TIMEX>)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> cover story, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>)

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Shepard</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor in chief</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, my extreme
apologies for the spelling mistake.
            

            
               As for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>: We now
see just how helpful an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> can be. By all means read the
original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> essay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> (notice that I did include
a link to that essay in my original piece), as well as the earlier articles on
the site, and ask yourself whether they did or did not appear to claim that our
favorable measured growth and inflation performance can be explained by
unmeasured productivity growth. If they did claim or even suggest that,
then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> has indeed been saying something very silly. Oh, and
by the way: Reread my
own piece, and ask whether I actually say that growth over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 18</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> should have been held down to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5 percent</NUMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> claims I "seem to
prefer."
            

            
               What I do know is that a
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have contacted me since reading my piece
and told me that the explanation of the speedometer fallacy was new to
them--that they were under the impression, from reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BW</ENAMEX> , among other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, that a hidden productivity boom was not only a possible explanation of
low measured inflation but indeed the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               I guess
my question is whether Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> is willing, even now, to concede that it is
a fallacy to invoke unmeasured productivity as the source of our good numbers.
(And I don't mean a judicious acknowledgment that there may be something to
what I say--we are talking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> here, with no wiggle room whatsoever.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extremism</ENAMEX> in the defense of arithmetic is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>.) If he is, then I am at
least prepared to consider the possibility that I (and everyone else I know)
have been misinterpreting all those articles. But I would like to have the
point acknowledged.
            

            
               Option
Pass
            

            I thoroughly enjoy

                  Slate
               , but I find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s assertion of

                  Slate
               's "journalistic integrity" as regards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme</ENAMEX>") to be without
merit.

            Consider the case where a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> discovers that he is presiding over a case involving a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX>.
The only ethical course of action is to step down and have some other judge
handle the case. Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> tries his best to be fair and unbiased, he
can never be sure of his own motives. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s own reputation
is at risk, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will not know if the relative in question was found
innocent due to subtle manipulation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock options and therefore
have a vested interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> beyond their own paycheck. If

                  Slate
                wants to prove its integrity, it should either refuse the
options or stop covering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> altogether.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
Greatest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleaze</ENAMEX>
            

            In "Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> seems to assert that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> (and lobbying)
grievances." That's lobbying . Exercising that right is no more sleazy
than exercising the right to speak or to worship. Clearly, there are sleazy and
unethical ways to go about it, but lobbying itself is vital to our democratic
principles.

            The best
solution to the problem of corporate money in politics is to reduce the role of
government in all our lives. Until that happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are irresponsible
if they fail to pursue the interests of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> by lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David C. Klug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harrisburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>

            
               You
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Rat</ENAMEX>
            

            I don't
know whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX> hangs out with (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"White Heat"</ENAMEX>), but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Cagney</ENAMEX>'s stock has never slipped at all with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">buds</ENAMEX>. More importantly,
her assertion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is unclear about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s true state of mind at
the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Angels With Dirty Faces</ENAMEX> is just plain wrong. The entire heart
of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> was his utter fearlessness at the prospect of dying; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX>
"goes yellow" only so that his reputation will be sullied among the youthful
wannabe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> who idolize him. It is an act of renunciation that ennobles
him in death and is undertaken solely due to the entreaty of his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connelly</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat O'Brien</ENAMEX>), who knows that asking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> to pretend he's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coward</ENAMEX> is the hardest favor he's ever sought. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerr</ENAMEX> to imagine anything at
all ambiguous in the ending of this movie not only calls into question her
judgment but forces <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to wonder if she's even seen the damned thing.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Murray</ENAMEX> Los
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>

            
               Javanile
Humor
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Shuman</ENAMEX> clearly has no
idea what he is talking about when it comes to the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Weak Java</ENAMEX>").

            Java, although this has
clearly escaped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX>'s keen eyesight, is not a programming language at all.
It is in fact a mountainous island in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX>, part of the very
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populous</ENAMEX> and highly authoritarian archipelago <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. It also
happens to be the site of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the world's most important archeological
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discoveries</ENAMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java Man</ENAMEX>, and of vast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> (hence the
common usage of the term java to mean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>). These simple facts get
lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shuman</ENAMEX>'s clutter of technical language. With his preposterous
characterization of the whole Java conflict as a matter of convenience for
personal-computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shuman</ENAMEX> completely obscures the real
struggles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Javanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            There is, in fact, no
surprise here, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shuman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> and lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, home of innumerable
coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>, who reap
billions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> from arms sales to the repressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Javanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> suffer endlessly, while
residents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emerald City</ENAMEX> sip unreasonably cheap caffè lattes
(subsidized with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>), ponder the importance of bandwidth, and root for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathetic Mariners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supersonics</ENAMEX>.

            Please, no
more harmful obfuscation from 
                  Slate
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuman</ENAMEX>.

            -- Jesse
Hoffnung-Garskof
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
