
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               I Can't
Hear You
            

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morning</ENAMEX>'s delivery of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" included an all-too-common error. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>
explained that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are feeling their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX> over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision upholding <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX> and are suggesting
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> and any other future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> to the post will face a tough new
standard on affirmative action." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> did not "uphold" <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX>. It simply declined to hear the case. This decision has absolutely no
precedential value, nor does it necessarily tell us anything about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s
opinion of the measure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> receives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of petitions asking it to
review lower-court decisions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. On average, it agrees to hear less
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> of them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> may decline to review a case for any number
of reasons. For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> may refuse to hear a case--even one that
presents an important constitutional question--because it contains procedural
irregularities or because the issue it presents has not yet "percolated"
through the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. Therefore, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> present the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s
decision to decline to review a case as "upholding" the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s decision,
they mislead and confuse the public. I hope that 
                  Slate
                will be
more careful in presenting the decisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>
in the future.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oona Hathaway</ENAMEX> law
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia WaldU</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S. Court of Appeals for the D.C.</ENAMEX>
CircuitWashington

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>' Note: The page
was corrected as soon as we realized our error.
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millionerds Maligned</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> is congenitally
incapable of being boring, but he comes damn close in his first Millionerds
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">missive</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"T.J. the Barbarian</ENAMEX>"). In it we see the uncomfortable sight of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> not fully engaged with his material: the weak opening, the clichés
("swaggering"?), the much-trodden <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upside / Forbes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASAP / Fortune</ENAMEX> material, the absence of anything tying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.J. Rodgers</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX>' purported theme--the organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. The article feels
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overrushed</ENAMEX> and underthought. It lacks the wisecracking edge and the snappy
repartee of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' best writing.

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>
doing this as a result of a lost bet, or has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX> got pictures of him
naked from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Kedrosky <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
Boor
            

            I find
"Pundit
Central" both your most enjoyable and most useful feature. By capsulizing
the inanities that pass for political commentary, you expose the vapidity of
the opinions and put these "opinions" in their proper perspective. I found the
"not ready for wartime" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> quote most telling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s not going to
suit up for service in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>, now or ever. But other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fighting and
dying makes good video. From the safety of a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX>'s ready to
have (someone else) pay any price, face any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX>. Keep up the good work,

                  Slate
               .

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham Moreno</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Auto
Erotica
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s excellent essay, "Car
Talk," on the key to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s gubernatorial and municipal elections,
redefines the word "autocracy." He did miss the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, however, on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX>
transportation-related election result. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> passed an
initiative that will expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">monorail</ENAMEX>, a quaint remnant of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>, elevating it from its current <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90-second</TIMEX>-tourist-ride status into
a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-mile</NUMEX> citywide transit system--at the estimated cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>. This,
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> approving a regional transit system of express <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>, commuter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trains</ENAMEX>, and light rail costing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $4 billion</NUMEX>. If, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> writes,
public transportation is a violation of nature in the West, Seattleites
obviously want to be violated.

            -- L.C.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>

            
               Nanny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nanny Boo Boo</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> had it close,
but not quite right, in his "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Scheck</ENAMEX>. Scheck, although supremely
skilled, was overconfident in advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX> to go for the "all or
nothing" verdict. By taking away the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s choice to consider a manslaughter
conviction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> gambled that they shared his ability to operate within a
"narrowed framework." They didn't. Given the aftermath of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> criminal
verdict, he ought to have realized that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> prefer too much justice (i.e., a
second-degree conviction) to not enough (acquittal).

            Don't get
me wrong, if I were guilty, I'd call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX>. But for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX>, he blew
it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cozzo</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
