
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Love
Them Clones
            

            I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myhrvold</ENAMEX>'s argument in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Clones: Why Not?</ENAMEX>" It is hypocritical of our leaders
to issue blanket statements that this type of research should be banned due to
some imagined threat to society in the future.

            The
medical procedures and wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> have been encouraged and
funded with full support of political and religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Modern medicine
has, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myhrvold</ENAMEX> stated, ended or possibly even reversed the evolution of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">human species</ENAMEX>, producing genetic weaknesses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, as a whole. But
we would never propose limiting or discontinuing medical research due to the
importance of human life. I think that the process of cloning should be looked
upon as a possible method of strengthening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>'s weakening genetic makeup
or of preventing some future genetic disaster. And I don't think that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">civilization</ENAMEX>, as a whole, will allow the predicted abuses of genetic
research.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Double
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vision</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> genetically identical
thumbs up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan Myhrvold</ENAMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Clones:</ENAMEX>
Why Not?" Not since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the heady days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s cold fusion has there been
such a complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonissue</ENAMEX> issuing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of science.

            To suggest
that genetic identity between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> of differing ages is of any
material consequence to their self-identity is the height of hubris. Identical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twins</ENAMEX> all over the world would face discrimination--and, what's worse, the
painful process of identifying which one of them was the real one. The
discussion of cloning has forgotten the complexity of human nature and centered
on the kind of loony sci-fi hysteria that embarrasses the relatively few of us
left who have any scientific literacy.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan C. Allen</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Marry,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marry</ENAMEX>, Quite Contrary
            

            The point
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frum</ENAMEX>'s argument in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX>
Marriage" dialogue seems to boil down to "Look at how severely and for the
worse marriage has changed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 30 years</TIMEX>." While I see him claiming that
permitting gay marriage is one more step along this path, I don't see him
providing any argument that such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> are themselves bad or any worse than
the other breakdowns of traditional marriage (such as interracial marriage,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple divorces</ENAMEX>, prenuptial agreements, and so forth). Neither does he
provide any answers to the problem, merely a wistful remembrance of how "good"
it was. And if his idea of "good" is forcing roles upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>,
alimony for life, and community shunning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> whose marriages did not
succeed, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX> is really criticizing modern society, not just marriage.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Drew</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Can't Buy
Me Biodiversity
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E.</ENAMEX>
Landsburg exhibited a rather alarming disregard for common sense in his recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knickers Off Your Grandchildren</ENAMEX>." The greatest foolishness contained in
the article is the assumption that the natural riches that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX> try to preserve can be equated with money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> Landsburg
should take note that money can't buy everything, and the ready cash that can
so easily purchase consumer electronics is powerless to restore vanished
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biodiversity</ENAMEX>. The breathtaking thoughtlessness exhibited in this piece has
appeared in lesser forms time and again in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everyday Economics"</ENAMEX> column.
This simple-minded writing misleads <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and slanders <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Yaron Minsky
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX>
replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yaron Minsky</ENAMEX> notes that money can't buy biodiversity and
jumps to the conclusion that money can't (at least partly) compensate
for a lack of biodiversity. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minsky</ENAMEX>'s reasoning, there's no reason to give
presents to sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, because presents can't buy health.

            
               It's the
Inflation, Stupid
            

            In the Dialogue on the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital-Gains Tax</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> is quite correct in noting
that, strictly speaking, the capital-gains tax is merely one particular
manifestation of the overall income tax. Nevertheless, he glosses over the
essential unfairness of the current system of taxing capital gains, namely, the
inflation problem.

            Suppose
someone purchases a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> and sells it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, in a somewhat
appreciated but not especially buoyant market. His capital gain, on which he
must pay tax, will seem like a fat profit. But even relatively low inflation
during the intervening time period will have caused the value of money to
dwindle, thereby diminishing his "gain" in real terms. Capital-gains taxes, to
be fair, must be indexed for inflation, otherwise many long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> must
pay tax on gains that are more than offset by inflation.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>
Corwin
            

            
               Racy
Headline
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mastio</ENAMEX> article about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government attempts to influence political events in
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> was interesting enough, but I don't know whom to blame for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headline</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Sam Plays John Huang</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang is an Asian-American</ENAMEX> with
well-known fund-raising problems, but it has not been proven that he is trying
to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics on behalf of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. The title, in the
context of the article, implies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> is a paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> of a foreign
government. Unless there is a connection between foreign-government funding and
political influence by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> made the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-too-common error of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">equating Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Chang</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
