
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Murdoch</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">= Sleaze</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Humanitarian?</ENAMEX>" was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s embrace of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> who has done
more to bring down the standards of journalism worldwide than any other.
Whether in newspapers or television, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> has consistently shown a disdain
for fairness, class, and appropriate journalistic behavior. And he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">single-handedly</ENAMEX> deserves responsibility for creating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>-television
phenomenon with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Current Affair</ENAMEX> , the worst affront to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
television-news standards of our era.

            As
someone from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, I can't be considered exactly the most objective source of
analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s media behavior (in light of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> cable's competition for
distribution and eyeballs with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Channel</ENAMEX>). So, I'll leave that
analysis for others. But you need only pick your medium or your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to
determine what he's left in his wake. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may be willing to embrace
his efforts to bring media (in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s case, sleazy media) to worldwide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>. You may even want to applaud his efforts to bust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. But to
ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s contribution to dumbing down and trashing media and journalism
is to only tell part of the story.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Brown</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            
               Santorum
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">= Saint</ENAMEX>
            

            In "Sen.
Symbol, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> unfairly chastises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX> for
opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D.</ENAMEX>) last-minute bill that would supposedly ban
all abortions after fetal viability. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> just didn't want to accept such a
hollow measure.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> proposal would
have permitted abortions after viability if continuing the pregnancy posed a
risk of "grievous harm" to the mother's health, a determination left solely to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> could be prosecuted for making such a false claim,
because no one else's opinion would matter. And of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have
previously held that "health" includes both physical and mental aspects. This
enormous loophole made the bill completely irrelevant.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> was a sham, designed to draw support away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santorum</ENAMEX>'s bill, which
actually would have done something to criminalize certain types of abortions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Criticizing Santorum</ENAMEX> for opposing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> bill simply so that he could
garner political points is an untrue and very unfair characterization of the
events.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Konig</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roanoke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               Do the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoes Fit</ENAMEX>?
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boycott Nike</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX> commits the usual error of outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> on
black culture: He sees it as monolithic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olajuwon</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>
is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olajuwon</ENAMEX>'s culture, for the better part of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> colonial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>'s was hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americana</ENAMEX>, with the
influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> slavery.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> can throw up a lot of
chatter about the ways that the shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are wrecking the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>
and offering sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for little black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to look up to, but the vulgarity
of his means--depicting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of wildly different cultures as if
they were culturally identical--belies the error of his agenda.

            The only
difference between spending a ton of money on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> shoes and on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci</ENAMEX> suit is
in what type of cultural expression you choose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> seems to think we should
boycott everything that expresses a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ego</ENAMEX>. It turns my stomach to read yet
another backdoor assault on the economically powerful models that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> have managed to establish. Those blanched <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX>, after
all, who dictated that humility could be measured in chinos and tweed, couldn't
have been assholes, too, now could they? Speak softly and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> a housing
project, then when that doesn't pan out, blame it on the shoes.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew DeBord</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>'s
Rump
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boycott Nike</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX> wants shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to sign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> who will help
inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> conform their conduct to the expectations of a suburban job
interview. I think that is terrible.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX>'s popularity
has nothing to do with a shoe contract. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX> works his ass off rebounding and
scrambling for the ball, and not only when everyone is watching and every game
is important. There is virtue and substance there even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> can't see it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX> is also popular because his rebellion and mad behavior are welcome in a
world where we're expected to be deferential and compliant.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>
doesn't understand that the reservoir of personality and influence in sport is
not controlled by Madison Avenue or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for greatness is the
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. Some waters run deep, others shallow. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>'s "I am <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woods</ENAMEX>" means something only because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX> traveled to a place where he
was not welcome and beat the bastards at their own game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> of course was
conspicuously absent from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s essay.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Love
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Neutral
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knife</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> wrote an
interesting article on the latest abortion hubbub in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>" on fetal viability.
But there was an outrageous error in the links for the article, which
identified the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan Guttmacher Institute</ENAMEX> as "nonpartisan."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institute</ENAMEX> is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planned Parenthood</ENAMEX>, the largest abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>. I submit that this oversight suggests either that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> isn't as
informed on the subject as he appears to be, or that his politics are showing.
I enjoy the usual "here are the facts--deal with them" tone of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate, and I</ENAMEX>
hope this mistake will not be repeated.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Murdoch</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wind Gap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>

            
               Ban
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Non-Voter Contributions</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mastio</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kiddie-Cash</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caper</ENAMEX>" was a great piece on the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> to launder campaign
contributions. Unfortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> failed to mention that the leading
bipartisan campaign-reform bill would end this sham. "It shall be unlawful for
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> who is not qualified to vote in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> election to make a
contribution ..." is the simple solution offered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>-Feingold
campaign-reform bill. This provision would outlaw contributions by resident
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aliens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            It is
important not to shrug our shoulders in despair over the current state of our
election process but, rather, to actively seek and support real solutions which
can revitalize <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy. I encourage anyone who is ready to simply
give up on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to remember that they are only there because
we sent them to be our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>. Let them know that you expect them to
support efforts to clean up the campaign-fund-raising system.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX>
Willmuth
            

            

               Checkered Out
            

            I thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Heard</ENAMEX>'s piece
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sore Loser</ENAMEX>" put
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Kasparov</ENAMEX>'s behavior in proper context, but as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the Chinook
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> (computer checkers), I would like to make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chinook</ENAMEX> did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">play Don Lafferty</ENAMEX> again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1995</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinook</ENAMEX> won that match with one
win, no losses, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> draws. While this result is no more statistically
significant than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX>'s recent win, both matches do constitute important
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> points. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> match is documented at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chinook</ENAMEX> Web site and
in a recent book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Schaeffer</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinook</ENAMEX> project.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
perfect play (which is not necessarily the same as inspiring or imaginative
play) in games like checkers and chess can be reduced to pure computation. So,
as computers get faster, they will surpass human capabilities in these limited
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">domains</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Lu
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Please include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone
number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
