
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exhibiting Contempt</ENAMEX>

            Art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> are under
pressure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. There's the constant hunger for money, exacerbated by the
decline in government funding. There is brutal competition for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and works
of art. Since the onset of the culture wars, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> also have faced the hazard
of political controversy and the chilling effect it can have on potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>. Perhaps most relentless is box office pressure--the demand to boost
attendance.

            A recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> article argued that these burdens have made the job of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> less desirable than it might seem. Perhaps so. But that doesn't
excuse the way some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> have responded to these pressures: with a style
of populism that is very different from a genuine democratic sensibility.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> populism is not quite the same as the blockbuster
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>. Though devised and marketed on a large scale, shows like the upcoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX> exhibition at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX>
retrospective at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Fine Arts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> fall within the traditional
boundaries of what these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> display. They may not contain much that
is conceptually fresh, but they do provide mass access to artistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterpieces</ENAMEX>. You can't really argue with that. The populist trend, by
contrast, draws <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> away from art their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators sincerely</ENAMEX> believe is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>--or sometimes away from art entirely. The current, defining example is
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Art of the Motorcycle</ENAMEX>," now on view at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solomon Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. Other examples include the exhibition of landscapes by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalist painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Wyeth</ENAMEX> that just closed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Art</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis Comfort Tiffany</ENAMEX> show that just opened at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populism</ENAMEX> began with an unlikely figure: a patrician medievalist by the name of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hoving</ENAMEX>, who was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967 to 1977</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoving</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> who came up with the idea of flying huge banners over the entrance to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX>. He also essentially invented the blockbuster show. His tenure began
with a splashy exhibition on royal patronage and built to the crescendo of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Tut</ENAMEX>," which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> waited in long lines to see in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>. In an
entertaining book published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making the Mummies Dance:</ENAMEX>
Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoving</ENAMEX> unabashedly recounts his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machiavellian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P.T</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnum</ENAMEX>-style hype. But despite his excesses,
Hoving was still in some sense a conventional-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX>. It never occurred
to him that you could herd even more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into an art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> if you didn't
force them to look at art at all. Thus it was left to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego Museum of</ENAMEX>
Art to mount, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seuss</ENAMEX> retrospective, and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>
to mount a fashion show titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Warhol Look</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jed Perl</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton Kramer</ENAMEX>, who predictably have decried the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> exhibit, might
reflect upon the fact that the populist approach it represents grew out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mapplethorpe</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX> controversy of the late
1980s--which they started.

            Charged with being out of
touch both with popular morality and with popular taste and punished with a
loss of funds, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> have been trying hard to demonstrate that they
are not elitist, difficult, and obscure. The best way to prove you're
not a snob is by not letting your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> seem empty. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of
preventing emptiness, while at the same time cultivating it, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas R.</ENAMEX>
Krens, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX>.

            The
hallmarks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krens</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 year</TIMEX> tenure have been aggressive global expansion--there
are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheims</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in addition to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>--and the
box office smash. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>, the iconic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lloyd Wright</ENAMEX> corkscrew, has mounted huge retrospectives of less difficult
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rauschenberg</ENAMEX>. Where
modern art ceases to be popular, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krens</ENAMEX> ceases to display modern art, at least
in a main-event manner. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krens</ENAMEX> cooperated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
government in mounting an exhibition titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"China: 5000 Years</ENAMEX>" that fell well
outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s charter. But with aggressive promotion, including
advertising in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese language</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> set new records for
itself, drawing an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 3,000</NUMEX> visitors a day. The commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Art of the Motorcycle</ENAMEX>" has dwarfed that. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly 4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a
day are paying an obscene <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> to see the shimmering machines, making
it by far the best-attended show in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX>'s history.

            An exhibition on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> design at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> would
be defensible if it made a better argument for either the cultural significance
or the aesthetic importance of the machines. Industrial design is a stepchild
of fine art, and the cross-fertilization of high and pop is an important part
of the story of artistic modernism. But the exhibition doesn't make the case.
The basic message of the show is: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorcycles</ENAMEX> are really cool; here are a bunch
of really cool <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX>. It includes too many machines--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX> in all. Some of
these are undeniably eye-catching, but by the end, the nonaficionado is bored
silly. Part of the problem is that, as you might expect from an exhibition
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">direct-marketed</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, the approach is design-technical rather
than design-aesthetic or design-cultural. The information plates that accompany
the exhibition and the catalog text both seem pitched at pre-established
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fanatics</ENAMEX>. Here's a snatch from the catalog entry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1914 Cyclone</ENAMEX>, one of a
few truly stunning <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> in the show:

            The hallmark feature of
the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">61-ci</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-twin Cyclone</ENAMEX> engine is its shaft-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">bevel</NUMEX>-gear-driven overhead-cam
and valve arrangement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> also contains a number of other important
features that presage modern high-performance engine technology: a
near-hemispherical combustion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>, the extensive use of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roller</ENAMEX> and
self-aligning ball bearings, and a precise, recessed fit of the crankcase,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cylinders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> all contribute to the engine's exceptional performance.
Even with its modest compression ration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5 to 1</NUMEX>, it is estimated that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclone</ENAMEX> produces <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">45 hp</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5000</TIMEX> rpm.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX>
of the exhibition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krens</ENAMEX> lays on this technical specification as a defense
against the charge of unseriousness. But in doing so, he more or less
eviscerates his own claim that these machines belong in a modern art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, as
opposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> focused on design, transportation, or history.

            
Perhaps ironically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> populism comes with
a tendency toward corporate exploitation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> is the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of an
exhibition that includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX>, including a current model. In its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> points out that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX>, fewer
than the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harleys</ENAMEX>. But the point is not that the sponsor
influences the content of the show. It is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> influences the fact
of the show. That a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> can get brownie points for art patronage
by promoting its own product is part of the reason that this exhibition took
place, instead of the one examining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> art at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>, which it replaced. The current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany</ENAMEX> show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> is
sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany</ENAMEX>. Everywhere, the border between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> and its gift
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> is growing more porous. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim SoHo</ENAMEX>, you can't enter the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> except through the gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> has been busy
rationalizing its decision to mount the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> exhibition. Krens, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorcycle enthusiast</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMWs</ENAMEX>, contributes an utterly
unpersuasive introduction to the catalog, in which he breezily declares that
the distinction between the unique work of art and the mechanically produced
object is now "irrelevant." In other words, it's open season for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> like him.
Others are embracing this philosophy of complete categorical breakdown. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Museum of Contemporary Art</ENAMEX> just hired its new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>. In
interviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX>, who styles himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, has said
he wants to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> friendlier to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. According to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, he
recently stunned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> by proposing to fill the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> with potted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> (they draw bugs--no good for paintings).

            Resisting empty populism
doesn't have to mean a haughty elitism. An aesthetic democrat says that more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could profit from the experience of art if those who ran <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> thought
more creatively about how to converse with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> says that
if you drop what is difficult in art, you can get more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to pay attention.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">democrat</ENAMEX> at the helm of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, a symphony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX>, or a publishing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> tries to expand his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> while challenging it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX>, by
contrast, panders to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, figuring out what it likes and then
delivering it in heaps. Where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">democrat</ENAMEX> exhibits respect for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> exhibits contempt.

         
      
   
