
   
   
      
         
            Judicial Restraint

            For the voyeur--especially
the prissy, law-abiding voyeur such as me--few literary genres satisfy as much
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> memoir. Some of this interest must undoubtedly be attributed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">sweaty Chained Heat</ENAMEX> -style sex fantasies. But mostly the fascination
stems from a kind of arm's-length sadism. What happens to someone stretched to
the psychological limit? What happens when you go to hell?

            As a
consequence, I was really looking forward to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sol Wachtler</ENAMEX>'s memoirs. If anyone
could describe the sickening plunge from respectability to degradation (and if
anyone could learn something from the experience), surely it would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX>,
who fell as far and fast as anyone can. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1992</TIMEX>, he was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and a rising star in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, famed for his
monstrous ego, his political ambition, and his jousts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX>.
Then he was arrested for stalking his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy Silverman</ENAMEX>, and
charged with extortion, interstate racketeering, and blackmail, among other
crimes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> had written her harassing letters in the guise of a fictional
alter ego, and mailed a condom to her young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> claimed mental
incapacitation: Jilted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silverman</ENAMEX>, he'd succumbed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">manic depression</ENAMEX> that
was exacerbated by an addiction to prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">amphetamines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> pled
guilty to sending threats through the mail. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1993</TIMEX>--less than a year
after he'd presided over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York's Court of Appeals</ENAMEX>--the 63-year-old
first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX> began serving an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-month</TIMEX> term in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. Now he
has published the story of his time inside, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After the Madness: A Judge</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Own</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Prison Memoir</ENAMEX> . It is quite an accomplishment: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> has managed to write
an uninteresting book about prison life.

            The best modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> memoirs-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autobiography of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm X</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Henry Abbott</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Belly of the Beast</ENAMEX> , Eldridge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleaver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soul</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ice</TIMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nien Cheng</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life and Death in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> --are stories about an agony that yields redemption. Each book
tells roughly the same tale: A corrupt society imprisons the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> for a
minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> (marijuana possession in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleaver</ENAMEX>'s case, juvenile delinquency in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX>'s, capitalist roadism in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheng</ENAMEX>'s). The narrators defy the prison
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> visit every horror upon the narrators--sexual
assault, beatings, isolation, psychological torture--at which point the
narrators harden. They find a code to live by--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam for Malcolm</ENAMEX>, black power
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleaver</ENAMEX>, a freaky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nietzscheanism</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX>. They become awesome,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">terrifying, .</ENAMEX> What happens when you go to hell? You become stronger than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">devil</ENAMEX> himself.

            
               After
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madness</ENAMEX> , however, has little such passion; in that, it is true to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX>. It's a memoir that carries almost no emotional punch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> is
neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> nor villain; he's not even a compelling character. His description
of prison life overflows with cliché. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is inedible, the noise is
unbearable, the stench is unimaginable, the "bend and spread 'em" searches are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unendurable</ENAMEX>. He supplies the requisite glut of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cockroaches</ENAMEX> and the necessary
quota of vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wachtler</ENAMEX> spends pages and pages excusing his
behavior--he was depressed, he was addicted, he never intended to harm anyone,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>--but even here his tone is oddly flat. (To his credit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> does not
ignore the rich ironies of his situation. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madness</ENAMEX> is sprinkled
with his awkward encounters. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> occasion he meets a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">con</ENAMEX> whose appeal
he denied. On another, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX>, wearing his stained, tattered prison uniform,
is paid a visit by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Blackmun</ENAMEX>.)

            Perhaps the blame for After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madness</ENAMEX> belongs to
the legal profession. It may be a problem of judicial restraint. Great prison
writing is mimetic. It reads like going to prison feels--suffocating and alien
and frightening. Consider this passage from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Belly of the Beast</ENAMEX> , a
farrago of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> and violence:

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>--a
middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX>--who tried to fuck me, I drew my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> on. I forced him to
his knees, and with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> at his throat, made him perform fellatio on my
flaccid penis in front of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>.

            This is the way it is
done. If you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, you must either kill or turn the tables on anyone who
propositions you with threats of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            Compare
this vivid lunacy to a passage from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After the Madness :</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would assume that now
that my depression, manic behavior, and causal toxicity (caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> I
was taking) have been evaluated and confirmed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s own medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butner</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>], there would be some understanding by the
public--not forgiveness, but some understanding. That will not happen. There
will always be those who will refuse to accept the fact that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can
function in what appears to be a normal fashion in his or her job, and still
suffer from a mental disorder.

            
               After
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madness</ENAMEX> reads like going to court feels.

            At the level of policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> has written a fine book, a
worthy dissertation on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> penal system. He is much more heartfelt
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> prison reform than about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> reform. He spends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> in the hole,
then chastises his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> for not considering solitary confinement a
"cruel and unusual" punishment. He befriends a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> doing hard time,
then sermonizes about the idiocies of mandatory minimum sentences. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blockmate</ENAMEX> confesses to robbery: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> takes the occasion to celebrate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Miranda</ENAMEX> warning. His tales work by accretion: After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">353</NUMEX> pages and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 months</TIMEX> in
prison, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> has made a persuasive case for penal reform: to free
nonviolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, scrap drug laws, fund prison education and training
programs, and more. The old joke is true: "What do you call a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> who's
been to jail? A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>."

            After I finished this worthy
and dull book, a distressing thought came to me: Its banality might be the
fault neither of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> nor of the legal profession. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> writes
clichés because <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> has become cliché. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generation ago</TIMEX>, even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years ago</TIMEX>,
jail was as alien <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">as Mars</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A month</TIMEX> in the hole, a cockroach infestation, the
stench of mystery <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>--these were topics that would revolt broad-minded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. Who knew that fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>--even the scummy ones--endured such
horrors?

            The bleakest lesson of
After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madness</ENAMEX> is perhaps that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> has lost its capacity to shock.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are in jail <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times as many as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>.
In some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> (though not the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> ones where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> live), a
prison term has become almost a rite of passage, something that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> do.
We are inundated with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> pop culture--with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, documentarians, TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who have gone up the river and returned with tales of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rapes</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cavity</ENAMEX> searches" and "shanks" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>." A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generation ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX>'s
book was hailed as a landmark, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">visionary exposé</ENAMEX>. Today, such a book--not that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachtler</ENAMEX> has written one--would be greeted with a shrug.

         
      
   
