
   
   
      
         
            Still Waters

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century</ENAMEX>" exhibition in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> are in for a surprise,
especially if they arrive in one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s pastel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle buses</ENAMEX> decked
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> lilies as if it had been dredged from a swamp. There are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>-inspired munchies to sample and a gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> crammed with the inevitable
Giverny-ana--everything for the fantasy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> except bulbs. All this
soft-focus packaging conveys the popular image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Monet</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1840-1926</TIMEX>) as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> pleasures, puttering around in his aqueous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX> and
filling his canvases with sunlit lilies reflected in the pink and blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rococo Fragonard or Boucher</ENAMEX> marooned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 20 th century</TIMEX>.

            Then you enter the
exhibition itself, and a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> takes over. This one is a bold
experimentalist way ahead of his time. A huge blowup of a of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in his
garden towers over the entryway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imperious Monet</ENAMEX>, his legs buried in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wisteria</ENAMEX> covering his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>, looks like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX> of some
tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX>. His eyes shaded by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> hat and a full white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> beard pointing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, he seems to be saying, "This is my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrain</ENAMEX>. Enter at your own risk."

            The timing of this lavish
show, which includes some paintings never before exhibited, could hardly be
better. Just as the art world is revving up for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX> Pollock
extravaganza at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, it's good to be reminded
just how far along the line of abstraction and monumentality <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> had traveled
by the end of his long life. As these late canvases wash over you with their
great swaths of paint, you can immediately see why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clement Greenberg</ENAMEX>, writing
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX>, spoke of the "rehabilitation" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX> and why "the most
advanced of advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> names no names) "were
enthusiastically rediscovering him."

            Actually, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Leja</ENAMEX>
points out in an interesting catalog essay, there's little evidence that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Rothko</ENAMEX> had much interest in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>. Nor did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX> need <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s validation--or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>'s, for that
matter. But it's true that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> purchased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX>'s
boldest big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> paintings (which later burned in storage), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> was no
longer viewed as merely a safe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> of pretty suburban sights.

            In a sense, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> had been
torn between pleasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> and taking risks all his life. Born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1840</TIMEX>
into a family of modest means, he lacked the financial security net of
aristocrats such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Degas, Manet</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berthe Morisot</ENAMEX>. He always had one eye on
the market, finding a motif--gardens, beaches, cathedrals--that would sell and
making multiple versions of it. He pretended that he did all his work outside
and on the spot, when actually he sketched rapidly in paint, then carefully
finished his canvases in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>. He even used photographs on occasion,
furtively, and was furious when he was caught in the act in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> while adding
details to his series of pictures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>, ever
respectful of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> (and potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>), never indulged in the harsh
jokes of his urbane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>. He was happy to disguise his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> as
a geisha (in a painting hanging elsewhere at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Fine Arts</ENAMEX>), but
there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> dressed up as odalisques in his work, no probings into
the murky secret lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisians</ENAMEX>.

            And yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> was, in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, as unyielding and uncompromising as any of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>. Never much
interested in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, he kept the Impressionist faith of showing the
effects of changing light on landscape. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of his early pictures, his
Impression, Sunrise of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX>, gave the movement its name. (A couple of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> views in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> show, with orange sun setting in the fog over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX>, closely resemble that painting.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, and
he was finally his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Building on the huge success of his series
paintings of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>--the cathedrals and haystacks (now awkwardly renamed
"grainstacks") and rows of poplars--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> could afford to paint for himself
alone. He still kept track of the market, though. In the opening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>,
especially, there are highly finished paintings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> (painted from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>'s luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savoy</ENAMEX>) and--in a glorious sunlit corridor--views of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>. An early cluster of smallish <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lily</ENAMEX> paintings, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> on circular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">canvases</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX> exhibited in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1909</TIMEX> are almost saccharine in their
placid beauty, visual equivalents of some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debussy</ENAMEX>'s prettier preludes.

            But shadows were beginning
to intrude. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX>, died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>; a year
later, he learned that he had cataracts; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> died. Under
the weight of these shocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> took some time off from painting, then
announced a bold new shift in his work, toward huge decorative panels. During
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last decade</TIMEX> of his life, working incessantly in the new white-walled and
high-ceilinged at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giverny</ENAMEX> (resembling a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoHo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX>) built specifically to house
these enormous canvases, he turned out paintings by turns ominous, terrifying,
sublime. In calligraphic studies such as (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916-19</TIMEX>), we feel like we've plunged
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few hundred feet</NUMEX> below the surface, into a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> realm of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medusas</ENAMEX> and
colorful anemones. A strange human skull seems entangled in the reflected
weeping willow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> scrawled at the lower left. Such paintings, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX>
never intended for exhibition, prefigure to a remarkable degree the work of the
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gestural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionists</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Kooning</ENAMEX>.

            The title of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> show
has a double meaning: the work <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> created during the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, and his work in relation to the various Modernist movements of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. While inviting comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> art during the
1950s, the show also insists on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX>'s involvement with contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>
history. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFA</ENAMEX> devoted an exhibition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX>'s series
paintings of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tucker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest curator</ENAMEX> of that show and the current
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, made a convincing argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> was celebrating the great motifs of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>: her land, her agriculture, her religion, and her
architecture.

            Then came the Dreyfus
Affair, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>'s faith in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> nationalism was shattered. A passionate
Dreyfusard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> supported his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zola</ENAMEX> in his defense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> army
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> falsely accused of passing secrets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>. Henceforth, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> sees it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> searched for a more private and less jingoistic tie to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> landscape and discovered it in the multiple layers of his own water
garden. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melville</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ishmael</ENAMEX>, who noted that "meditation and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> are
wedded for ever," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> found that all his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moods</ENAMEX> found echoes in the reflected
weeping willows and tangled lilies. During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, as he conveyed
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> quartered nearby and refused to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giverny</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> advanced, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> took on some of the dark mood of war. At
war's end, he arranged to contribute some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> as a sort of victory
monument to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>--the gift that eventually became the glorious circular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">water lily chapel</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orangerie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>.

            "How terrible it is to reach
the end of one's life," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> had written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899</TIMEX>, after the death of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landscapist Alfred Sisley</ENAMEX>. Intimations of his own mortality turned out to be
premature. As his fellow Impressionists died <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after the other--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pissarro</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ</ENAMEX>©zanne in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Degas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX> ended up, once
again, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ishmael</ENAMEX>, at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby-Dick</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX> I am the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>," he sighed. He was the last Impressionist, but he also
traveled the farthest, pushing the limits of landscape until he broke right
through them.

             

         
      
   
