
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dread</ENAMEX>

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of law,
wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Paine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1805</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislative</ENAMEX> law is the law of the land,
enacted by our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>, chosen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for that purpose.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> 
               law is a mass of opinions and decisions which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have instituted themselves." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paine</ENAMEX> liked the first kind of law better.
So does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX>. As the most intellectually consistent and stylistically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX> has never hidden his enthusiasm for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tradition of mistrusting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. The basics of his
judicial philosophy are now usefully collated in this volume, which consists of
an essay by the associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>, followed first by responses from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Tribe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Ann Glendon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Dworkin</ENAMEX>, and then by a reply
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scalia</ENAMEX>.

            According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX>, the problem begins in law school, where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> digest a
steady diet of fusty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> appellate decisions, and
taste--for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time--the joys of reasoning by analogy and precedent. A
few of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> befriend their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, or find some other way to become
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>; by that time, they have internalized what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX> calls the
"common-law attitude," and they become a dangerous lot. Faced with an ambiguous
statute or regulation, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, reared on the common law, too often treat
the enacted text as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> more precedent to circumvent. In other words, they
hijack the democratic process.

            Scalia offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> antidotes to this epidemic of judicial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lawmaking</ENAMEX>: textualism and originalism. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Textualism</ENAMEX>" is just what it sounds
like. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX> puts it, "The text is the law, and it is the text that must be
observed." The only democratically binding feature of a statute is its literal
language, because that language alone has been ratified by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. "Originalism,"
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX> defines it, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of textualism particularly relevant to
constitutional interpretation. Its adherents tether their interpretations to
plain meanings as they were understood when the text was first penned.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Originalists</ENAMEX> believe, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX> puts it, that a constitution's "whole purpose
is to prevent change--to embed certain rights in such a manner that future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> cannot take them away."

            None of
this is new to anyone who has paid attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s opinions and other
writings over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>. Yet, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Matter of Interpretation</ENAMEX> , his
reprise of the traditional jeremiad against judicial usurpation concludes with
a twist. The specter raised by common-law judging, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX> says, is not the
unelected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> determined to impose the values of an elite few upon the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masses</ENAMEX>, but that old Tocquevillian villain, the tyranny of the majority.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s argument goes like this: As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> persist in bending the law, the
majority of the moment will begin to insist ever more stridently on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> of
its particular ideological stripe. Once on the bench, these judicial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> (emboldened by their anything-goes common-law attitudes) will set
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> encoding the popular will into law, to the detriment of unpopular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>.

            
As law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Ann Glendon</ENAMEX> points out in
her response, this is an odd coda, especially given the majoritarian premises
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s philosophy. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glendon</ENAMEX> shares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s distrust of undisciplined
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, but hers is the more traditional anxiety, rooted in a fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>.)
At the end of the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scalia</ENAMEX>, defending his prediction that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> will carry
democracy too far, contends that the individual rights favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> tend
to be the same ones championed by popular majorities. Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s list:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights, racial-minority rights, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> rights, abortion rights, and
"rights against political favoritism." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s notion of what constitutes a
popular cause does seem questionable--racial-minority and gay rights are not
nearly as universally supported as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX> seems to think they are. His
nightmare scenario is also far-fetched: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>-tenured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are dubious
vehicles for implementing a popular will that changes from moment to moment.
Besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> can't be relied on: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX>, for instance, are
famous for disappointing their appointers.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s
prescriptions have long drawn fire from legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>. Some of their
criticisms are repeated here by legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Tribe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dworkin</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s originalism is too glib, because it doesn't distinguish
between what the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> says and what its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> expected it to
do ; too malleable, because it merely substitutes the guesswork of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> for the musings of moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>; too value-laden, because it
imputes an anti-evolutionary purpose to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. And so on.

            Yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX> is refreshingly right in several particulars.
He justifiably laments the virtual disregard of statutory interpretation in
law-school curricula, where the hoary common-law case-study method still
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">predominates</ENAMEX> despite the fact that most law nowadays takes the form of statutes
and regulations.

            Scalia
also rightly rejects the use of "legislative history" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> reports and
floor debates) as a guide to divining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>' intent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> reports are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">worthless</ENAMEX>, not only because they lack a democratic pedigree, but because they
are infinitely pliable. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Leventhal</ENAMEX>'s quip that using
legislative history is like looking over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> at a cocktail party until
you spot your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.) And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX> is right to object to the caricature of the
textualist/originalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> as wooden and unimaginative--nontextualists, after
all, can be plenty wooden and unimaginative themselves.

            
Admitted nontextualists, incidentally, are
becoming harder and harder to find. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s "plain language" approach has
certainly become more popular among his bench <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>. The simplest proof of this
is the remarkable increase in citations to dictionaries in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
opinions. A recent study found that dictionary definitions were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> times more
likely to appear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s decisions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s swearing-in
than they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> before it. (The originalists, of course, like to dust
off old dictionaries--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1785</TIMEX> edition for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>,
for instance.) This lexicographical trend won't cure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">textualists</ENAMEX>'
reputation for stiltedness; reading some of these opinions is like listening to
the high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">valedictorian</ENAMEX> who inevitably begins, "I didn't know what to say
today, so I looked up the word 'commencement.' "

            Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living Constitution</ENAMEX>" like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribe</ENAMEX> now declare their fidelity to
text. It's surprising that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribe</ENAMEX>'s essay doesn't discuss his textualist
argument for the unconstitutionality of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment 2</ENAMEX>, which forbade
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to enact anti-discrimination ordinances based on sexual orientation.
Citing almost no cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribe</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>
initiative violated the letter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Protection Clause</ENAMEX> because it denied
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gays</ENAMEX> alone the protection of the anti-discrimination laws. Not an airtight
argument (all anti-discrimination laws pick and choose among protected
classes), but a cleverly textualist one--and one that seems to have helped
convince a majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to strike down the amendment, despite a lack
of helpful precedent. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX> offered a different textualist reading of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Protection Clause</ENAMEX>, grounding his arch dissent firmly in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">majoritarianism</ENAMEX>--"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> has mistaken a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kulturkampf</ENAMEX> for a fit of
spite.")

            So how often are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> actually as willful as Scalia
claims they are? It still sometimes happens. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last spring</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Due Process Clause</ENAMEX> a constitutional
right to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>-assisted suicide by relying on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato, Montaigne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
More, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roper</ENAMEX> poll. Its decision, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribe</ENAMEX> defended before the court
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>, is almost certain to be reversed, probably on textualist
grounds. Most of the current textual infidelity, though, occurs because the
doctrine of stare decisis --which dictates adherence to precedent--forces
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to live with adventurous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decisions from earlier in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>. Not surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX> is no big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of stare decisis : In
his dissents, he often calls upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to scour away layers of encrusted
precedent in order to get at the original meaning of the underlying text.

            How <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> interpret statutes
and constitutions is, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX>, "a question utterly central to the
existence of democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." That's hard to dispute. Yet, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> of early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--shows in his essay, it's also a question we've been
asking since the colonial era, fitting the answer to the needs of the moment.
The revolution of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>, for instance, was fueled in part by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX>'
resentment of the overweening powers of royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>. As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as the 1780s</TIMEX>,
however, the pendulum had swung back, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> looked to the courts
to check the excesses of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scalia</ENAMEX>, however, the idea that
judicial power responds to the demands of the time merely proves that "there
have always been willful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who bend the law to their wishes."

            Seen from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective, Scalia</ENAMEX>'s view of the debate over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX> does look a bit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manichaean</ENAMEX>. But it would be a mistake to dismiss him for that reason. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>'s
arguments have shaped the debate in our time; he has gone a long way toward
changing how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> interpret the letter of the law. Not all the way--he has
not yet succeeded in building a durable majority on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Does this mean
that unpopular individual rights are in peril? More likely, it simply goes to
show--as do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> in this stimulating book--that there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to read a text.

         
      
   
