
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psycho Dramas</ENAMEX>

            To my mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> is the most formidable and fascinating of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold Warriors</ENAMEX>.
"Their panic is my peace," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chambers</ENAMEX> wrote, speaking through the persona of "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>" (a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> with his eye on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>) in a bizarre, compelling essay for
Life <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>. Some thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> was the devil. As an
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who kicked off the internal <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> by naming a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX>, he was certainly the
instigator of a national panic. He remains the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>'s best evidence
that a first-rate intellect (and he was that) could see the world in the
black-and-white terms the right has long favored. His torrential, lurid
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">masterpiece Witness</ENAMEX> , a best seller in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> and still <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
favorite book in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, ranks as one of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autobiographies</ENAMEX>.

            He was
born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vivian Jay Chambers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX> to an unhappy, impoverished, middle-class
family on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>. As a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, the brilliant and tormented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropout</ENAMEX>, consorted with married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, was caught stealing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of books from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>, and bummed his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orleans</ENAMEX> (he would later identify with Beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kerouac</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginsberg</ENAMEX>). Vacillating between wildly opposed political views, he fervidly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supported Calvin Coolidge</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1920s</TIMEX>, only to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>. He spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX> as a party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, serving under various aliases as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courier</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> ring infiltrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Horrified by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s purges, increasingly convinced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> were literally the
party of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> and that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> without mysticism is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>," in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> he broke
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. He soon announced himself a radical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and a right-wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, becoming in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX> a top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
magazine. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, in a case that played itself out on television (a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>) and
in the national headlines, he successfully brought explicit charges of perjury,
and implicit charges of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> espionage, against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX>, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Endowment</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>, in other words, is one of the most controversial
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last half-century</TIMEX>, his life a story rife with histrionic
tableaux, profound ideological warfare, and high-level scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Tanenhaus</ENAMEX>,
a free-lance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, has written the first serious biography of him. Yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanenhaus</ENAMEX>' book, while well-researched and lucid, hardly does justice to its
subject. Tanenhaus submits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> to a genteel alchemy in which the
wonderfully low is transmuted to the dismally high, and vitality is traded for
status.

            There is much that is
tantalizingly unclear about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> case, mysteries I would have
expected a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> to elucidate. We know little about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>'
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> activity, which terminated, he assured the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, with his
break from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. I wanted to learn more about his marriage and his
relations with his imperious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laha</ENAMEX> (with whom he continued to spend much
of his time after his marriage); with his unhappy, aloof, bisexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>;
and with his alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>, who committed suicide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">begging Whittaker</ENAMEX> to join him.

            We need to
learn more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>, too. What about his <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less-than-manly</NUMEX> side?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> referred to a "mince" in his walk, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, a staunch
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, always believed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>' family
background was as lurid as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>'. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was cold and controlling; his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> both committed suicide (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907 and 1929</TIMEX>, respectively); his
beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX>, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> was beginning his
superbly calculated rise out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> muck to suave and well-tailored
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eminence</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>.

            
For light on the psychological aspects of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> story, the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> remain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Weinstein</ENAMEX>'s authoritative
Perjury: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers Case</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1978) and Chambers</ENAMEX> himself, who, in
Witness , is far more revealing about himself than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanenhaus</ENAMEX> chooses to
be. But I had also hoped that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> would analyze the
historical controversies over the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' views are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">central</ENAMEX>. One can believe, as I do, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' testimony against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> without
accepting his interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet-American</ENAMEX> confrontation. Tanenhaus,
however, though he points to some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' blind spots and ideological
excesses, does not doubt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>' more or less total culpability for the
long disaster we call the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. In his telling, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers'</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> in general "willfully" refused to mount a
full-scale espionage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the war years</TIMEX> (when the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>). None of the important revisionist work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Appleman Williams</ENAMEX> and others--work that poses a powerful
challenge to such assumptions--is cited in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanenhaus</ENAMEX>' footnotes or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bibliography</ENAMEX>.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> is to be believed, he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> met in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early-mid-1930s</TIMEX>. They became
intimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> as they collaborated in stealing government documents and
transmitting them to their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>. At their last meeting, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>
was preparing to flee the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, he begged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> to join him, but the supercool
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> seemed to admire just what horrified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> behavior--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>
"played for keeps," as he put it--and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Priscilla</ENAMEX>, termed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>'
agonized apostasy "mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">masturbation</ENAMEX>."

            By all accounts, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> did not meet again until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>, among others, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Un-American Activities Committee</ENAMEX>. Most of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> and others named
initially took the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUAC</ENAMEX> (though they confessed to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> shortly after). Some were murdered or committed suicide in mysterious
circumstances early in the investigations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Dexter White</ENAMEX>, once a top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>, succumbed to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1948</TIMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>, against the advice of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>,
chose to defy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUAC</ENAMEX>, insisting that he had never even met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chambers</ENAMEX>,
much less been a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>.

            From the
start, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>, impeccably groomed and eerily calm ("It might be someone else who
was on trial," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> marveled), relied on his patrician credentials.
By now, he had admitted to knowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>, but merely as one "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
Crosley," a "deadbeat" he'd been kind to in passing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade earlier</TIMEX>. How could
the testimony of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chambers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> asked with icy contempt, visibly
unkempt, overweight, and "forbiddingly drab" (in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel Trilling</ENAMEX>'s phrase),
with no style and little personal status, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had lived, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>' words,
"in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewers</ENAMEX>, plotting against his native land," possibly outweigh the simple
facts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>' career as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX>, trusted aide to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yalta</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>? It was a drama of politics and
class, the "liberal" aristocracy of the New Deal pitted against the ill-bred
ugly upstarts of right-wing reaction, a prelude and cue to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCarthy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>.

            
Most of all, it was a competition in
truth-telling (or falsifying), a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> duel in credibility occurring amid a
mounting pileup of classified information, exposés, and oxymoronic jargon that
would eventually donate euphemistic doublespeak terms like "dual hegemony,"
"limited nuclear war," and the slogan "win the peace" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> language.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> was eager to take a lie-detector test, on television (his lawyers
dissuaded him). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> never volunteered to take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, but he pointed out to HUAC
that it was "inconceivable" that he, a highly public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, could have fooled
for so long the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX> who saw "my every facial expression,"
"heard the tones in which I spoke," and "knew my every act." It was, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> saw it, a crisis of faith. Whom, and what, could you believe?

            During
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUAC</ENAMEX> hearings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Hébert</ENAMEX> commented, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whichever</ENAMEX> one of you
is lying is the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has ever produced." Or as one
headline succinctly put it, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's the Psycho Now?</ENAMEX>" If a "psychopath," a term
that enjoyed its greatest vogue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, is someone who meets no
inner resistance in the act of uttering and maintaining what the world holds to
be untruth, the honors must go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>. The evidence that has accumulated over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, mostly from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> archives, has overwhelmingly favored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>'
version of the facts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tellingly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> he met in prison
the "healthiest" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there, because they "had no sense of guilt." But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> had his own secrets and hidden motives--his pathological drive toward
martyrdom, his homosexuality (the sin of sins in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> era, routinely
treated as a synonym for treason), and his undoubted obsession with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>. He,
too, "began to play the part assigned to me," he writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Witness</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strangely</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanenhaus</ENAMEX> chooses to withhold all information
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> until he gets to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chambers-Hiss</ENAMEX> confrontation. He omits
altogether the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>, though he never doubts
its authenticity. He identifies unavoidable references to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX> only in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">footnotes</ENAMEX>, and finally presents their relationship in a brief flashback in the
course of detailing the trials. By this awkward, deflationary reordering and
compression, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanenhaus</ENAMEX> clearly means to assert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' importance independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiss</ENAMEX>, to give him the dignity that comes with autonomy. But this is to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">desert</ENAMEX>, even betray, his subject. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' peculiar fate, and choice,
to live a life that was inseparable from another's. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have been
joined forever in an intimacy deeper and more complex than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or
sex.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>
developed increasing reservations in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> about the direction the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX> was taking, distancing himself first from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe McCarthy</ENAMEX>, then
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, and even from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Buckley Jr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> .
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' importance lies, finally, not in his politics but in his romantic
penchant for the extremes of the psychic and political undergrounds. With his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">susceptibility</ENAMEX> to ridicule and parody, his air of furtive portentousness, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apocalyptic Manichaean</ENAMEX> vision of purity overtaken by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, his dazzling
displays of the uncanny intuitive skills that sometimes accompany obsession, he
was a pulp-fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dostoyevsky</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> he admired above all others.

            
Though he would have considered himself a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champion</ENAMEX> of high art, melodrama was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>' medium. The roles he picked for
himself were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dostoyevskian</ENAMEX> ones--the doppelgänger, playing unheeded guilty
conscience to a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mephistopheles</ENAMEX>; the high-pitched prophet, trying to
break what he saw as the "invincible ignorance" of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> blinded to the
"crisis of history" by its prosperity and misguided generous-mindedness. For
Hegel, history was a slaughter bench; for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>, it had become an emergency
room. He has not been adequately served by a biographer unwilling or unable to
understand the nightmare of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> epistemology, the place where politics and
pathology become indistinguishable.

         
      
   
