
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic Pride</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Butler Yeats</ENAMEX> liked
to organize his life into zones and areas, but he was a biased cartographer of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' map of himself, there are no obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, and all
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> lead to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. His was, as he saw it, a continuous poetic journey, aided
here and there by slaves or muses--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Symons</ENAMEX>, the symbolist who introduced
him to the poetry of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Verlaine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stéphane Mallarmé</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>; Maud
Gonne, who made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> nationalism romantic; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Augusta Gregory</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aristocrat</ENAMEX> who collaborated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> in his search of old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">folklore</ENAMEX> and legends; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezra Pound</ENAMEX>, who stiffened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' soft "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Celtic</ENAMEX>" verse
with a little modernist geometry.

            In his
later verse and in many of his letters, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yeats</ENAMEX> interpreted those friendships as
inevitable. They fed his destiny, which was, as he saw it, to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s
greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX> have too often collaborated in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">legend</ENAMEX>, separating their accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> into green "developments" and golden
"phases." The result is a fairly schematic narrative: The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hothead</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">early Celtic Revivalist</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> produces lovely impracticalities until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> explodes; he learns about reality, becomes a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> of civil war,
and a modernist to boot; after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>, or thereabouts, he becomes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those
"monuments of unageing intellect" about whom he writes in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sailing</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantium</ENAMEX>"--the splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complainer</ENAMEX> of the late verse. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ellman</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poet</ENAMEX>'s finest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Foster</ENAMEX>, followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeats</ENAMEX>' own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of
himself into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> opposing selves--the great bard and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who sat down to
breakfast <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each morning</TIMEX>.

            In this superb biography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> unscrambles destiny and
complicates it into life. The most distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> alive, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX>
floods his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Yeats</ENAMEX> with historical detail. He is less interested in literary
exegesis than in historical accident; indeed, his criticism of the poems is a
little spare. But he attends to the chaos of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' early life, a bohemian
shuffle during which he was at the mercy of his improvident peripatetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.B. Yeats</ENAMEX>. He gives a deep description of the tensions and
ambiguities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' shabby-genteel <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> origins. His sketch of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hierarchical</ENAMEX> and socially touchy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1880s</TIMEX> is almost
novelistic--something like the caste-frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX> of some contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>
fiction.

            How silly
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeats</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auden</ENAMEX> uses the adjective in his elegy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>, and it is
supposed to include all of us: "You were silly like us." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeats</ENAMEX> had a
singular silliness, which is what makes his early poetry so patchy. Bounced
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, he was not at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> school long enough to collect a
rounded education. Throughout his life, he fed on scraps--in particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
literature, and magic. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1880s</TIMEX>, he was snared by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madame Helena</ENAMEX> Petrovna
Blavatsky, the eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> who invented theosophy--a blend of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>
mysticism, occult optimism, and universal brotherhood. He never really escaped.
When he shaved off his beard in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1889</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blavatsky</ENAMEX> (then living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>)
lamented the loss of "the mesmeric force that collects in a beard."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> remained a devotee of various forms of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spiritualism</ENAMEX> and mesmerism. Theosophy was the craze of the age and, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>, who had a keen interest in the occult, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeats</ENAMEX> was on the creative qui
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vive</ENAMEX>. But he seemed to swallow far too much tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. He believed almost
all of it. He confessed that he saw no reason not to believe in the actual
existence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> fairies and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goblins</ENAMEX>. A faith in magic, in the spirit world,
became his aesthetic: He denounced naturalism, fought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>'s
"mechanistic" vision (he once had a dream in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> appeared, clicking like
a sewing-machine and smiling insanely), and proposed a poetry of dream and
Celtic twilight that would shun the hustle of the world. He would "live alone
in the bee-loud glade," as he put it in "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Isle of Innisfree</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX>),
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the early poems that established his renown.

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">perfumed hermeticism</ENAMEX> produced early verse that is easy to love and hard to
like. It is poetry to which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> swooned as an adolescent. Looking again at the
poetry written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1889 and 1914</TIMEX>, one notices the scattered petals of
familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, the secondhand imagery, the automatic despondency (far too
much "ancient sorrow"), the druids, fairies, hermits, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witches</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Goodness,</ENAMEX>
here is something called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Druid vapour"</ENAMEX>! Too often, the poetry yields no
intellectual sap. One longs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX> to clear the mist.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> was huge: It survived by consuming its
own weaknesses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> effectively shut down his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic</ENAMEX> dream world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX> with
the starker, more acute verse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Responsibilities</ENAMEX> . He let the realities
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s civil war invade and occupy his poetic world. More than this, he
used the earlier romanticism of the verse as a wainscot against which he might
scuff his heels: "Romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s dead and gone," he wrote in "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX>." His later poetry tolled this bell again and again. Yet this "Romantic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland"</ENAMEX> was largely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yeats</ENAMEX>' own poetic creation in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. He turned
his own earlier verse into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> at the very moment of its abandonment. It
was a brilliant feat of personal expansion.

            Besides,
the early poetry is tougher than it seems. There are realities, homely details,
and gorgeous originalities alongside the more sentimental visions. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hermits</ENAMEX> meet on a beach, one of them is not concerned with being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seer</ENAMEX>,
but is scratching himself--"rummaging for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flea</ENAMEX>." One is never far from
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drinkers</ENAMEX>' randy laughter." Or from lines that fly beyond
accountability: "the leopard-coloured <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">; "For God</ENAMEX> goes by with white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">footfall</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s biography shows us this double-masked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poet</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dreamer</ENAMEX> who never strayed very far from reality. Above all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> is
ruthless about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' ruthlessness: He shows how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> went about building
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> literature in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> at the end of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, and how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goblins</ENAMEX> and fairies were foot soldiers
in that campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mythology</ENAMEX> had to be dragged into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> poetry. Yeats
was energetically shameless in this regard. He wrote kind reviews of books on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history and mythology by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Gregory</ENAMEX>. He demolished, in
print, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. He was especially harsh with his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Dowden</ENAMEX>, who espoused a benevolent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Irish cosmopolitanism</NUMEX> in opposition to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' literary nationalism. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1887 and 1892</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> published more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> items in newspapers and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. He also wrote his long (and beautiful)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poem</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wanderings of Oisin</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1889</TIMEX>); published, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX>, a list of the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX> books; edited a book of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> verse; and, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Gregory</ENAMEX> as co-worker,
toured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> for their folk memories.

            Very
occasionally, one wishes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> would look up from his table of details
and survey the larger literary scene. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' literary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is a case
in point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> might have attended to the poems and shown how willfully they
use place-names (and in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> verse, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>' names) to erect
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> literature. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> wants to leave his "traces/ On Munster
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connemara</ENAMEX> skies." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pushkin</ENAMEX>, who was building <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> poetry out of
very little, did something very similar in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Onegin</ENAMEX> , only 50 years
before. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Pessoa</ENAMEX>, almost exactly contemporary with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>, was doing the
same thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> literature, producing patriotic and nationalistic
verse.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s expertise is historical, and he warns us that
he will write as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>. No one is going to better him in this area. He
goes behind the wrestled solemnities of the poetry to reveal the effort, the
strategizing, and the silliness. We learn, for example, that on his field trips
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Gregory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> had difficulty understanding the thick <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> accent of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>. The incomprehension was mutual. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of this anthropology
looked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' stylish black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> suit--he was always a careful, "poetic"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dresser</ENAMEX>--and took him to be a proselytizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergyman</ENAMEX>.

            Above all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> shows us a
historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, propelled and limited by his inheritance. Yeats was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protestant</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, which, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> suggests, might have led him to
overcompensate with a romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> fiercer than that of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX>. At the same time--and this is where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s careful
discriminations are so useful--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeats</ENAMEX> hated obviously ideological poetry. He was
that unfamiliar compound, a political aesthete. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irish poets</ENAMEX>, learn your trade/
Sing whatever is well made," he grumpily advised in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> in "Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Bulben</ENAMEX>,"
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his very last poems. This struggle between "the marvelous and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">murderous</ENAMEX>," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seamus Heaney</ENAMEX> has put it, is still acute in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> poetry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s book is not only a fine account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' early life; it is a subtle
introduction to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> nationalism.

         
      
   
