
   
   
      
         
            Queen Katharine

            The saga that unfolds in
Personal History , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">625</NUMEX>-page autobiography, is worthy
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Campbell</ENAMEX> exegesis: A young Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Meyer</ENAMEX>, marries
his aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Agnes</ENAMEX>, and they spawn a royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> princesses
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>. Dominated by their overbearing literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and ignored by
their dismissive multimillionaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, these virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orphans</ENAMEX> are raised by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Frumpy Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine</ENAMEX> shivers with
inadequacy.

            But wait! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charismatic Philip</ENAMEX>
appears from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> (by way of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law</ENAMEX>) to rescue the grown-up
Katharine, enchant the queen, and seduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> with his magic. (Actually,
the old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monarch</ENAMEX> falls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>'s flattery, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> other powerful elders
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix Frankfurter</ENAMEX>, for whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> marries
Katharine, and the king gives them the ink-stained duchy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> bear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progeny</ENAMEX>, and the duchy grows mighty--mighty
enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> to anoint a king himself (LBJ).

            Darkness
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">descends: Worn</ENAMEX> out by his labors on Wall Street, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> dies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dominates Katharine</ENAMEX> as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> did, goes mad over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>
and then kills himself. The cruel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>'s lights finally expire. Only then does
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale begin. The self-doubting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katharine</ENAMEX> raises the queen's tiara to
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slays</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon the Awful</ENAMEX>, holds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> and around the
world, buries the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Star</ENAMEX> , and builds an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> as she prepares
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>, for the throne.

            The story is irresistible, as is the telling. Just when
you're ready to credit the copy to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gottlieb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> quotes
an old letter of hers, a sharp critique of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that she, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 17</TIMEX>,
sent her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> bought the paper. The woman
can write.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autobiographies</ENAMEX> are more
about concealing than telling, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> ropes off relatively little. Her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s personal lives are deliberately excised from the book; the cowardly
episode in which she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Bradlee</ENAMEX> misused their inordinate power to scuttle
a wretchedly flawed book about her ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine the Great</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>, published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>) is not mentioned; and she only hints at her post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
romantic life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai Stevenson</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McNamara</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Heath</ENAMEX>? An
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> stallion? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watch Graham wink</ENAMEX>.

            Oddly,
Personal History largely echoes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Felsenthal</ENAMEX>'s unauthorized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Privilege</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX>
Story-- oddly, because its publication in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> incensed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lally Weymouth</ENAMEX> compared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felsenthal</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe McCarthy</ENAMEX> in the
Post op-ed pages, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Graham</ENAMEX> excoriated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> 
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> letters page. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX>, published a rave by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Steel</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grahams</ENAMEX> were enraged by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felsenthal</ENAMEX>'s cold and detailed charting of the psychotic free fall of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katharine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, New Deal/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Frontier</ENAMEX> bright-light <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Graham</ENAMEX>. Felsenthal
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine</ENAMEX> both report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> assumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agnes</ENAMEX>' role as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> and emotional
abuser, but only the biographer writes that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> lost his mind, he taunted
his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> slurs.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s aptly named book crosscuts between the
engrossing social history of her life and times--populated by the likes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Curie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Steichen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auguste Rodin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Mann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Baruch</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Lippmann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Capote</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Mitford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scotty Reston</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emperor Hirohito</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Paley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>--and her agonizing
personal history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s portrait of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, the social-climbing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">booze</ENAMEX>-hounding, domineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agnes</ENAMEX>, makes a persuasive case for matricide.
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">otherhood</ENAMEX> was not exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s first priority," she writes. Or again,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX> set impossibly high standards for us." At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>
complains, she was taught little about "the practical aspects of life," like
"how to dress, sew, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, and, rather more important, relate to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
any kind, let alone young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>."

            Married
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Katharine</ENAMEX> comes to "enjoy the role of doormat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>." When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> arrive, she becomes a self-described "drudge" who has "no idea how to
organize a meal." Just when you think that the ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duckling</ENAMEX> has snorkeled to
the bottom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marianas Trench</ENAMEX> of her lowest self-esteem, she dives still
deeper: "I ignored the fact that [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>] was frequently using [his] wit at my
expense. [He] was often critical or cutting in his remarks when things weren't
just right--either about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or my clothes, for example, which left lots
of room for disparaging remarks."

            Depleted of self-confidence? Not quite. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> constantly
discovers new reserves of emptiness. Seated next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> at a
party, she panics that she'll bore him to death. (She does fine.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> intimidate her--"Despite my own background and actually having been born
there, I always felt like a country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>"--no matter that her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had introduced her to high society while she was still in diapers, and
that she had frolicked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paleys</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitneys</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mellons</ENAMEX> as an
adult. The business world spooks her, too. Following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>'s death, she assumes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Co.</ENAMEX> helm with trepidation because she is "uneducated in
even the basics of the working world."

            Can't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cook</ENAMEX>, can't sew, can't run a household, can't stand up to her imperious mom and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, can't make small talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> or notables, can't run a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune 500</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, what did you learn to do in your first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46 years</TIMEX> on the planet?

            
All modesty is false, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s extravagant
humility is no exception. If you apologize for your shortcomings, you can count
on harvesting sympathy. If you apologize for your nonexistent shortcomings, you
harvest sympathy and blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> to your genuine shortcomings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>
plays both games, perhaps because there's truth, of a sort, to her claims of
inadequacy. At critical points in her life, she chose brilliant and charismatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to marry (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law Review</ENAMEX> ), hire
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX>--well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX>), or go into business with (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffett</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modern Midas</ENAMEX>). Against this backdrop of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, any mortal would quake. But her
"I am inept" self-portrait is still hard to swallow. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> died, she ran
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and birthed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, rubbed political shoulders with everyone
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>, contributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> campaigns, worked the back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> at
a slew of national political conventions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1948 and 1960</TIMEX>, and sat in on
negotiations as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> purchased the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> ,
television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .

            Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s earliest confessions of incompetence are refuted by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
transparent scheme to groom her for some top slot at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . After she
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>, he arranges a job for her as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco News</ENAMEX> , and afterward hires her as a
Post editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Meyer</ENAMEX> was a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chauvinist</ENAMEX> with no intention of letting his most
talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> run a newspaper. But if he sinned against his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and her
gender by giving his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wunderkind</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> the controlling interest in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> (no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> should have to work for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> said),
then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> surely sinned against her eldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lally</ENAMEX>, for
handing the keys to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Co.</ENAMEX> to the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>. Ownership
has its privileges.

            Personal History's false modesty begins to evaporate after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>'s suicide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>. Seizing control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katharine</ENAMEX> swats the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">newspaper jackals</ENAMEX> who want to steal it: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Newhouse</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Thomson</ENAMEX>. She orders the top eye-shade to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as
a partnership with her, just as he did with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>, even though she doesn't
really grasp business. She does understand editorial, though, and better than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> did. (He was more interested in becoming a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> dude, writing
speeches for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>, running <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMSAT</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, and joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAND</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>)

            Impressed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX>'s remark that he'd "give his left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>" to edit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , she
imposes him on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> over the objections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. And
she <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffett</ENAMEX> to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Co.</ENAMEX> public, which makes
everyone involved nasty rich. She triples the editorial budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1966</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX> to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great</ENAMEX>. She hires and fires top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> as wickedly as any male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>. She publishes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Pentagon Papers</ENAMEX> at
great peril to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and stares down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> when he
threatens to revoke the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s lucrative broadcast licenses. She battles and
beats the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pressmen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> who think they, not she, own the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

            
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> associate the risk-taking cockiness
and gaiety of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine-Ben-</ENAMEX>era <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX>. But, as anyone
who has seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> run a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>' meeting knows, she is an agile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrogant</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gracious beast</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is as much a product of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">personality</ENAMEX>, talents, and priorities as it is of his. I refer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doubters</ENAMEX> to the
Post as published by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and his hand-picked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Downie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> It's as humdrum and safe as they are.

            Truth be told, the ugly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duckling</ENAMEX> never needed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX>'s left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to transform herself into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">carnivorous swan</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
