
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dungeons</ENAMEX> and Dragons

            It has
always been easy to make fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1833-1898</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
Pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Raphaelite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>. How could a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contemporary of Degas</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manet's</ENAMEX>, spend his time filling medieval ghost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>
with somnambulant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX> and maidens? Who are these anorexic figures with
their stoned expressions and "over-shampooed hair" (as Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Pope-Hennessy</ENAMEX>
once quipped)? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, never much of a showplace for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> art, has mounted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> exhibition that in its sheer size and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensiveness</ENAMEX>--there's always <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more room than you thought, including a
dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> decorated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>--asserts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s importance. But
you've got to be in the mood, for this is an art that, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagnerian</ENAMEX> opera or
sumo wrestling (both wickedly caricatured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX>), requires a
suspension of ordinary impatience. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX>, who reviewed a key exhibition
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1878</TIMEX>, wisely advised his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> to approach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> "good humouredly
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liberally</ENAMEX> [since] he offers an entertainment which is for us to take or to
leave."

            It is easy
to laugh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX>. It is harder to understand him. He knew exactly what
he was doing, and he did it exceedingly well. "I mean by a picture," he wrote,
"a beautiful romantic dream of something that never was, never will be--in a
light better than any light that ever shone--in a land no one can define, or
remember, only desire." It is the piling on of negatives that is significant
here, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> was a profoundly reactive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. The Impressionists have
trained our eyes to see the modern world of work and leisure in a certain way
and in a certain--natural--light and to think that it is a good thing to banish
myth from modern painting. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> hated that light and that world,
inventing another one from Arthurian romances and early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> paintings. "The
more materialistic science becomes," he boasted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>, "the more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angels</ENAMEX> shall I paint."

            Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>, the stronghold of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
industrialism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a gilder and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framer</ENAMEX> whose handicraft
traditions predated the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a week</TIMEX> of
his birth. The theme of recovery--of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s craft ethos, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
soothing presence--runs through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX>' career. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> he met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, another middle-class dreamer in flight from the modern world. They took
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1856</TIMEX>. Their idols were the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pre</ENAMEX>-Raphaelite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ruskin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dante Gabriel Rossetti</ENAMEX>, whose passion for medieval
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> art before the individualizing tendencies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> (hence
"pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX>") they shared. Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> studied briefly with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rossetti</ENAMEX>, and his
early work, with its intense floral patterning--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> on the ground
blending with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maidens</ENAMEX>' costumes--could easily be mistaken
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rossetti's</ENAMEX>.

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> launched a design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> joined up
as a founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> form an interesting contrast.
Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rail-thin</ENAMEX> and reclusive, had a single-minded devotion to the
visual arts and especially to drawing. The overweight <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>, caricatured in
several of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX>' witty sketches and nicknamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Topsy</ENAMEX>," applied his
capacious mind to every aspect of culture and society: literature and art,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> and politics, architecture and city planning. He was one of the
towering figures of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and remains a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>--he's a darling of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> and the academic left--in its intellectual and political life.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> wanted to work out the nuts and bolts of an actual socialist society to
replace the capitalist, industrial society he so hated.

            Burne-Jones hated it no less, but there's little of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> in his temperament. He was content to accept commissions and to
leave the arguments to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>. He was the brilliant medieval craftsman
envisioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, turning out extraordinary designs for just about
everything--not only such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">staples</ENAMEX> as tapestries, stained glass, tiles,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">furniture</ENAMEX>, and book illustrations but also jewelry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, and embroidered
shoes. All but the shoes are on view at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> emphasis on the
handmade, the rough-hewed, and the handed-down--what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thorstein Veblen</ENAMEX>, a year
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX>' death, wickedly called the "exaltation of the
defective"--did not reverse the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machines</ENAMEX>, after all,
make things more cheaply.) Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauhaus</ENAMEX> and other utopian schemes to
redesign the world, however, it left a lasting and positive imprint on
international taste.

            In his
paintings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> almost never portrays the world of the artisan (except
in a caricature of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>, his fat ass as wide as the loom at which he works).
His languid figures lined up across the canvas do almost nothing; they can
sometimes work up the energy to idly pluck a lute, or to roll the dice on a
backgammon table (see , at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX>). Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> prefers stasis to
activity; he likes to paint <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> asleep, turned into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, or
chained up (like the maiden waiting to see if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dragon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> gets
there first). In the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Briar Rose</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">or Sleeping Beauty</ENAMEX>) he found a
perfect theme, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX> and maidens and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> and queens all asleep amid
the flourishing underbrush. Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> seem always in freeze frame,
like the frustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pre-Raphaelite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">touchstone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keats</ENAMEX>' "Ode on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grecian Urn</ENAMEX>": "Bold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, never, never canst <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thou kiss</ENAMEX>,/ Though winning near
the goal." The beautiful (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868-77</TIMEX>, also at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX>), where the mood is
so lulling that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cupid</ENAMEX> has drowsed off, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX>' idea of bliss.

            When his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> unexpectedly wake up, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galatea</ENAMEX> in his
"Pygmalion" series or the spurned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> emerging from the almond <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> in
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1881-82</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merseyside</ENAMEX>), it's often disconcerting, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> look as though
they should have let sleeping maidens lie. The culminating image in this vein
is (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1873-74</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merseyside</ENAMEX>), in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> found biographical resonance in
the scene of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magician</ENAMEX> lured to his doom by the femme fatale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nimue</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> for the temptress with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX> in her hair was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Zambaco</ENAMEX>, a
sculptress of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> background who was in turn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupil</ENAMEX>, studio
assistant, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> before he broke with her in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1869</TIMEX> and returned to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">long-suffering wife</ENAMEX>. Modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with their sexual appetites remained in his
mind a threat as great as modern machinery. In a bizarre late painting called
(ca. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1891-98</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ringling Museum of Arts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>), an armored <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> with
oversize phallic anchors looms in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of which are lined with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scantily</ENAMEX> clad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> explained, with characteristic vagueness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>, that he had depicted "a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirenland</ENAMEX>--I don't know when or
where--not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Sirens</ENAMEX>, but any sirens, anywhere, that lure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on to
destruction."

            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> was
among the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>; his reputation, thanks to
international exhibitions and traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, was as high in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. He who had painted so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX> accepted a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">baronetcy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> died, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a few months</TIMEX> of the
publication of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelmscott Chaucer</ENAMEX> , which had illustrations by
Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>--one of their greatest collaborations. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years</TIMEX> after that, Sir
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> died of a heart attack. He had spent a lifetime imagining solemn and
ritualized occasions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX> arranged a memorial service in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Cathedral</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> had been so honored. It
was the one scene in his life--the right mix of ceremonial and stasis--that
Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> himself might have found visually appealing.

             

         
      
   
