
   
   
      
         
            Shut Up, He Explained

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Fiss</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX> and a highly regarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> of constitutional law. The
subject of this short book is the present direction of the law governing the
freedom of speech. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiss</ENAMEX> has to say about it is worth attending
to not merely because of his prominence in the field but because his argument
is planted in the common assumptive ground of a lot of contemporary academic
thought about the bankruptcy of individualism. The thesis of the book is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss'</ENAMEX>,
but the wisdom is conventional.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiss</ENAMEX> thinks the present direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> law is a bad one, and he
has an idea about how we might improve it. The short way to put his argument
(though it is not quite the way he puts it) is to say that our approach to
speech has become increasingly permissive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> have become more and more
reluctant to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to interfere with the rights of individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> to say what they wish, and it is time to roll back that permissiveness
and to embark on a new approach that would permit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to silence some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> and promote others, but still, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX> argues, in the name of freedom of
speech.

            This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiss</ENAMEX> means by the "irony" in his title: that
true freedom of speech for all requires suppressing the speech of some. This is
not, technically, an irony. It is a paradox. An irony would be the observation
that an attempt to increase freedom for all often entails, despite our best
efforts, a decrease in freedom for a few. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX> had addressed the subject of
free speech in this spirit, as an irony, he would undoubtedly have had some
interesting things to say, for he is a learned and temperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. But he
has, instead, chosen to address the issue as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> he
regards as politically disadvantaged--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of racial-hate
speech, the poor (or, at least, the not-rich), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are critical of
market capitalism--and to design a constitutional theory that will enable those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to enlist the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in efforts either to suppress speech they dislike or
to subsidize speech they do like, without running afoul of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>.
Embarked on this task, the most learned and temperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in the world would
have a hard time avoiding tendentiousness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX> does not avoid it.

            
               The
Irony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Speech</ENAMEX> is a discussion of several speech issues:
campaign-finance laws, state funding for the arts, pornography, speech codes,
and equal time. These discussions are not doctrinaire, but their general
inclination is to favor state intervention, on political grounds, in each of
those areas--that is, to favor restrictions on campaign spending, greater
regulation of pornography, and so on. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX>' analyses of specific cases are
presented against a lightly sketched historical argument. Light though the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sketching</ENAMEX> is, the historical argument is almost the most objectionable thing
about the book, since it involves a distortion of the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> law that is fairly plain even to someone who is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX>.

            
The argument is that "the liberalism of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteenth century</TIMEX> was defined by the claims of individual liberty and resulted
in an unequivocal demand for liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, [while] the liberalism of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> embraces the value of equality as well as liberty." The constitutional
law of free speech, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiss</ENAMEX>, was shaped by the earlier type of liberalism--he
calls it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">libertarian"</ENAMEX>--which regarded free speech as a right of individual
self-expression; it is now used to foil efforts to regulate speech in the name
of the newer liberal value, equality. Contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, inheriting both
these traditions, find themselves in a bind. They want, let's say, black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to be free from harassment at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> where they are, racially,
in a minority, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> worry that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> cannot be "equal" if
they feel intimidated. But those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> get upset at the thought of
outlawing hate speech, since that would mean infringing upon the right of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to express themselves.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestion</ENAMEX>--this is the chief theoretical proposal of his book--is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> should stop thinking about this as a conflict between liberty and
equality and start thinking about it as a conflict between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberty</ENAMEX>: social vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>, he says, was intended to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foster</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Brennan</ENAMEX>'s words) "uninhibited, robust, and wide-open" debate
in society as a whole; speech that inhibits or monopolizes that debate should
therefore fall outside the protection of the law. We can maximize the total
freedom of speech by silencing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who prevent others from speaking--when
they utter racial epithets, represent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in degrading ways, use their wealth
to dominate the press and the political process, or block the funding of
unorthodox art.

            The historical part of this analysis rests on a canard,
which is the assertion that the constitutional law of free speech emerged from
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">19 th -century</NUMEX> classical laissez-faire liberalism. It did not. It
emerged at the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, and the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> in its
creation--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Learned Hand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Wendell Holmes Jr.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Brandeis</ENAMEX>--were not
classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>; they were progressives. They abhorred the doctrine of
natural rights because, in their time, that doctrine was construed to cover not
the right to "self-expression" but the "right to property." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Turn-of-the-century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> did not display a libertarian attitude toward civil rights; they
displayed a libertarian attitude toward economic rights, tending to throw out
legislation aimed at regulating industry and protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> on the grounds
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had a constitutional right to enter into contracts and to use their
own property as they saw fit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brandeis</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX>
consistently supported state intervention in economic affairs--the passage of
health and safety regulations, the protection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, the imposition of
taxes, and so on. The post-New Deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> with the
value of equality are their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> of the19 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th -century</ENAMEX>
classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> "liberalisms"
are, in fact, almost entirely different political philosophies.

            Hand,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandeis</ENAMEX> based their <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> opinions not on some putative
right to individual self-expression (an idea <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> referred to as "the right
of the donkey to drool") but on a democratic need for full and open political
debate. First <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> law since their time has performed its balancing acts
on precisely that social value--the very value <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX> now proposes we need to
insert into <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment jurisprudence</ENAMEX>. We don't need to insert it, because
it was there from the start.

            
Why does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiss</ENAMEX> portray the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Amendment jurisprudence in this perverted way? Because he wants to line up his
own free-speech argument within the conventional academic view that our
problems are mostly the consequences of an antiquated and discreditable
ideology of liberal individualism, and that they can mostly be solved by
adopting a social-constructionist, or communitarian, or "intersubjective" view
of human nature instead. The merits of liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individualism</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communitarianism</ENAMEX> can await another occasion to be debated. For since the law
governing the freedom of speech does not emerge out of libertarianism, the
matter does not boil down to replacing an obsolete belief in "self-expression"
with a more up-to-date belief in "robust debate," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX> would like to think
it does. What it boils down to is whether we need to replace the
Hand-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brandeis</ENAMEX> way of maximizing the benefits of free speech in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> society, which tries to push the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as far out of the picture as
possible, with a different way, which tries to get the state farther into the
picture.

            Here,
assuming we want to try the interventionist approach, it is hard to see how a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-size theory can possibly fit all cases. The issues underlying pornography,
hate speech, arts grants, campaign finance, and equal-time provisions are all
different. The ideological impetus behind judicial developments in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last two</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, campaign finance and equal-time provisions, is related less to speech,
except as a kind of constitutional cover, than to a revival of the old "right
to property"--that is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> tends to disapprove of legislative and
administrative efforts to require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> to carry "opposing viewpoints"
on the grounds that since it's their property, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of television stations
should be able to broadcast what they like. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX> believes that the need for
equal-time laws is as urgent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, which is peculiar in
light of the proliferation of media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> does arguably have
an interest, compatible with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>, in stipulating the way those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> are used, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX>' discussion of those issues is the least aggravating
in his book.

            Still, that discussion, like his discussions of the other
issues, rests on a claim long associated with the left--the claim, in a phrase,
that the minority is really the majority. In the case of speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiss</ENAMEX> appears
to believe that the reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is less enlightened than he
would wish it to be concerning matters such as feminism, the rights of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>, and regulation of industry is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are denied access to the
opinions and information that would enlighten them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is denied this
access because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, in thrall to the ideology of individualism, refuses
either to interfere with speech bullies--such as pornographers--who "silence"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, or to subsidize the speech of the unorthodox, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mapplethorpe</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX>'
analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mapplethorpe</ENAMEX> case offers a good example of the perils of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interventionist</ENAMEX> approach. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> policy is, unquestionably, a mess. The solution
usually proposed is divorce: Either get the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> out of the business
altogether or invent some ironclad process for distributing the money using
strictly artistic criteria. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Fiss</ENAMEX> rejects both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX>; he wants the
criteria to be political. He thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> should subsidize art that will
enhance the "robustness" of the debate and should therefore prefer unorthodox
art--though only, of course, if it represents a viewpoint the endowment
considers, by virtue of social need and a prior history of exclusion, worthy of
its megaphone. (No <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> art, in other words.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mapplethorpe</ENAMEX>'s photographs seem to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX> to
qualify under these guidelines, since, he says, "in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
crisis confronted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in the starkest fashion and provoked urgent questions
regarding the scope and direction of publicly funded medical research. To
address those issues the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>--represented by the casual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>--needed an understanding of the lives and practices of the gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, so long hidden from view." This seems completely wrongheaded. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
(for the most part) didn't find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mapplethorpe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> 
               Portfolio
photographs objectionable because they depicted homosexuality. They found them
objectionable because they depicted sadomasochism. The notion that it was what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiss</ENAMEX> calls a "source of empowerment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the gay community" to
have homosexuality associated with snarling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> prancing around in leather
jockstraps, using bullwhips as sex toys, and pissing in each other's mouths, at
a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> had become a national health problem and the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> was about to arise, is ludicrous. Any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairperson</ENAMEX> who had the
interests of the gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> at heart would have rushed to defund the
exhibit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> could not have demonized homosexuality more
effectively--which, of course, is why he was pleased to draw public attention
to the pictures. Now that is what we call an irony of free speech.

            Awarding funding to the work
of a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> because gay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> need more political clout is an
effort at cultural engineering, and the problem with cultural engineering is
the problem with social engineering raised to a higher power. We have a hard
enough time calculating the effects of the redistribution of wealth in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>. How can we possibly calculate the effects of redistributing the right
to speak--of taking it away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiss</ENAMEX> feels have spoken long
enough and mandating it for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he feels have not been adequately heard? One
thing that is plain from the brief unhappy history of campus speech codes is
that you automatically raise the value of the speech you punish and depress the
value of the speech you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>. There are indeed many ironies here. Maybe
someone will write a book about them.

         
      
   
