
   
   
      
         
            Hungry for Love

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> is a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel about anorexia. A young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Simon</ENAMEX> suffers from it, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Zimmerman</ENAMEX>, is on an all-consuming quest to
understand and cure it. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them, who met in college, have been living
together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> when the novel opens. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> has been
obsessively maintaining a reasonably healthy weight, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> has been
earnestly hoping that his loving devotion will ease her self-loathing (and
improve their sex life). But suddenly he has reason to suspect her of bingeing,
and the solicitous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> turns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sleuth</ENAMEX>. A "binge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>," he makes it his hidden
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vocation</ENAMEX> to amass clues to the secret of anorexia. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> range from
clinical studies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Bell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anorexia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Nude</ENAMEX> , not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>'s diary and the recesses of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anatomy</ENAMEX>. (He peruses her teeth for signs of decay from recurrent vomiting; he
flips through her laundry checking underwear for pubic-hair shedding, a sign of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malnutrition</ENAMEX>.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six months later</TIMEX>, when the novel ends, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> has become a wraith
and checked into the same private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> she was sent to as a starving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>, who has nearly had a breakdown, has come to a jolting
conclusion: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> wasn't a book. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was simply the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. I had been
misled by metaphors as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>."

            If this
book were a body, it would be an anorexic one. From the outset, the contours of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>'s problems are skeletally clear. She fits a standard anorexic
profile: overachieving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> from a well-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, with a distant father
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> whose ambitions (intellectual and sexual) have left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> feeling
overshadowed and neglected. She struggles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> with a grossly distorted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-image</ENAMEX> and an unrequited hunger for love. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sensitive Joseph</ENAMEX> is a striking
departure from male stereotype, yet the key to his anomalous solicitude and
eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">empathy</ENAMEX> could not be more obvious. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>'s older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn</ENAMEX>, the good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in the hard-working and undemonstrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zimmerman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, committed
suicide when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>. He has been guiltily preoccupied with the mystery of
female misery ever since.

            On top of these bare bones, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rosen</ENAMEX> gives his book a
big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>--another telltale feature of the anorexic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>
observes. ("Even with its turtleneck top doubled over, I could see, could
almost feel, that her neck was unnaturally thin, giving her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> ... an
enlarged look.") As if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> can't see right away that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> has an
appetite as perverse as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>'s (because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> himself doesn't see it right
away), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> the narrator laboriously mulls over the lessons he is learning
about her and about himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> provides him with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, too, a lapsed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychoanalyst</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Flek</ENAMEX> who discourses more definitively. It's Flek
who gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> his reading list, even as he warns him of the futility of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quest</ENAMEX> in oracular tones:

            Can't
you see, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>? You're not just trying to save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>. You're trying to solve
the riddle of female sadness itself. You're trying to solve the
self-destructive urge of humanity. You're trying to crack the mystery of the
body. Take it from someone who once tried to do these things for a living: it
isn't possible. You've been hunting the white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> and it isn't going to end
well if you don't take care of yourself.

            
Fiction inevitably loses some of its absorbing
appeal when you can see every muscle of the story move. There are moments (like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flek</ENAMEX>'s sermon) when this novel can make you wince. But it is precisely the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">artless</ENAMEX> refusal to pad out the psychological drama, coupled with a fastidious
attention to the most mundane physical details, that give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>
its interest. In his awkward novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> captures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> awkward, important
truths about anorexia: that its peculiar logic is not just tragic but comic,
and that despite the fascination it holds for those who suffer from it, and for
those who seek to make sense of it, anorexia is in fact quite boring.

            This
romantic book is saved by unexpectedly wry realism. In sensitive-obtuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> has found a humorous guide to the upside-down world in which an anorexic
suffers. In a typical scene, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> desperately needs to find out whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>
is bingeing. A kiss becomes a pretext for checking out her dental enamel, a
stroke of her hair for testing the firmness of the roots--a gawky parody of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>'s own involuted, detached sexuality. All the poking and prodding rouses
the irritated victim herself to a joke, an unusual display of wit at her and
his expense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> reaches down to her crotch (while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>'s heart pounds in
excitement), and "between pinched fingers she held a single, wirelike hair. She
offered it to me, a wildflower from a forbidden field. 'For you,' she said."
The quirky physical moments are easier to convey than the psychological
monotony of the obsession. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> dares to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> as lacking
in distinctive contour as she wishes her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> were. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> finds her enigmatic,
but the only real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enigma</ENAMEX> about this self-absorbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that we're ever aware
of is her anorexia. The rest of her life is dwarfed by her fixation, which only
becomes larger and more symptomatically classic--and more of a problem for him
and for her--the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> fixates on it. The novel's epigraph from, what
else, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kafka</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Hunger Artist</ENAMEX>," is a warning:

            "I always
wanted you to admire my fasting," said the hunger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.

            "We do
admire it," said the overseer, affably.

            "But
you shouldn't admire it," said the hunger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>'s relentless visits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>'s
relentless visits to the bathroom scale and, in her mind's eye, to the meals
she has eaten <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> records just how tedious, how paradoxically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul-entrapping</ENAMEX>, it can be to live and to ponder the anorexic urge to escape
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyrannical</ENAMEX> order is, in fact, the essence of the disease, as Flek
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teaches Joseph</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anorexia</ENAMEX>, he intones, is "all about control--about keeping
chaos at bay." And then concentration-camp-thin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>, in a burst of unusual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clarity</ENAMEX> and impatience, shakes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> up with the most mundane diagnosis of
all: "I'm just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westchester</ENAMEX> who has trouble with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. This isn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. You can't liberate me. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. And you can't
bring me back from the dead. I'M NOT DEAD."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> turns out
to be a sturdier book than it seems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> finally finds his way through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">metaphors</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> proves himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the more prosaic but rich art
of the simile. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>'s greedy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>, "was like [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>'s] hunger gone out of
her--prowling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>, nosing in the cabinets, leaping on the table at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dinnertime</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot</ENAMEX> "perched suddenly on the windowsill and shuffled himself
like a pack of cards." Waking up to the sound of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> jumping rope late at
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> heard "the soft, rhythmic thump of her bare feet on the floor,
like the beating of a giant heart." There's surprisingly ripe flesh to be found
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
