
   
   
      
         
            How the West Won

            Titles can be dangerous.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis Gaddis</ENAMEX>, the most eminent of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's Cold War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historians</ENAMEX>, has taken a risk by naming his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Now Know</ENAMEX> . For, the
big surprise of the opening of so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> archives is that we have learned so little that seriously alters the
known contours of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-year</TIMEX> confrontation.

            True, much has been
confirmed by the ongoing opening of the archives and the sterling work
of the special <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> research project at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodrow Wilson Center</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, on whose delvings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaddis</ENAMEX> leans heavily. To wit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s hopes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> would come to power, more or less
legally, in the western chunks of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> can now be reliably dated back to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1945</TIMEX>. We can establish that but for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s veto in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1945</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> might well have ratified the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bretton Woods</ENAMEX> postwar financial
system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s role in egging on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Koreans</ENAMEX> to invade the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> is now clear, and so is the secret <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> accord that kept quiet the
air battles between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter pilots</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bombing of an air <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> soil.

            None of
this, however, changes the old consensus that the grand strategy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War was set, at the latest, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>. By then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> was in place to
contain the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> on its western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX> established a
similar containment on the eastern front, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> was building
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railways</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> assembly lines and performing the same
miracle that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marshall Plan</ENAMEX> funds were achieving in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. When the Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> fought, they either lost (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suez</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and, later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>) or were held to a
bloody draw (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>). But, by avoiding
direct war, and by learning to avoid entanglement in local struggles, the West
eventually won the peace. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> prevailed because nuclear weapons imposed a
brittle truce, shifting the conflict to the economic rivalry in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s greater resources and adaptability could produce both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>,
both family <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft carriers</ENAMEX>.

            It is within this generally agreed-upon context that all
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> debates take place--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaddis</ENAMEX>' thoughtful but often
long-winded book broadly accepts this framework. But here comes the surprise.
In the past, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaddis</ENAMEX> picked a careful course between the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> who
always blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revisionists</ENAMEX> who thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' hunger
for markets and raw materials was at least as responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. Now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaddis</ENAMEX> has finally taken sides. On the politically (if not historically)
pivotal issue of who was to blame, his conclusion is "authoritarianism in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> in particular."

            Having
identified the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> in particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaddis</ENAMEX> widens his argument to identify the
Evil in general: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> system. To prove his point, he cites figures
suggesting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had been raped by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conquering Red Army</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1945 and 1946</TIMEX>. The point is worth making, even
though such awful spoils of war hardly address the moral argument of good and
evil in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> itself. And even though it was widely known that many of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> in Wehrmacht uniform had fled to be
taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX>, abandoning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to pay for the dreadfulness
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">menfolk</ENAMEX> had inflicted on the eastern front.

            
The moral superiority of the West has always
been difficult to argue. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> must grapple with the ugly facts of
racial segregation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>; of the latter's hardheaded if
spasmodic support of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>' futile efforts to cling to their colonial
empires; and of the West's readiness to support loathsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regimes</ENAMEX> in the name
of the greater cause. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, that most tragic of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s Third World campaigns, falls outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaddis</ENAMEX>' sadly truncated survey,
which ends with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> missile crisis. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaddis</ENAMEX> does not really tackle the
most egregious moral disaster for the West.

            Nor were
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> too nice in their discriminations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaddis</ENAMEX> cites a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX> cable
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX> that bluntly states the case for
Realpolitik : "Question whether <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ho [Chi Minh</ENAMEX>] as much nationalist as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commie</ENAMEX> is irrelevant, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stalinists</ENAMEX> in colonial areas are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>. With
achievement of natl. aims (i.e. independence) their objective necessarily
becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordination of state</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commie</ENAMEX> purposes." Normally the most
clearheaded of cold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acheson</ENAMEX> must have been dozing when he wrote that.
Or, at least, he was conveniently forgetting that he had argued to supply <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in civilian aid and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 million</NUMEX> in arms to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Marshal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, which, while nominally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>, had hardly been subordinated to
"Commie purposes." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> get disappointingly short shrift in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaddis</ENAMEX>' analysis, as does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s still mysterious decision to pull out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>-administered sector of northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. These are areas where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Ministry</ENAMEX> and party archives have so far yielded little that is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illuminating</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> military and intelligence archives are still
tightly controlled where they have been opened at all. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaddis</ENAMEX> does look
at the breach between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>, it is to buttress his case that as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were far more relaxed about managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> politics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Stalin</ENAMEX> was.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX>'s complaints about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> relationship,"
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Gaddis</NUMEX> points out, "were no more serious than those that arose routinely
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>" over such questions as the treatment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> were not interested in keeping their disputes in
hand. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> wanted outright subservience; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX>, unique in having liberated his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with his own partisan resources, was far too prickly to knuckle under.
In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaddis</ENAMEX> writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> saw nothing strange in
combining executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> with a careful acknowledgment of individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sovereignties</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> handled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> much as they did the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>: by cutting deals instead of imposing wills." Gaddis claims, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essence</ENAMEX>, that this managerial style went beyond the difference between Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> satellites, even beyond the distinction between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' soft <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> of consenting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s hard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> of secret
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and satrapies. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, he says, even the steeliest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military
authoritarians were products of a more benign political heritage than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>-sponsored regimes were: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> ran
the alliance much as [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gens</ENAMEX>.] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacArthur</ENAMEX> had run occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>: in ways that reflected democratic culture."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> would not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unreservedly</ENAMEX> agree. However foolish their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> conspiracy with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to
recapture the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Suez Canal</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> decision <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to vote with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> to
condemn them at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and then to apply what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaddis</ENAMEX> calls
"crushing economic pressure" on their currencies was hardly a collegial way to
run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> responded to this highhandedness by embarking on a
crash program to develop its own nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, and by evicting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> forces
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> soil. And, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaddis</ENAMEX> concludes, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> lost influence in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> as a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suez</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> gained it."

            If Gaddis
wants to blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> and authoritarian rule for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, he must explain
why the confrontation lingered on so long after the old brute's death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaddis</ENAMEX>' answer, of course, is that the game was under way by then: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> were condemned to play by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> rules. But this undermines
his entire case about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s unique responsibility. For, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>
brought their own historic baggage to the task of creating a new world order
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. They were locked into a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> divided by military deployments; an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> in turmoil after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s defeat and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>'s triumph; and a rivalry between
capitalist and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> that long predated both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            There is no doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> was a brute. We knew that
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> still raged. It took a little more courage for a Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> to say that then than it does to say it now, with the long
confrontation finally over. But does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s guilt automatically establish
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> innocence in other areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>? Obviously not--it would be hard
to fault <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> for the destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of Hue 15 years
after his death. However unsatisfactory and over-argued the revisionist case,
it did make one serious point: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had clear national and
economic interests and found the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> an unusually congenial way to pursue
them.

            Perhaps the most acute
epitaph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> was written at its birth, by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX>
Vyacheslav <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Molotov</ENAMEX>, who objected to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> demands for "an open door" for its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">industrialists</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>: "We would probably live to see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when
in your own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, on switching on the radio, you would be hearing not so
much your own language as one <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> gramophone record after [another] ... on
going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>, you would be seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> films sold for foreign
consumption," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molotov</ENAMEX> argued. "Is it not clear that such unrestricted
applications of the principles of 'equal opportunity' would in practice mean
the veritable economic enslavement of the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and their subjugation to
the rule and arbitrary will of strong and enriched foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, and
industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>? Was this what we fought for when we battled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fascist invaders?</ENAMEX>"

            Yes, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molotov</ENAMEX>. Given half
a chance, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movies and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> pop songs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">limos</ENAMEX> and all the
glitzy glamour of rumbustious capitalism were exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wanted. The
West prevailed because it was rich, rather than because it was good. It would
be nice to say that we were rich because we were good, but the randomness of
the market and the casual ethics of the hidden hand allow no such theocratic
conclusion.

         
      
   
