
   
   
      
         
            Little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boxes</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Cornell</ENAMEX> was like the
simple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy tale</ENAMEX> who picks up odds and ends--a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>, a broken
jug, perhaps a rusty nail--as he mooches toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> with his strong and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handsome</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, who mean to vie for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>'s hand. He is the least
likely of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitors</ENAMEX>, but the odd fragments he has assembled serve as answers
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>'s dark riddles, which leave his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> stammering. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s
art consists of useless found objects that, when arranged in boxes and placed
behind glass, seem like answers to forgotten riddles set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long ago</TIMEX> by brilliant
and perverse princesses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kant</ENAMEX> analyzed the concept of beauty as implying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purposiveness</ENAMEX> without any particular purpose, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s boxes have that
kind of beauty, since they convey a sense of meaningfulness while resisting the
assignment of any specific meaning. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">boxed</ENAMEX> objects, of little intrinsic
worth, are transformed into the components of a revelation we can only guess
at, through hidden affinities we cannot doubt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX> found his materials in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bins</ENAMEX> and boxes in dusty secondhand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in the less glittering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. He fitted them together <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX>, over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> table in an
undistinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Utopia Parkway</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flushing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, after his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped brother</ENAMEX> and a tiresome, widowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, with whom he shared the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>, had gone to bed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Curtis</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s who would
have been the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to put your money on in a contest with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> for a
prize--said: "His boxes were like dreams and you had no idea where they came
from. A stamp, a photograph, a rubber band, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX>, marbles that had
perhaps outlasted the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they were made for ... all these
different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> were somehow tied together and interrelated to one another
like ... like ..." And here, predictably, like the marvelously endowed brothers
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtis</ENAMEX> stammers.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s
life was in certain respects very like his art. A meaningless job, which anyone
could have done, an undistinguished education, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> like any other in a
crushingly ordinary neighborhood, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">commute</TIMEX>, no particular vices, and
nothing to speak of in the line of contact sexuality--a white, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX>,
middle-class life which, in external respects, was lived by innumerable
unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> answerable to family responsibilities, and marked by the lonely
longings of a protracted virginity probably not all that unusual at the time,
especially when, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s case, there were no riddling princesses to
overcome his natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shyness</ENAMEX> and unprepossessing looks. His art came out of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hobbies</ENAMEX>, and from celibate crushes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> marked, as a general rule, by an a
priori unattainability, though in truth one gets the sense that attainment was
less central to his fantasies than were the ritual adorations of a fan. It was
such adoration that defined his hobby, which consisted in rummaging expeditions
in search of memorabilia in which the ballerinas and actresses of his distant
passions were present, as the loved one is fetishistically present in scraps
and ribbons, snapshots and locks of hair, faded clippings and yellowing dance
cards. The miracle is that he found a way to make art out of the substance of
his affective life, and to turn his ephemera into visual poetry that no one
else--certainly not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Curtis</ENAMEX>, who aspired to be a box-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> himself--could
match. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s boxes are like reliquaries infused with deflected eroticism
and the magic of hopeless wishes.

            The life and art are reciprocal in that it is hard to
imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s art made by someone with a life greatly different from his.
This makes biography unusually relevant to critical appreciation in his case,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the rare examples in which someone's art is almost a transcription of
lived experience--transfigured, to be sure, by a kind of magic that biography
would have no way of accounting for. More than in any of the recent handsome
artistic biographies--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Breslin</ENAMEX>'s life of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothko</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Levin</ENAMEX>'s life of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Hopper</ENAMEX> or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Richardson</ENAMEX>'s stupendous biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>--we
actually come away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Solomon</ENAMEX>'s fascinating account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s life
with an enhanced understanding of the art. Remarkable as those other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
are, they all went to art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and learned to paint and draw, and in
consequence, their lives are, in most essential respects, not unlike those
described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giorgio Vasari</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1550</TIMEX>. A
change in the concept of art in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20 th century</TIMEX> made it possible
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX> to become an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> directly, using his eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peregrinations</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secondhand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and the feelings that provoked them as the only preparation he
needed. He had the historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> to recognize that media such as collage
"eliminated the need to paint and draw," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> observes. "Books could provide
almost all the materials. Everything was ready-made and in reach of anyone who
chose to put it together." The occasion was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s discovery of a curious
box by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Ernst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La</ENAMEX> femme <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cent</NUMEX> têtes , that consists of collages made
out of snipped and pasted cuttings from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> engravings,
fitted wickedly together to form a semipornographic narrative. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX> stumbled
onto the art world of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> surrealism--a complex of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and, above all, a body of thought about art--which
enabled him to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, and even an admired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Had it not been for those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">encounters</ENAMEX>, he might have lived out a reclusive life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, filling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scrapbooks</ENAMEX>. Without the transformative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> of the art world, he would have
been what we now call an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider artist</ENAMEX>--if he had been an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> at all. He
hit upon the device of the box, with which his vision is inextricably bound up,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>.

            The
surrealist art world was like an opening onto a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> of reality that a
middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unmarried son</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, a commuter and breadwinner with
solitary hobbies and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autodidact</ENAMEX>'s knowledge of the history of theater, of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX>, and of dance, might otherwise have never entered. There he met actresses
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballet stars</ENAMEX> who inspired real art, even if he interposed between himself
and them the internal distance which always separates the fantasist from his
objects. The story of his life and of his art from that point forward is the
story of these attenuated relationships, lived out on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> at once, like
waking dreams. The boxes and the collages are monuments to abstract affairs
with flesh-and-blood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s psychology required him to flatten
into paper effigies so that his imagination could go to work. He even sustained
a short, worshipful relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sontag</ENAMEX>, whose image he used for one
of his boxes. He was, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yayoi Kusama</ENAMEX> reported, "deeply
impotent," the adverb acknowledging that normal sex was something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX> only
believed he wanted, the way he might have thought he ought to learn to draw in
order to be a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. His art was made up of outward embodiments of inward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fixations</ENAMEX>. The affairs were made up of wishes collaged with phone calls and
unsatisfying visits, letters, and diary entries, gifts of art, and the frugal
lunches of weak <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> and store-bought <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX> physically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subsisted</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inasmuch</ENAMEX> as the sublimated sexuality of his
relationships is so central to the form and spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX>'s art, only the
kind of biography licensed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our decade</TIMEX>'s disregard of privacy could hope to
explain how the art came about and what it meant to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> has narrowed the distance between the life and the art, chronicling
everything with a sympathy and even a generosity one would hardly have dreamt
possible in our cynical and deconstructive age. But biography has its limits,
even if it will take us further with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX> than with perhaps any other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> himself included. It is no criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>'s lively and
fascinating book that she has not sought to explain how an array of the most
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>--a cordial glass, a bubble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some glass</NUMEX> disks, a
map--should release powers of evocation in one another and quiver into an image
that overcomes the personal and the biographical to attain universality,
profundity, beauty, and truth. Facing that riddle, we all stammer.

         
      
   
