
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror Stage</ENAMEX>

            The suspicion about
psychoanalysts that is currently fashionable creates an interesting dilemma for
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> of a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> is always tempted to prove
something, to second-guess the dubious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. Since psychoanalysis as a
treatment is itself about the possibility and, indeed, the value of
biographical truth--psychoanalysis as the biography that is supposed to improve
the biography--we are likely to want something specific from this callow new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX>. We want to know whether these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should have been trusted, and why
and if we should go on trusting their so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. In other words,
biographies of psychoanalysts make us wonder what it is that makes a person
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trustworthy</ENAMEX> to us, and what, if anything, this has to do with the significance
we give to their lives.

            By the
conventional standards of psychoanalytic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Lacan</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900-1981</TIMEX>)
was a heretic. His notoriety was based on his shortening of the psychoanalytic
session--sometimes to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>. His fame was based on his radical revisions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX> and his insistence on the ways in which language and sexuality disrupt
a life. Toward the end of his life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> of psychoanalysis <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roudinesco</ENAMEX> tells us, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX> "usually saw his tailor, his pedicurist, and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">barber</ENAMEX> while conducting his analyses." So what?

            There is a tension in any biography between what the
subject wanted to be--who he or she was always wanting to become--and what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer</ENAMEX> wants the subject to be. In this sober, incisive, and riveting book,
a well-documented history rather than a novelistic evocation of the man
himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roudinesco</ENAMEX> cannot conceal her dismay that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX> was not better
behaved, more temperate in his appetites, less baroque in his provocations. She
wants him to be more poignant and less boastful.

            It was, of
course, about excesses--of desire, of meaning, of emptiness--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX> wrote
so eloquently. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was by definition in excess of himself. He
believed there was something fundamentally unintelligible about the vagaries of
a life. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roudinesco</ENAMEX> neither takes pleasure in nor makes intriguing sense of
the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s theories "denounced the omnipotence of the ego in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, though he himself asserted the supremacy of his own." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s writings
are clearly, among other things, the confessions of a self-justifying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">megalomaniac</ENAMEX>--unusual in itself, because such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't tend to explain
themselves. But by the same token these are also the most inexhaustibly
interesting and stylish psychoanalytic writings since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud's</ENAMEX>. The Lacan
characterized in this book as flamboyantly voracious for the Freudian
triumvirate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, money, and power is, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roudinesco</ENAMEX> suggests, a Balzacian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>: a triumph of appetite over class. This is a story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with an
amazing talent for finding what and whom he needed to make himself what he
wanted to be, the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>.

            
As always, from the evidence available, there
is no obvious reason why this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> should have produced that
particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychoanalyst</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> owned a very successful vinegar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distillery</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were respectable bourgeois <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Catholics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s
adored youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> spent most of her
married life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indochina</ENAMEX>--so clearly some distance was needed from what was
otherwise a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of a certain type. Very early, as one might
have expected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX> wanted to be top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, though in fact he wasn't an
especially talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. He had a precocious intellectual curiosity. He tended
to read, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roudinesco</ENAMEX> remarks, rather than play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> with the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>.

            Of
course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s life here is being read retrospectively, partly through the
prism of his writings, whereas he was living it prospectively (we have to
remember, given that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s work was the theorizing of life stories, that he
himself never knew what was going to happen next). If one of the dominant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motifs of Lacan</ENAMEX>'s early life is his contempt for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, as it is in this
account, then it can seem virtually inevitable that his early work was about
the terrible cultural consequences of the "weakening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> imago"
(there were no strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> anymore), and that much of his later work should
be obsessed by what he called "the-name-of-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>" and the symbolic
significance of the phallus. But psychoanalysis--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX> was particularly
shrewd about this--has always been essentially a critique of straightforwardly
casual accounts of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> become who they are. Indeed, what distinguishes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychoanalysis</ENAMEX> is that it can show us the ways in which a life is not
merely the effect of its causes (biology, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, etc.).

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX> progresses through psychiatry, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> (as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>), surrealism, psychoanalysis, structuralism--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s life was
apparently a magnet for everything intellectually interesting happening in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>: He was, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>--he seems to have had a
knack for finding useful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>. His friendships with the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">critic Georges Bataille</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Merleau-Ponty</ENAMEX>, anthropologist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude LÃ</ENAMEX>©vi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strauss</ENAMEX>, and linguist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Jakobson</ENAMEX> were formative in ways that he
either fails to note or misleadingly acknowledges. Here Roudinesco is rather
limitingly censorious, wanting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX> to pay his debts rather than being amazed
by what he could make of what he found in the work of these remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Lacan was apparently always dismayed by how little his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX> were influenced
by him. In this book, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s craving for recognition--his almost demonic
hunger to be unforgettable--that drives him; and that, every so often, is
gently pathologized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roudinesco</ENAMEX>.

            Roudinesco alludes to many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mistresses</ENAMEX>, though always discreetly, in the abstract. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s private life,
however, was really a tale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> marriage, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 20s</TIMEX>, to
Malou, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> of a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, with whom he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; and then
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sylvie, Bataille</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>, with whom he has his adored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and acolyte <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> marriage are told
nothing of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> marriage until they are young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX> leads a
bizarre double life. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most chilling scenes in the book is when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX>,
Sylvie, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX> stop at a traffic light in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. They approach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX> drives off. Confronted with
some of the most callous follies of this extraordinary life, the "so what?"
question becomes more and more pressing.

            "An act always misunderstands
itself," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacan</ENAMEX> wrote. Indeed, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s writing is an elaborate meditation on
the ways in which--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> by which--we can never be transparent to
ourselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacan</ENAMEX>'s life was a struggle against the institutionalization of
knowledge, and he flourished by creating havoc, both publicly (in a famous
break with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Psychoanalytic Institute</ENAMEX>) and privately (among
some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>). He wanted psychoanalysis to be a science of
self-deception, a proof against the old pieties. It would be strange to wish
that he were more lovable, or honest, or familiar. His life is exemplary in the
modern sense, not as a picture of virtue, or even as a struggle to live out
some kind of personal truth, but rather as a question: How complicated can we
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be before we stop trusting them?

         
      
   
