
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fanciful Traces</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
as everyone knows by now, has an image problem. What better solution than to
export some of their most prestigious but rarely seen images, the drawings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>, for public display in the wide world? Tucked away in a
ground-floor corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Wing of the National Gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, are some of the finest drawings to be seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> just now.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> himself (as compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 10</NUMEX> in all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> collections combined), and another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> drawings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">successors</ENAMEX> that betray his influence. Fanned out in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> arranged like a
beehive, with the lights turned low to protect the fragile treasures (and lend
a mood of reverence to the occasion), the enthralling show is called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Michelangelo and His Influence: Drawings</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windsor Castle</ENAMEX>."

            Even in
his own time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1475-1564</TIMEX>) was recognized as having no peer in
sculpture, drawing, or architecture. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">multitalented</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo da Vinci</ENAMEX>,
with his greater intellectual range, rivals the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. "Anyone who has seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> has no
need to see anything else by any other sculptor, living or dead," gushed his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>, his contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giorgio Vasari</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vasari</ENAMEX>'s account of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s heroic labors in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine Chapel</ENAMEX> has entered popular lore.
It's hard not to think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Agony and the Ecstasy :</ENAMEX>
Alone on the high scaffold, paint dripping into his upturned eyes, he pushes
forward with his Sisyphean task as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Harrison</ENAMEX> (playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s
impatient patron, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Julius II</ENAMEX>) paces angrily below.

            
Heroism, seriousness, monumental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grandeur</ENAMEX>--these are all part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> legend. But the drawings in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> invite us to discover another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delicacy</ENAMEX> and pictorial wit. Consider the exquisite airborne <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archers</ENAMEX> ,
who, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cupid</ENAMEX> sleeps in the foreground, send their errant arrows toward the
target. Few hit their mark, and no wonder--for those archers, we suddenly
realize, aren't holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bows</ENAMEX>. No one knows the meaning of this enigmatic,
red-chalk drawing--while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cupid</ENAMEX> sleeps, love goes awry? But the sheer joy of the
image is contagious. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archers</ENAMEX> suggests the light-footed world of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dreams</ENAMEX>, the grotesque mask situated among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ideal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heads</ENAMEX> in the first
room--its headdress borrowed, it seems, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX>--evokes an
earthbound world where the human and animal realms are not easily
distinguished. Is this a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> disguised as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> turning into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?
The bared teeth are clearly human, but the feral eyes, looking sharply to the
side; the curling upper lip; and the bristling facial hair suggest a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>-person
ready to pounce.

            Leonine,
too, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, performing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> labors in one of the dazzling
Presentation 
               Drawings --finished drawings that were given to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX>--in the next <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. As he pries open the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vulcanian</ENAMEX> jaws of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nemean</ENAMEX> lion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>-skin disguise hovers like a halo over his
back, as though he can't throw off his animal identity so easily. Across the
same sheet, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX> fumbles with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hydra</ENAMEX>. We know he's going to lop off
those serpentine heads, one of which is biting him brazenly in the rear. But as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> conceives him, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX> seems to be dancing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hydra</ENAMEX>, as
though he's drawing from this encounter some of the writhing, erotic energy of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>. A humorless pen-and-ink drawing of the same subject by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX>
that appears later in the show depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX> staring down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hydra</ENAMEX>. The
awkward crosshatching makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> was so competitive, not
to say bitchy, about his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>. "What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX> had of art," he wrote in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1542</TIMEX>
letter, "he had of me." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX> had been dead for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s metamorphic wit, somewhere
between the nightmare transformations of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Florentine</ENAMEX> Dante Alighieri
and the baroque fantasies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Bernini</ENAMEX>, is nowhere better displayed than
in his famous drawing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhaÃ«thon</ENAMEX>'s fall. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PhaÃ«thon</ENAMEX>, you'll remember, wanted to
drive his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>--that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX>'s--across the sky. He lost control, as
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> will, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>, astride his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eagle</ENAMEX>, shot him down with a
lightning bolt. Intertwined with his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhaÃ</ENAMEX>«thon turns
his splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> toward us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last time. "An image of the consequences of
pride and vanity," says the sober wall label. Perhaps. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhaÃ«thon</ENAMEX>'s fall,
like the cascading forms in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine Last Judgment</ENAMEX> , has
its own headlong ecstasy. His <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> anxious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, watching from the ground
below, are beginning to turn into <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>--their punishment for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hubris</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> gave the drawing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhaÃ</ENAMEX>«thon to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tommaso de' Cavalieri</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nobleman</ENAMEX> to whom he addressed some of his most passionate sonnets--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted poet</ENAMEX>, too. "According to your will," he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavalieri</ENAMEX>, "I'm hot
in the harshest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, cold in the sun." While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s homosexuality
has long been assumed--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Pater</ENAMEX> wrote of his "vague
and wayward loves"--there is no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cavalieri</ENAMEX> reciprocated his
feelings.

            
Another drawing given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavalieri</ENAMEX> takes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s transforming wit to a whole new level. It depicts the giant
Tityus, whose punishment for raping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leto</ENAMEX> was to have his liver
ripped out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> by a vulture, only to have it grow back <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each night</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tityus</ENAMEX> reclines on his craggy bed of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>, from which his
muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> seems to have been sculpted. His punishment looks like another
rape, with the vulture having its way with the bound and lustful (and
apparently acquiescent) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> with an open-jawed face--one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dante</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">damned souls</ENAMEX>, perhaps--screams in the background.

            Then, as
if this weren't masterly enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> did something amazing. He flipped
the sheet of paper over, rotated it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">90 degrees</NUMEX>, and traced the now-upright form
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tityus</ENAMEX>. The tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> became the risen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, stepping from his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> goes around and around the free-standing frame to see just how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> did it. And what subversive intent, what wicked wit, was at work
here? Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> mean to imply an erotic side of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, a mortification of
human desire rewarded by bodily resurrection? No wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> were in awe of him and tried to follow his intimidating
lead.

            
Exhibitions billed as showing a major artist
"and his influence" are sometimes excuses for including inferior art to fill
out an occasion. While there are a few too many drawings by various
accomplished hands "after" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX> originals, this show feels winnowed
down and sharply focused. Some of these drawings have their own distinctive
flavor, showing less <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s influence than his provocation. Annibale
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carracci</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignudo</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1597</TIMEX>) transforms one of the languorous young male
nudes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine</ENAMEX> ceiling into a wily, satyr-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">character</ENAMEX>--he
could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercutio</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the grandeur and flashing wit of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surly Florentine</ENAMEX> and the enigmatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX> have much in common. There are
the towering achievements of both--the public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, the tragedies--and the
unexpected delights on a smaller scale.

            We expect to be awed by the
sheer size and marmoreal magnificence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine Chapel</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">dome of St. Peter's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. These have a public purpose, captured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poet William Butler Yeats</ENAMEX>' lines about the best-known <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine</ENAMEX> image: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> at puberty may find<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/ The first Adam</ENAMEX> in their thought." There's a
different, but no less intense, pleasure to be derived from these miracles
worked up from the meager materials of paper and chalk. Never designed for
public exhibition, these experimental sketches and gifts for intimate friends
have a distinctive power, like secrets revealed, or conversations
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overheard</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N.B.</ENAMEX>:
The preceding images are not from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Michelangelo and His Influence: Drawings</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windsor Castle</ENAMEX> (online reproduction of art in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX>
exhibition is forbidden). They are photographs of works from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Louvre</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
