
   
   
      
         
            Thank Heaven for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Girls</ENAMEX>

             

            Is it tasteless to suggest
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>--the cute, blond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> who was strangled
to death <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>--that it is her grisly death, rather than her career
as a juvenile beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>, that makes her so uncannily resemble a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in a
fairy tale? For while a pageant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> is merely tacky, a murdered
pageant princess takes her place in the illustrious line of pretty young girls
in what, pace multiculturalists, we might call our collective lore, to
meet, or at least be threatened with, a gruesome end. Little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Riding Hood</ENAMEX>,
Goldilocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gretel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alice</ENAMEX>--there is an intimate connection in our culture, it
would seem, between being a sweet young miss and getting garroted.

            By
curious coincidence, this fairy-tale conjunction of appealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nymphets</ENAMEX> and gory
murder is currently the subject of an unusual show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folk Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>: an exhibition of eccentrically magnificent watercolors by
the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Darger</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> were alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, he would
be fascinated by the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darger</ENAMEX> collected clippings on the
subject of little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, murdered and otherwise, and went on to write and
illustrate a truly amazing, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scheherazadean</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,145</NUMEX>-page epic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX> cute
prepubescent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> being tortured by brutish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who like to capture little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in order to enslave them and torture them and take their clothes off. In
the course of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s story--titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Story of the Vivian Girls, in What</ENAMEX>
is Known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Realms of the Unreal</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Glandeco-Angelinnean War Storm</ENAMEX>,
Caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child Slave Rebellion</ENAMEX> --the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivian Girls</ENAMEX>) manage
to escape from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glandelinians</ENAMEX>) time and time again, but countless
less fortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>-slaves are spectacularly mutilated and slaughtered along
the way.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> is what is known as an "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>--which is
to say that he didn't receive any formal art training; was not, during his
lifetime, part of the art world; and was exposed very little, if at all, to
traditional art in general. As such, he is presumed to have produced his work
out of some unusually pure sort of inner compulsion, rather than in response to
other art. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> spent nearly all his life living alone in a rented <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, earning his living as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, going to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> frequently, and coming home at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to work on his paintings and his
writing. He was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1892</TIMEX>, sent to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> home at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, and then
placed in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> for the feebleminded, from which he escaped at the age
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>. Shortly before his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> moved out to a nursing
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> opened up his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and discovered, amid piles of presumably
artistic debris (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> pairs of smashed eyeglasses, balls of string, old
pairs of shoes, scores of empty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pepto-Bismol</ENAMEX> bottles), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one 2,600</NUMEX>-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">autobiography</ENAMEX>, an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year</TIMEX> weather log, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX> watercolors, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> pencil drawings, and
the tale of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivian Girls</ENAMEX>.

             

            The Darger
watercolors on exhibit include both peacetime tableaux of tiny lassies, some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">naked</ENAMEX>, some in dresses, disporting themselves among <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX> and enormous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and odd little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>--and scenes of maniacal carnage, in which the same
tiny lassies are strangled naked (distorted faces, tongues stuck out) and
disemboweled by merciless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glandelinians</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presumably</ENAMEX> in anticipation of a
fainter-hearted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, the gorier pictures were excluded from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Darger</ENAMEX> exhibition at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa</ENAMEX>, of which this show is an expanded
version.) Some paintings combine the two types of scenes, with comic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonchalance</ENAMEX>. In one, a group of placid girls jump rope while immediately behind
them lie the severed heads of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, horrified expressions on their faces,
and pairs of disembodied hands (their own? their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>?) still clenched
around their necks. In all paintings, the colors are extraordinary and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fantastical</ENAMEX>--a cross between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Submarine</ENAMEX> and a pastel version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> produced a lot of his little-girl
pictures by tracing comic strips or magazine illustrations (on occasion he cut
pictures out and stuck them on the paintings directly). In some works he
transposed the illustrations more or less intact; in others he stripped off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>' clothes and added penises (all his naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> have penises). Several
images appear over and over again in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Darger</ENAMEX>'s work, often within the same
painting--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> mixing something in a bowl, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> sitting on a fence, a girl
running fearfully away from something, her school bag flying out behind her.
Often these repeated images are rendered identically (same colors, no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alterations</ENAMEX> in the pose), and sometimes they even appear next to each other in
series of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as eight</NUMEX>. But the effect is not at all proto-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX>. It's
subtler, less programmatic. It's reminiscent, if anything, of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angels</ENAMEX> or monks or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in medieval manuscripts in which some of the
figures are identical to each other, and others only slightly different--but
the repetition seems to be employed for the purpose of visual economy, in order
not to divert attention from the picture's central theme, rather than to draw
attention to repetition or image-making itself.

            Of the enormous quantity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material Darger</ENAMEX> produced, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watercolors</ENAMEX> have received the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of
attention. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of American Folk Art</ENAMEX> did sponsor a reading of passages
from the written version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivian Girls</ENAMEX> . Still, it's a pity there's
none of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s writing in the exhibition itself, because it's marvelous,
strange stuff, quite as startling as the paintings--in dizzying magnitude as
well as vividness, since in the written version, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s gory battle scenes
extend for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> pages. Take this excerpt, for instance (don't read this
if you're squeamish):

            
               Indeed the screams and
pleads of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> could not be described, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> went
insane over the scene, or even committed suicide. ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About nearly 56,789</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were literally cut up like a butcher does a calf, after being
strangled or slain, in all ways, indeed the sights of the bloody windrows
[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX>] , with their intestines exposed or gushed out, was a sight that no one
could bear to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> without losing their reason. Hearts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were hung
up by strings to the walls of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, so many of the bleeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> had been
cut up that they looked as if they had gone through a machine of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knives</ENAMEX>.
            

            The writing also complicates the naked-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> scenes in the
pictures, since it combines vintage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darger</ENAMEX> bloodthirstiness with the gentlest,
softest grandpa porn. For instance, "The little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> were even glad to leave
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, which they hastily did after looking for their clothes which they
could not find, having to leave in their nighties."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>-art movement
responsible for raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> from obscurity to fame is a rapidly expanding
niche of the art world that has come into its own in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade or so</TIMEX>: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outsider Art Fair</ENAMEX> took place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX>
ago in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>; there is a new federally funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> art
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, pieces by the most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider artists</ENAMEX>, of which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> is one, are priced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX> to high <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-figures.

            But while
the notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> art has proved an effective marketing concept, it is
often an unfortunate interpretive one--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider artists</ENAMEX> tend to attract a
particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> and irritating kind of psycho-biographical analysis. Chief
culprit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Darger</ENAMEX>'s case is one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John MacGregor</ENAMEX>, an art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> to whom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX>, now his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executor</ENAMEX>, has bequeathed semi-exclusive
access to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> material, and who is thus the main disseminator of
Darger criticism. Despite the fact that virtually nothing is known about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s inner life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacGregor</ENAMEX> (typically, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> art) writes
confidently about how compulsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darger</ENAMEX> was; how he couldn't control his urge
to produce all that crazy stuff; how he couldn't distinguish between fantasy
and reality; how he was a potential serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>; how he got sexually excited
writing descriptions of burning forests. MacGregor careers from the vulgar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudian</ENAMEX> to the idiosyncratically bizarre--for instance, "The trauma of
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s] death was represented in his later life by an obsessional
preoccupation with weather." "Clearly," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacGregor</ENAMEX> wrote in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> exhibition
catalog, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darger</ENAMEX> was not free."

            
It's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s more gruesome pictures
can be a little disturbing. But think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> in the context either of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books and cartoons (anything from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom & Jerry</ENAMEX> to the
terrifyingly brutal but also extremely popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strumpelpeter</ENAMEX> ) or of contemporary art (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie Robbins</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fetish</ENAMEX>," for instance--a naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> doll stuck all over with little nails),
and it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacGregor</ENAMEX> who begins to look like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>. Indeed, seen in a
contemporary light, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darger</ENAMEX> begins to look like a progenitor of that rather
common, campy sensibility--what might be called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mouseketeer Gothic</ENAMEX>--that sees
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">angelic</ENAMEX> pop-culture figures as actually creepy and frightening. (Think "It's a
Small <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World</ENAMEX>" or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX>.)

            It's ironic, too, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacGregor</ENAMEX> persist in seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> as an unself-conscious
obsessive, unable to separate his life from his created fantasy world, since in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fact Darger</ENAMEX>'s work is full of precisely the sort of self-referentiality that in
a contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider artist</ENAMEX> would be read as a rather ordinary example of
postmodern detachment. Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s watercolors, for instance, include
depictions of framed pictures whose images are indistinguishable from the
images outside them. In the written epic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darger</ENAMEX> himself appears as several
different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, on both sides of the conflict--private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger, Darger</ENAMEX> the
war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, volcanology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hendro Dargar</ENAMEX>, etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s very title
draws attention to the fact that the epic takes place "in What is Known as the
Realms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unreal</ENAMEX>." And the written version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s epic even contains a
number of amusing references to the strange task of drawing and writing about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX>'s own grisly subject. To wit:

            
               About
noon, a frenzied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glandelinians</ENAMEX> came swarming for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Violet</ENAMEX>
and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>. The standards they followed were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> and even gashed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> beautiful little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, with their intestines protruding from
their bellies, and every one of these were on pikes dripping with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>.
...
            

            
               [When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Violet</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> appeared] they thrust up on to their windows the heads
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of these lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and managed to cast them inside amongst
them. Then, bursting into the doors, they thrust the heads into their laps,
ordering them to make a copy of them in pencil.
            

            
               Although
it seems to them that they would die of horror, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Violet</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>]
thought it best to obey. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]hey started to draw the hideous bodies and
heads, being good at drawing pictures in the most perfect form.
            

            What to make of this?
Depending on your taste, you might conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> is indeed a deranged
outsider confusing himself with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. Or you might see him as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">latter-day Grimm</ENAMEX>, in whose macabre universe getting your intestines torn out
and sketching other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s severed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> are regrettable but quite ordinary
parts of life as a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. On either interpretation, though, the paintings
remain extraordinary, and extraordinarily beautiful.

             

         
      
   
