
   
   
      
         
            All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work, No Play</ENAMEX>

            "What tedious work it is,"
confessed a spinster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> tending to her fatherless nieces and nephews in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>.
"The same things over and over. It requires a load of patience and I am
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">principled</ENAMEX> against showing any impatience to little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> lest it should lessen
my influence." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This mid-19 th century</TIMEX> godsend--whose letter is quoted
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">At Odds: Women and the Family in America From the Revolution</ENAMEX> to the
Present , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Degler</ENAMEX>--was an unusual recruit to the enterprise of child
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rearing</ENAMEX>: She neither romanticized her mission nor vented her frustration on her
charges.

            What
clear-eyed calm! Such sanity has been rare in discussions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> rearing in
the "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>," as the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> was christened at its start
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> and social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive</ENAMEX> era, experts
extolled parenthood as an ennobling profession set apart from the workaday
grind. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postwar years</TIMEX>, child rearing was being touted as enriching fun.
At least nowadays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are allowed to complain about the burdens their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> impose. But somewhere along the way, they've--we've--also lost all
patience for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. This is the disconcerting news delivered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlie Russell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX> in her important new book, a sequel to her best-selling The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> Shift: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working Parents</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>).

            In that book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX> explored the dilemmas faced by
two-career marriages, in which, she found, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> still shouldered the bulk of
the child care and housework. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               Bind charts the
transformation of the workplace in the intervening period, and looks at how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are coping now. More provisions have become
available for part-time and flexible employment in successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Does that mean that stressed-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> are finding
better ways to balance their home and work lives? The answer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hochschild</ENAMEX> says,
is no. Parents are working ever longer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, and are startlingly frank about
why: Staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is "tedious work," especially when you could be
out earning money in a self-esteem-enhancing workplace.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX>'s subtitle-- When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Becomes Home and Home Becomes</ENAMEX>
Work --telegraphs her basic argument. "A cultural reversal of workplace and
home" has taken place. In an increasingly work-obsessed society, life on the
job has been "feminized," thanks to efforts to engineer a homelike, caring
culture for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, complete with solicitous "climate surveys" and
stress-reduction workshops. The home front, meanwhile, has been "masculinized."
It runs like the soulless assembly line of old. Ruthless efficiency,
compartmentalized schedules, too little autonomy, too much anomie: No wonder
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would rather stay late at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX>'s own work has the air of being effortlessly
well timed. Here, as she did in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Shift</ENAMEX> , she's grabbed a social
problem out of the air that ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> groan about a great deal and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> generalize about equally ineffectually. She gives
the problem a local habitation--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amerco</ENAMEX>, a (pseudonymous) Fortune 500 company
rated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> most "family friendly" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 and 1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX> interviewed senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, and
clerical and factory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. She shadowed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> as they did, and
didn't, participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Work-Life Balance Program</ENAMEX>," which offers
various child-care options and arrangements for working more flexible or
shorter workdays. She followed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> home from work, met their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
became attuned to the tone of their <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX>. And she spoke with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, child-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> new to the payroll of a
business that had lately converted to the "Total Quality" philosophy. That
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, the creation of the management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Edwards Deming</ENAMEX>, replaces overtly
bureaucratic control with self-managing work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and an emphasis on a "common
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> at every level of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Amerco</ENAMEX> fit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX>'s profile
of distracted parenthood. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vicki King</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> who strongly endorses the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s family friendly policies, works <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">inflexibly long hours</TIMEX> herself and
juggles her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' lives like a bustling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>. She looks back on her
maternity leave without any nostalgia: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> I didn't
have anybody to talk to. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are at work. The things that interest me
are at work." The work needn't be fascinating to exert its pull. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workaholic</ENAMEX> whose low-level job is stacking and loading boxes, loves his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
but can't wait for his shift with them to end: "It's very stressful mentally,
and I get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sick</ENAMEX> of hearing myself scream." Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb</ENAMEX>, refuses
to cut down on her work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> because she knows it means <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> will
cut back on the home front.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blunt</ENAMEX> about why she likes the status quo, despite the stress of arranging child
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>: "At work I can do more of what I want. At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, I have to do what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> want." You can almost hear her stamping her tiny foot. These Amerco
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> can sound like, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hochschild</ENAMEX> calls attention to a
psychological reversal accompanying the cultural reversal: We used to feel
immature at work and independent at home. Now it's the other way around.

            
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hochschild</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Quality</ENAMEX>
"presumes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> is a capable adult, not a wayward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deming</ENAMEX>'s
emphasis on worker autonomy and a joint "conversation" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
goals revises the much stricter model of "scientific management" championed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick W. Taylor</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were
expected to be obedient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drones</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX>'s radical proposal is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylorism</ENAMEX> now reigns. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> is where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> feel
infantilized, trapped on a treadmill of efficiency. They've "outsourced"
functions that used to be part of their responsibility (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX>, tutors,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camps</ENAMEX>), creating a fragmented regimen. The fast-paced pressure of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overscheduled</ENAMEX> lives has produced a balkiness in their hurried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--and in
their own harried selves--that they feel helpless to deal with.

            But is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Quality</ENAMEX> workplace really as homelike as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX> claims? And is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylorized</ENAMEX> home front quite the downsized operation she describes? Her own
evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> "fleeing a world of unresolved quarrels and unwashed
laundry for the reliable orderliness, harmony, and managed cheer of work"
points to a diagnosis that is, if anything, more disconcerting. Perhaps parents
are eager to go to work not because it gives them autonomy but because it lets
them be safely and comfortably childlike. At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, they face the daunting
challenge of being superadults. Hochschild acutely observes that "what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spock</ENAMEX> did for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> rearing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Quality</ENAMEX> is doing for work." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX> was
not, pace his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, a permissive advocate of giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> real
power or of giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> an easy break. He envisioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> as the
"friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>," vigilantly and solicitously manipulating a naturally docile
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.

            At work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> don't really get to do what they
want, only to enjoy what they have to do. They have been given satisfyingly
discrete tasks, for which they are rewarded with boosts to their self-esteem.
Their needs are defined and ministered to; support is constantly made available
in the form of organized workshops and counseling sessions. The goal is not
independent self-reliance, but a more internalized sense of dependence on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> and the rest of us--whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amerco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
free-lancers with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, like me--don't exactly fit the model of mere
repetitive-motion machines. We're more like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Quality</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>, and we're
just what many new-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> are: overwhelmed by a vast therapeutic mandate to
keep control while dispersing power and to ensure not just the health but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">happiness</ENAMEX>, not just the productivity but the loyalty, of our charges. What's
striking, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Hays</ENAMEX> recently pointed out in The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural Contradictions</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motherhood</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), is how tenaciously we cling to "intensive
motherhood," as she calls this ambitious mission, despite its increasing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impracticality</ENAMEX> and despite how guilty it can make us feel.

            
The truth is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> hasn't suddenly become
work. It has always been work--endless work, and such close restraint. "The
same things over and over." No "recognition ceremonies" for tasks well done,
few clear-cut goals or tidy limits to responsibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professionalizing</ENAMEX> and
romanticizing that work, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have tried to do throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, has not made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-rearing more spiritually satisfying or relaxing. It
has made it more anxiety-inducing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hochschild</ENAMEX> wants to say that
we can reclaim safe haven in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> life from a market-dominated world, but
her idea of a solution ends up sounding like the ultimate triumph of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">commodified</ENAMEX> mentality. In vacuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demingese</ENAMEX>, she announces that we need to
learn from "public debate about the need for 'emotional investment' in family
life in an era of familial divestiture and deregulation." Actually, Taylorism
might be more in order. More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> need to buckle down on the home front,
which would improve the attitude and motivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> too. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX> should remember that growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are the fastest-paced
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of them all. Surely that is, paradoxically, the most persuasive
reason to slow down a bit at work and hang out more at home. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will be
gone in no time.

         
      
   
