
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweetness</ENAMEX> and Bite

            Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1906</TIMEX>, a
certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Detective Young</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> testified before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Parliamentary</ENAMEX>
Committee examining issues of public morality. He had seen "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and girls
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kissing</ENAMEX> and smoking and cuddling away at each other" in an ice-cream parlor, he
said. He had encountered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> lured into prostitution by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>.
Then the following exchange occurred:

             

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Do you ask us to believe that the downfall of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> was due to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ice-cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>?
               

               
                  A: I believe it
is.
               

            

            That delirious transcript
is part of the story of the triumph of refined <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> over old-fashioned honey
that takes up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Mintz</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tasting Food, Tasting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Freedom: Excursions Into Eating</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture</ENAMEX>, and the Past . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX>, an
anthropologist at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins University</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweetness</ENAMEX> and
Power (a more detailed look at <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> and its meaning), also explores other
topics, ranging from the broader relationship between political power and food
to more idiosyncratic excursions such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Color, Taste</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purity</ENAMEX>: Some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Speculations on the Meanings of Marzipan</ENAMEX>."

            But it's the saga of
refined <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> that forms the core of this book, a tale <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX> punctuates with
telling historical surprises. In the sweetener competition, for example, sugar
received an early and unexpected boost from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1537</TIMEX>, when the king
abolished the monasteries, the decline in demand for candle wax slowed the
honey output and opened a window for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detective Young</ENAMEX> was able to indulge
in his cheap moralizing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four centuries later</TIMEX> because back then, everything
about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>--its novelty and potency, its exotic origin in Moorish
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, its pure pharmocopoeal whiteness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, was one of
our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> (dating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paleolithic Era</ENAMEX>). It was comparatively mild in
taste, always locally produced, natural and gooey--trustworthy, even good for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>.

            In time, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> became "the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> imported luxury to become a cheap <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> necessity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>," and,
along with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> and tobacco, it "probably provide[s] us with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> instance
in history of the mass consumption of imported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food staples</ENAMEX>." As
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> aristocrats wallowed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>, the working
class yearned for it, creating a demand that would underlie the expansion of
enormous sugar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, and hence the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> became "an eminently taxable commodity," and "acquired many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champions</ENAMEX> in the press, in the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Office</ENAMEX>, and in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>." It introduced the West to a new source of political power--mass
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, before whom elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> would need to bow and scrape.

            We've
never stopped linking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> with notions of good and evil. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX> quotes some
astonishing speeches by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abolitionists</ENAMEX> who easily equated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane sugar</ENAMEX> with
murder, one of them even providing the precise calculus: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]n every pound of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> used (the product of the slaves imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>), we may be
considered as consuming <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two ounces</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sugar</ENAMEX>'s aura of evil endures to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX>--that's what those pink and blue packages on every restaurant table
signify. At the same time, vestiges of its virtue--dating from a time when a
gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confectionery</ENAMEX> was both rare and prized--survive in every box of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>. No one who reads these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> will scoop up another
spoonful of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> without reflecting on the history of ambivalence, global
turmoil, and centuries of suffering needed to put it on the table.

            None of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX>'s other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> is quite as satisfying as
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>. Still, this is a book whose bibliography includes
monographs entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Private Tooth Decay</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Economic Virtue</ENAMEX> and
tomes such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The History and Social Influence of the Potato</ENAMEX> --so the
rest of it is still loaded with nuggets worth finding. The dominance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>,
for example, in the cola wars may date to the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Marshall</ENAMEX>
(a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southerner</ENAMEX>), who was able to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>-based) exempted from the
wartime rationing of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>. As a result, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX> bottling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> were built in both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theaters</ENAMEX> of battle, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">148</NUMEX> bottling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> served there. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bottlers</ENAMEX>
gave their lives for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            Toward the end of the
book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX> tells a story about offhandedly mentioning in a lecture that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has no "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' reaction was swift and contentious, as
if their feelings had been hurt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX> seems puzzled, musing that it wasn't as
though he'd said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> had no literature. But it does hit a nerve, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX>
spends his last chapter pondering the question of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has a cuisine
after all.

            He
answers with an academic distinction. "Regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cuisines</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX> says, are
"authentic" because they use "local ingredients" and involve "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who eat it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> it, have opinions about it, and engage in dialogue
involving those opinions." On the other hand, "national cuisines" are largely
artificial constructs: You won't find a "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for
obvious reasons. The blue-plate specials typically offered as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American</ENAMEX>
cuisine"--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>, fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>, hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>--aren't worth
considering, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX> says, despite such "irrepressible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>" as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edna Lewis</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Fussell</ENAMEX>. (His nouns in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> do begin to grate.) He then
concludes: "I don't think anyone wants to call that array a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>." (That's
right, "array.")

            Mintz dismisses our regional cuisines--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cajun</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Dutch</ENAMEX>--because they have been ruined by the
environmental impact of overfishing local stocks, and by ferocious marketing
that dilutes their "authenticity" and ends in "bowdlerization." But this is
food, which means that it's not easy for all "irrepressible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>" to sit
still and listen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX> means to start an argument, to lay out a polemic, but
what's nettlesome is not his answer but the question. If cuisines emerge
organically over time from rooted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, then why pose the question about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have come to epitomize rootlessness?

            Instead, he might have
consulted the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.B. Jackson</ENAMEX>, the architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> who observed that
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> architecture isn't meant to last. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> throw up office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip malls</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>, tear them down the next, and build something else. So
to judge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s fleeting architecture by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s canonical standards is
preposterous. Ditto with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> make no time for dialogue, much less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cuisine</ENAMEX>. They're scouting out new food fads, scarfing them down, and then
rooting about for the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Had a blackened <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">redfish</ENAMEX> lately? Probably not.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Prudhomme</ENAMEX> was so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. Enjoy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s mesclun salads. The end is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nigh</ENAMEX>.

            Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX> senses the
bathos of ending his book on such a weak note. So he tacks on different ending
by turning, in his own words, to "an unbelievably grim scenario." He cites one
of those suspiciously <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malthusian</ENAMEX> studies forecasting a biblical future of
scarce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, arid fields, and a desperately hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Then he ... well,
surprisingly, he *moralizes.* <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintz</ENAMEX> suggests that "consumption gluttony" will
prompt another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Desert Storm</ENAMEX>, but this time for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>. "Its effects on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> moral integrity," he intones, "would be utterly disastrous." Worse,
"we might let our obsessive notions of individual freedom destroy our
democracy." Oh, for the restraint of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detective Young</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
