
   
   
      
         
            Talking <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Bout His Generation</ENAMEX>

            In a logical world, the
number of books written about a political movement would have some rough
connection with its ultimate importance. The noisy crusades that became
historical footnotes would all be literary footnotes as well.

            But we are living in a
different sort of world, one in which it is possible, for example, to fill up
the better part of a library with volumes written by, and about, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftists</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. Anything you want to know about the sectarian
ideological warfare of these quarrelsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Socialists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stalinists</ENAMEX>,
Trotskyites, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schactmanites, Lovestonites</ENAMEX>--you can find in masochistic
detail.

            That's
not because their arcane disputes held any fascination for most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> at
the time. Nor is it because of their impact on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> that followed. I
have never heard anyone suggest that the key to understanding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> postwar
politics lay in the arguments among the competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCNY</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX> or
their subsequent recreations on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Riverside Drive</ENAMEX>. The truth is that 1930s
leftism became a literary genre because those who indulged in it enjoyed
writing books, and were also willing to buy them.

            It would be a mistake to conclude that, as those leftists
depart from the scene, the tradition of political verbosity will die out.
Rather, a new generation of aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftists</ENAMEX>--the campus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>--is
emerging, and off to an appropriately windy start. If you happen to be
interested in the internal factionalism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hayden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX>
Huron statement of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>, a large collection of books is available to help you.
Or you can purchase a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-volume account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sorbonne</ENAMEX> uprising in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>,
compressed into a tidy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,311</NUMEX> pages.

            Now
there is another book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Tale of Two Utopias</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Berman</ENAMEX>, a veteran
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> leftist wars who writes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , the New

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , and other organs of the nonmilitant journalistic mainstream.
The difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX>'s volume and most others I have seen on the
subject is that his is an entertaining book, readable and unpretentious, a
little softhearted toward his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX>, but more than willing to take them
to task for their absurdities.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O ></ENAMEX>f all those
absurdities, one stands out in high relief, and also links the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftists</ENAMEX> of the
1960s to those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. It is their consistent overestimation
of their own significance. That the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX>'s generation
believed a political revolution to be within their grasp may seem a little
puzzling from the vantage point of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>, but is perhaps understandable as a
product of youthful exuberance: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berman</ENAMEX> himself lapses into a romantic nostalgia
when he describes what it felt like to be in the vanguard of something new and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magnificent</ENAMEX>--in politics, in culture, in the way human beings treat each
other.

            "A utopian exhilaration
swept across the student universe," he writes on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> page. "Almost
everyone in my own circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> was caught up in it. ...
Partly it was a belief, hard to remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, that a superior new society was
already coming into existence. And it was the belief that we ourselves--the
teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX>, hippies and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>--stood at the heart of a
new society."

            This
was, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX> readily concedes, an illusion. But what can it claim for its
legacy, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation later</TIMEX>? A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tale of Two Utopias</ENAMEX> is a lucid,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-pronged attempt to answer that question.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX>'s quests for a larger meaning--in the
experiences of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who led the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> and
the other leftist political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>--is not a pretty one. By the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, the idealism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> had degenerated into personal bickering
and a flirtation with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Maoist</ENAMEX> terrorism that could be written off as mere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">goofiness</ENAMEX> had it not resulted in the loss of innocent lives on both sides of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>.

            That the radical
enthusiasms of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> left no permanent political imprint upon the Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">democracies</ENAMEX> is a conclusion that a simple electoral history of the ensuing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>, would seem sufficient to
prove. Berman sadly acknowledges it. But the politics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> were a
challenge to culture as well as politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berman</ENAMEX> locates his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> search for
meaning in the "gay awakening" that had its symbolic start in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> protest
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stonewall</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX> had marched
and chanted and proclaimed "it is forbidden to forbid" had been arguing for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberation</ENAMEX> of the oppressed of virtually every kind, and when it comes to the
sexually oppressed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berman</ENAMEX> says, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two decades</TIMEX> can be seen as a victory.
"There is reason to think that on the matter of homosexuality," he writes,
"some small but important aspect of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> has begun to change."

            That
may be true, but the connection between the gay awakening and the student
rebellion of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> is an oblique <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Gay liberation, like feminism, is central
to the whole individualist ethos of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two decades</TIMEX>. But it doesn't
exactly count as a trophy from the barricades. The world would have conceded
the claims of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> without the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> of a single
lecture hall anywhere in the world.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T ></ENAMEX>here is one
more search for meaning, and it takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berman</ENAMEX> across the ocean. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Michnik</ENAMEX> was
arrested in a demonstration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warsaw</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February of 1968</TIMEX>, went on to become
the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity</ENAMEX> protest movement of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, and
survived to take up a role as middle-aged statesman in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> political
world that succeeded the collapse of communism in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Václav Havel</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 1968</TIMEX>, participated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> strike at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joined Alexander Dubcek</ENAMEX> in the short-lived <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> uprising in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, and became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. Shortly after
taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, he entertained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Zappa</ENAMEX> on a state visit.

            Perhaps, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">speculates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Havel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Michnik</ENAMEX> represent the true legacy of the worldwide
revolutionary sprouting of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> or the
Sorbonne, they persevered, and they won--something. But what?

            The
peaceful revolutions in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> were indeed a defeat for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. That they were the incarnation of the dreams
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> seems a stretch, to say the least, even if some of the important
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> came out of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX> does not make such a
claim. He ponders the hopeful predictions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Fukuyama</ENAMEX> that Western
civilization is moving gradually, if fitfully, toward greater individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>. But he closes with the darker speculations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Glucksmann</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sorbonne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> and a later convert to conservatism, that
the utopian enthusiasm of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> simply did not take sufficient account of
the fundamental reality of evil in the human psyche.

            And so, at the end of his odyssey, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX> finds a bit of
meaning, but little reassurance. How does the world feel as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> comes to a close? "The world feels this," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berman</ENAMEX> declares: "humble,
skeptical, anxious, afraid, shaken."

            Maybe so. On the other
hand, it is an oddly grandiose conclusion to an appealingly modest book. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX>
presents almost no evidence about the way the world is feeling. What he tells
us is how the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> are feeling, and that they
are not feeling very well. In magnifying the global significance of their
discontents, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berman</ENAMEX> ultimately succeeds in reinstating his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> membership
in the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
