
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luce Canon</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pick Clare Boothe Luce</ENAMEX> as
the answer to a game of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twenty Questions</ENAMEX>, and you'll probably stump your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interlocutors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luce</ENAMEX>'s fame was a floaty, ineffable thing, not easy to get at
with "yes" or "no" inquiries. Was she a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>, Luce wrote The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> , an unapologetically catty satire of female competition that achieved
a lasting notoriety and a venom so pure it was almost guileless. But though she
turned out a couple of plays after that, they never achieved the same kind of
critical or commercial success. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Women</ENAMEX> lives on primarily in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Cukor</ENAMEX>'s film version, where the preposterous hats those society dames
wear are half the joke. Was she a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1930s</TIMEX>, she served
briefly as the managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , then a deco dream of a
magazine gleaming with smart chat. When <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> broke out, she filed
dispatches from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> , the picture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> launched by her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>, based on an idea she'd whispered in his ear. But reporting soon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palled</ENAMEX>. Was she a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>? As a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congresswoman from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>
and later, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, she brought a jaunty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Realpolitik</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Communist</ENAMEX> cause. But she didn't say much about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> threat that wasn't already being said, to a wider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, in her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> .

            What made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clare Boothe</ENAMEX> Luce famous had nothing to do--directly, at least--with the
lasting value of any of these accomplishments. What made her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> is that she
did all these things in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one lifetime</TIMEX>, like a paper doll that comes with
different costumes for different vocations (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, the war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>); that she did them all and was beautiful; that
she did them all in a perfumed cloud of scandal and glamour, trailed by many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> and by gossip that she herself stoked with her acerbic tongue and her
thirst for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>.

            In a way Luce is the ideal subject for this particular
moment in the art of biography. The relative slightness of her work is part of
the attraction. It forms the latticework through which we can peer at the
risqu√© private life, the slender pretext for voyeurism's pleasures. Well into
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, biography was the art of inspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with the spectacle of
an exemplary life, or of offering insights into an exemplary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of work. This
narrowed the range of subjects to the conventionally eminent, mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
Now--thanks to feminism, a general skepticism about the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> theory of
history, and an even more general interest in the details of sexually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adventurous</ENAMEX> lives--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX> are more likely to focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, less likely
to care about their canonical status. Bohemian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> whose lives beckon with an
erotic shimmer while their artistic output goes unread--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vita Sackville</ENAMEX>-West,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabel Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Luhan</ENAMEX>--are in. So are clever and seductive limelight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luce</ENAMEX>. The life's work matters less than the lifestyle. And, frankly, it helps
to have slept around.

            As it
happens, this premium on the juicy stuff has emerged in unlikely tandem with a
new professionalization of the biographer's trade. Biographies these days are
likely to be heavy and clanking with scholarly apparatus--exhaustively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">researched</ENAMEX>, loaded with random information about far-flung <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">progenitors</ENAMEX>, and
long. And so arrives a peculiar hybrid, the dishy biography that is also a
formidable work of research. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three hundred</NUMEX> pages into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Jukes Morris</ENAMEX>'
Rage for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX> and mostly enjoying myself, I was astonished to flip to
the last page (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">473</ENAMEX>) and discover that this was only Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. I'd been dumped
unceremoniously in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>, having just seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clare</ENAMEX>--by now I was certainly on
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name terms with her--off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
Like one of her hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>, I'd been left without so much as a
forwarding address. And in churlish retrospect, I began to wonder how much we
really needed to be told that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clare</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> pet was a fluffy chick named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pip</ENAMEX>
that lived "only a short time."

            
That said, this is a biography that nicely
captures the schemes and dreams of an ambitious young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the pre-feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luce</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX> mark her as a classic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">upstart</ENAMEX>. Born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who never married (her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Boothe</ENAMEX>, was already married to
someone else), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clare</ENAMEX> was the repository of her socially frustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
yearnings for a brilliant destiny. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were poor, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snyder</ENAMEX>, obsessed with trading first on her own beauty and then on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clare's</ENAMEX> for a
life of satin sheets and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> sailings on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conte di Savoia</ENAMEX> . Neither
was especially nice about it. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> (whose once-promising
career as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> had devolved into an impecunious one as a roving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">violinist</ENAMEX>), she hooked up with a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Jacobs</ENAMEX>.
He kept her and her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in grand style, even after she married <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. But none of that prevented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann</ENAMEX> from rejecting a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> because it
was "a dirty place full of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>" (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clare</ENAMEX> later put it), or from explaining to
Clare that she could never marry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobs</ENAMEX> because "I don't want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to
have a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>."

            As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clare</ENAMEX> herself was given to pronouncements like: "Matrimony! It
should be spelled matter o' money." At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>, she made good on her pun when, with
her mother's active encouragement, she married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Brokaw</ENAMEX>, who
was very, very rich and not terribly bright. He wrote her love letters in baby
talk, and when he got drunk--which was often--he serenaded his elegant young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> glee-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> songs rendered on the banjo. "Don't worry," her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother soothed</ENAMEX>. "He'll fall down those marble stairs soon enough." But after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six long years</TIMEX> of marriage and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, he wasn't yet in "dying condition,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Clare</ENAMEX> complained, "and I am not going to waste my life waiting for him to get
in it." The divorce left her a wealthy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> indeed.

            In a double-barreled biography this big, you're bound to
get some extraneous details. But in general, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Jukes Morris</ENAMEX> has an
excellent eye for the telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anecdote</ENAMEX>, and with the help of Luce's tattletale
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diaries</ENAMEX>, she has unearthed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after another. The stories she tells about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luce's</ENAMEX> magazine career make up a kind of profile in chutzpah, and are
particularly fun to read. When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clare</ENAMEX> applied for her first magazine
job--writing picture captions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogue</ENAMEX> --and heard nothing from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> writes, "she put on a gray dress with white collar and cuffs,
went back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Graybar Building</ENAMEX>, and persuaded an assistant that she was a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>. She took a seat at an empty desk in the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and
waited for some work to arrive. After a while it did." When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief
returned from her vacation "and found <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clare</ENAMEX> in place, looking both businesslike
and elegant, she assumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cond√</ENAMEX>© [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nast</ENAMEX>] had hired her. He, in turn, thought she
had." As a junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clare</ENAMEX> started an affair with
the managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Freeman</ENAMEX>, who was brainy, homely, and enthralled by
her. By the time he died, in a car accident that may have been an act of
suicide provoked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clare</ENAMEX>'s indifference, she'd learned enough from him to step
into his job with assurance and fill it with panache.

            What
Rage for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX> makes abundantly clear is how essential the patronage of
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitors</ENAMEX> and would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitors</ENAMEX> was for Luce, and probably for other
career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> as well. A female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> was
still something of a novelty act in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s and '40s</TIMEX>, a luxury that male
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> could forgo without compunction or a lawsuit. It was harder to forgo
the beautiful ones--elegant, blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clare</ENAMEX>, for instance, with her hard-won
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hauteur</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly Dach√</ENAMEX>© hats and petal-white skin. But if beauty was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handmaiden</ENAMEX> to ambition, motherhood was not. Luce packed her young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> off
to distant boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camps every chance she got. "It's a
beautiful, well-constructed fa√ßade, but without central heating," as one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clare</ENAMEX>'s escorts said of her.

            
Maybe the best way to portray a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clare Boothe Luce</ENAMEX> would be to transport her to fiction. There, you could leave
behind the old expectations of biography--grand deeds, historical
importance--and bring an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ironist</ENAMEX>'s sensibility to her inner life. You could
imagine, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Wharton</ENAMEX> writing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boothe</ENAMEX>, as she did of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily Bart</ENAMEX>,
that to Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boothe</ENAMEX>, "acquiescence in dinginess was evidence of stupidity; and
there were moments when, in the consciousness of her own power to look and be
so exactly what the occasion required, she almost felt that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> were
plain or inferior from choice." But we have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Wharton</ENAMEX>, and this is the
age of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real Lives</ENAMEX>. Rage for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX> will have to do.

         
      
   
