
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Boys</ENAMEX>

            Every so often, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in
the computer industry will develop an unrealistically charitable view of their
place in the world. "I'm not here to get rich," they pronounce. "I'm here to
change the world!" Easy to say, when you happen to be getting rich. Why don't
they work in pure research? "Research is an ivory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>," they respond.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shipping</ENAMEX> products is the way you change the world." And so they find
themselves in the cozy position of believing they're beyond materialism while
they cruise around in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraris</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po Bronson</ENAMEX>'s novel The First <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 Million</NUMEX> Is Always the
Hardest have it much harder. The fictional nonprofit research laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> provides an opportunity to work with the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the field,
designing products for other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to sell. They may be changing the world,
but they're also underpaid. They have their reasons for being there: For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marketer Andy Caspar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Honda</ENAMEX> is an opportunity to leave struggling chip maker
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omega Logic</ENAMEX> and prove he's one of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ironmen</ENAMEX>" who make the technologies that
drive the information age. For chip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Benoit</ENAMEX>, it's, er, a way to
leverage corporate resources without corporate interference. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Honda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Menzinger</ENAMEX>, it's a way to change the world without doing the
actual work himself. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omega Logic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Acheson</ENAMEX>, uh ... actually it's
hard to figure out why his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would fund an external research laboratory
instead of having its own. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Honda</ENAMEX> is an unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>, and pretty quickly
into this book it starts to smell a whole lot like a plot device. Only in such
a place would the motives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> in this novel combine in the convenient way they do. Fortunately,
about halfway through, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caspar</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> leave to form a start-up, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Honda</ENAMEX>'s strange odor fades into the background.

            They're starting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to make a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">VWPC</ENAMEX>"--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Computers</ENAMEX>. They can do so only if they
ignore the conventional wisdom that every new computer must be faster than the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> and do more. What's better, their simplified software will run on any
computer, uniting the world in a new technological brotherhood. Needless to
say, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavericks</ENAMEX> have an uphill battle to sell their idea.

            Where
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 Million</NUMEX> succeeds is as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> study. According to the book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jacket, Bronson</ENAMEX> has written about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired</ENAMEX> , the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes ASAP</ENAMEX> , and he has clearly understood
something about the psychology of the place. The misanthropic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, the
monotonic human-resource drones, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">evangelistic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX>, even the
nontechnical but talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> all strike painfully home. I know these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. They are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. We see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> at work,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> at play (which is to say, at work), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> in love, and of course some
nerd humor. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> ... we'd all have to switch to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caspar</ENAMEX>. (Have him killed.)

            
So long as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronson</ENAMEX> stays inside their heads, I
accept everything that happens, even when the technology and events veer away
from a world I recognize. It's only when the plot forces him to hide the cards
of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, which it does periodically, that my disbelief is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsuspended</ENAMEX>. When we can see into their heads, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benoit</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX> are avowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. The next thing we know, they are teaming up to steal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VWPC</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caspar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and we can't really see how or why this might have
happened. Suddenly they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in a novel, not in my life.

            The lack
of a profit motive is what really jars. Even when our start-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> go out
on their own, they are doing it because it's the only way to get things done.
They hardly seem to care about the money. They give away rights for a song.
They are totally focused on delivering technology to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>. I concede that
this is admirable, but everyone I know who has gone the start-up route has been
pretty certain that they were also in it for the financial upside. It's almost
as if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronson</ENAMEX> had started believing all the "I'm not in this to get rich"
speeches he must have heard as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>.

            Otherwise, this book is pretty convincing, and one of the
reasons it is, even (or especially) to those in the know, is that its plot is
essentially a novelization of real-life technology and events. The fictional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VWPC</ENAMEX> and its enabling software "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hypnotizer</ENAMEX>" look a great deal like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">real-life Network Computer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>. If you don't already know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> is a
programming language well suited to the Internet. Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX>, you can create
programs that are downloaded directly off the Internet and run on almost any
computer. In theory, this makes it possible to create a simple computer that
runs directly off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and doesn't even need a hard drive.

            The soap
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX> that begat Java deserved to be written as a novel. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> working on a set-top box for interactive television devised a new
language. They were ignored for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a year</TIMEX>, until someone finally realized
this was the perfect language for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX> and top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> fought it out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> for control of the language, and
won. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> is now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>'s core technology asset, and most of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> have
left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            
This user-friendly computer is not, however,
the magic bullet that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronson</ENAMEX> make it out to be. The
lowest-common-denominator approach its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> take to solving the problems of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s heterogeneous computer systems is highly controversial, and not just
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> (who have the most to lose if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> approach
wins out) say so. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> works because it lets everyone run the same program, but
it is not clear that everyone wants to run the same program. For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has had a difficult time producing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> versions of its
products. Why? Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> programs, not warmed-over
Windows programs. Java threatens us with a world where every program feels
warmed-over in the same way--functional, but not optimal.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 Million</NUMEX> would be
a good read even if you know nothing about computers, but it's an even better
read if you do, since it delves intriguingly in and out of the psychoses and
oddball situations rife in this industry. Just don't ask any hard questions of
the book, because it won't answer them.

         
      
   
