
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poet of Sexual Gloom</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Spencer</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1891-1959</TIMEX>)
was the major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> of the period between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Wars</ENAMEX> and one
of the key <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, but his work is barely known in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. Few of his paintings have made their way into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> permanent
collections--I counted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> in the extensive exhibition now on view at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirshhorn Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C. Spencer</ENAMEX>'s work--figurative, regional,
allegorical, religious, and just plain weird--fits uneasily into the
isms of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> art. To an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s
paintings at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance resemble those of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thomas Hart Benton</ENAMEX> (born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>) in their often monumental and mural-like style, but they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">richer</ENAMEX>, kinkier, and more idiosyncratic than anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX> did.

            Suddenly,
unexpectedly, the time is right for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Spencer</ENAMEX>. Within the space of a year
came the successful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> run (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Gems</ENAMEX>' intense
biographical play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Pople</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> biography, and an admiring profile by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Schama</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> . The recent attention showered on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s flesh-obsessed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">successors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucian Freud</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Bacon</ENAMEX> (a movie about the latter is due out
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX>), makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> seem more mainstream.

            It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Englishness</ENAMEX>, more remote and
more visually unfamiliar than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Degas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, that makes him
difficult to grasp. Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cookham</ENAMEX>, some <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 miles</NUMEX> west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">River</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> had such an idyllic childhood that he spent the rest of his
life re-imagining it in paint and seeking (often with disastrous results) to
restore it. "I wish all my life I could have been tied to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s apron
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strings</ENAMEX>," he confided. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> bore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, whom his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> tried to
support by giving piano lessons and playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> organ.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> was
recognized early, and he joined an extraordinary generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slade School of Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. A photograph of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Slade summer</TIMEX> outing, circa
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>, shows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> surrounded by such gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dora Carrington</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Gertler</ENAMEX> (whose erotic snafus were chronicled in the recent film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrington</ENAMEX> ), as well as by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bomberg</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX>. Recognized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomsbury</ENAMEX> set, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s early work--heavily
influenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gauguin</ENAMEX>'s neoprimitive paintings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christs</ENAMEX> and angels in Breton
costumes--was included in one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Fry</ENAMEX>'s influential group
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhibitions</ENAMEX>, which introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cézanne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s magnificent self-portrait of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>, dark and mysterious as a
Rembrandt, was snatched up by an important <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX>.

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s instincts remained insular and domestic. The better known he became,
the more he burrowed into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cookham</ENAMEX> backyards and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Centurion</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Servant</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX> evokes the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> grew up. It is
based on a story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> healing a sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from afar; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> placed himself
in the role of the convalescent--still recumbent but already striding from the
sheets--and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> as praying supplicants. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bed</ENAMEX> itself,
with its red, patterned skirt and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">luminous china knobs</ENAMEX>, dominates the picture.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mentally</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> later observed, "I have been bedridden all my life."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> interrupted this cozy idyll. The undersized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>, just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 feet 2 inches</NUMEX>, signed up for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>, he found deep satisfaction in nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> shipped back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>: It was "wonderful," he said, "to dress nearly every wound in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ward</ENAMEX>." Later he served in the same capacity on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Macedonian</ENAMEX> front and then,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> relaxed its standards in its need for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cannon fodder</ENAMEX>, in an infantry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battalion</ENAMEX>.

            Unlike so many of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shell-shocked</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> had a good war, even--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiona McCarthy</ENAMEX>
writes in her catalog essay--a "cozy war." He made a triumphant return to
painting, completing the dreamlike <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Swan Upping at Cookham</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915-1919</TIMEX>).
Ostensibly concerned with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> ritual of tagging the swans along the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX>, the painting is really a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leda and the Swan</ENAMEX> in reverse.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> once claimed, commits "a kind of spiritual rape on every
thing." This time it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who carry off the swans--or hold them in bondage
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>--while awaiting the mattresslike bedding that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> dutifully
convey. The erotic edge of this stylized composition is confirmed in a little
scene on the iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> above, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> look yearningly at each
other.

            Some of
that same hallucinatory involvement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> found its way into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Travoys With Wounded Soldiers Arriving</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dressing Station</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smol</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX>). Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s famous mural sequence at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sandham War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cookham</ENAMEX>, bristling with resurrected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, is often considered
his masterpiece, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travoys</ENAMEX> is more moving in its simple and devastating
design. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> "travoys" converge on a brightly lit window. The mules peek
curiously at the surgical operation in progress, one of the strange and
inexplicable rituals of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> at war.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> came late to sexual maturity, and he tried, after
his marriage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda Carline</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>, to make up for lost time. "A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> raises a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s dress with the same passionate admiration and love for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> raises the host to the altar," he wrote. But as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilda</ENAMEX> cared
for their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and for a sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> looked elsewhere for
those sacred apron strings. He fell in love with another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slade</ENAMEX>-trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Preece</ENAMEX>, whose "high heels and straight walk" gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>, as
he cruelly confided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda</ENAMEX>, "a sexual itch." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Preece</ENAMEX> lured him into marriage,
then refused to consummate it, making clear that she expected to live instead
with her female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> spent his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> forlornly with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilda</ENAMEX> and
many years afterward longing for a reconciliation. Their eldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>,
ironically named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilda</ENAMEX> were divorced on her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>
birthday), stares accusingly out of the wonderful portrait <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilda, Unity</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolls</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity</ENAMEX>'s piercingly innocent gray eyes contrast with the
nightmarish black holes that substitute for the dolls'.

            Like many another would-be
prophet of sexual glamour (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.H. Lawrence</ENAMEX> comes to mind), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> ended up as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> of sexual gloom, especially in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pitiless double portraits of naked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX> and naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX> painted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936 and 1937</TIMEX>. A raw leg of mutton in the
foreground of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the paintings matches the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s tired flesh while a
stove burns brightly--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>'s repressed desire, perhaps--in the
background.

            A relief to turn from these
pictures, which seem to prefigure our own sexually anxious age, to such comical
dreams of resurrection as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s exuberant The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dustman</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>), in
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cookham</ENAMEX> garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has returned from the dead and is cradled like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, while neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> offer gifts of empty cans
and other trash. In The 
               Dustman , wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>, "I try to express
something of this wish and need I feel for things to be restored. That is the
feeling that makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> take out the broken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> pot and empty jam
tin."

             

         
      
   
