
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Works</ENAMEX>

            Amid the flamboyant world of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> painting, no scandal attaches to the name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baptiste Camille Corot</ENAMEX>, no vivid anecdote or outrageous, in-your-face work of
art. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Degas</ENAMEX> longed to be "celebrated and unknown," it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corot</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painter Degas</ENAMEX> greatly admired--who achieved this paradoxical wish. His
self-effacing devotion to his art, and especially to landscape, helped to pry
open the jaws of academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convention</ENAMEX>. He claimed to have "only one goal in life
... to make landscapes," a commitment that precluded any other "serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attachment</ENAMEX>," including marriage.

            Corot was
born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1796</TIMEX>, and his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 th</NUMEX> birthday is the pretext for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
mesmerizing shows in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>: a wide-ranging retrospective at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, and a more specialized show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>
built around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> visits. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX>
modistes , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> in hats and accessories, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corot</ENAMEX> lived comfortably on a
trust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> until he himself became the fashion, both among wealthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">industrialists</ENAMEX> (who treasured his visions of the very rural serenity they were
threatening) and among the rising young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> of the impressionist
Corot," even as he disdained their "blinding use of color." He died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX>, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> after the first impressionist exhibition.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX> is often referred to as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> of plein-air
painting, but as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> show, called "In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Light of Italy</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Early Open-Air Painting</ENAMEX>," makes clear, the practice of making outdoor sketches
in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> was well-established by the time of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> campaign in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1826</TIMEX>.
The show places <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of an international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">painters</ENAMEX>--including the little-known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Welsh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jones</ENAMEX>, who produced
some astonishing studies of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">moldering</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Neapolitan</ENAMEX> walls, with drying laundry
dangling from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX>--all of whom worked outdoors in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and its environs
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the 1780s</TIMEX> to about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1840</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corot</ENAMEX> could as well be called a
pleine-eau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>, so fluid and watery are his works. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiber</ENAMEX> weaves
among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> sketches of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1820s</TIMEX>, and, like several of the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> exhibition, he pays obligatory homage to the falls at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tivoli</ENAMEX>. Still, there's something parched in these
paintings, where the air is crisp and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> have a solidity
of form and contour that recalls and betrays the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poussin</ENAMEX>.

            Then, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1835</TIMEX>, after his return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX> painted his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament</ENAMEX> scene
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hagar in the Wilderness</ENAMEX> --the first major painting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> show--which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portrayed Ishmael</ENAMEX> and his mother dying of thirst in the desert. An angel
appears above them, a sort of cosmic bartender bringing a drink. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> thinks of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Larkin</ENAMEX>'s poem about a religion based on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>: "And I should raise in
the east<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/ A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> of water/ Where any-angled light/ Would congregate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endlessly</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hagar</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Corot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next four decades</TIMEX> the
floodgates were loosed. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Water</ENAMEX> is everywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corot</ENAMEX>'s work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>, in an
effort to show off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corot</ENAMEX>'s strengths in genres other than landscape, makes room
for his large-scale <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> paintings, few of which exist in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
collections. In these he reprised such religious and mythical shower scenes as
the baptism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> as she was spied upon by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Actaeon</ENAMEX>. (During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX>
final year of his life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corot</ENAMEX> was still fidgeting with the unconvincing antlers
sprouting from poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Actaeon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.) In smaller-scale works <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corot</ENAMEX> wrought
changes on a variety of more secular riparian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>: ferrymen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> washing laundry or tossing each other playfully into the current.

            
Something happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s work around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848</TIMEX>,
as though that revolutionary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> had shaken his certainties as well. He moved,
however, not toward anything resembling social protest; one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s rare
representations of modernization--a view of a textile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> with a woman
sitting at a pre-industrial spinning wheel in the foreground--is more wistful
than indignant. Rather, the change is stylistic. All that was solid in his art
begins to melt, creating the "vaporousness" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> and others so admired in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s work. The boundary between water and land, so clear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sketches</ENAMEX>, is increasingly blurred in the great "souvenirs" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1850s</TIMEX>,
imaginary landscapes in which lakes, reflections, and mist-enveloped <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> all
meld together. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> complained that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s foliage was "like mashed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peas</ENAMEX>," but another praised the "intoxicating limpidity" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>: "Even
if we camped out in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, we could never learn in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> how he
succeeds in rendering the beauty of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>."

            None
other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Napoleon III</ENAMEX> himself snatched up the glorious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souvenir de Mortefontaine</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3,000 francs</NUMEX> and hid it away in the palace
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fountainebleau</ENAMEX>, where he could admire in private the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">great horizontal</ENAMEX> sweep
of the central <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, and the standing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s posture echoed in another, barer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>, who obviously loved the painting, hung a photograph of it over
his own bed.) Such paintings, widely reproduced even during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX>,
confirmed his lasting fame as a landscapist. After the gloomy events of the
Prussian siege of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and the slaughter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commune</ENAMEX> that followed, the
glistening countryscapes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX> exhibited in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX> seemed like a
reaffirmation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Belle France</ENAMEX> herself.

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX> was drawn to the contemplative and even the
monastic life (he painted a peculiar series devoted to monks reading, playing
the cello, and praying), he was by no means immune to feminine charm. He
praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in particular--"their asses are spectacular," he
confided to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>--though he thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whores</ENAMEX> were overpriced. The
Metropolitan retrospective also makes a case for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s figure studies, many
of which were painted during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final years</TIMEX> of his life. In the ravishing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lady</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX>, the adaptive model <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma Dobigny</ENAMEX> (a favorite of
Degas as well) shows off a cascade of blue cloth--she's a waterfall in repose.
The painting was owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Degas</ENAMEX>' good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX> and amateur
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painter Henri Rouart</ENAMEX>, who put it on public view for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Parisian Exposition Universelle of 1900</ENAMEX>. It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> of that show, as
perhaps it will be of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> retrospective. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> is
hardly representative of the more austere figure studies that line the walls in
the final <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s exhibition. These uncompromising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, with their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dry</ENAMEX>, marmoreal features, appealed to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Derain and Picasso</ENAMEX>; but they'll probably
send contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> back to the landscapes.

            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>,
the most advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> were learning all they could from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s example.
For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s reputation was fixed "like the sun itself." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>, taking
refuge in his own liquid world of waterlilies, proclaimed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX>: "There is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> here--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corot</ENAMEX>. We are nothing compared to him, nothing." It is
precisely the astonishing popular success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX>'s generation that has made
it difficult <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to view <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX> as anything other than as a precursor. The
sheer profusion of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exhibitions, with their welcome mix of the
familiar and the little-known, should prompt a much-needed reassessment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corot</ENAMEX>'s subtle art. To enter these shimmering shows now is as refreshing as a
drink of cool <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
