
   
   
      
         
            No Cigar 

            The austere
installation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Close</ENAMEX>'s big portraits at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York City</ENAMEX> begins where any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> wants the narrative of his career to begin:
with fully achieved art. No juvenilia, no hesitant casting about, no "finding
of the voice." You walk into the first white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and bam! There's the Big
Self-Portrait of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967-68</TIMEX> staring right at you. This unforgiving image
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glories</ENAMEX> in its sheer seediness. A trickle of cigarette smoke takes a detour
around the caterpillar mustache before negotiating some nose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hairs</ENAMEX>. The stubble
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s close-up cheeks and neck is so magnified that the hairs are an
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">unshavable inch long</NUMEX>. The whole portrait is a celebration of hair--facial,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nasal</ENAMEX>, chest, eyebrow, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>--the freak flag, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Crosby</ENAMEX> called it, of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '60s</TIMEX>.

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Thomas Close</ENAMEX> took a while to turn into "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Close</ENAMEX>," the disheveled,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">unmade</ENAMEX> bed of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with the black glasses. Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, he
was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of a failed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plumber</ENAMEX> who died when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> taught piano and encouraged his interest in painting. He
attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> and did graduate work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'64</NUMEX>. (His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> included such current art-world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painters Brice Marden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Bartlett</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sculptor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Serra</ENAMEX>.)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, he returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, where--with a brief interruption in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, when
a paralyzing seizure left him in a wheelchair--he has worked ever since.

            During his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 20s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> experimented with a variety of
provocative styles. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>, obviously inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jasper Johns</ENAMEX>, he cut up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> flags, sewed them up in new shapes--a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushroom cloud</ENAMEX>, for example--and
painted over them. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, he learned to paint <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX> rip-offs with such
facility that he once told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX> that he'd painted more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">de Koonings</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX> had. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1960s</TIMEX>, like others of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, he'd left the
gestural art of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX> behind (though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX> could have
painted the swirling chest hair in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Self-Portrait</ENAMEX> ) and begun using
photographic images as the basis for his cooler, less openly expressive
work.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>,
the campus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. Mass</ENAMEX> dismantled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s first solo exhibition, which
included drawings loosely based on photographs of album covers. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> showed Bob
Dylan exposing himself. Close left for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, where he painted
his <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">21-foot-long</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Big Nude</ENAMEX> , an impressive black-and-white image of a
reclining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with a bikini suntan, based on photographs he'd taken in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amherst</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> he started his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Self-Portrait</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years</TIMEX>
later, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artforum</ENAMEX> interview referred to Close by his nickname,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck"</ENAMEX>--which an assistant had scrawled on some photographs for the piece--and
the name stuck as his professional moniker.

            None of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s in-your-face '60s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shockers</ENAMEX>--the desecrated
flags, the oversize nudes, the rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>' genitalia--is included in the MoMA
show (though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Nude</ENAMEX> is reproduced in the exhibition catalog); nor, for
that matter, are some large-scale photographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nudes</ENAMEX> he made during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1980s</TIMEX>. Close's career of deliberate provocation is airbrushed out. What
this means is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Self-Portrait</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967-68</TIMEX> seems to come out of
nowhere. One is left with the somewhat misleading impression of an
establishment figure: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> who plays an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Degrees</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Separation</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> did), who paints pictures of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity friends</ENAMEX>,
who takes a formal photographic portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, in the
catalog).

            This
interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> is reinforced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX>'s focus on his technical and
formal innovations to the exclusion of his subject matter. The paintings and
drawings are grouped in such a way that we follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s progression from the
black-and-white enlargements of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '60s</TIMEX> to his puzzling attempts during
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'70s</NUMEX> to reproduce in paint the chemical process by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid</ENAMEX> cameras
make color images. Instead of mixing his colors on the palette, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> built up
his images by applying thin layers of primary colors directly onto the canvas.
Many of these color portraits have a faded pallor, like old snapshots, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exuberant Linda</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975-76</TIMEX>) has a dispersed energy, derived from the
spidery network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hendrix</ENAMEX> hair, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crow</ENAMEX>'s<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-feet</NUMEX> wrinkles, fissured lips, and eye
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capillaries</ENAMEX>. While moving into color, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> found ways to engage the crisscross
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grid</ENAMEX> that had always been part of his procedure for enlarging photographic
images. First, he made the grid an explicit element of his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX>. Then,
he experimented with different ways to fill that grid: pointillist colored
dots, blobs of papier-mâché, fingerprints and, finally, the colorful Symbolist
doodles he now favors.

            All this focus on technique, while fascinating in itself,
is a distraction from the emotional impact of the paintings. (And the most
interesting and dramatic technical transition, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gestural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooningisms</ENAMEX> to
Pop cool, is missing from the show.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX>'s coy refusal to identify the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of the portraits (wall panels give title, date, and medium) suggests
that their identities don't matter, even while <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name titles imply that
they do--that intimacies are being explored and revealed. The result is that
the show has an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiderly</ENAMEX> feel. Many will recognize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>) is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Glass</ENAMEX>; or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy II</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), in a rare Closean
profile to show off the ponytail, is the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>. But how many
will know, as I do, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marge R</ENAMEX> . (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>) is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">realtor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amherst</ENAMEX>?

            An example
of this coyness is the pair of paintings hanging side by side in the first
room. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>) could be a still from a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'50s</NUMEX> film noir: She looks as
if she has just caught sight of a stalker on the stairs. The sharp-focus
treatment of certain details--light glinting on the uneven, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali McGrawish</ENAMEX> front
teeth; the asymmetrical eyes; the squashed nose that looks as if it's been
broken at least once--give a victimized, menaced quality to the composition.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> with the fuck-you sneer depicted in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>), a magnified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mug</ENAMEX> shot hanging to her right, could be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> she's just caught sight of.
But--here's where the in-group stuff kicks in-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> is the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Graves</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Serra</ENAMEX>, whom she married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>. Is Close
(with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX>'s cooperation) suggesting there were violent tensions in this
marriage, which ended in divorce?

            Nor are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s experiments with filling his grids as
merely "technical" as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> show makes them seem. In several unsettling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portraits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> fills his grids with his own fingerprints inked on a stamp
pad. These works have none of the finger-painting naiveté of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' art that you
might expect (though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>). Rather, with
their clearly indicated whorls, they look like police fingerprints used for
identification. Is it an accident that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are mug
shots and fingerprints? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX>'s "new-ways-to-fill-the-grid" narrative
discourages any such speculation about the buried themes of criminality and
violence beneath <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s cool images.

            Close's work from the '80s
and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX> loses something of his earlier provocativeness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> II
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucas Samaras</ENAMEX>) has a wild-man intensity--part <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezra Pound</ENAMEX>,
part <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Garcia</ENAMEX>--accentuated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s one-time experimentation with a
radiating circular grid. But most of the other recent paintings are jeweled,
engaging, user-friendly. The colorful little symbols filling the grids remind
me of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gustav Klimt</ENAMEX> (whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> studied in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>), especially when
Close is luxuriating in the dark tangle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiki Smith</ENAMEX>'s hair
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiki</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>). If you take a closer look, though, you notice that instead
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klimt</ENAMEX>'s erotic glamour, which hints at dangerous passions unleashed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unconscious</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doodles</ENAMEX> depict doughnuts, hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, and lozenges. The
candy-store colors that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> reined in for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> return here with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vengeance</ENAMEX>, but they seem more frivolous than emotionally charged. These
top-dollar portraits of art-world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luminaries</ENAMEX> look good enough to eat.

             

         
      
   
