
   
   
      
         
            Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Really Feed the World</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>'s hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are
both pathetically weak and astonishingly powerful. Alone on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the parched</TIMEX> plains
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, they lack the strength to lift even a kernel of
precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX>. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> blink of a starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s hollow eyes, captured on
videotape and broadcast to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>, can galvanize the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emotions</ENAMEX>, finances, and armies of the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> on earth.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Maren</ENAMEX>'s view, this is not only a paradox but a perversity. Far from
demonstrating the good will of Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and charitable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last decade</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> of mercy to places such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> have compounded the crises there. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maren</ENAMEX>--a former
a freelance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>--has seen Western aid programs up close. He
has come to view aid and charity "as an industry, as religion, as a
self-serving system that sacrifices its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> and intended
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> in order that it may survive and grow." Sometimes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maren</ENAMEX> contends
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Road to Hell</ENAMEX> , aid can be "positively evil."

            Maren may seem hardhearted, but he has a point. While a few
of the West's massive relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>--have ended
short-term suffering, many more have failed to root out the violence and
corruption that gave rise to famine and anarchy in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. If
international humanitarianism is to preserve its legitimacy, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
and private humanitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> must confront critiques such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maren's</ENAMEX>.

            Maren views
humanitarian intervention as an instance of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> call "moral
hazard." The classic example of moral hazard comes from insurance: Because you
have it, you feel protected against your own mistakes and behave in a riskier
manner, increasing the chances that you will suffer a loss. Fire insurance
increases the chance your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> will burn down; for those inclined toward
fraud, it even raises the incentive to burn the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down. In the sphere of international aid, it is pretty clear that
the infusion of Western food and cash has often undermined the determination
and capacity of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to pull themselves up by their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bootstraps</ENAMEX>. Maren reports the lament of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Cassidy</ENAMEX>, a CARE worker
who nearly went mad trying to teach <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Somali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to adopt irrigated
cash-crop farming: "How the hell am I going to convince these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get out
there and dig if they get more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> than they can eat free from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CARE?</ENAMEX>"

            Western
help also cushions venal Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> from the consequences of their
own actions--or enables them to pursue destructive policies. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>,
Maren reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARE</ENAMEX> continued to supply <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> despite mounting
evidence that donated goods were being appropriated to further then-President
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Siyad Barre</ENAMEX>'s takeover of parts of neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile,
ostensibly destitute <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Somali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> led lucrative secret careers as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">black-market merchants</ENAMEX> of relief supplies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siyad Barre</ENAMEX>'s military misadventures
generated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, destroyed previously self-sufficient
nomadic cultures, and got the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Somali</ENAMEX> economy hooked on cheap foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> and
foreign currency. Maren shows how this previously underreported history set the
stage for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> famine and the subsequent ill-fated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military
intervention.

            Withering as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maren</ENAMEX>'s anecdotal indictment is, he doesn't
clinch the case for abolishing international assistance entirely. The
appropriate response to his horror stories is, "Yes, but." Yes,
arson-for-profit plagues the hazard-insurance business, but we still need
insurance. Yes, domestic welfare programs are riddled with perverse incentives,
but we still need a social safety net. Yes, international aid is frequently
both corrupt and corrupting, but surely, well-designed aid programs or foreign
intervention can ameliorate or prevent some humanitarian disasters.

            Of course, that means
coming up with guidelines that preserve the moral purpose of humanitarian aid
and intervention while addressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maren</ENAMEX>'s critique. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Ethics</ENAMEX> and
Politics of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humanitarian Intervention</ENAMEX> , the eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Hoffmann</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> civilization at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, takes on this task. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffmann</ENAMEX> tries
to define the components of what we consider "good causes" and then to set up
"a hierarchy of concerns" to deal with the often contradictory demands of
trying to honor "sovereignty, self-determination, democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and
individual rights." What he comes up with is specific and nuanced in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prescriptions</ENAMEX>, but not altogether satisfying. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> places sovereignty <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. For him, it's OK to link
economic assistance to the democratic inclinations of a recipient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
Aid to a democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> facing a rebellion is also acceptable. So is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterintervention</ENAMEX> to help such a government repulse foreign invasion. But
when it comes to unilateral intervention, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffmann</ENAMEX> is skittish. A powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> should intervene on its own, he says, "only if licensed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>" or a
relevant regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, and then only after noncoercive remedies have
been exhausted.

            This near-doctrinal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aversion</ENAMEX> to unilateral intervention is puzzling. It fetishizes the national
sovereignty of half-baked multiethnic congeries (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>,
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>) whose collapse into tribal warfare suggests they
may not really be organic "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>" after all. It also fails to recognize that sometimes, the only
effective option is the swift, quasi-imperial intervention of a powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sterba</ENAMEX> points out in another essay in the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffmann</ENAMEX>'s
criteria would rule out much of a role for leadership by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (or,
for that matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>). Wouldn't we all have been better off, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sterba</ENAMEX> asks, if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, on its own, had dispatched a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">warships</ENAMEX> to stop the
Serbian barrage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubrovnik</ENAMEX> before it spiraled into the all-out war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>?
And, I might add, hasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' noninterference in its colonial
stepchild <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX> served mainly to prolong that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s agony? Hoffmann, in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterresponse</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sterba</ENAMEX>, concedes the point. But as a result, sovereignty no
longer stands as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffmann</ENAMEX>'s chief organizing principle, and his final list of
policy "maxims" reads less like an antidote to the current confusion than an
eloquent recapitulation of it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maren</ENAMEX> also
has trouble fitting sovereignty into his analysis. On the one hand, he is
particularly good at documenting the phenomenon of the aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> who mutters
scornfully about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household servants</ENAMEX>. In almost every frustrated development
professional, good intentions mutate into unbounded, quasiracial contempt. Some
of those who "do development" tend to blur the distinction between assisting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> and dominating them. "It was difficult to sit back and watch
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village leaders</ENAMEX> taking money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> who worked so hard to pay
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s school fees," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maren</ENAMEX> writes of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> stint in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>.
"Yet the only thing I could have done would have been to get involved
politically, to take power, to lead, ultimately to rule." He suggests the
consequences of that impulse are always dangerous. Just look at what happened
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military when it briefly succumbed to the temptation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>. On
the other hand, he writes at another point, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humanitarianism</ENAMEX> is political. It
takes commitment. And it comes with risks." But this formulation would suggest
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> was not too aggressive but too
timid.Maybe what humanitarian intervention
requires is a stronger element of, shall we say, behavior modification--"tough
love" sent abroad. All financial assistance to the developing world should be
contingent not only on economic reform in recipient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> but on political
freedom as well. When military intervention proves unavoidable, we should be
less fastidious about national sovereignty, and all the more determined to set
right the underlying political conditions that led to disaster.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, on their arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>--their moment of greatest
strength--had arrested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlords</ENAMEX> and destroyed their heaviest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> might not have been drawn into bigger factional problems later
on. The overly respectful way the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> handled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribal warlords</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> sent an enormously harmful signal to the authentic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>-gloves treatment reflects our
ostensible reluctance to involve ourselves in costly overseas conflicts, and
our ostensible respect for the national sovereignty of the foreign countries.
But once we're in, we're in. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX>, perhaps, to sort things out thoroughly in
the short run, and to prevent even greater devastation for all concerned down
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>--even if that means suffering a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>, or opening ourselves
up to the charge of imperialism.NomadNet, a page on "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peacekeeping</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relief & Economic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development Issues</ENAMEX>" run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Maren</ENAMEX>, has been shut down, but its archives
are still open. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development and Foreign Aid</ENAMEX> section includes a piece by Maren
titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Food-Aid Racket"</ENAMEX>.) Among other destinations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NomadNet</ENAMEX> will link you
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humanitarian Assistance</ENAMEX>, published at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virtual</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library on International Development</ENAMEX> is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for material on
these issues. To approach humanitarian aid from the perspective of a few of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency for International Development</ENAMEX>'s home page, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARE</ENAMEX>'s site, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ReliefNet</ENAMEX>, "a non-profit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> dedicated to helping humanitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> raise global
awareness and encourage support for relief efforts via the Internet." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Centre</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humanitarian Reporting</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> often only report on the
"crisis of the moment," and aims to "encourage better reporting of
humanitarian, development and related issues." Meanwhile, a site established
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">WorldAid '96 Global Expo and Conference on</ENAMEX> Emergency Relief,
which took place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>, gives you a firsthand glimpse of the frequently
crass world of the relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> (note the long list of commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exhibitors</ENAMEX>
in attendance).

         
      
   
