
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">STOP the World, I Want to Get Off</ENAMEX>

            I'll bet that very few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who begin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Greider</ENAMEX>'s new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">528</NUMEX>-page book will read every word of
it. Like his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">799</NUMEX>-page tome on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secrets</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>), it would have been vastly improved by being cut, perhaps in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>.
Entire arguments and quotations are repeated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter to chapter</ENAMEX>. Most of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> include a tedious travelogue. Here, for example, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greider</ENAMEX>'s
description of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX>: "Its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> grace notes, the broad boulevards and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">castles</ENAMEX> inherited from colonial eras, were splashed with wild, magical colors
that could only be described as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'Mexican</ENAMEX>.' "

            But I
would also bet that anyone who gets through this book (except, perhaps, for a
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>) will feel a pang of regret for not
taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> more seriously <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Not that the author
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buchananite</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perotista</ENAMEX>; a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and
currently a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX> is liberal and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cosmopolitan</ENAMEX>. But in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One World, Ready or Not</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greider</ENAMEX> explains why
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> should feel anxious about their place in the new world economy--an
anxiety that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> addressed, however imperfectly, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and many of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> ignored. I may be prejudiced
because I share <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX>'s political point of view, but I think this is the best
book to date on the perils of the new world economic order. It does for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-Bretton Woods</ENAMEX> world of currency swaps, runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, and technology
transfers what his earlier book did for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. It makes a daunting subject
somewhat comprehensible--and harrowing.

            The book contains a core argument about industry and labor,
which I believe to be true. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX> contends that in many key
industries--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">autos</ENAMEX>, textiles, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>,
computers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are capable of producing far more
than the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> can buy. Such overcapacity in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">autos</ENAMEX>, for instance,
runs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as high as 25 percent</NUMEX>, and will probably rise as each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> tries to
develop its own automaking industry. And the overcapacity problem is getting
worse, for a couple of reasons. Advances in technology allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> to
produce more goods with fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (in effect, creating more supply but less
demand). Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have adopted
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mercantilist</ENAMEX> trade strategies: that is, they have sought, through barriers or
government subsidies, to guarantee surpluses. By definition, such a strategy
expands the supply of goods without proportionately boosting demand.

            
Overcapacity reduces the incentive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to invest and leads to slower
world growth, as supply continually threatens to outrun demand. Put this
together with the new mobility of capital--the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to move
their manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> wherever the costs are lowest--and you have the
ingredients for an international race to the bottom in wages and social
benefits, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> seek to cut costs in the face of this overcapacity and
heightened competition for markets.

            
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the quest to lower costs
encourages corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. It's the class war all over
again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greider</ENAMEX> notes, only worse. "In historical terms," he writes,
"revolutionary capitalism has circled back to its original fight with socialism
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX> and reopened the ideological argument, but from a much stronger
political position. Labor and the left are in retreat almost everywhere;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commerce</ENAMEX> and finance predominate in politics and have adapted centralized
government to their own uses."

            Greider
also undertakes an ambitious analysis of global finance. In this area, I am
less confident of my own knowledge--and therefore, of his conclusions. But his
arguments are provocative and address seeming anomalies that conventional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> have failed to address, let alone explain. For instance, Greider
argues that the unexpected rise in interest rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>-- after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had reduced the deficit--was the result of an entirely
separate drama played out among private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX>, who wildly overinvested
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>. In explaining why economic growth has lagged over the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX> singles out the deregulation of finance by both national
and international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. The ensuing volatility of currency-exchange rates, he
argues, has made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>' projections of profits from trade increasingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unreliable</ENAMEX>, thereby discouraging productive investments and growth.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX> also argues that deregulation helped make the value
of advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>' financial assets grow faster than their actual economies.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1980 to 1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greider</ENAMEX> notes, financial assets from advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have
expanded at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, about twice as fast as the economies themselves
were growing. That has led to a worldwide situation comparable to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
bubble economy, where, with assets systematically overvalued, a crash became
inevitable. But while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of Finance</ENAMEX> has ably managed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s crisis, there is no comparable global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to police the world
system.

            In
Secrets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greider</ENAMEX> warned that central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> had taken over
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic policies. He now acknowledges that power has shifted to the
global market and its private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, who, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX>, possess the
power to overturn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> currency decisions. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greider</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the world held <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$139 billion</NUMEX> in foreign exchange
reserves, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> that was traded, on average, in
foreign-exchange markets. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$278 billion</NUMEX> in
reserves, but the private market was trading <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$623 billion</NUMEX> a day. As the power
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> has grown, government economic policy has become
hostage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financiers</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>' fears that economic growth will
spur inflation, which will reduce the value of their holdings. So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financiers</ENAMEX>' prescriptions for curbing inflation--slower growth
through a balanced budget and higher interest rates. They end up doing all they
can to eliminate the one instrument--rapid economic growth--by which they might
close the gap between finance and industry. "This commitment to slow growth,"
writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX>, "does protect the value of money and financial assets, but it
is like a noose thrown around the advanced economies, sure to deepen their
imbalances in production and employment."

            
The upshot of all this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX> worries, might
be a repeat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that decade</TIMEX>, industry and finance were also
strangely out of step with each other, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> also faced a conflict
between popular welfare and the imperatives of the market. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX>, the
rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and right-wing nationalism in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is a
foretaste of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st -century</TIMEX> fascism. As an alternative, he suggests
a "moderate" middle ground between the rentier capitalism's status quo
of balanced budgets and wage and benefit cuts on the one hand and a "hard,
reactionary politics that can shut down the system" on the other. The latter
would probably call for shutting off immigration, erecting permanent,
high-tariff walls, and "solving" the problem of unemployment by stigmatizing
the least employable. Between these extremes lie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX>'s own solutions, which
he summarizes thus:

            Restore
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> controls over global capital. Tax wealth more, labor less. Stimulate
global growth by boosting consumer demand from the bottom up. Compel trading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> to accept more balanced trade relations and absorb more surplus
production. Forgive the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">debtors</ENAMEX>, especially the hopeless cases among the very
poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. Reorganize monetary policy to confront the realities of a
globalized money supply, both to achieve greater stability and open the way to
greater growth. Defend labor rights in all markets--prohibit the ancient abuses
renewed in the "dark Satanic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX>."

            Some of his more specific suggestions strike me as less
than helpful. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX> wants to "change the tax incentives and subsidies for
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> by rewarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that fostered greater employment and
penalizing those that did the opposite." That would, in effect, penalize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for efficiency and productivity. But other suggestions make sense. He
wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to join with other financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in adopting a
"transactions tax" on currency exchanges to stanch speculation and inhibit wide
swings in currency values. (Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Summers</ENAMEX> once
endorsed this idea.) He wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to adopt an "emergency tariff"
of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 10 percent and 15 percent</NUMEX> on imports to force other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to
abandon their mercantile trading strategies. And he wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> to adopt binding standards for international labor rights to slow
the race to the bottom.

            Unfortunately, even these
suggestions are unlikely to be adopted. The same trends in the world economy
that cry out for reform are themselves weakening the hand of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>. For
instance, as the mobility of capital reduces the power of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, the chance
for including labor rights in the world trade treaty known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
Agreement on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade and Tariffs</ENAMEX>--grows remote. As <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">multinationals</ENAMEX> ship
their production overseas, the likelihood of getting business to support an
import tariff (which would now tax their 
               own imports) becomes
equally small.

            But does that mean that we
face a repeat of the dark years of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup kitchens</ENAMEX> and brownshirts leading up to
world war? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greider</ENAMEX> suggests we could "replay the terrible conflicts of the
twentieth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>." I find that a little extreme--or, at least, difficult to
foresee. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX>'s less bold (but still frightful) assertion that "the
global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> ... will probably experience a series of terrible
events--wrenching calamities that are economic or social or environmental in
nature" seems well within the realm of plausibility.

         
      
   
