
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mystery of Life</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, the New York
Times reviewed a book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Behe</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biochemist</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehigh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>. Titled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Box</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biochemical Challenge</ENAMEX> to
Evolution , the book contended that the molecular machinery of living things
works too well to have been produced by chance alone. Life must have been
designed by some intelligent being, possibly one that was divine. Reading the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX>--surprisingly respectful, considering that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> was a science
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>--I had to smile imagining the vein-popping fury that it would arouse in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dawkins</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fools</ENAMEX>! he would mutter . I am surrounded by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fools</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dawkins,</ENAMEX>
an evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University</ENAMEX>, is "the most brilliant and
compelling propagandist of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired</ENAMEX> recently put it. He
is also an adamant atheist. His work is basically one long argument that
natural selection, and natural selection alone, is sufficient to explain the
seemingly miraculous variety, beauty, and ingenuity of living things. The
mystery of life, he declared in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> best seller <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Blind</ENAMEX>
Watchmaker , "is a mystery no longer because [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>] solved it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX> is one of those rare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> whose writings both
persuade his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and charm the public. He excels at coining pithy phrases and
metaphors that express anew the power of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> theory. In his first book,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selfish Gene</ENAMEX> , published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, he set forth his brutally
reductionist view that all <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> are vehicles created by genes seeking to
make copies of themselves. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Extended Phenotype</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>), he
introduced the notion that culture consists of self-replicating ideas called
"memes." As many profilers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX> have remarked, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawkins</ENAMEX> himself is one of
the most successful meme-propagators on the planet.

            His latest book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Climbing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Improbable</ENAMEX> , is erected around yet another compelling meme. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>
asks us to imagine the myriad forms of life inhabiting a vast mountain. At its
foot are the least <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>--and hence most probable--<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">algae</ENAMEX>. On the peaks are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> that seem least likely to have
been produced by happenstance, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spiders</ENAMEX>, whose webs are marvels of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>
reminds us that natural selection produces such <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> through a series of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incremental</ENAMEX> steps that "smear out" their improbability over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long</TIMEX> periods of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. To reinforce this point, he tells us how he constructed a computer
program that, with only a few rules for guidance, could "learn" to construct
webs remarkably similar to those built by real <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spiders</ENAMEX>.

            

               A >s in his previous books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>' tendency toward donnish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">didacticism</ENAMEX> is more than counterbalanced by the transparency of his prose and
his genuine delight in the intricacies of nature. His description toward the
end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Climbing</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Improbable</ENAMEX> of wasps enmeshed in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX>
power struggles with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fig trees</ENAMEX> is a model of nature writing, at once lyrical
and lucid.

            In an era
when even reputable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> indulge in mysticism, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>' rejection of
intelligent design is also bracing. He openly loathes those who discern divine
intentions behind natural phenomena, such as fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> who view
the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> virus as divine punishment for sodomites. Dawkins spares no one. He
describes a conversation in which his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> speculated that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> were put on earth to "make the world pretty." "I was touched by this,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawkins</ENAMEX> recalls, "and sorry I had to tell her that it wasn't true."

            Despite its blunt charms, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Climbing Mount</ENAMEX>
Improbable strikes me as being the least convincing of all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>'
books. In focusing on the notion of life's improbability--or lack
thereof--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX> has inadvertently drawn attention to the greatest weakness of
Darwinian theory. There has always been something disturbingly retroactive,
after-the-fact, about natural selection as an explanation of life, even when
propounded by someone as eloquent as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>. Life, explained by natural
selection alone, just does not seem inevitable enough.

            Addressing
this issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX> sometimes resembles a flack for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotto</ENAMEX> assuring us that
winning the big one is easy. He allows that at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, it seems almost
miraculous that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Blow</ENAMEX> would win the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> jackpot. But by retracing
the steps that culminated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s good fortune--the printing of the fateful
ticket, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s purchase of it at his local liquor store, the selection of that
number by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawkins</ENAMEX> demonstrates that each conforms to
well-understood principles of physics, biology, and social science; no miracles
were required. Well, true enough. But that does not make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe any</ENAMEX> less
lucky.

            
It is not only religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creationists</ENAMEX> who are
bothered by this problem but also some prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Kauffman</ENAMEX> claims to have glimpsed--deep in his
computer simulations--a mysterious "antichaos" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that counteracts the
tendency of all physical systems to drift toward disorder. This force
supposedly makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> "self-organize" into galaxies, and inanimate molecules,
into living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>.

            Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorists</ENAMEX>, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Sloan Wilson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University of New York at</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binghamton</ENAMEX>, have proposed that natural selection may sometimes favor
"altruistic" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, who sacrifice their own selfish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> for those
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX>, or their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, or even the entire ecosystem in which they are
embedded. The most extreme version of this concept, called "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> selection,"
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaia</ENAMEX>, which suggests that all of life cooperates so as to ensure its
continued survival.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX> has rebutted these notions convincingly, showing
that the phenomena they attempt to explain can all be accounted for with
conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> theory. But his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX> of natural selection sometimes
lend it more power than it really has. In one passage, for example, he likens
it to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> or "pressure" that "drives evolution up the slopes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount</ENAMEX>
Improbable." This image offers a grossly distorted view of evolution. For
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> of life's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.5 billion</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year</TIMEX> history, it was entirely made up
of single-celled <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">algae</ENAMEX>. Then, for some
reason--we will probably never know precisely why--the era of trilobites,
triceratops, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">multicellular creatures commenced</ENAMEX>. Viewed this way, the
ascent from the foothills of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Improbable</ENAMEX> to its multicellular aeries
hardly seems inevitable.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>' own honesty and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thoroughness</ENAMEX> undermine his case in other ways as well--for example, when he
brings up the origin of life. "My guess is that life probably isn't all that
rare and the origin of life probably wasn't all that improbable," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX>
remarks. "But there are arguments to the contrary." There certainly are.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawkins</ENAMEX> himself notes that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of searching, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have found no
conclusive evidence that life exists elsewhere in the universe. (The discovery
of organic matter in a meteorite, reported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early August</TIMEX>, represents at best
an extremely circumstantial piece of evidence for life on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>.)

            Moreover,
as far as we know, life emerged here on earth only once. In spite of the
immensely powerful tools of modern biotechnology, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> still cannot make
matter animate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>. They really have no idea how exactly life
began, or whether its emergence was in some sense inevitable or simply a
prodigious bit of good fortune.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theorists</ENAMEX> also disagree over why, once life
began, it was able to persist for so long and to proliferate into such an
astonishing variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawkins</ENAMEX> enjoys pointing out that among all the
possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">variants</ENAMEX> of a given <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, the vast majority never reproduce; they
are failures, dead ends. There are many more ways to be a loser in the game of
life, he asserts, than to be a success. Surely that holds true for all of life,
not just for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent</ENAMEX> parts. The essence of the selfish-gene model is
that each individual pursues its short-term interests regardless of the
long-term consequences for life as a whole, or even for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. Given that premise, why couldn't one species--a bacterium or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>,
perhaps--run amok and destroy all other life on earth before finally succumbing
itself? But life has managed, nonetheless, not only to endure but also to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">produce spiders</ENAMEX>, newts, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX>.

            I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawkins</ENAMEX> knows how
utterly improbable we are, because I have discussed the matter with him. Yet he
seems to think that if he allows us weak-minded mortals to perceive that naked
truth too directly, we will succumb to creationism or mysticism or theories
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaia</ENAMEX>, which is wishful thinking dressed up as science. Of course, most
of us will succumb. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawkins</ENAMEX> should at least give us the chance to savor one
of the great paradoxes of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> before we slip into darkness: The more that
science explains our existence, the more implausible we seem.

         
      
   
