
   
   
      
         
            Whistling <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dixie</ENAMEX>

            "A perpetual debate goes on
about how much of the real <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> is left," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Applebome</ENAMEX> observes near the
start of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> tour. "Is it still distinctive or is it now just
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Topeka</ENAMEX> with more fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, road kill, heat and history?"

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dixie Rising</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applebome</ENAMEX>'s eminently balanced portrait of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, the veteran
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> turns this debate on its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. He asks, instead: Is the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> distinctive, or is it now just
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macon</ENAMEX> with worse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX>, manners, and musical rhythm<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "The most striking
aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century's end</TIMEX>," he writes, "is how much the
country looks like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>."

            This
fresh take on the region should disabuse anyone who still imagines the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> amalgam of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deliverance , Gone With the Wind</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> photos of hollow-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sharecroppers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applebome</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> is economically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vibrant</ENAMEX>, politically and culturally self-confident, and racially more
integrated than the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dixie Rising</ENAMEX> is no blithe blurb
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun Belt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applebome</ENAMEX> warns that if the Southern doctrines now sweeping
through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' rights, low taxes, and quasi-fundamentalist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christianity</ENAMEX>, among other things--do for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> what they've done for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixie</ENAMEX>, we may all be in trouble.

            In his earnest efforts to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> a fair shake,
Applebome, a native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Long Islander</ENAMEX> now raising a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, begins by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">puncturing Northern</ENAMEX> stereotypes and sanctimony about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. He points out
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Belt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi Delta</ENAMEX>, long regarded as racist backwaters,
now have more black elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. We see
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">penitent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX> joining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in celebrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1965 Selma</ENAMEX> march
and telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lowery</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Christian Leadership</ENAMEX>
Conference, "I love you. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> and white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> love you." And we see how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX> has become the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s new industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heartland</ENAMEX>, creating half the new
jobs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>; even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, long the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s bottom-feeder, has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prospered</ENAMEX> thanks to legalized gambling.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dixie</ENAMEX>
Rising is structured around visits to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX> locales, with each one
used to illustrate the confluence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> and national trends. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Race</ENAMEX>,
inevitably, emerges as a principal theme. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Applebome</ENAMEX>, no place in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> has tried harder to overcome the region's harsh racial legacy than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX> It was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>-white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> to elect a
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>-failed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> aspirant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Gantt</ENAMEX>), and remains committed
to school integration--even as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have flocked to private
"seg academies."

            
But this racial progress is fragile and, in
some ways, phony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>'s racial comity has not been born solely of its
residents' love of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. A calculated civic boosterism (so exuberant
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber of commerce</ENAMEX> slogan was once "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>--A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Place to</ENAMEX>
Make Money") has spurred the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s desire to appear enlightened. And
integration has its limits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Applebome</ENAMEX> recounts his visit to a white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that
recruited a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastor</ENAMEX>, only to see its transracial experiment fail. The
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parishioners</ENAMEX> fled, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> retreated to the borderline separatist
rhetoric of empowerment and self-reliance.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> is also a
cautionary blueprint for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> when it comes to economic development.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applebome</ENAMEX>'s discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> probes the dirty secret behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie</ENAMEX>'s
stunning rise from poverty: its rabid anti-unionism, or what one historian
calls "the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>'s most respectable prejudice." (As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> says of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>, "He'll accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> now, but you still don't see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom</ENAMEX> shaking
hands with union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>'s "Faustian bargain"--send us jobs, any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX>, in exchange for cheap, nonunion labor--has undermined Northern workers
and made the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> "the bad-job capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." This balmy business
climate has also led to gross neglect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' safety. To cite just one
example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> died during a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>-plant fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>,
due to "locked exit doors that were blocked off so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> wouldn't steal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dixie</ENAMEX> 
               Rising 's account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>'s political rise covers more
familiar ground: massive population shifts toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun Belt</ENAMEX> that have tipped
the electoral balance; the adoption by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party of Southern</ENAMEX>
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stances</ENAMEX>, most of them rooted in a visceral hatred of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>; and
the ascent to power of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority leader</ENAMEX> and majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>.

            Some of this political analysis, shaped by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> landslide, has been lapped by events. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Applebome</ENAMEX> devotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s district in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cobb County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ga.</ENAMEX>, which he says epitomizes the
national trend towards suburban, white-flight, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>-right conservatism.
But the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election casts doubts on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cobb County</ENAMEX> as a model for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. While
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> may still be moving rightward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unpopularity</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Democrats</ENAMEX>' ability to hold their own this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, suggests that the relentless rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie</ENAMEX>'s right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republicanism</ENAMEX> has
slowed, at least for now. The evangelical tone of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie</ENAMEX>-driven conservatism may
also help account for the growing alienation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> and the industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>.

            And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applebome</ENAMEX> goes too far when he suggests that an even more reactionary strain of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> thought--"neo-Confederate" ideology--has gone mainstream in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
It's true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lost Cause</ENAMEX> is resurgent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, albeit
stripped of its once-blatant segregationism. It's also true there are close
parallels between the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With America</ENAMEX>" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> constitution,
which not only enshrined <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' rights but also included term limits, budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">balancing</ENAMEX>, and limits on taxation. But when neo-Confederate ideology went
national with the presidential candidacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who passionately
defended displaying the rebel battle flag over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina statehouse</ENAMEX>,
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--indeed, most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Carolinians</ENAMEX>--found his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retro-rebel</ENAMEX> views too
extreme. To suggest, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applebome</ENAMEX> does, that "it's hard to know these days
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Confederacy</ENAMEX> ends and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> begins," is to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
with some far-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>, many of whom genuinely believe in black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World Order</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX> and the genetic inferiority of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>.

            
Such occasional overreaching aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applebome</ENAMEX>'s
is a shrewd, fair, and entertaining guide to the region. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>, he shows
how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western has become the predominant music of white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> having outsold every recording <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> except
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applebome</ENAMEX> mixes vivid landscape writing with
visits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s tacky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>. Throughout, he displays a deft and lively
grasp of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> history and letters, popular culture and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>. ("Pickled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>' feet are the opposite of an acquired taste," he writes. "Unless you're
born eating [them], you never will.") The narrative is laced throughout with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colorful</ENAMEX>, distinctly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">store owner</ENAMEX> who
displays a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Holidays</ENAMEX> sign year round ("[w]e have a holiday every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months or so</TIMEX>") and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> whose " rock 'n' roll temple" fuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> ways ("[w]e're sort of reconformadox").

            Nowhere
is this book's love/hate affair with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> more obvious than at the end,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Applebome profiles Lewis Grizzard</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humorist</ENAMEX> and newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> who asked that his ashes be spread on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> yard line of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulldogs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>. After an admiring review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzard</ENAMEX>'s wit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> turns
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for peddling a nostalgic vision of a homogeneous pre-integration
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzard</ENAMEX>'s idealized <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> was the world before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> and
affirmative action, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> stayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> where they belonged, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> pretty much meant the world of small-town white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> like him."

            
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> that is triumphant now," concludes
Applebome, is one that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">neo-Confederates</ENAMEX> would celebrate, "a
place of feel-good nostalgia, easy answers, and painless solutions, forever
looking backward through a pale mist and seeing only the soft focus outlines of
what it wants to see." It exalts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' rights while ignoring the doctrine's
ugly racial legacy, and rants against the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> while conveniently
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">forgetting Washington</ENAMEX>'s role in salvaging the region's economy with military
spending and other aid. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Applebome</ENAMEX> sketches the alternative promise of a proudly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interracial South</ENAMEX> that "has gone through the fire of change and come out
redeemed." The problem is, little else in his book suggests that this dream
will become reality.

            Having recently traveled to
many of the places <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Applebome</ENAMEX> visited, I found his warm but withering portrait
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie</ENAMEX> to ring true. The much-hyped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New South</ENAMEX> may have shed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie</ENAMEX>'s overt
racism and acquired the same neon surfaces as the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. But it can
still look a lot like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old South</ENAMEX>. And it remains a far cry from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Topeka</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
