
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnum Farce</ENAMEX>

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>, I've been
driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> nuts with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> impression. I don't do an especially
good one, but then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> is not especially difficult to do. You lower your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>, pull it back into your throat so that it's breathy, verging on a rasp
and yet smooth, almost plangent, then expel the line from The Outlaw

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Josey Wales</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>) addressed to the bounty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> who insists that he's
only trying to make a living, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dyin</ENAMEX>' ain't much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">livin</ENAMEX>', <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>." It's a
bedroom voice, menacing but seductive, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-deliberate diction that
implies, "I'm so powerful, so coiled, so masculine that I have to modulate my
tone--or else." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dirty Harryisms</ENAMEX>--"Ask yourself, 'Do I
feel lucky?' Well, do ya, punk <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" and "Go ahead, make my day"--are
purring come-ons: The bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is practically compelled to submit to this tall,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handsome killer</ENAMEX> with his long Magnum <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Submit</ENAMEX>, in many cases, by going
for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and getting blown into orgasmic nonexistence.

            Eastwood
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the great movie voices of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>, but it's also kind of ridiculous.
Probably no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> could get away with it if he weren't such an image of cool, as
beautiful and remote and self-contained as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garbo</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chet Baker</ENAMEX>. What has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enraptured</ENAMEX> so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, among them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel in Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> , is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor-director</ENAMEX> has learned to play with his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inexpressiveness</ENAMEX>--to make a joke of his frigid machismo without (and here's
where the supreme balancing act comes in) travestying it. Eastwood, in this
view, contains within himself both the myth and the anti-myth. I think that
he's a fine, lightweight comic presence at times (his scowl is a psychotic
version of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX>'s classic slow burn), but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schickel</ENAMEX> goes further. He calls
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> "one of the great ironists of the age" and a "postmodern" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint</ENAMEX>'s gift," he writes, forever on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name basis with his subject, "is
to let us see the dark comedy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>'s contorting, distorting
attempts to achieve his masteries of the moment while at the same time not
entirely discrediting the tradition that makes him bid that effort."

            Whew: That's some gift. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX> is alternately sycophantic
(toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eastwood</ENAMEX>) and pugilistic (toward any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> who has ever had unkind
words for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>--particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kael</ENAMEX>, who did seem to have a mission
to make the tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnum</ENAMEX> shrivel). The book has the breathless indulgence
of a campaign biography ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint</ENAMEX>'s lack of selfishness, his predilection for
throwing scenes to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>--partly out of generosity, partly out of a
serene confidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of his own presence ... "). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, Schickel
seems happiest simply basking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>'s aura, preferring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> "in the fading light of certain wintry <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX>" to trudging around
and interviewing anyone with a different version of events or a contrasting
point of view.

            That
doesn't surprise me, since contrasting points of view don't make it into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s movies, either, which is why I have some trouble accepting this
notion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor-director</ENAMEX> as an "ironist." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirty Harry</ENAMEX> movies or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">rabidly</ENAMEX> right-wing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> Heartbreak 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ridge</ENAMEX> (which ends with a
potency-reclaiming invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>), there's little irony in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s
superiority to the succession of louts, prisses, and psychopaths whom his
character inevitably clobbers or blows away, or in the fact that he is of
greater stature than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> with whom he surrounds himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> might
acknowledge the faint absurdity of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, but none is ever ultimately
proved wrong. Even the hell-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Munny</ENAMEX> in the compelling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unforgiven</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>)--who does, admittedly, shoot a rather nice young
cowboy in the gut, but instantly regrets it--ends up killing the sort of people
who, when all is said and done, need killing.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX> stops duking it out with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antagonists</ENAMEX>, his analyses can be trenchant. He's especially evocative on the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"spaghetti Westerns</ENAMEX>" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eastwood</ENAMEX> made with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sergio Leone</ENAMEX>, for whom the
actor forged his amusingly taciturn on-screen persona. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schickel</ENAMEX> writes,
developed a style that alternated cunningly between extreme wide shots and
extreme close-ups partly in an effort to monumentalize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s face; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s mise en scène became "a landscape of masks." But then it's
back to the issue of "irony," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX>'s evasions can make your jaw drop.
The rousing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Harry</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>) is inarguably a template for the modern,
right-wing vigilante picture, replete with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">digs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda</ENAMEX> rights, due process,
and the burgeoning civil-liberties movement. Yet here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schickel</ENAMEX>, quoting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s insistence that the film has no larger political agenda: "It's just
the story of one particular police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in a frustrating situation on one
particular case." (And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Horton</ENAMEX> is just some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> concludes,
"It is as a rule absurd, and utterly unrealistic, to see ideological motives,
let alone ideological malevolence" in action pictures; he is conveniently
omitting any reference here to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Milius</ENAMEX>, the gleeful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal-basher</ENAMEX> who scripted many of the banner lines in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Harry</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnum Force</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>). Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Enforcer</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>) , Schickel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, "Certainly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, attitudes having radically changed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint</ENAMEX> would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retract</ENAMEX> [the movie's] casual contempt for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>, admittedly a feature of
his early action films." That would be mighty white of him! And for this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer</ENAMEX>, "one of the most tasteful campaigns in the history of modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s run, as a property-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>--was one in which the star likened a civic ordinance that
would ban <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> kitchens to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX> knocking on your door."

            OK, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s not a rocket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schickel</ENAMEX> does
seem to see him as some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delphic oracle</ENAMEX>, and his attempts to translate
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s monosyllabic pronouncements make for hilarity: " 'Women,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint</ENAMEX> says,
a sort of sad befuddlement in his tone, 'always want to know what you're
thinking.' " Schickel enlarges: "It is a mystery to him, this desire to
penetrate the deepest reserves of his privacy. It is equally a mystery to him
why anyone would think that bringing things up out of this murk and discussing
them would profit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">either party</ENAMEX>. At our cores, he believes, for whatever reason,
we are what we are, and there is nothing much to be done about that--beyond
simply accepting the hard facts of personality."

            "We are
what we are, and there is nothing much to be done about that" doesn't make for
a very interesting aesthetic, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s dry, dodgy movies (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX> touts
"their directness of address, their plainspoken psychological realism") bear
the stamp of this shrunken worldview. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> could make the case that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>'s legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promiscuity</ENAMEX>, with its attendant insulation and fear of
commitment, has artistic consequences. Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Parker</ENAMEX>,
for instance, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eastwood</ENAMEX> idolizes and about whom he made the reverent biopic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel O'Brien</ENAMEX>, in his modest, more
objective new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood Film-Maker</ENAMEX> , suggests that Eastwood
wouldn't actually put up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">saxophonist</ENAMEX>'s unruly
passion, his commitment to his art, is the antithesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s manly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frugal</ENAMEX>, shoot-it-and-move-on way of working. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schickel</ENAMEX> is starry-eyed. He
compares the films (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s masculine posing) to the modern-jazz manner,
"a powerful desire--almost amounting to a morality--not to woo the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> ...
a profound desire not to make what he does look costly to him, emotionally or
intellectually."

            
One could argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> has merely masked
his inadequacies as artistic choices. But I wouldn't want to go too far. I
frequently enjoy his movies, and there's no arguing with the fact that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stardom</ENAMEX> has endured for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than three decades</TIMEX>. There might be a kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> here, but it's the genius of a seducer, not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> makes
use of the traditional tools--his size, his handsomeness, the aura of mystery
he so manifestly cultivates. But the seduction also occurs in unexpected ways.
Reading the book, I found myself conscious of, and moved by, the ways in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX> has been drawn in by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eastwood</ENAMEX>, compelled to fill all kinds of sad,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moody</ENAMEX> spaces. The author doesn't simply idolize his subject, he feels he needs
to cover for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s failures and rationalizations the way one might for an
absent or inadequate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. Above all, he wants us to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misunderstood</ENAMEX>, under unfair attack from all sides--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who demand
something more than his sexual favors, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> with its shrill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> and snobby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elitists</ENAMEX>.

            In an age
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> has slipped into the haze of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX> writes movingly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> clinging to stereotypical notions of machismo
as they're laid off their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> jobs and symbolically robbed of potency, it
can put a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> in your throat to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>--like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> in
Field <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of Dreams</ENAMEX> --a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> whom so many elements of the
culture have come to undervalue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s decision to play dumb, in films
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Gauntlet</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bronco</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>), was a
shrewd one. It allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX> to write lines like, "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rude beast</ENAMEX> has been
perceived slouching toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Masculinity</ENAMEX>, waiting to be
reborn in more cuddlesome form."

            It also, to be fair, means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> can go where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzeneggers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Seagals</ENAMEX> daren't. His
performance as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Horrigan</ENAMEX>, an aging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In The Line</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fire</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), was the most affecting he has ever given--a fallen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stereotype</ENAMEX>, a glimpse of the human caught in the pose. But does the film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subvert Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s on-screen persona, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX> argues it does? How? He bests
the bureaucratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX>. He outwits the psychotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX>. He beds the young,
beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s other movies really subvert the whole action
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX>? Compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Bronson's</ENAMEX>, maybe. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Munny</ENAMEX>'s assertion, in
Unforgiven , that "it's a hell of a thing, killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. You take away
everything he's got and everything he's ever gonna have," was hailed by some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> as a brave line for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> to utter, given that he has dispatched so
many anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> so offhandedly for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave</ENAMEX>, but hypocritical.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> did more to make killing casual than anyone in mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>. He
paved the way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronsons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Norrises</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Dammes</ENAMEX> and all the other righteous slayers of post-midnight
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX>-movie-channel programming. Will history judge the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schickel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boswellian tome</ENAMEX> as "ironic" and "postmodern"? Or as an enlightened
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neanderthal</ENAMEX>, profitably pretending to evolve?

         
      
   
