
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Innocence Abroad</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mavis Gallant</ENAMEX> is one of
those strangely positioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> rank her near the top of the
literary ladder but who remains, to the rest of the world, not much more than a
name. A quick rundown, then, of her long and impressive career: It begins in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallant</ENAMEX> was born and lived till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 27</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, she quit
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> job and moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, allowing herself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> to publish
fiction or find another line of work. You might expect a painful drama to
follow, a piling up of drafts and rejections. Instead, she was instantly
mature, prolific, and publishable. Her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> submission to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> was returned with a friendly letter, but on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> try she got
in. Since then she's published <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 100</NUMEX> stories there, more than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> so
far.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arithmetic</ENAMEX> is the measure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallant</ENAMEX> must be the quintessential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four decades</TIMEX>, up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>--when the magazine
changed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and began to emphasize the news--her quiet professionalism, her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wry</ENAMEX>, mildly gloomy sensibility, and her knack for perfect detail were a
near-perfect fit. This last gift of observation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallant</ENAMEX> explains in the
introduction to her huge new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Collected Stories</ENAMEX> , dates back to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">bifurcated</ENAMEX> childhood:

            

               One's beginnings are regional. Mine are wholly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protestant</ENAMEX>, yes, but with a strong current of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>. My young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> sent me off on that current by placing me in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent school</ENAMEX>,
for reasons never made plain. I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I give
up." It was a singular thing to do and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> unheard of. It left me
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> systems of behavior, divided by syntax and tradition; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> environments
to consider, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> becalmed in a long twilight of nineteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">religiosity</ENAMEX>;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> codes of social behavior; much practical experience of the difference
between a rule and a moral point.
            

            Here is the split mind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>, raised in
this hemisphere with excessive propriety and then thrust, unprotected, into old
and indecipherable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> traditions. Note the characteristically airtight
yet elliptical prose, the world-weary delicacy that records "the difference
between a rule and a moral point" but commits neither to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> nor the other.

            Later,
living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallant</ENAMEX> took up the Jamesian theme of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX> abroad, though
she sometimes sketched her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expatriates</ENAMEX> with the quicker, more economical
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX>. Yet she arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, a time of drab
poverty and rubble, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one century</TIMEX> after rich New World <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> made their first
bewildering return trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> long shock-filled war after the jazz
age and its tremors. To that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallant</ENAMEX> brought a new bemused realism and
an acquaintance with such petty facts as train schedules and plumbing. She
became a deromanticizer, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adjuster</ENAMEX> of expectations. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Gallant character</ENAMEX> who
cultivates decadent aristocratic airs or tries too hard to hold on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">freshness</ENAMEX> is at best a self-punishing neurotic, at worst a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>.

            
As if to emphasize the documentary nature of
these pieces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallant</ENAMEX> has arranged them chronologically in her collection, by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s through the '90s</TIMEX>. The stories weren't necessarily written
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> they're filed under: The opening work, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moslem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wife</ENAMEX>," about
Netta, a strangely sheltered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Englishwoman</ENAMEX> who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern France</ENAMEX> with her
callow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>, evokes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vichy</ENAMEX> period but was written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netta</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> run a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> is a philanderer and eventually leaves, and
Gallant traces them through separation and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and a pragmatic
last-minute reconciliation--"the same voyage, at the same speed" as the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> around in their disastrous affair--in a bus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallant</ENAMEX>'s
stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--and these include a few tales of trusting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> let
down by untrustworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--follow a basic pattern: Someone (possessing a
naivet√© perhaps reminiscent of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27-year-old</TIMEX> who ran off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> to write)
offers someone else his or her love and is let down, but still manages to get
up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next several decades</TIMEX>. These stories are the tightest
and the best designed, and they yield her most memorable lines, dark, ironic
compressions of incompatible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worldviews</ENAMEX>. Netta, for instance, "took it for
granted, now she was married, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> felt as she did about light, dark,
death, and love," and from that we understand that separation is inevitable. Or
take this moment from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Between Zero and One":</ENAMEX>

            
               When
I was young I thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had small lives of their own creation. I could
not see why, born enfranchised, without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> and constraints attendant
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, they set such close limits for themselves and why, once the limits
had been reached, they seemed so taken aback.
            

            Elsewhere, the wandering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> predominates, and the
stories gain weight in the quest for clinical accuracy. Besides the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> in
the south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, we get lifestyle portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanians</ENAMEX> scraping by on
fake passports in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> slumming in dirty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>
returned from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison camp</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>; in the later stories, we meet <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX>
coping with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> strays. Often, Gallant keeps the plot to a minimum, merely
visiting her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> several times over a span of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The young grow up,
and we learn about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> exams and then the petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hierarchies</ENAMEX> in the
civil service. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> are defined by their memory of past events. From the
opening to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Plain Sight":</ENAMEX>

            
               On
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>, sharp at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>, an air-raid siren wails
across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, startling pigeons and lending an edge to the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> news. Older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parisians</ENAMEX> say it has the tone and pitch of a newsreel sound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>. They think,
Before the war, and remember things in black-and-white. Some wonder how old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and if he really did escape to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. Others say
an order to test warning equipment was given in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, at the time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suez</ENAMEX>
crisis, and never taken off the books.
            

            This passage could easily belong to a piece of
nonfiction--to one of the witty old "Letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>" that used to run in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> . And in fact, in the best of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> studies, a
vivid picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>--infected with mediocre rhetoric, imprisoned
by fake boundaries, inhabited by numb and ambivalent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--begins to take
shape. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> give way to the shabby backdrops of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Le Carr√</ENAMEX>©'s
novels. Yet, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Carr√©</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallant</ENAMEX> does not believe in plot, or in
speculating on the meaning of her stories. Character is everything; facts make
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallant</ENAMEX> sometimes achieves the same high notes that great reporting
does, her less-successful stories resemble the more meandering old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker human</ENAMEX>-interest profiles, in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s fleeting thoughts,
neurotic habits, and random memories are woven into a pattering portrait.
Consider the opening to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End of the World</ENAMEX>," which introduces an angry son
who, as the story goes on, will be called to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> to care for a selfish dying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>:

            
               I never like to leave
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, because I'm disappointed every time. I've felt disappointed about
places I haven't even seen. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> once. When
they arrived there, they met some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> who told them about a
sign saying NO <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CANADIANS</ENAMEX>. They never saw this sign anywhere, but they kept
hearing about others who did, or whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> had seen it, always in different
places, and it spoiled their trip for them. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, like them, have never
come across it but have heard about it, so it must be there somewhere. Another
time I had to go and look after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>.
            

            There's a healthy faith in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX> in this kind of story, and a democratic interest in human nature.
But there's also a cool complacency, an indifferent shrug. By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallant</ENAMEX>'s own
admission in the introduction, she composes with an eye to craft, not the
deeper heart of a story. Each local ironic effect has to be placed precisely;
each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> name has to be gotten right the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. "I could not move on to
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> sentence until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence sounded true," she writes somewhat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diffidently</ENAMEX>. "True to what? Some arrangement in my head, I suppose. ... The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> flash of fiction arrives without words. It consists of a fixed image,
like a slide or (closer still) a freeze frame. ... Whole scenes then follow,
complete in themselves but like disconnected parts of the film." But a film and
a slide show are not the same thing as fully imagined fiction. These stories
make up a time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capsule</ENAMEX> assembled by a skilled social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, a rich gallery
of plausible lives. They are well observed, well written, and remote, and no
more than a handful, if that, will last.

         
      
   
