
   
   
      
         
            Bathroom Beauty

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX> has buried its <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Bonnard</ENAMEX> retrospective in windowless
basement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>. The puzzling decision to relegate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> of
sun-drenched tablecloths and rainbow gardens to the underground makes some
sense given the direction and drift of the show, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> MoMA retrospective
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s work since his death just shy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 80</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Elderfield</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> in charge, has banished some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s most popular and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beguiling</ENAMEX> works--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proven√</ENAMEX>ßal landscapes with red-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, windows looking
out from laden breakfast tables, flowering <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>--to the periphery of the show.
He asks us to focus our attention instead on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major clusters of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s
work: bathroom scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marthe</ENAMEX>, undressing, primping, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">toweling</ENAMEX> herself off; scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marthe</ENAMEX> submerged full-length in a bathtub; and
self-portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX> peering at himself in the bathroom mirror. You could
call the show, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingmar Bergman</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scenes From a Marriage</ENAMEX>," since Bonnard
includes his very clean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 384</NUMEX> paintings. Then again, you could call
it, with equal justice, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scenes From a Bathroom</ENAMEX>."

            Elderfield
thinks these bathroom pictures raise most insistently the problems of
perception--peripheral vision, scanning rhythms, and so on--that for him are at
the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s art. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elderfield</ENAMEX>'s ponderous and mechanistic catalog
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> is filled with such insights as the following: "While the global rhythms
have a pulsatile aspect owing to the regular bounce provided by the edge, which
rebounds the gaze, the chasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rhythms</ENAMEX> have a more spasmodic aspect owing to
the more extended and irregular scanpaths they follow." (If you're hungry for
more, the show's Web site adds explanatory diagrams.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX> is indeed a
visually complex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, whose constant experimenting with peculiar
compositional schemes--especially his habit of concealing figures on the
margins of his paintings--requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> and prolonged viewing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s
paintings grab you by the throat; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s paintings dawn on you. But all
these "adventures of the optic nerve," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX> calls them, were means,
not--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elderfield</ENAMEX> believes--ends. We're not taking a course in optics in these
paintings; we're looking at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, and a mighty strange <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Degas and √âdouard Manet</ENAMEX> in the previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1867-1947</TIMEX>) was born into the high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bourgeoisie</ENAMEX> (his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> served in the upper echelons of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">War Ministry</ENAMEX>), and
like those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> he had a taste for the demimonde. He attended the posh
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lyc√©e Louis-le-Grand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Degas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>, and like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Degas</ENAMEX> seemed destined for a
law career. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> nearly simultaneous events sealed his fate. He flunked the
civil service exam and won a contest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1889</TIMEX> to design a poster for a champagne
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. In his winning design, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> tips a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne glass</ENAMEX> forward, and the
cascading foam obscures pretty much everything but her cleavage.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s
early influences were the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gauguin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> prints, both of
which confirmed his interest in bold colors and strongly delineated design. He
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prophets</ENAMEX>"), a loose-knit brotherhood of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> who worshiped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gauguin</ENAMEX> and, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX> later recalled, "envisaged a
popular art that was of everyday application." The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> exhibition, composed
entirely of oil paintings, ignores <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s dazzling drawings, lithographs,
decorated screens, book illustrations, set designs (for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Jarry</ENAMEX>'s Ubu
Roi , for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Nijinsky ballets</NUMEX>), puppets, and masks, thus obscuring both the
breadth and the nature of his career. The decorative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> called (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916-20</TIMEX>)
gives a taste of this improvisatory and populist side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s work, with
its hidden <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>--a peacock and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>, for example, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> above the
strangely modern-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX> was first making a name for
himself as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, his effervescent brilliance in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> medium spilled (like
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>) into others. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">salmon</ENAMEX>-pink illustrations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Verlaine</ENAMEX>'s
soft-porn poems ("I want you almost nude, not nude ... through a cloud/ of lace
the glimpse of/ your flesh, which my delirious mouth/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> across") became the
basis for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> of paintings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> in black stockings. Perhaps to give
such pictures a classical sanction, he often borrowed the poses from well-known
antique sculptures. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>) is based on the marble <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermaphrodite</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louvre</ENAMEX>. Such erudite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allusion</ENAMEX> could also add to the kinky mixing of high and
low, as when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX> put high heels on a model posed as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Medici Venus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Fischl</ENAMEX> (as reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Hyman</ENAMEX>'s
excellent new study of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>) has identified the partially concealed hands of
Bonnard jutting into this painting, offering up a red-stained (sanitary?) cloth
to the yellow nude.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX> had met the high-heeled, diminutive model for many
of these paintings of nudes around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>. She introduced herself as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marthe de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M√©lingy</ENAMEX>--the sort of mock-noble name that demimondaines such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proust</ENAMEX>'s Odette
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">de Cr√©cy</ENAMEX> liked to assume--and claimed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>. Her real name was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Boursin</ENAMEX>, and she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX> didn't find out these details
until, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proust</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swann</ENAMEX>, he married her. The marriage, kept secret from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, was the result of a traumatic development in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s life.
He had had affairs with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> before, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years earlier</TIMEX> he had
fallen in love with a statuesque blonde--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> physically the opposite of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marthe</ENAMEX>--called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ren√©e Monchat</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chaty</ENAMEX>" to her intimates). In several paintings,
including (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--in this case the brunette leaning over the table
to the right and the peripheral blonde to the extreme left--seem to vie for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">viewer</ENAMEX>'s attention. (The optical mechanisms arising from such tensions between
central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> and partially hidden peripheral figures are a major subject of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elderfield</ENAMEX>'s essay.)

            Bonnard
found himself unable to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marthe</ENAMEX>, his lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ren√©e</ENAMEX> killed
herself in despair. By some reports she shot herself; others, perhaps
influenced by the obsession of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s late paintings, say she drowned
herself in her bathtub. In any case, it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> of his marriage,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX> first painted his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> full-length in the bathtub, where she
retreated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> at a time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. The usual line is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marthe</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paranoid</ENAMEX> and neurotic, had a mania for cleanliness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Whitfield</ENAMEX> (who
installed the show for its previous run at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London's Tate Gallery</ENAMEX>), while not
denying the compulsive nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marthe</ENAMEX>'s bathing, has suggested that
hydropathy was a popular treatment for such ailments as tubercular laryngitis,
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marthe</ENAMEX> suffered from and eventually, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>, died of. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> late
paintings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marthe</ENAMEX> in the bath--considered by many to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s crowning
achievements--are on view at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX>. They have a jeweled, hallucinatory quality.
The modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> with its linoleum floor, ceramic tile, and enameled tub--as
banal a setting as one could imagine--is transformed in these late masterpieces
into a world as rich and exotic as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tutankhamen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> (, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marthe</ENAMEX> looks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embalmed</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX>, her features dissolving before our eyes.

            In some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marthe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX> marks his
own voyeuristic presence at the margins--a knee jutting into the canvas here, a
hazy profile there. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MoMA</ENAMEX>'s beautiful of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>, the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> keeping vigil
seems like a stand-in for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>. An alarm clock on the washstand is set
forever at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 o'clock</TIMEX> as though to mark this epiphany, when the white light
struck the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s breast just so. Then, in the enigmatic self-portraits
grouped in the final <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> show, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX> is suddenly fully there,
though back-lit and shadowed in the bathroom mirror. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the very late
self-portraits have the wartime blackout curtains pulled aside, as though
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX> is exposed in more ways than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>), though, is surely the
strangest of the self-portraits. Almost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chaplinesque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX> as depicted here
looks like the very last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> you'd bet on. His face looks bruised and
battered, and his small, sunken eyes show the marks where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glasses</ENAMEX> were just
removed. But he holds up his hands gamely, as though to say that with these
hands, bloodied and unprotected, he painted some of the most extraordinary
paintings of his quickly ending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>.

             

         
      
   
