
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fat Man Sings</ENAMEX>

            
It's a pity that eating disorders have been
pasted over with banal notions such as "body image" and "self-esteem," and
unappetizing medical terms such as "morbidly obese," because obsession with
food is by no means a dull subject. How much could be said that has nothing to
do with olestra or the bad example set by supermodels about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> absorbed
in strange, hostile negotiations with her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>! There is no end to the
mental, or at least non-nutritive, uses to which <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> can be put; and no end to
the rituals surrounding that perverse form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> auto-eroticism known as a
meal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">EAT FAT</ENAMEX> tries to reclaim one aspect of eating--getting fat and
feeling bad about it--from the boring debates about health and fashion in which
it's usually stuck. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EAT FAT</ENAMEX> is a "postmodern diet book," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> puts
it (employing a rather eccentric definition of postmodern, which seems roughly
to amount to "counterintuitive"): an encomium to corpulence and an excoriation
of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> that encourage you to be skinny. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>'s goal is to
transform an uncontrolled and miserable hatred of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX> (his and yours) into a
flabophilic delight that, by robbing fat of its malevolent power, will lead to
becoming thin. His idea is that you can dissipate an obsession by
aestheticizing its object and embracing your urge to indulge in it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deconstructive</ENAMEX> variety, has done this kind of thing before: A couple of years
ago he wrote a book (his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cigarettes Are Sublime</ENAMEX> ) in praise of
smoking, in order to stop. It worked then, and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>--who, as we discover,
is on the chubby side--is doing it again. But while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> who wrote
Cigarettes had succeeded in mastering his obsession (by the time he'd
finished the book he'd quit smoking), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAT Klein</ENAMEX> is still in the process
of recovering from the throes of diet. Consequently, he has written an
extremely strange book: In reading it, you are subjected to changes in
personality as abrupt and jarring as nasty little electric shocks administered
to the base of your spine.

            You'll be
floating contentedly along in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>'s pleasant, foamy prose--"the gorgeous
display of her colossal adiposity, her thundering, moonfaced, creviced
posterior, evokes a vastly delicious, (sub)lunar landscape in which an explorer
could lose himself in pleasure forever. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> blessed fat!"--when all of a sudden,
Dzzzzz! "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> and authority come together to serve each other, to make money
and murder fat." The writing gets bubbly for a bit--"the profusion of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">décolleté</ENAMEX>, flesh billowing up and cascading down over and out of their
dresses"--and then, Dzzzzz! "Evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> foist new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> on desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> die of starvation, and the rest, sooner or later, get fat."

            
There are, you are forced to conclude, not one
but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Kleins</ENAMEX> lurking in this book. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Klein</ENAMEX> No. 1 is an urbane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> who delights in a clever, lyrical celebration of creamy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fleshiness</ENAMEX>. His
evil twin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Klein</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, is hurt and angry at the system for making him
feel bad about himself all his life and perpetuating evil, unattainable images
of thinness to get him addicted to its demonic diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and make him sick and
miserable; plus it's not just him but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
who are falling victim to the greedy maw of the medical-industrial
conspiracy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Klein</ENAMEX> No. 1 has
written an elegant, seductive book that sets you to musing how nice it might be
to put on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 or 90 pounds</NUMEX> to feel that sensual, private, fatty softness all
over. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klein No. 1</ENAMEX> can tell any number of amusing fat-related anecdotes. Did you
know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX> used to dance every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> to keep his weight down? That
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Théophile Gautier</ENAMEX> declared he could
not, in his youth, "have accepted as a lyric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> anyone weighing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 99</NUMEX>
pounds"?

            Best of
all: fat <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX>! Citing an essay by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Keyes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> quotes lines from
the play (e.g. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Gertrude</ENAMEX>, about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>: "He is fat and scant of breath.")
that suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX>'s indecision may be due more to the lymphatic
temperament of a pudgy little porker (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ham</ENAMEX>-let, get it?) than to heroic
paralysis. The interpretation certainly makes the play funnier. Is not this
line of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet's</ENAMEX>, for example, lent a certain zing when read as a diet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fantasy</ENAMEX>?: "Oh, that this too too solid flesh would melt,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/ Thaw</ENAMEX>, and resolve
itself into a dew!"

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Klein</ENAMEX> No. 2 delivers snoozy tirades against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beauty Myth</ENAMEX>, "designed to oppress and exploit us all ... invented,
manufactured, sustained, and promoted by a vast industrial, ideological system,
in order to obscure the reality of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>." (Why is it, one wonders, that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beauty Myth</ENAMEX> is oppressive, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Superbly Rendered Sonata Myth</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brilliant But Also Commercially Successful Book Myth</ENAMEX> is not?) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klein No. 2</ENAMEX>
throws around the silly word "vast" in order to convey a sense of imminent diet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apocalypse</ENAMEX> (as in, "vast unknown consequences," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of these drugs
on a vast scale"). And he displays a certain naïveté about scientific standards
--asking, for instance, about a diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>: "What perfect assurance can the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
give that the dex effect won't be the same on human brains? Why take chances on
a massive scale with human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neurons</ENAMEX>, until proof of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dex</ENAMEX>'s safety can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unambiguously</ENAMEX> established<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" (How does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> propose to establish a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>'s
safety with perfect assurance? Surely "safety" is the product of an ad
hoc cost-benefit analysis, rather than some kind of empirical property that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> does or doesn't have.) In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Klein</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> quenches our pleasure
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Klein</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in much the same way that the health and beauty
industries are supposedly determined to quench our pleasure in fat.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>,
being a post-structuralist, is fascinated by the materiality of signs--that is,
in this case, by the way words look and sound, as opposed to what they mean.
This fascination crops up in the book in a number of ways, which will seem
thought-provoking or irritating, depending on taste. The book is liberally
seasoned with wordplay and typographical experiments (the words "eat fat" are
always in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX>, with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FAT</ENAMEX>" printed directly under "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EAT</ENAMEX>," so you can see how
similar the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words are) and rhymes ("why this should be so at this moment in
history is a mystery. A mystery of history."). The book's first sentence is:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SKIP THIS PREFACE</ENAMEX>!"

            
The most pervasive sign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>'s brand of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> post-structuralism, though, are his narrow ideas about pleasure and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>, control is always bad--whether it's the evil
health-and-fashion industry dictating our ideas about beauty, or the
beleaguered dieter struggling to curb his cravings in a spirit of misguided
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-hatred</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> has a horror of what he rather predictably perceives to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Puritan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> attempting to eliminate bad-for-you indulgences
such as fat or cigarettes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pleasure</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>, is the opposite of control:
It's all about gratification and excess.

            But there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of
pleasure: the pleasure of doing, and the pleasure of not doing; the pleasure of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indulging</ENAMEX>, and the pleasure of abstinence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> can be fun. And it is a
rather uninteresting, one-sided kind of hedonism that fails to take this into
account. If only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> weren't so categorically <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">averse</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> health
culture, he might allow that a little self-imposed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Puritanism</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX>--a
little punishing exercise here, a little culinary deprivation there--can be a
sensual pleasure too, albeit of a different sort.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cigarettes</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>'s mascot was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baudelairean</ENAMEX> dandy--that rare figure for whom the
cultivation of personal elegance is more important than health (and who is,
therefore, a model for the unrepentant smoker). So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>, of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, should
appreciate the stricter kinds of pleasures. Because while the dandy stands for
beauty and elegance, he also stands for the restraint and self-discipline
required to appear refined at all times. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baudelaire</ENAMEX> put it in his essay "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Painter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Life</ENAMEX>": "All the complicated material conditions to which
[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dandies</ENAMEX>] submit, from an impeccable toilette at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every hour</TIMEX> ... to the most
perilous feats of the sporting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>, are no more than a system of gymnastics
designed to ... discipline the soul. ... The strictest monastic rule ... [was]
no more despotic."

            You would think that
cultivating a taste for such ascetic modes of enjoyment would be at least as
effective a diet strategy as glorifying blubber, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> fails to entertain
this possibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, all he writes about, all he thinks about, all he wants
to do, is give in to fat.

         
      
   
