
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State of Mind</ENAMEX>

             

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every summer</TIMEX> there is an
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> when the wind has scrubbed the sky over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> to a blue
translucency, and the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> looks as though it has just finished an
extremely satisfying game of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> (winning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>), taken a long
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shower</ENAMEX>, and is now sitting on a shady porch with a tall glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mint</ENAMEX> iced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>
in its hand and absolutely nothing on its mind. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that afternoon</TIMEX>
turned up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>. It was not an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> you wanted to spend in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX>. But having lived for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, with little prospect of
escape, I decided, on a perfect day for bananafish, to go up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX>, to visit a show called NYNY: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambition</ENAMEX> and find out what this place is all about.

            Tall
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, is the answer. Also: dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>' hats. The show,
which is curated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth Sussman</ENAMEX>, has on display paintings and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>'
models and comic strips and film clips and photographs and a few items of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothing, all made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> in and of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900 and 1960</TIMEX>. There are photographs by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Stieglitz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul Strand</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin Langdon Coburn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Bourke-White</ENAMEX>, paintings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Hopper</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>, scale models of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rockefeller Center</ENAMEX> (which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumford</ENAMEX> originally hated) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Building</ENAMEX> (which everybody originally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hated</ENAMEX>), drawings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reginald Marsh</ENAMEX>, comic strips by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Eisner</ENAMEX>, and a bolero
jacket by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles James</ENAMEX>. If you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and have lived here long enough,
you'll have seen most of this stuff already, but you'll like this show anyway.
I liked the show anyway.

            The photographs steal it. A lot of the power of the
paintings to compel astonishment or pathos has leaked away: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Weber</ENAMEX>'s fantasy
painting of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> department store (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>), once an icon of modernity, now
seems quaint. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> no longer exactly leads the world in big department
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>; big department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are the sort of thing you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> for.
But the photographs, especially the photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coburn</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Flat-Iron Building</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stieglitz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer Building</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bourke-White</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>
Building--are as grand as ever. Those early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> must not have
believed their luck at finding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of brick and steel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> jammed
together for them on a little island, with new ones blasting up out of the
ground like constructivist <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. The compositional possibilities
must have seemed endless, every change in the light disclosing a fresh set of
visual effects waiting to be captured. It was better than a haystack. They knew
what they had, and they took advantage of it.

            The dead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> are a more specialized taste. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> has plunged rather deeply
into the oeuvre of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Fellig</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weegee</ENAMEX>) for this show. He's
represented not just by his homicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> and his famous shot of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Critic</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> grande dames in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> dress stepping out from their limo as a
bag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> appraises their fashion sense), but by a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-minute</TIMEX> film, called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weegee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>), as well. The film--a long series of crotch
shots on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coney Island</ENAMEX>, followed by a long segment of drunks at a cocktail
party--gives the game away a little. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weegee</ENAMEX> didn't seek out the underside; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underside</ENAMEX> was all he saw. He is one of the great chroniclers of midcentury
luridness, but his photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> grinning at a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX>
are like those photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> milling around after a lynching: They
are undeniably riveting, but you don't really want to stop to think about what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> was doing there in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            
The greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> street
life, I think, is probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Klein</ENAMEX>, whose collection titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Is</ENAMEX>
Good & Good for You in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , first published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> and
long out of print, has just been reissued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dewi Lewis Publishers</ENAMEX> under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954-55</TIMEX> . I have never seen the original edition; the new
one is said to have been completely redesigned and to include many more
photographs. Several are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> show.

            The
formal trick in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>'s pictures is the multiplication of focal points. There
is almost never a single subject in the frame, and as soon as the eye picks out
a face or an object as the thematic center of the composition, another face, or
another object, suddenly displaces it, and the center moves off someplace else.
The key to the effect is that the various "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>" are nearly always
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incongruous</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> with the pompadour staring with a smile of lighthearted
menace straight at the camera is in a different visual world from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demurely</ENAMEX> checked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">kerchief</ENAMEX> with her eyes somewhere else and her mind on
lunch.

            Most of us look at a midtown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> and see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>, there is no such thing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. There are only a lot of faces, all
inscrutable, but differently inscrutable. His pictures are advent calendars on
which none of the doors will open. It's the kind of instant de-homogenizing
sensation you sometimes get in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, when you suddenly awaken to the fact
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the dozen</NUMEX> faces you've been staring vacantly at across the aisle from you
belong to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> different moral universes--not just in the trivial sense that
we all see the world differently, but in the distinctly nontrivial sense that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sitting right next to each other really can have nothing in common--and
that you'll never know a single <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Sometimes this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> is moving, and
sometimes it's just creepy. But it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> sensation.

            When you find yourself
reflecting on the phenomenology of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, you have had enough art for the
day. Outside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> had all gone home, but there was still a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> sky, and
an empty iced-tea <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> was sitting on the porch. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> seemed like the
least ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the world.

             

         
      
   
