
   
   
      
         
            Inside Out

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About 25 years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Burden</ENAMEX> arranged to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> shoot him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX>. He
also crawled over broken glass and was briefly crucified on top of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen</ENAMEX>
Bug. Works like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot</ENAMEX>" made Burden famous within art circles, after a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guinness Book of World Records</ENAMEX> fashion. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burden</ENAMEX>'s masochistic
performance art had something in common with more mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s and 1970s</TIMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop</ENAMEX> and minimalism, it was provocatively easy to
make. Aside from the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> spent documenting such feats, and recovering from
them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burden</ENAMEX>'s art didn't occupy much of his time.

            At this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitney Biennial</ENAMEX>, the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">roundup</ENAMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burden</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pizza City</ENAMEX>" is one of the highlights of the show. There are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> or glass
shards here, however; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burden</ENAMEX> has abandoned drama for a childlike laboriousness.
Composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of miniature parts, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pizza City</ENAMEX>" is a scale model of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sprawling</ENAMEX>, whimsical metropolis, laid out on table tops--a model train set
minus the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX>. Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> actually come
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>-set <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. The other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> are miscellaneous: plumbing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fixtures</ENAMEX>, kitchen appliances, yard-sale leftovers, all ingeniously recycled to
become skyscrapers, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeways</ENAMEX>. The result is likable, but not much
more. It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s toy, albeit one that an established <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> devoted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of his life to making.

            Such cottage industriousness is the ruling spirit of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 Biennial</TIMEX>. At its best, it translates into a kind of stoop-sale liveliness.
There's lots to look at; most of it has an introverted, made-from-scratch
intensity. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ashkin</ENAMEX> does scale models, though his are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">solemn</ENAMEX>, not whimsical: stretches of miniature Western highway so realistic that
photographs of them are indistinguishable from photos of real <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashkin</ENAMEX>'s fastidiousness pales beside that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Ray</ENAMEX>. For a film project
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Self Portrait</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homemade Clothes</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> learned how to sew his own
clothing and grind his own eyeglasses, then traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> to learn to
make a watch from scratch. Obsession is the name of the game. Devote three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to a project, and you're a hobbyist. Devote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>, and you're in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biennial</ENAMEX>.

            Obsession
has always been a buzzword in the art world, a less corny, more
secular-sounding synonym for "inspiration." But suddenly it's a word that art
is measured against. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obsession</ENAMEX>, after all, is what connects increasingly
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider artists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Darger</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> who painted and wrote a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX>-page fantasy about little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> with penises, to insider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> such as
Burden, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ashkin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darger</ENAMEX> isn't in this exhibition, but his work ethic
is. In the catalog essay, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Philips</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Neri</ENAMEX> give a nod to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider-outsider</ENAMEX> connection, but they dismiss it as a fluke of economic
history--they claim that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s weak market, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> have more time on
their hands. This is ridiculous. For most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, fewer sales means
less time to work, more time spent paying the rent. The explanation for
the ethos of laboriousness strikes me as much simpler--it serves as proof of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s personal commitment. Even the worst work demands from you the
admission that at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> are authentic. They've put in too much
sweat equity to be bluffing.

            
Of course, getting shot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> is about as
far as you can go in the "I'm not bluffing" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, which may be why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">curators</ENAMEX> call Burden one of the two role models for the mostly younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Biennial</TIMEX>. (The other is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vija Celmins</ENAMEX>, who paints numbing, meticulous
copies of nature photographs.) But the real role model here is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel Duchamp</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchamp</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bride Stripped Bare by Her Bachelors</ENAMEX>, Even," familiarly known as
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Large Glass</ENAMEX>," is the granddaddy of this kind of hands-on conceptualist
art. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchamp</ENAMEX> worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 12 years</TIMEX> on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Large Glass</ENAMEX>," devising pet
names for its idiosyncratic imagery and writing detailed, incomprehensible
notes. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Tomkins</ENAMEX>, an ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duchampian</ENAMEX>, calls them "magisterially
unclear.") As anyone who has ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> to see it knows, the
result isn't particularly engaging. By the time he made it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duchamp</ENAMEX> was opposed
to visual art as such. He disparaged painting as "retinal stupidity."

            Many of
the works on display here could be seen as personal variations on the "Large
Glass." They vary enormously in appearance, since appearances are not
necessarily important. They can be big and messy, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Rhoades</ENAMEX>'
factory-floor<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">-style installation</ENAMEX>, or small and neat, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Conner</ENAMEX>'s
inkblot drawings. The only visual quality they have in common is a dogged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intricacy</ENAMEX>. This intricacy isn't just unlike minimalism; it is its ideological
opposite. Minimalist art was simple, serious, and totally public. It sat on the
wall and left us to make up our own minds about what it was all about.
Obsessivism drags us into its space, though we remain voyeurs. Minimalism
enforced a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>-faced code of silence. Obsessivism chatters to itself in a
bizarre idiolect. Both, however, leave us out in the cold.

            For me, the low point of the show--and of obsessivism in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>--is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette Lawrence</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX>" series. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> draws large spirals
composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of calendar dates ("<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12/2/95</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12/7/95</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/1/96</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/5/96</NUMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>), arranged, we're told, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mayan</ENAMEX> counting system. Once, work
like this might have at least had a polemical feminist edge. Now it just comes
across as a new form of navel-gazing. It's menstrual narcissism.

            In his
most recent book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Danto</ENAMEX> claims that this bleak retreat into
the fortress of the self is a permanent one. Art history has flickered out, he
says, and though art will continue to be made, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> will follow his or
her bliss, without any larger motive or connective scheme. It's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pizza City</ENAMEX>"
forever. Walking around this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biennial</ENAMEX>, which happens to be the last of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, I had the glum feeling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danto</ENAMEX> was right.

            
On the other hand, millennial melancholia has a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of being wrong. There are reasons to be optimistic about the future of art,
even at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kara Walker</ENAMEX>, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> who makes narrative murals in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>-style silhouette technique. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX>'s works are a sort of lewd fantasia
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old South</ENAMEX>, full of sex, cannibalism, chivalry, folklore, and humor.
It isn't always easy to figure out what she is talking about. Her stories, too,
can seem hermetic, like pictures from a private universe. But most of the time,
her cutouts are generously imaginative and outward-directed, connecting viewers
to their shared national past. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> makes History painting, that musty
patriarchal fossil, seem like the most seditious and vital new idea of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
