
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love Bomb</ENAMEX>

            
               (Part 2
of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part article. For Part <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1,</ENAMEX> click here. )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claus Schenk Graf von</ENAMEX>
Stauffenberg, who set off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> that nearly killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>, was one of the most spectacularly odd figures to flash across the world
stage. Under his military exterior he was a pure aesthete, a devotee of
esoteric literature and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">musty medieval romanticism</ENAMEX>, a kind of tactical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">symbolist</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> amounts to nothing more than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">myth</ENAMEX>, as the books I reviewed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> suggested, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX> was aiming at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">myth</ENAMEX> and nothing less. He knew by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1944</TIMEX> that his conspiracy had little
chance of success, but he drove ahead regardless. He was determined to commit
an act that might start a rumor of residual goodness in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. Even more, he
wanted to save the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> myths from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s corrupting touch. It was an
unreal, crazy, but terribly earnest mission.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffmann</ENAMEX> has written good general histories of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>, but his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX> takes a new tack. Decades of exhaustive research are
telescoped into a swift biographical narrative, at times matter-of-fact and at
times unexpectedly passionate. It is the first book to do justice to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strangeness of Stauffenberg</ENAMEX>'s world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had lived in the southwest
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swabia</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, and believed itself to be descended
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hohenstaufen</ENAMEX> dynasty, whose lineage included the Holy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> emperors
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Barbarossa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX> II. More recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had served the
eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bavaria</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claus</ENAMEX>' older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berthold</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, were
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">twins; Claus</ENAMEX>, too, had a twin, who died in infancy. "For a time he often
brought his mother <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s grave," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffmann</ENAMEX> writes in one of
his surprising sentimental touches. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Countess Stauffenberg</ENAMEX> moved in various
artistic circles, befriending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainer Maria Rilke</ENAMEX>, among others; it was through
her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> met the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stefan George</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, who lived from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868 to 1933</TIMEX>, is ranked high among
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> lyric poets for his elegant Symbolist visions. The teen-age Stauffenberg
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brothers</ENAMEX> were the most ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> of his last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> took them
in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all because he liked to have handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> around him.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eyebrow</ENAMEX>-raising photographs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hoffmann</ENAMEX>'s book show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> posing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in medieval costumes.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> was also fascinated by the Stauffenberg
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lineage</ENAMEX>, particularly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hohenstaufen</ENAMEX> connection. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick II</ENAMEX>, the
alternately splendid and frightening <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">th century monarch</ENAMEX> who earned
the nickname stupor mundi , was, for him, the model of an enlightened
authoritarian. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> lingered in modern times as a "secret
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers providentially</ENAMEX> appeared as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of boy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princes</ENAMEX> who could take command. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claus</ENAMEX> was told that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> himself may
have awakened in him, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> of sleep beneath a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Swabian</ENAMEX> mountain.

            All this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smacks of Hitlerism</ENAMEX>, of course. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> did share <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s contempt for
democracy and devotion to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> myth. He also bandied about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phrases</ENAMEX>, despite the constant presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in his circle. But his worldview
departed from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s in several respects. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, he was steeped in foreign
influences. He translated <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> poetry, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
Symbolists his principal poetic model. His love of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Romance</ENAMEX> languages
incited a highly subversive orthographic innovation: the elimination of capital
letters on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> nouns. And, for all his elitism and secretiveness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> had
a most un-Hitlerlike strain of gentleness. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX> (and like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Mann</ENAMEX> in
his conservative phase), he saw authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> ushering in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of
"ardor and love."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> died too soon for his real attitude
toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> to become clear. (As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffmann</ENAMEX> notes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> would later
spend much energy trying to expunge tentatively pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> remarks from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> oeuvre .) Stauffenberg, following the lead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>, showed
vague enthusiasm toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazism</ENAMEX> early on. While training for a career as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1920s</TIMEX>, he displayed fashionable contempt for the Weimar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>, he posed for a model of a massive storm-trooper monument
sculpted by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Mehnert</ENAMEX>, also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> disciple. He refused,
however, to don a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> uniform, and struck an attitude that was deemed
insufficiently fascist by the monument <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. He criticized the vulgarity
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> but never exhibited any deeper opposition to its ideals.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffmann</ENAMEX> writes that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> expressed surprise after the coup attempt
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>: "Many had thought of him as the only real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Socialist</ENAMEX> in the
family."

            What
caused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX> to turn so suddenly against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943 and 1944</TIMEX>?
Standard theories about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and their disillusionment with the
regime seem inadequate. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>'s secret "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," Stauffenberg
went only so far in his devotion to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>; he was not acting simply to
save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s murderous ineptitude. Perhaps what enticed
him was a sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George's</ENAMEX> ideals could flower in the ruins of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, and that he himself might become the prophesied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>. Stauffenberg
was a shadow-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> in some ways: His youthful love of architecture, music, and
stage design coincides precisely with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s cherished dreams. In a school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX> wrote of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Speer</ENAMEX>-like architectural ambitions: "Every
building will, so to speak, represent a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> dedicated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>
and fatherland." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> noted in him "a streak of demonic will to power
and a belief that he was born to take charge."

            Weighing against these authoritarian traits are
descriptions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s essential sensitivity to others. His military career
shows him repeatedly choosing human values over material gains. His specialty
lay in the supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> on the front and, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> invasion unfolded,
he grew horrified by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s willingness to cut off entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whim</ENAMEX>. He was also angered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. At a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavs</ENAMEX> were being massacred by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, he engaged in an
ideologically incorrect effort to assemble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> and
give them equal status with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>. When his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> was pinned down by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fighter-</ENAMEX>bomber attack in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>, he sustained incredible wounds--the
loss of an eye, a hand, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more fingers--directing the evacuation.

            More
problematically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffmann</ENAMEX> presents <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX> as one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> who
came to the defense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. According to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, the chief
conspirator repeatedly named the mass murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> on the Eastern front as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>'s ultimate crime. But the question of his real feeling toward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
is shadowed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berthold Stauffenberg</ENAMEX>'s testimony at his treason trial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>,
to the effect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> subscribed generally to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> "racial
principle" and abhorred only the violence of its application. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffmann</ENAMEX> sought
out <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolmates</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Claus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and asked if they had perceived
anti-Semitic attitudes in him. They remembered him as an unusually friendly and
generous gentile. The ambiguity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX>'s attitude toward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> can be
sensed in this inscrutable sentence from a resistance manifesto: "We want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
Order which makes all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the state and guarantees them law
and justice, but we scorn the lie of equality and we bow before the hierarchies
established by nature."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX> stormed into a small, chaotic
resistance movement and gave it at least the appearance of purpose. He set up
an intricate plan for military rebellion across the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> and took it upon
himself to bring a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s Lair" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Prussia</ENAMEX>.
Despite his injuries, he also insisted on arming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> himself. He was
interrupted by a phone call and succeeded in activating only one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
packages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>; had he left the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> package in the briefcase, it too
would have exploded, greatly increasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> and killing
everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. He brought the weakened <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s briefing room
and nudged it as close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> as he could, then left on a mumbled
excuse, drove off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>, and flew to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>. He struggled for several
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to keep the rebellion together, but innumerable weak links were revealed
in his improvised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>. Since he had probably resigned himself to
failure from the beginning, he kept up a confident exterior to the end. As he
faced a firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>, he shouted out a phrase that was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">variously</ENAMEX> reported as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX> live holy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>!" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX> live hallowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>!" ( heiliges or geheiligtes 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutschland</ENAMEX> ). One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> claims that the true message, understandably misunderstood, was
"secret <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>" ( das geheime 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutschland</ENAMEX> ).

            Conventional history can do
nothing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Count Stauffenberg</ENAMEX>--this military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aesthete</ENAMEX> who confused himself
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> and found reality in the musings of a visionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pederast</ENAMEX>. History wants movements, tendencies, collective motion; Stauffenberg
is merely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stauffenbergian</ENAMEX>. Nor is he of any use as an instructional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>--neither a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrat</ENAMEX> nor a capitalist, he gives little comfort to modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. But he did disprove, for an unimportant but magnificent moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auden</ENAMEX>'s dictum that poetry makes nothing happen.

         
      
   
