
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limousine Republican</ENAMEX>

            After years of fighting turf
battles as a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson A. Rockefeller</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> to face a far more
daunting challenge: his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. All around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Center</ENAMEX> were reminders that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller Jr.</ENAMEX> was lord and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the world's biggest fortune, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were not. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s
response to powerlessness was architectural: He transformed part of the fusty
old family <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> into a sleek "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauhaus</ENAMEX> fantasyland" for himself and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brothers</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> exclaimed
when he showed his father the redesigned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, "isn't this all
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">impressive?</ENAMEX>"

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>," said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patriarch</ENAMEX>, "whom are we trying to impress<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            Whom
indeed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Rockefeller</ENAMEX> was born into a family of such wealth, power, and
influence that it's hard to understand how he could have been so perennially
eager to please. His childhood on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s sylvan <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,500 acre</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">estate</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pocantico Hills</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, was one of almost unimaginable privilege, yet from the
beginning he felt compelled to flatter, cajole, and even engage in abject
self-criticism if that's what it took to get his way, particularly with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">puritanical</ENAMEX> and disapproving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. His efforts to insinuate himself were so
relentless that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cary Reich</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of this sprawling new biography (and of
an earlier biography of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andr√© Meyer</ENAMEX>), refers to his subject as a
"patrician <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Glick"</ENAMEX> (though he never reaches the heights of heeldom
demonstrated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budd Schulberg</ENAMEX>'s novel about pre-war <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
back-stabbing). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> never won the presidency--despite all-out campaigns
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964 and 1968</TIMEX>--but he served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX> and then
completed his public career as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. He had an enormous
impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics and the landscape of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. More than 15 years
after his death, you can still start a fight by calling someone a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>." Among other things, this book helps explain what the term actually
means.

            To admirers, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>" alludes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s
creation of an outstanding state university system, a vast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, housing projects, mental health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, water treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, it refers to a legacy of bankrupt state
government and failed social programs. What is most striking about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Life</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson A. Rockefeller</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Worlds</ENAMEX> to Conquer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908-1958</TIMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a
projected two volumes), though, is that this duality--the push to achieve wed
to a penchant for flamboyant failure; the ability to win a passionate following
yet alienate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could keep him in power--was evident well before he
thought about running for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            It was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>, after all, who single-mindedly campaigned for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
to be established in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, persuading his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> to buy and donate the East
River property for its site. During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> forged a defense
alliance among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to ward off <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> influence. He then
transformed it into an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> on the eve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. He
pushed for foreign aid and investment throughout the developing world and
helped persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> to come up with his famous <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Point Four</ENAMEX>
formulation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, which set the framework for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economic assistance
overseas. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">undersecretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education, and Welfare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
helped pioneer the idea of national health insurance. As overseer of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
propaganda, he fought for and won adoption of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX>'s "open skies" proposal
linking inspections to the cause of nuclear arms control. But in almost every
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these efforts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> either overextended himself or managed to
make so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> he ended up being ousted from power.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s generally quite readable--though
occasionally overly detailed--book, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> strands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s character
emerge, all of them reflecting the same degree of urgent vitality and,
sometimes, an edge of self-destructiveness. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the womanizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>, a persona the public only glimpsed at his death, in
flagrante with a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female staff member</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> focuses on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Braden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Hanks</ENAMEX>, and on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s empty marriage (and
separate living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>) with his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who could be seen weeping
quietly when he was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>. The stories fill in some blanks,
but not, unfortunately, in a way that explains what his philandering might
actually have been about.

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s passions was for art, especially the abstract expressionists
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. Scheming to take over an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had
helped to establish, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> oversaw every detail
of its construction and acquisitions--all by the time he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>. He brought the
same zeal to his own collections, asking <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> to weave tapestries out of his
own paintings, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Matisse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernand L√</ENAMEX>©ger to create murals for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. L√©ger actually came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and painted his mural
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. With the nonchalance of someone ordering a touch-up,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> then asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> if, while he was at it, he could stay and do
murals for the staircase and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s enthusiasm for art and sculpture,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>, was his dyslexia, which made reading treacherous. As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bureaucrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> certainly preferred big colorful charts to text in
laying out plans to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> might have gone further, however, by
noting that dyslexia is often accompanied by hyperactivity, which seemed to
characterize the astonishing and sometimes undisciplined energy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
brought to everything.

            Which brings us to the third
side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s personality and the main theme of the book, that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">empire</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> was probably destined for politics from the start, when
he was named after his mother's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson W. Aldrich</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island,</ENAMEX>
whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln Steffens</ENAMEX> once called "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch-</ENAMEX>representative of protected,
privileged business." He was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, but from his
earliest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> he was determined to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefellers</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 20s</TIMEX>, he was already striving to forge his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> into a
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, organizing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> to confront their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> with
a demand that the family assets be turned over (gradually) to the next
generation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> also carried out what was in effect a coup d'etat at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Center</ENAMEX>, forcing out the retainers loyal to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> so that he
could take over himself.

            Early on,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> got into the habit of tapping his own financial resources to surround
himself with talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. He was forever commissioning huge semiacademic
studies of problems by an array of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>, a practice
which throughout his life elicited resentment from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> less flush with
cash. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s addiction to living in an expensive realm of his own, for
creating his own entourage, ultimately accounted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>'s decision to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">toss Rockefeller</ENAMEX> overboard and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> as his running mate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>
(something that will presumably be discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s next book).

            
His involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> was indicative
of how he would mobilize resources to get something done, then go to such
extremes he'd have to abandon the project. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> first became interested
in the region through its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, and then through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Venezuelan</ENAMEX> subsidiary
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Oil of New Jersey</ENAMEX>--the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. To ward off increasingly
strident demands from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> wanted to create <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that
would raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s standard of living; using his own resources, he set up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>, grow <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>, market <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, develop natural resources,
and build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX>. Before long, however, many of these projects went bust, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> had to turn to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for financial assistance to ward off
bankruptcy. Eventually, he decided that only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could
supply the resources to do the job.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s
urge to enter the public arena was partly the legacy of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Foundation</ENAMEX> helped create the modern science of philanthropy, though
its underlying purpose was to expunge the malevolent connotations attached to
the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> in the wake of the predations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Oil</ENAMEX>
trust. (The philanthropic worldview also informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s ambitious ideas
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> government spending, which would eventually make him an easy target.)
Another influence was that patrician <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, who was,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller</ENAMEX>, the focus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s relentless sycophancy and
black-belt bureaucratic infighting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> tells the story of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
got wind <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> of a scheme to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to eliminate his
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>. He quickly found out who was
going to be seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>--it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Wallace</ENAMEX>--and
persuaded him to win a stay of execution. But unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
never developed the resilience to stay in power. Eventually, his forced
resignations from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> to
turn to elective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> as the one way of establishing an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">base</ENAMEX>.

            Upon first hearing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> might run for governor
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire incumbent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Averell Harriman</ENAMEX> dismissed it as a joke.
He even let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> head up a commission on the state constitution, though
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tammany</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> warned he would regret it. As they predicted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> used
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> to educate himself and build a case for change in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>. What
surprised everyone was that he turned out to be a most charismatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX>,
with a much more down-to-earth touch than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harriman</ENAMEX> ever exhibited. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, these
subways are neat!" said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>. "I don't know why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> complain about
them." It didn't matter that he was naive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> wanted somebody they knew
could not be bought.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s book ends as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> stands on the threshold of a new era of expansive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the
presidency beckoning in the background. By then, we already know what being a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Republican</ENAMEX> consists of: a mixture of lavish spending, arrogance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambition</ENAMEX>, scheming, and pragmatism; a belief in expertise and big projects;
and, above all, excitement about the sheer adventure of governing. For all his
failures and disappointments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Rockefeller</ENAMEX> set a standard for excellence
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will not see again any time soon.

         
      
   
