
   
   
      
         
            Auto-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da</ENAMEX>-f&eacute;

            The
naming of autobiographies is a minor art. A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">great</ENAMEX> title can be nobly direct
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov's Speak</ENAMEX>, Memory ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Paar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Kid You Not</ENAMEX> ), bitterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cryptic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josef von Sternberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun in a Chinese Laundry ; Adolf Loos</ENAMEX>'
Nevertheless ), or too clever by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polanski</ENAMEX>). In this
obscure pantheon, a place must be reserved for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klaus Kinski</ENAMEX>, the erratically
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">gifted Polish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> and noted mal 
               vivant , who tried to
publish the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> version of his autobiography in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> under the massively
ironic title All I Need is Love . The book was caught in a copyright
dispute between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, with huge libel
problems looming; it was withdrawn shortly after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, and became one of
the books most often stolen from public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>. Now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> after its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s demise, it has re-emerged as Kinski 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uncut</ENAMEX> . Despite the
unfortunate change of name, this ghastly and hypnotic memoir lives up to its
long-festering legend. The whole witless genre of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> confessional
undergoes a horrifying self-disembowelment.

            Kinski, with the huge, burning eyes, the weirdly colored
hair (yellow? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orange</ENAMEX>? rotting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>?), the sandpaper voice, the glint of a sharp
intellect beneath a brutish exterior. He emitted a strange kind of electricity;
before he even said a word on screen, he put everything and everyone on edge.
(In his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> role in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhivago</ENAMEX> , he seems to be performing with
a wax statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Sharif</ENAMEX>.) There was no visible technique to his acting,
other than radiating ineffable Kinski-ness. His secret weapon was, perhaps, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playfulness</ENAMEX>, his sense of being slyly amused by a mad world and his own mad
self. He will live into posterity on the strength of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> films he made
with the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Werner Herzog, Fitzcarraldo</ENAMEX> and
particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aguirre, Wrath of God</ENAMEX> ; his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aguirre</ENAMEX>, the languidly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nihilistic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martinet</ENAMEX> who leads an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> expedition toward nothingness, is one
of the great human monsters in movie history. But for the most part, his
talents were wasted, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski Uncut</ENAMEX> shows how he went about wasting
them.

            He was
born <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niklaus Nakszynski</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX>, in the old free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danzig (now Gdansk</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>). Growing up impoverished in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, he was drafted into the rag-tag
teen-age and old-age <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> that fought for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
II. He showed no enthusiasm for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> cause, and soon deserted. On the other
hand, he said afterward that he would have outdone <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> if he had been given
the part. He began acting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> and regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, developing a
reputation for savagely accented classical performances and electrifying
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man shows. In the latter, he would read mad scenes from plays, poems of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rimbaud</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">François Villon</ENAMEX>, and other programs of his own devising. He began
acting in movies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>; from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> on, he made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> film <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and
sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T ></ENAMEX>he film career
began promisingly. He appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Sirk</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Time to Love and a Time</ENAMEX>
to 
               Die ; a film by the mildly celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Käutner; Sergio Leone</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">For a Few Dollars More</ENAMEX> ; and several crisp
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English thrillers</ENAMEX> and war flicks. Addicted to quick work and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">upfront</ENAMEX> salaries,
he quickly gravitated toward the lower road: countless crime serials,
low-budget horror films, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spaghetti Westerns</ENAMEX>, other multinational genre pictures
of no distinction. Even when he began the seemingly career-transforming
collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herzog</ENAMEX>, he kept spewing out atrocious B, C, and D movies,
right up to his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. He was the kaiser of crap, and took pride in his
bad taste. Several times in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kinski Uncut</ENAMEX>, he lists the famous directors
he turned down: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fellini</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visconti, Pasolini</ENAMEX>, and so on. He passed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost Ark</ENAMEX> for something called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Venom</ENAMEX> , because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> didn't
pay enough.

            The nearly unrelieved
squalor of this career goes side by side with a self-consciously decadent and
degenerate lifestyle. Episodes recorded in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski Uncut</ENAMEX> fall into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
categories: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) sexual encounters with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, beautiful and ugly,
young and old, in a grotesque pornographic idiom that excludes sensual
pleasure; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) Céline-esque voyages of degradation and misery, often involving
vomit, excrement, and delirium; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) excoriations of incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, and generally, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who are
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinski</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) bouts of self-righteousness mixed with intense self-loathing. He
actively sets out to make himself appear the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creep</ENAMEX> who ever walked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX>.

            "Once
when I was asleep I pissed on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> because I dreamed she was a tree,"
writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX>. "I believe there is no stench that I haven't stunk of," writes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX>. "The chick with the blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curls</ENAMEX> ... yells 'Kinski!' which sounds like
'Fuck me,' " writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herzog</ENAMEX> is a miserable, hateful, malevolent,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">avaricious</ENAMEX>, money-hungry, nasty, sadistic, treacherous, blackmailing, cowardly,
thoroughly dishonest creep. His so-called 'talent' consists of nothing but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tormenting helpless creatures</ENAMEX> and, if necessary, torturing them to death or
simply murdering them. ... Every scene, every angle, every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shot</ENAMEX> is determined
by me. ... I can at least partly save the movie from being wrecked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herzog</ENAMEX>'s
bungling," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX>. (This behind-the-scenes mastery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> did not
seem to bear fruit in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> directorial debut, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paganini</ENAMEX> , which has
been described as unwatchable by the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have watched it.)

            On and on it goes, sickening and tedious by turns. But this
book is weirdly enjoyable for what is not in it: conventional film gossip,
name-dropping, show-biz folly of any kind. Here is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who reports working on
For a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Few Dollars More</ENAMEX>, but fails to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>. For good
long stretches, you'll be wondering, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What year are we in?</ENAMEX>" or even, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">decade?</ENAMEX>" There are no dates, and few hard facts; movies are referred to as
"some piece of crap," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, as "some idiot." (The "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> slut"
referred to on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">309</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX>. For other helpful annotations, see
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX> filmography
attached.) He doesn't even give the full names of his various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. You also
wonder whether certain things actually happened. Some of the sexual escapades
sound curiously like unfulfilled fantasies. Phrases recur in them like literary
motifs.

            
Eventually, a genre crisis sets in. Is this autobiography, or an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">autobiographical</ENAMEX> novel? It becomes an interesting game to guess at the real
feelings behind this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kinski</ENAMEX>-esque <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kinski</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herzog</ENAMEX> sections
ring particularly false; if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herzog</ENAMEX> was a bungling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>, why did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX> keep
making films with him? Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Gosling</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> about the making of
Fitzcarraldo , or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chatwin</ENAMEX>'s essay on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cobra Verde</ENAMEX> , and you
discover a rather different Kinski: an irascible, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX>, lovable eccentric,
whose fits of rage come and go like squalls, whose childish enthusiasm for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmaking</ENAMEX> and playacting bursts through the put-on cynicism. The camera
faithfully recorded his impishness; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aguirre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrath</ENAMEX> of God and
Fitzcarraldo are grand, dark, but also comic, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX> supplies the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of the wit.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S ></ENAMEX>o why is
Kinski such a glum book? Part of the problem may be the translation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim Neugröschel</ENAMEX> is a respected and experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>, but he tries too
hard to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX>'s thuggish prose into slinky <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> slang. Idioms are
sometimes not quite on the mark--for example, references to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX>'s pals
sleeping with "minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>" and "minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>." The translation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinski</ENAMEX> made
himself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>--I found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> remaining copy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>--was
more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch</ENAMEX>, cold, stylish. Also, there are strange discontinuities between the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> versions: each has material omitted from the other, and the new "uncut"
edition is actually much more cautious naming names. All this will have to be
sorted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinski</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> of the future.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the book is
another performance, another ranting Kinski creation. If asked for a
Siskel-and-Ebert yea or nay, I wouldn't know what to say: It can be recommended
only to certain tastes. Amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> may enjoy it as a sort of
high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> game of bombarding sexual neuroses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> of human
misery can savor its underlying sadness and futility. And as always with
Kinski, there's a taunting taste of comedy; the tears on his cheeks are from
laughter. As I put this wretched book down, I thought I heard a cackle from
somewhere, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with red eyes rasping, "Idioten !"

         
      
   
