
   
   
      
         
            Sisters Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mink</ENAMEX>

            Has anyone noticed the
spooky resemblance between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these two</TIMEX> memoirs? Both were written by actresses
famous for playing ethereal, damaged, or somehow incomplete <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>. Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">actresses</ENAMEX> chronicle restless, unstable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">childhoods</ENAMEX>, capped, in each case, by a
quick rise to fame. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regretfully</ENAMEX> conclude that they were unprepared for
this early acclaim, and that missing out on the trial and error of adolescence
caused them permanent damage. Considering how successful these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have been,
each of them spends surprisingly little time talking about her work and quite a
lot discussing her ill-chosen romantic adventures. The great love of each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s life was a difficult genius known for his neurotic, darkly comic
musings on the battle of the sexes. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>'s case, it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow's</ENAMEX>, of course, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>. In both cases, the affair was
a long, ugly, and finally public catastrophe.

            Which
leads us to another intriguing similarity between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leaving a Doll</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
and What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls Away</ENAMEX> : Both have met with awkward, squeamish reviews.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have asked tough questions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' judgment and motives: How
could these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> just sit by and let this happen? Why should we believe either
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when she says that her book is an attempt to understand what happened, and
not a bid for revenge? In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX>
complained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> asks for more sympathy than she deserves. In a pitiless
review in a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>
wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> exaggerates the emotional damage wrought by an early bout
with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX>, unfairly vilifies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, and tries to "solicit sympathy in the
court of public opinion." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merkin</ENAMEX> doubts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>'s claim that she was helpless:
"One can discern, through the pious gloss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> puts on the events of her life,
the shrewd maneuverings of a stage brat." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> of exploiting
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> and touting her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous friends</ENAMEX> ("the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glitterati</ENAMEX> chorus"), and
says that the account of her battle with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> "will satisfy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peeping Fan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>."

            Why the discomfort? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>, in part, a generational
explanation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feminists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--or at least, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> within the small circle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> assigned to write about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for the elite media, many of them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>
or two younger than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX>--are more upbeat than they used to be, but
also more arrogant and hardhearted. They have a "buck-up" attitude. They want
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to stop harping about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and start taking care of their own lives. Most
of all, they think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> control what they do with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. As long
as they consent to something, they can't be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. This last idea is, in
fact, rather weirdly prominent in the work of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merkin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>. A few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> before she reviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>'s book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merkin</ENAMEX> wrote a long personal essay for
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> about how much she likes to be spanked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s review
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> precedes by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> her much-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gossiped</NUMEX>-about new memoir, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiss</ENAMEX> , about her consensual love affair with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            Or maybe
the reaction points to a new, jaded distrust of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when we
felt sorry for the famous are over--nowadays, we dislike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> who plead
confusion, insecurity, and no common sense. While this sounds reasonable
enough, it overlooks the most gruesome similarity of all: that in the case of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> both, it is crippling passivity that brought them to the
public eye in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place and crippling passivity that kept them there.

            
Early on, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> demonstrated a
flair for acting--and an eerie inertness in their relations with other human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> started appearing on stage at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>. But for all her worldly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambition</ENAMEX>, she writes, "to become an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> as young as I did was to enter a
cloister of my own making. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woefully</ENAMEX>, painfully ignorant of the most basic
facts of life, I was always ill at ease in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX>'s entry
into the cloister was even less thought out. She was born into it. Her father
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>--another difficult genius, and a violent alcoholic to
boot--and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>. Dead earnest even
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrow</ENAMEX> planned to escape the narrow, competitive world of acting,
to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Carmelite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pediatrician</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, until her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s death
forced her to start earning money. Thereafter she never left the fishbowl, and
when she says she never enjoyed it, you believe her. She bounced from one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous husband</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>, who made her sit around while he drank until
dawn with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rat Pack</ENAMEX>) to another (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">André Previn</ENAMEX>, who made her schedule her
work around his).

            Neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">actress</ENAMEX> knew what she wanted, and each was rewarded for her ignorance. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Bloom</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX> recognized that her preposterous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inexperience</ENAMEX> and eagerness to please made her the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> to star
opposite him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Limelight</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa</ENAMEX>, "an ideal of pre-Victorian
self-immolation." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrow</ENAMEX> says that after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Polanski</ENAMEX> cast her in the
career-making role of the young, pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> , he
took advantage of her lack of an instinct for self-preservation and filmed a
scene of her threading dangerously through oncoming traffic. ("There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">127</NUMEX>
varieties of nuts," he marveled approvingly. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">116</NUMEX> of them.")

            In their love lives, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miracle-Gro</ENAMEX> to
an especially prized kind of male creativity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX> coolly plumbed his
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> for material. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, he even planned to name a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in his novel Deception --a hideous, dowdy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> and an
"ever-spouting fountain of tears"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire</ENAMEX>. (She found out, and made him change
it.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, of course, made repeated cinematic use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX>'s skinny, creepy
beauty, and her pained, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abstracted</ENAMEX> stare. (She accurately describes herself as
"eyes perched on a stalk.")

            To be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX> emerges as the tamer monster. But here, too, the analogies are
uncanny. Each courtship begins with the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> sending charming but oddly
formal notes to his beloved or having his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> call to determine the time,
place, and sometimes the precise length of their meeting. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
hold forth on the subject of their favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> (for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Céline</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kafka</ENAMEX>; for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, the old jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greats</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Bechet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jelly Roll Morton</ENAMEX>), but
are less interested in the women's recommendations. Both loathe their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and strive to avoid them. Each acts as if everything is all right,
then lets loose with crushing invective. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX> resents having to go to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX>, having to make arrangements for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s funeral, and (less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unreasonably</ENAMEX>) having to deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>'s nervousness in the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> throws a tantrum when he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> are walking together on the Upper
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Side</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrow</ENAMEX> points to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and asks if it belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>. Her sin: She was forgetting that he had pointed out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to
her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>. There were explosions, too, writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX>, "when I didn't
know the name of a certain kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta</ENAMEX>; and again when I was off in my
estimate of the weather by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only four degrees</NUMEX>."

            
To put up with any one of these things, let
alone all of them, requires an almost monstrous lust for effacement--a taste
for masochism . These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are character studies in the most terrifying
sort of selflessness, the kind that results from the failure to develop a self.
Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> didn't shield them from the consequences of their passivity. In
fact, we have watched them be passive on screen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and we have
applauded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passive Woman</ENAMEX> has long been one of the most cherished staples of
our culture, high and low. Who better to play her on screen?

            Not that any of this
justifies the truly rotten choices both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> have made. And you
can't help but be glad that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> these days are at least being told to take
care of themselves. But it is curious that these actresses should be attacked
instead of encouraged in their efforts to change. (Or maybe it isn't so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curious</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Weiss</ENAMEX> tellingly led his attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> in the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> with a little temper tantrum at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.) Leaving a
Doll's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls Away</ENAMEX> seem less like vindictive,
manipulative performances than like baby steps in the right direction. They're
every bit as awkward as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> accuse them of being. It's unnerving to
hear the muse speak at last, as if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> had escaped from fiction to tell
her story for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. Her voice is unsteady, and her conclusions
sometimes seem canned, evasive, not yet complete. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> glides over her
motives. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX> is humorless and steeped in a bottomless melancholy. Still,
better late than never. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passive Woman</ENAMEX> deserves a little more of our
support. It'll be a good thing for all of us if she finally gets into the habit
of speaking for herself.

         
      
   
