
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rules</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Washington</ENAMEX> was
virtuous, but was virtuousness altogether a good thing? This entirely
reasonable question turns out to be extremely old. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stendhal</ENAMEX> posed it in the
1830s in his novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucien Leuwen</ENAMEX> , in which the wealthy young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX>
hero contemplates fleeing the corruptions of monarchical old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for a new
start in virtuous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">republican America</ENAMEX>. But would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stendhal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> be able to
stand the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">virtuous republicans</ENAMEX>? He considers paying a visit on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> himself--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--at home on his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>. But would he
find <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s conversation bright and sparkling?

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> would have bored
me to death," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stendhal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> concludes. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are aghast.) "I
would prefer by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> times the elegant manners of a corrupt heart."

            Now comes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX>, with a handsome new edition (published on elegant paper
with a lustrous black cover) of the writings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> himself, more than a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> pages of letters and documents of every sort, which allows us to judge
for ourselves. The book makes a strange impression. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX>, in
its admirable effort to present <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s literature and classic political
documents in pristine form, has adopted the rather extreme policy of publishing
its volumes without any sort of introductory guide, which is probably just as
well in the case of literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> whose work is easily approached.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> require an introduction, though--political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, especially. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX> produced a fat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX>-page volume of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years ago</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s writings turned out to be a shapeless
heap of private letters and peculiar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">jottings</TIMEX> intermixed with an occasional
manifesto of immortal grandeur--and to make your way through them unaided was
nearly impossible. Likewise with the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> volume. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> was not
a book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, or any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at all, professionally speaking, but took
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quill</ENAMEX> in hand merely to address particular situations as they arose. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Writings</ENAMEX> , as a result, offer a puzzling mass of personal letters,
military records, presidential orations, ringing statements, and random
insignificant scribblings, all of them put into chronological order by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX>--which is to say into very little order at all, except that
of chance.

            Still, the
patriotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> plunges in--and instantly discovers, in the volume's first
entry, a document of capital importance in re the insidious, Gallically
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> accusation offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stendhal</ENAMEX>'s novel. The opening document,
dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1747</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>, is a numbered catechism of dos and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">don'ts</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Rules of Civility & Decent Behavior in Company</ENAMEX> and
Conversation." Whether this document belongs in a collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">writings</ENAMEX> seems a little dubious, given that (as the assiduous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> will
discover with a glance at the note on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,094</NUMEX> by the volume's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodehamel</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> did not actually write these Rules but merely copied
them from an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> translation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">French-language</ENAMEX> Jesuit text from the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 th century</TIMEX>.

            
The Rules contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> numbered passages
offering such worthy bits of advice as this, from No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>, "[B]edew no mans face
with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spittle</ENAMEX>, by approaching too near him when you Speak," or this, from
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, "Do not Puff up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheeks, Loll</ENAMEX> not out the tongue, rub the Hands, or
beard, thrust out the lips, or bite them or keep the Lips too open or too
Close." No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> says, "Being Set at meat Scratch not neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spit Cough</ENAMEX> or blow
your Nose except there's a Necessity for it." And, at once, from the opening
document of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Writings</ENAMEX> , the suspicion arises that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Country</ENAMEX> was, in truth, a hideous Bore.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>! But
what makes the unhappy discovery truly appalling is the further incredible
discovery that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s earnest and humorless Rules are considered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to be the key to his entire career, and therefore, in some respect, a
key to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s two centuries of national success. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> a conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Brookhiser</ENAMEX> published a biography, titled Founding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rediscovering George Washington</ENAMEX> , which made the point that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, by keeping in mind his carefully inscribed numbered Rules
throughout his momentous life, conducted himself correctly in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways</ENAMEX> (no bedewing of others with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spittle, Hats properly Doffed</ENAMEX>, and so forth),
which led to right conduct in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Ways</ENAMEX>, too, thus to political and military
triumph.

            Supremely convinced of this point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhiser</ENAMEX> has gone
ahead and brought out his own little edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s rules under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title Rules</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Civility: The 110 Precepts That Guided Our First</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> in
War and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> , slightly altered to eliminate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th -century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">idiosyncrasies</ENAMEX> (a pity) and emended with small commentaries by Brookhiser
himself, some of them pertaining to events in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s life, others
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">solemnly applying</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s rules to circumstances of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            Yet, even
Brookhiser, for all his sober devotion to civility as the key to everything,
cannot escape noticing something ridiculous, therefore comic, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s
rules. And so, bravely embracing what he cannot deny, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brookhiser</ENAMEX>, in his
edition of the rules, throws in some jocularity of his own, with the sure
lightness of touch you would expect from an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> who has based his biography
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> on a guide to etiquette. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rule No. 2</ENAMEX> proclaims (in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX>'s superior <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> version), "When in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX>, put not your Hands to any Part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Body</ENAMEX> not usually Discovered." To
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gruesomely</ENAMEX> adds, in his own edition, "A rule often flouted
by rap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> ." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rule No. 4</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the</ENAMEX>
Presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Others Sing</ENAMEX> not to yourself with a humming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noise</ENAMEX>, nor Drum with
your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fingers or Feet</ENAMEX>." To which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brookhiser</ENAMEX> adds, "Don't carry a boom box
either ." And the embarrassments pile up, one upon the other, and the
patriotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> wilts in his chair, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ends up too ludicrous for
words.

            
At least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX>'s
Writings contains an endless supply of additional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. There are
military entries full of wampum and warpaths (during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French and Indian War</ENAMEX>)
and complaints to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> (during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolutionary War</ENAMEX>), which are
interesting to read, even if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX> from the
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX>--was not much of a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. There is a long amiable letter to
the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lafayette</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1779</TIMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, in a giddy mood, drifts into
a reverie about competing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lafayette</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lafayette</ENAMEX> himself--a
funny bit of teasing, followed abruptly by a rueful reassurance, worthy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stendhal</ENAMEX> himself, that "amidst all the wonders recorded in holy writ no
instance can be produced where a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woman</ENAMEX> from real inclination has
preferred an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." It is interesting to see how warm he grew toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Hamilton</ENAMEX> (he signed his letters "I am <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Affectionate"</ENAMEX>), and how
awkward and self-conscious toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> were berating
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> "in such exaggerated and indecent terms as could scarcely be applied
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nero</ENAMEX>; a notorious defaulter; or even to a common pick-pocket."

            
Naturally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX> edition also contains, hidden here and there
in impossible-to-find locations, a number of solemn and stirring documents of
state--for instance, the reply, genuinely dear to my own multiculturally
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jewish</ENAMEX> heart, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> made, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, to a letter from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew Congregation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newport</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX> had written to
congratulate him about something or other (unspecified by the notes), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> replied:

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States of America</ENAMEX> have a right to applaud themselves for having given to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mankind</ENAMEX> examples of an enlarged and liberal policy: a policy worthy of
imitation. All possess alike liberty of conscience and immunities of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizenship</ENAMEX>. It is now no more that toleration is spoken of, as if it was by
the indulgence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that another enjoyed the exercise of
their inherent natural rights. For happily the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
which gives to bigotry no sanction, to persecution no assistance, requires only
that they who live under its protection should demean themselves as good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizens</ENAMEX>, in giving in on all occasions their effectual support. ...
            

            
               May the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the
Stock of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>, who dwell in this land, continue to merit and enjoy the good
will of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inhabitants</ENAMEX>; while every one shall sit in safety under his
own <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX> and figtree, and there shall be none to make him afraid.
            

            The letter is wonderfully
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gracious</ENAMEX>--and yet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">graciousness</ENAMEX> owes everything to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s feelings
about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">republican revolution</ENAMEX>, and nothing at all to what could be learned from a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> manual of courtly behavior.

         
      
   
