
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe Sociology</ENAMEX>

            Studio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX> was a singular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disco</ENAMEX>. Let me give you an example of what I mean.

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One night</TIMEX> there--a fairly
typical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, as I recall--I noticed that I was standing next to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupant</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> throne. He seemed to be enjoying himself,
though he looked a little anxious when a paparazzo took his picture.
("How am I going to explain this to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archbishop</ENAMEX>?" he might have been
thinking.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that week</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> came to visit me in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. We were
watching a local newscast in her hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and there was a story about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> raiding a disreputable midtown disco. The TV showed images of a youngish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX> being led out by the cops. "Goodness!" my mother
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exclaimed</ENAMEX>. "Are there a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Studio 54</ENAMEX>?" (She's from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>," I
replied, beaming a bit, "the last time I popped in, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> was
there."

            It's hard to convey how much more interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> was
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX> than it is now. There was a sense of unlimited possibility in
the air. Everywhere else--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>--seemed provincial and dull by
comparison. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sparrow</ENAMEX>, the late warden of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All Souls College</ENAMEX>, put it nicely:
"My impression is that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> anything might happen at any moment. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, nothing could happen, ever."

            Shortly
after I arrived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, an unknown from the sticks come to learn
philosophy at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, I went uninvited to an opening at an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art gallery</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Side</ENAMEX>. I met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> there who turned out to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>'s silk-screener,
and he introduced me to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX>, who then introduced me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Carey</ENAMEX>, who then introduced me to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Vreeland</ENAMEX>, of whom I had never
heard. The next thing I knew I was in a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room upstairs</ENAMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>
having dinner with the lot of them. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s easy!" I thought. (What I
didn't realize is that you don't become rich and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, or even enduringly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fabulous</ENAMEX>, by osmosis; at some unhappy point, you have to work.)

            
The sense of possibility reached its most
intense pitch in that little patch of space-time known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Studio</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>.
Temporally, it spanned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand days</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977 to 1979</TIMEX>; spatially, it
occupied a handsome former opera <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that was also a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> ( The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Benny Show</ENAMEX> , What's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Line</ENAMEX>? , <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Captain Kangaroo</ENAMEX> ) on
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">54 th Street--254 W. 54 th St.</ENAMEX>, to be exact. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oddly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
had called it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Studio 53</ENAMEX>.")

            It was
thither that I--emboldened by my earlier brush with greatness--hopefully hied
myself around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one autumn</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> in order to shake my booty,
or possibly my groove thing. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">An hour</TIMEX> later I was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zulu</ENAMEX>-dancing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Tyler</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cavett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Trudeau</ENAMEX>, and--for all I know--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of this engrossing book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Haden-Guest</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Last Party</ENAMEX> is more than the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Studio 54</ENAMEX>. It is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibbonesque</ENAMEX> chronicle of the rise and fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> night life from the
postwar period to the present. The chief cultural innovation of the period was,
of course, the discothèque. The great early discothèques were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Vadim</ENAMEX>--the director <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigitte Bardot</ENAMEX>--coined the word by
analogy with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cinémathèque</ENAMEX> . The concept swam into the ken of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fellini</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Dolce Vita</ENAMEX> .

            What is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disco</ENAMEX>? It is the perfection of voyeurism. Playing recorded music allows the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX> to get rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>, so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have nothing to look at
but one another. They are the spectacle. But you have to have the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
lest the spectacle prove disagreeable. The disco in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Fever</ENAMEX>
was the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">2001 Odyssey</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, a hustling, polyester-draped mass of rutting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guidos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guidettes</ENAMEX>. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> article titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"DISCO</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hottest Trend</ENAMEX> in
Entertainment," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> claimed that "there are now more than
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10,000 discotheques</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>" Yes, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> of them was any good.

            
What made Studio <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> seem like the center of the
universe was that every world--art, royalty, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, fashion, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">literary</ENAMEX>, gay, political, bohemian, blue-blood--brilliantly intersected there.
It solved, for a brief shining moment, what in game theory is known as the
"coordination problem." Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Taylor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rockefeller</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mick Jagger</ENAMEX> will go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX>, but only if they are
reasonably certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador Dali</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Baryshnikov</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX> will
show up too--and vice versa. (Actually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX> didn't get in. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief doorman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Benecke</ENAMEX>, was under the misapprehension that he was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cypress Gardens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>.) Halston, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>, and Bianca
will be there regardless. Studio <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> delivered this critical mass almost every
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 1,500 or so</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were simply beautiful or interesting
to look at, plus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haden</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guest</ENAMEX> and me.

            But why
did all these "competing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>" blend together so ecstatically? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason, I
think, was a giddy feeling in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX> that the End was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nigh</ENAMEX>, so
everything was permitted and there was no reason to compete. The rest of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> had endured <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam and Watergate</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> had its own little
problem: bankruptcy and physical collapse. It was like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> in the waning days
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>: Let the great debauch proceed!

            And if there was a bit of buggery and whatnot going on up
in the balcony, what of it? "You would look around and you'd see somebody's
back," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> quoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haden</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guest</ENAMEX>. "And then you'd see little
toes twinkling behind their ears." In the warren of grungy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> beneath the
dance floor--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>' sanctum sanctorum--the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX> was consumed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linear</ENAMEX> foot, and (according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>) the odd <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> contessa could be
found handcuffed to a water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX>, getting squired from the rear by one of the
pretty shirtless busboys. In short, the place made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosch</ENAMEX> look like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist</ENAMEX>
picnic. "I don't know if I was in heaven or hell," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Carter</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, after a visit. "But it was wonderful !"

            Outside,
the vetting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> at the door kept the great unwashed in their horrible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disco regalia</ENAMEX> from getting past the velvet ropes. Attempts at dramatic
entrances were not always successful. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> occasion recounted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> rented a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, stripped naked, and arrived at the door, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godiva</ENAMEX>-style. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">doorman</ENAMEX> looked her over and said, "OK, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> can come in,
but you have to stay outside." Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, desperate after repeated rejection,
tried to climb into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> through a vent but got stuck. He was found a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days later</TIMEX> in black tie, dead. OK, the door policy was cruel, but at least it
kept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>-in-chrysalis <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Musto</ENAMEX> out.

            
And so the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> went jollily on, night
after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, presided over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Rubell</ENAMEX>, irrepressible though always
zonked on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'ludes</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Schrager</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer Lansky</ENAMEX> lieutenant,
was all but invisible). It seemed it would never end. But all the while the
shadow of doom was creeping <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearer and nearer</NUMEX>, till came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> when it pulled
off its whiskers and pounced.

            It was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 14, 1978</TIMEX>, to be precise. That was when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>,
who had been denied entrance when they came to boogie, returned in a more
official capacity. They found numerous cash-stuffed Hefty bags that had been
hidden in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> ceiling--"the skim"--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> packets of white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder</ENAMEX>. I
was there <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of the raid, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> was exceptionally good. It was
even better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half</TIMEX> later, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rubell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schrager</ENAMEX> went
to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. (They had tried to implicate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> as a coke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> in the meantime, but the ploy didn't work.)

            Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rubell</ENAMEX> is dead of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schrager</ENAMEX> owns the
half-dozen most chic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Halston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
are dead, along with an alarming percentage of those named in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haden</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guest</ENAMEX>'s
index. Studio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX> has had numerous reincarnations, but the bloom was permanently
off the thing by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. I know, for since then I have been to: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tunnel</ENAMEX>, the
Red Zone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Visage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save the Robots</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ice Palace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisco Disco</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.G</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnum</ENAMEX>'s, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roxy, the Limelight, the Cat Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club USA</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Palladium</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mudd Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM/PM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Magique</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underground</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Area</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Milk</ENAMEX>
Bar, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nell's</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surf Club</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peppermint Lounge</ENAMEX>, the Pyramid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinity, Hurrah</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vandam</ENAMEX> whose
name I can't remember, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Café Society</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Xenon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Parrot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Au Bar</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Danceteria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interferon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regine's</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. (I have not , however, been to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Village</ENAMEX>
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Studio Filthy Whore</ENAMEX>.")

            You might think that I spoof.
That I invent the names. I do not. These were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX> of the highest
standing and chic. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fabulous people</ENAMEX> sought the
entree to them. All are defunct, or moribund. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s "club <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>" take boring
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> on end, until they find themselves sawing the legs off their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roommate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> (as chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">club kid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Alig</ENAMEX> was recently arrested for
doing). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Last Party</ENAMEX> leaves no doubt: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightworld</ENAMEX> is
dead.

            Let's go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
