
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wandering Jew</ENAMEX>

            By
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Benfey</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>)
            

            You're
greeted at the door by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page boy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX>'s, his hand extended for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pourboire</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Page Boy</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxim's</ENAMEX> , circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>). At first the figure
looks almost cute in his fire engine red suit, but is that a roll of bills in
his left hand or is he making an obscene gesture? And those hollow black eyes,
scarred hands, and sunken chest--don't they seem just a bit sepulchral? Is he
welcoming us to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX>'s or to the underworld?

            For the moment, at
least, he's guarding the entrance to the stunning show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Museum</ENAMEX>
devoted to the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaim Soutine</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894-1943</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lithuanian</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> who worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> between the world wars. This is the first major
exhibition in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> to be devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s work in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 50</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--since, that is, the epoch-making retrospective of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX>. The timing of that show, mounted just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s
death, was in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense perfect and in another highly problematic. It coincided
exactly with the extraordinary rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionism</ENAMEX> and the seismic
shift of the center of the art world from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> were eager to see in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soutine</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX> precursor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kooning</ENAMEX>--who claimed to be "crazy about Soutine"--and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson Pollock</ENAMEX>. The
extraordinary landscapes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX> painted around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX> in the provincial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town of C√©ret</ENAMEX>, with their swirling wreaths of thick paint and decentered
structure, could easily be mistaken for early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Koonings</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for an example.) "Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soutine</ENAMEX> at this time what might
be called an abstract expressionist?" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monroe Wheeler</ENAMEX>
asked rhetorically in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> catalog.

            But in other ways, the timing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> show was awkward
and even potentially embarrassing. As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> was welcomed back to the postwar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, no one felt like asking tough questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acquiescence</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950</TIMEX> catalog, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wheeler</ENAMEX> implied that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> had little to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occupation</ENAMEX>. "Soutine," he
wrote, "suffered no specific persecution or violence during the war. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>,
he was offered an opportunity to come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, but he would not take
advantage of it. He lived with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> ... in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Touraine</ENAMEX>." And so on. But, as
the art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remy Golan</ENAMEX> notes in a catalog essay for the current show,
"after having provided hospitality to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> like him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> essentially abandoned them to
their own fate during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> occupation." Soutine wasn't just
"living with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" in the countryside. He was in flight from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> and
their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">functionaries</ENAMEX>, hiding and constantly on the move. He returned to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> only when a severe stomach ulcer condition necessitated a last-minute
operation. It came too late, and he died.

            So the current show at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Museum</ENAMEX> offers an opportunity both to re-evaluate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s
connection to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> and to dig more deeply into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s
relation to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> culture and to his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewishness</ENAMEX>. The show is arranged in a
manner to do just that, though with a resulting wrenching of chronology and
little attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s life. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> paintings in the show are hung in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> sections, each corresponding to one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have viewed
Soutine: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soutine</ENAMEX> as an untutored "primitive" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>, which is how he was seen
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soutine</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> and the last great hope for traditional
painting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>--his reputation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soutine</ENAMEX> as a prophet of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionism</ENAMEX>, which is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> thought in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>, when they
"rediscovered" him. It is this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> phase that leads to the biggest
dislocation in the show, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> see the "abstract" paintings of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C√©ret</ENAMEX> period last, though they were among the earliest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX> painted. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> phases--from primitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>--happen to follow pretty much
directly from the circumstances of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s life, to the extent that we know
them.

            The youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soutine</ENAMEX> seems to step right out of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bashevis Singer</ENAMEX> story. Since he left almost no paper trail--few letters, no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drawings</ENAMEX>, no artistic manifestoes--the same stories gleaned from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> have been recycled over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. Soutine was born the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to an impoverished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tailor</ENAMEX> (or more precisely a "mender") and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Smilovitchi</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minsk</ENAMEX>. Legends about his childhood--of
which he may have been the source--include his theft of some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> utensils
to buy his first colored pencil, and his early portrait of a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rabbi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, evidently responding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> injunction against graven
images, beat up Soutine, then paid a reparation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 rubles</NUMEX> toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soutine</ENAMEX> trained <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minsk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vilna</ENAMEX>, then made the
journey to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, where he studied briefly in a formal art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> while living
in the most abject poverty.

            Some of his earliest
still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifes</ENAMEX>, dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916 to 1918</TIMEX>, look like little parables of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deprivation</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> anorexic herrings on a plate with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forks (why <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>?)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groping</ENAMEX> across them ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Still Life With Herrings</ENAMEX> , circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>). The table is
tipped upward, almost meeting the picture <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. Such paintings, along with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">swirling C√</ENAMEX>©ret landscapes, struck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> as "naive," just the
sort of unschooled stuff you'd expect from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slavic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of the shtetl .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waldemar George</ENAMEX> wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>, "Is this not the art of an exile, or
even a savage?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s big break came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>, when one of those
connoisseurs of the "primitive," the eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educator</ENAMEX> Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Barnes</ENAMEX>, bought up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s paintings, making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soutine</ENAMEX> an art world
celebrity almost <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>.

            But almost as soon as he had experienced this
Cinderella-like reversal of fortune, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX> developed second thoughts about
his work up to that point and tried to destroy as much of it as he could get
his hands on. No longer the wild and visionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">improviser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX> now
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apprenticed</ENAMEX> himself to the great painterly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> of the past: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courbet</ENAMEX>,
Chardin, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>. If you preferred his early landscapes, it was easy to
regard this new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Soutine</ENAMEX> as--in the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clement Greenberg</ENAMEX>, who reviewed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> show--"a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>." But if you liked the later paintings, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX> tended to do, they seemed like the next step in the
great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> tradition. Soutine the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slavic</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> quickly became
Soutine the quintessential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX>, a masterly upholder of the standards of
sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> art.

            Never
able to paint anything unless he had it before his eyes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX> set about
re-enacting some of the classic paintings he loved most. He persuaded peasant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to hike up their skirts and stand in cold streams, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX> had
demanded. He acquired a skate from the fishmonger and painted a loose
paraphrase of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chardin</ENAMEX> still life. In imitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>'s flayed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX> on
display at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Louvre, Soutine</ENAMEX> hung a carcass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>. In a
carnivalesque reassigning of roles, he hired a model to sweep away the flies
from the decaying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>. To keep the colors fresh, he dabbed the carcass with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> from a pail, then grabbed his paintbrushes to capture those lurid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reds</ENAMEX> on
canvas. This was the kind of scene that an action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> could relish. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kooning</ENAMEX> could have been thinking of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soutine</ENAMEX> when he observed, "Flesh
was the reason why oil painting was invented."

            You'd think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soutine</ENAMEX>, with his obsessive delight in flesh,
would paint <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nudes</ENAMEX>, but no; he painted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in his whole career, and it's a
minor painting. But at the same time he was painting his carcasses of cattle
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX>, around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX> painted a series of portraits of uniformed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>--bellhops, pastry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX>, grooms--of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page boy</ENAMEX> is
probably the best known. This parallel obsession elicited the interesting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestion</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Tuchman</ENAMEX>, that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (especially
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sacrificed animals</ENAMEX>) and uniformed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">domestics</ENAMEX> were scapegoats of sorts. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>--unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chagall</ENAMEX>, to whom he is sometimes compared--did not paint
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">stereotypically Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, he may have been alluding, with those dangling <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX>, to a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Yom Kippur rite</ENAMEX> in which a slaughtered
chicken was whirled around a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in a ritual of absolution. It may
also be worth noting that with their red or white uniforms, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">allowed Soutine</ENAMEX> to retain his lurid, fleshy palate.

            It has
been tempting to see in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s flayed forms a premonition of things to come.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Museum</ENAMEX> show, in a volley of questions, invite such a
response:

            Mightn't the eviscerated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX> in the throes of death be experienced as modernist mementi
mori, fetishistic reminders of the darkest, cruelest, and most primitive human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instincts</ENAMEX>? Couldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s eruptive, vertiginous landscapes be construed as
recollections of a ravaged <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, or even as the foreshadowing of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apocalyptic</ENAMEX>, post-atomic future?

            And so
on.

            The irony is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soutine</ENAMEX> seems to have viewed the arrival
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>, at least initially, with a certain equanimity, more cheerful than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fatalistic</ENAMEX>. Perhaps he had so thoroughly identified his art at this point with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> national traditions--was he not the legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courbet?</ENAMEX>--that he
hardly imagined himself to be a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX>
recalled him reading with admiration editorials by the collaborationist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">idealogue Charles Maurras</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action Fran√ßaise</ENAMEX> , and explaining that he
approved of social inequality "because it presented magnificent opportunities
for everyone." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One day</TIMEX> she said to him, "You have had great unhappiness in your
life, haven't you, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soutine?</ENAMEX>" He replied, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>! What makes you think that? I have
always been a happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            Nonetheless, the image from
his late work that stays with you is a little picture from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillips</ENAMEX>
Collection called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Return From School After the Storm</ENAMEX> (circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>). Here
the paint is as swirling and thick as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soutine</ENAMEX>'s earliest landscapes. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> hold hands fearfully as storm clouds hover ominously above them. The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> vulnerable figures are literally molded of paint; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s left hand juts
out a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">quarter-inch</NUMEX> from the canvas in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thick dab. The title is not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soutine's</ENAMEX>. I don't think it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are running from,
and I don't think the storm is behind them.

         
      
   
