
   
   
      
         
            Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unmannerly</ENAMEX>

            With her latest book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s etiquette <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> does something she'd never condone: She overstays
her welcome.

            In the guise of a
lorgnette-waving, muff-carrying, white-gloved <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Manners</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Martin</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , launched an etiquette
column in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. Twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Style</ENAMEX> section she archly instructed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">up-and-coming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> on appropriate personal, social, and professional
decorum. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>'s idea was to reinstitute the raised eyebrow as an instrument
of social commentary and guidance--an idea that itself was supposed to raise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eyebrows</ENAMEX>, and did.

            At
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>, the implausible new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arbiter</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prime</ENAMEX> topic of conversation among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX>, who then sent their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> thank-you
notes in blue or black ink, as she prescribed. It was a hoot, and it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">polite</ENAMEX>, too. Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX> was wittily practical with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gentle Readers</ENAMEX>" who
wrote in for advice on cleaning up their acts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministering</ENAMEX> to their sense of
irony and their sense of insecurity at the same time, she was the perfect campy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">connoisseur</ENAMEX> of propriety for a tie-dyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> now into ties. Her basic
principle--the importance of "shifting our attention from our own feelings to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s thoughts"--sounded amusingly outlandish in the wake of the
let-it-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-hang-out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>. Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manners' Guide to Excruciatingly Correct</ENAMEX>
Behavior was a bestselling success in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>.

            The risk, of course, lay in taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Manners</ENAMEX> too
seriously. (Review her book with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-volume treatise on the history of
manners by a famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX>? I did it myself.) Leave it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>, who was born wearing a bow tie, to give her cause a pedigree. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Anointing</ENAMEX>
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX> a deep-thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of 1960s liberation and license, he made
her sound like a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX>, only in taffeta<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Her quill</ENAMEX> quivered on
behalf of the same neat, elite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> standards that he with his fountain pen
defended on the editorial page. In his best core-curriculum name-dropping
style, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> compared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Manners</ENAMEX> on the civilizing power of social convention
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metternich</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Fathers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Pius</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IX</NUMEX>.
"She insists, wrongly, that she deals with manners rather than with morals,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> informed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. As the conservative, acquisitive 1980s took off,
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX> was conscripted for the conservative values crusade.

            Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX>, who
doubtless blushed at such treatment, has been trying to live up to the
philosophical flattery and live down the ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> ever since.
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manners Rescues Civilization From Sexual Harassment, Frivolous</ENAMEX>
Lawsuits, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dissing and Other Lapses in Civility</ENAMEX> , as its title indicates,
represents her most sweeping effort so far. The etiquette <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> doesn't want
to be mistaken for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> stick-in-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>--she's all-American, she's
egalitarian, she's up-to-date--but she's become a self-important, name-dropping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crusader</ENAMEX> in the civility wars herself. This <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>-page book, in which Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX> does a lot of recycling, isn't likely to raise an eyebrow, a hackle, or
much of a smile.

            Miss
Manners underrates the popularity of etiquette in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, and overrates its
power. According to her, only she, along with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>, in
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Far Eastern</ENAMEX> civilizations, [takes] etiquette seriously, ... in
the correct belief that manners are a virtue akin to morality." Everyone else,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resorting</ENAMEX> to "counter-rudeness, violence, and ... lawsuits" in the face of
incivility, spurns "the gentler, freer, extralegal system of etiquette." Yet
her current book, to say nothing of life itself during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> and a half
since her first book, offers ample proof of a mania for manners. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> more
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guides</ENAMEX> , it's worth noting, sold well in the interval.)

            Listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. Invoking decorous values like
self-restraint, decency, respect, personal and parental responsibility, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compassion</ENAMEX> has become an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pastime. The "E word" may not crop up much,
but that doesn't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shudder at the concept, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Manners</ENAMEX> claims.
Dress codes, curfews, sexual-consent codes (fine in spirit, she feels,
"unnecessarily tiring" in practice) are in; so are forks. The service economy
has brought professional etiquette back into fashion--even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in cheerful civility. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teach Your Toddler Manners</ENAMEX>" is
a staple of every parenting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.

            And
listen to Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX> herself, who has to admit there has been progress: "When
the nostalgic moan about the decline of etiquette, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX> turns contrary
and points out that it is only recently that frank expressions of prejudice
have become socially unacceptable." She gushes that "netiquette," the rules
being codified for computer behavior, proves the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> understands
the "legitimacy of etiquette as an essential factor in community life." Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX>, when it comes right down to it, acknowledges that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> aren't
at sea about standards of politeness at all, heterogeneous though our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
standards may be. Even "allowing for the unawareness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> and for
regional difference," she observes, "we can all distinguish good American
manners from bad."

            In short, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX> is in danger of being out of a job.
What's more, it becomes clear that the job, as she stakes out her
middle-of-the-road liberal conception of it, can only accomplish so much.
"Here's what strikes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Manners</ENAMEX> as a fair division of labor," she writes on
her favorite subject, child rearing: "She will nag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to teach manners to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and everyone else will find them the time in which to do this." Now
there's an undertaking: "Just restructure society so that a reasonable person
can manage both a job and a private life." (Presumably the same goes for her
cure for sexual harassment: She insists that a firm distinction between working
and socializing will clear everything right up.) And where greater zealots
might enlist "etiquette's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> of disapproval" to try to restructure society
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> life--sanctioning, say, births "out of what was sternly called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wedlock</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Manners</ENAMEX> demurs: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Manners</ENAMEX> does not oppose the use of social
pressure to encourage stable family life. She only insists that it take a less
cruel form."

            Rather than suggest some
gentler form, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manners proclaims National Civility Week</ENAMEX> beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24</TIMEX>.
It sounds suspiciously like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Secretaries Week</ENAMEX>: penance that allows
everyone to be thoughtlessly rude <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other 358 days of the year</TIMEX>. But then Miss
Manners' "peculiar profession" depends on "sensitive but indignant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> ...
complaining to her about their disgusting fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boorishness</ENAMEX> is good
for business.

         
      
   
