
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Woman</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermione Lee</ENAMEX>'s biography of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Woolf</ENAMEX> is a revelation. Not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> offers any startling new gossip.
On the contrary: The facts that she juggles have sat in the public domain for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and the story has been worn to threads by frequent telling. Woolf was
born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Stephen</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1882</TIMEX>, the freakishly talented, spectacularly
cheekboned youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Stephen</ENAMEX>, a successful but depressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Duckworth</ENAMEX>, a stoic beauty who brought to the
marriage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of her own. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX> were drenched in book
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chat</ENAMEX>, but otherwise not so different from other crowded, stifling Victorian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">youths</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> had a swarm of spinster aunts, curious animal-inspired
nicknames like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ape</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marmot</ENAMEX>," and not a moment of privacy.

            Then disaster struck,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">struck</ENAMEX>, and struck again. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s mysterious and saintly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> broke
under the strain of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s work--nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">invalids</ENAMEX>, running a staff
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>--though the immediate cause of death was rheumatic fever. Then, her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in his grief selfishly leaned on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX>, for
support and, after a period of exhausted servitude, she died too. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia</ENAMEX>
spent her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> getting over a nervous breakdown (the recovery was delayed by
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">half-brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, who chased her around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and fondled her).
When her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX> to the grave, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vanessa</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thoby</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian</ENAMEX>, left their posh family
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for the decrepit neighborhood of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomsbury</ENAMEX>. They invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thoby</ENAMEX>'s smart,
ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lytton Strachey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clive Bell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> over for unchaperoned partying. Soon they began to talk about and
experiment with sex, straight and otherwise (except, perhaps, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, whose
libido at this stage was, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, dribbled away on childish crushes
on maternal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>). Most of all, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> wrote, supporting herself with a
brutal workload of reviews, dreaming of delicate but radical new ways to tell a
story.

            This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s back story, as it were, the preface to her bohemian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>. Even in the bare-bones narration, it's fertile. Almost too fertile,
in fact--as open to selective interpretation as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rorschach</ENAMEX> test. Depending on
whom you consult, following her apprenticeship in suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolf</ENAMEX> became the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To The Lighthouse and The Waves</ENAMEX> , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stream-of-consciousness pioneer</ENAMEX> and a cool, ethereal priestess of high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modernism</ENAMEX>. Or the rage-filled victim of abuse and feminist crusader of A
Room of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Own</ENAMEX> . Or, to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>, a frivolous gossip. Luckily for
us, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> isn't especially invested in any of these eye-catching slants. She
accepts that all these versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX> are more or less fair. And she
believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s writing reflects a lifetime spent contemplating her
strange tangle of traits.

            For lack of a better word, this is the most lifelike
biography I've ever read. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> counts on our basic familiarity with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s
story, and this frees her up to tease it into all kinds of subtle themes in
much the same way you or I might retrospectively organize our lives under such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motley</ENAMEX> headings as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Under Reagan" or "The Period When I Was Especially</ENAMEX>
Close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>." A visceral early chapter on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s childhood
tells us what sensory data the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> would have absorbed: the constant
smell of cigars, the pale yellow shade covering the window that overlooked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX>. Later chapters calmly walk us through some of the more hotly debated
Woolfian themes, matching each exactly to its place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s life. Female
friendships supplied critical nurturing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> says, and the famous affair with
Vita Sackville-West was a thrill, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolf</ENAMEX> never saw herself as a strict
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sapphist</ENAMEX>." As for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard</ENAMEX>, he earned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s complete loyalty
by stoically caring for her during her breakdowns, but he comes across as
stiff, humorless, and inclined to unconsciously pull male rank.

            Maybe it's
the unusual non-mustiness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s approach, but I was struck by the number of
current concerns that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s life anticipates. Living at the mercy of her
quixotic brain chemistry, she took notes on her moods, observing when her head
felt "cool and quiet" or "sizzling." She was precociously attuned to the
interplay of mind and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, far more so than her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. One also wonders
whether, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX> were alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, she would join the hordes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
abandoning fiction for the memoir. Probably not: Her ambition, love of
make-believe, and need to experiment would have driven her back to the novel.
Yet she felt the impulse to tell her story directly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> guesses that it was
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolf</ENAMEX> predicted in advance the ridicule of her male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">literary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>) that she kept herself from doing so. Here is her
despairing diary entry after she visited a memoir <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and read a chapter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aloud</ENAMEX>: "I couldn't help figuring a kind of uncomfortable boredom on the part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>; to whose genial cheerful sense my revelations were at once mawkish
and distasteful. What ever possessed me to lay bare my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>!"

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> demonstrates brilliantly the centrality of
this issue of male censorship, real and perceived, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s writing. Growing
up in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolf</ENAMEX> felt perfectly comfortable writing like a smug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victorian patriarch</ENAMEX>. But she understood that a tone of cool authoritativeness
left no room for her childhood catastrophes, her anger at getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s
paltry education, her palpable delight in reading. To discuss such experiences
she needed a less omniscient voice, a new style--one that in its fragmentation
would become a hallmark of modernism. But she was afraid to go too far, to
alienate all the "genial cheerful" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> whose standards she continued to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internalize</ENAMEX>. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX> constantly seesaws in her writing between
revealing and concealing. To be perfectly honest, I think the tension hurt her
fiction. I've always admired her novels, but found the experience of reading
them frustratingly indirect, circular, dissociative. Now I begin to understand
why.

            On the
other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s back-and-forth led to insights that escaped the male
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modernists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s essays are badly undervalued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, and
she's right. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>," the defense of modernism she
delivered before a puzzled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>, seems, in retrospect,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wiser</ENAMEX> and more realistic than just about everything else on the subject. In
that essay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolf</ENAMEX> explained that she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX> and the rest had no
choice but to abandon baggy old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victorianism</ENAMEX>. Why? Because, as she famously
proposed, "on or about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>, human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> changed," and it was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s duty to explain this change to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. Note the humble attention to
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, not just to high art and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolf</ENAMEX> stood up
for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>, but she also understood if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> found her overweeningly
concerned with style, or found Eliot obscure, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> obscene, "a pimply
undergraduate." She knew that modernism was a work in progress, not a new
system to be defended to the death.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s hands, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s feminism becomes more radical and
more flexible than one might think. She was no dogmatist. She even thought
"feminist" was a "dead and corrupt word" now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had the right to earn a
living. But later in life she argued that it was not enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to get
rooms of their own in which to become towering, dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. She
challenged the ugly human desire to be towering and dominant. She went, as
always, to the question of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, wondering if there might be a moral
advantage in the centuries <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had spent as anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of no status.
She played with the notion of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Outsiders</ENAMEX> "without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, meetings,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, or any hierarchy, without so much as a form to be filled up, or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to be paid."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s supple "outsiderism"
might seem to have worn pretty well. But in the partisan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930s</TIMEX>, it was
dismissed as dotty and vague. She sank into depression. It didn't help that
fiction writing was becoming harder, and that war was approaching. Given that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s mind was beginning to cloud over again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> thinks that her decision to
kill herself by walking into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ouse</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day in the 1940s</TIMEX>, was, in its way, a
brave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. But it cast a shadow over her life. It made her story too readily
available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wanted to see her as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, or a crusader, or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> to art. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s biography reveals is much more interesting. Woolf
devoted herself to literature and believed in the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, but both
these passions were part of a humbler--and therefore grander--pursuit. Getting
down to "the essential thing" is how she put it when talking about literature.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Freedom</ENAMEX> from unreal loyalties" is the striking phrase in her late feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">essay Three Guineas</ENAMEX> . In either case, the goal was to see life a little
more clearly.

         
      
   
