
   
   
      
         
            The Other L-Word

            Are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> on a roll?
If you begin with the recent election to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Paul</ENAMEX>, a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libertarian</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>; note the emergence of cyberlibertarians as
a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX>; factor in the collapse of communism; and quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s admission that "the era of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is over," you have what
sounds like a compelling case. There are other signs as well: the rise of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato Institute</ENAMEX> as one of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX>; and the general
accrual of credibility to what, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, was a fringe-y movement of Ayn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> and risqué <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            Yet,
there is an equally strong argument to be made that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is only
moving toward libertarian-style minimalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in the same way that you
get closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> when you drive east to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Libertarian</ENAMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Browne</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 500,000</NUMEX> votes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. This
was an increase over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> but only a slight improvement upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX>
vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, and a far weaker performance than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>, whose aims are antithetical to those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX>, make
the plausible claim that it is they who are winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> and influence by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> now knows to eschew "big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> have also learned their lesson about
attempting to make government truly smaller.

            The appearance of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books counts as an entry in the
plus side of the ledger. Each attempts to make libertarianism more respectable
and popular. They are pitched, however, at different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>
is a conservative trying to persuade other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> that the absence of
restraint will in fact make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more moral. He rather reluctantly defends
the legalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, prostitution, and pornography, and concedes that
government has to play some more-than-minimal role. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boaz</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato Institute</ENAMEX>, sees libertarianism as neither conservative nor liberal,
and aims to convert everyone. But while he is more ecumenical, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boaz</ENAMEX> is far more
extreme. If you insist on keeping national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> or old-age pensions, he has
some advice on the least bad way to run these things--but, given his druthers,
he wouldn't run them at all.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s more laconic account is based upon a
classical liberal argument: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> is bad; cooperation is good; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>; ergo, the only legitimate functions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are to enforce
voluntary agreements, and to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and fraud. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> accepts, though,
that there also exist limited "public goods." The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> he names are
environmental protection and education. These exceptions to the rule of the
minimal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are probably necessary to make libertarianism palatable to
mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. The problem is that they require an admission--which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> never makes directly--that decisions made by a democratic government
within the boundaries of a constitution are not merely "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>" but also
"cooperation," albeit with a certain degree of legitimate coercion.

            In an
attempt to distinguish those public purposes that are tolerable from those that
aren't, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> posits that, to be valid, public goods either have to be
"nonexclusive"--interventions from which everyone benefits--or else must arise
to counter "externalities," costs passed on to others that, in practical terms,
cannot be compensated, as in the case of the chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">incinerator</ENAMEX> that pollutes
the air. What this scheme leaves unclear is why education and the environment
are valid public goods while other efforts he opposes--insuring elderly people
against poverty, say, or providing national health insurance--are not.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> and the environment are not purely nonexclusive goods. Some people
who either don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or who don't like to visit national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>--or
both--will be taxed to pay for them. And if the standard of nonexclusivity is
not absolute, then programs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> rejects, such as welfare and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, can
reasonably qualify. Anyone may fall upon hard times, and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> anticipate
being around long enough to benefit from nationalized health care for the
elderly.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s next strategy is to try a series of more pragmatic
arguments against government action. To show how little sense regulations make,
he proposes a thought experiment. Why not give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> a choice, he asks,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> whether to use regulated or unregulated products (unregulated products,
he stipulates, would have to be labeled as such). This merely demonstrates that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> has failed to understand his own argument about externalities as a basis
for public goods. The point of regulation is not merely to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>,
but to protect innocent <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> would be better off
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> gave them the right to buy appliances built by polluting
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> and low-cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor. (In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> already can, so long as
the pollution and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor are foreign and not domestic.) These regulations
exist for the benefit of those who live downstream from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who would otherwise be working inside it.

            Or, to
take an example of regulation employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, consider the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55-mile</NUMEX>-per<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-hour</TIMEX>
speed limit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> says there is no reason to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from harming
themselves. But speed limits don't just prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who willingly take the
risk of driving faster and more dangerously from hurting themselves. They
improve the odds for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the back seat, and for the safe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> in
the opposite lane, whom the reckless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> might plow into. With this example,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> undercuts himself in another way. He says regulation only gets more
onerous over time. But the national speed limit is an example of precisely the
opposite point. In most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> you can now drive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65 or 70</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeways</ENAMEX>. Like
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> high-dudgeons himself into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeane Kirkpatrick</ENAMEX>
position of ascribing historical inevitability to a trend that is actually in
the midst of reversal.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> involves himself in more serious
contradictions by drawing in arguments from his earlier books, each of which
presents a different case against public action to fight poverty. In Losing
Ground (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>), the work that made him famous, he contended that government
anti-poverty programs had done much to create the underclass. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curve</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), he said that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--namely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>--were genetically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inferior</ENAMEX>, a condition that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could do nothing about. In What It
Means to Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> , he says government intervention is morally
wrong.

            He means these arguments to
be mutually reinforcing: Government social programs don't work; they can't work
on account of human nature; and if by chance they do work, they're morally
unjustified anyhow. But this triple argument in the triple alternative actually
obliterates itself. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> contends that government
can't really help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. In the version of that argument given in What It
Means , he asserts that "most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> interventions are ineffectual"
because "modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> has the inertia of a ponderous freight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>." But if
government can't reroute the freight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> in a better direction, it's hard to
see how it can derail it. The metaphor undermines the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Losing Ground</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who writes that "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">u</ENAMEX>]ntil the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> began masking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> costs created by large numbers of fatherless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, civilized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> everywhere stigmatized illegitimacy." The "futility"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thesis</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can't help--and the "perversity" thesis--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> makes
problems worse instead of better--are at odds. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can't do anything,
how can it do so strongly the opposite of what it intends?

            Dimly
aware of this problem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> brings in a more sweeping illegitimacy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thesis</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is unjustified--to trump all the others. But this exposes
his underlying bias, which casts doubt on the critiques of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in both
Losing Ground and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murrays</ENAMEX> play a kind
of fugue throughout this book. In fact, there seems to be a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Murray</ENAMEX>
struggling to get out. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX> who says late in the book
that he half-supports the idea of a negative income tax--a guaranteed income
for everyone. This would seem to violate all the aforementioned principles. It
would create a powerful incentive (of the kind attacked in Losing
Ground ) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not to work; it would be an attempt to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> says can't be helped anyway; and it would certainly
violate What It Means to Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> 's admonition against forcing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to pay for dubious public goods. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> likes about the idea is
that it would finally discharge society's obligation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
underclass. They might not be better off, but they would have to quit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bellyaching</ENAMEX>. Combined with a new, heartfelt attack on civil-rights laws (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Murray</ENAMEX>
says bad, prejudicial discrimination is inseparable from good, economically
sensible discrimination), this passage leaves one with the sense that in
declaring himself a libertarian, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> has not yet removed the final veil.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boaz</ENAMEX> has written a more stimulating, more consistent,
and more dogmatic book. After a long history of libertarian ideas, he proposes
a version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s basic argument, which he calls the "nonagression
axiom"--no one can use force against anyone else. That's it. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boaz</ENAMEX> draws no exception for public goods. He does not pander to political
reality by accepting large expenditures for national defense, environmental
regulation, or publicly funded education. He does not believe in national parks
("private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stewards</ENAMEX>" will exercise "proper stewardship"). Nor does he believe in
military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">conscription</ENAMEX> in wartime ("[t]he libertarian believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will
voluntarily defend a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> worth defending").

            Though
this version of libertarianism seems to flirt with anarchism, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boaz</ENAMEX> isn't
worried about disarray. In the absence of malign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> intervention, there
will emerge what he calls "spontaneous order." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boaz</ENAMEX>'s model for this is the
Internet. He neglects, of course, the fact that the Internet began life as a
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> project. But the real question Boaz begs is why the laws he
thinks are necessary for society to function, including fair chunks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>, count as "spontaneous" and good while everything else is defined
as coercion. Capitalism may arise spontaneously, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> is as
much a man-made construct as the food-stamp program.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, it is futile to argue with this
view. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boaz</ENAMEX> has worked out every possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">detail</ENAMEX> of his libertarian heaven in an
utterly comprehensive and slightly mad way. He takes pains to say he is not
offering a plan for a perfect society, merely a "framework for utopia" (the
phrase is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Nozick</ENAMEX>'s). But his heart is clearly with the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
philosopher Lao-tzu, who wrote: "Without law or compulsion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would dwell in
harmony."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, too, is afflicted
with millenarianism. "That <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is not the land of universal plenty it
should have become is for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX>, including me, the source of our
deepest anger about what big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has done to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," he writes at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point. He offers instead "a society that is prosperous and virtuous, but
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that is exciting and fun as well." I was reminded of the famous passage
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> writes that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> future, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> will spend part of
his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day</TIMEX> fishing, part writing poetry, and only part working at his lathe. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Marx</ENAMEX>
believed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would wither away. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Libertarians</ENAMEX> believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> must wither
it. But really, their utopias are not so different. They share a wishful vision
of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perfectibility</ENAMEX> dressed up as an idea of justice.

         
      
   
