
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prosecution Never Rests</ENAMEX>

            There is no such thing as
eternal life in politics--unless, that is, one is lucky enough to secure
appointment as an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. In that case, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is free to
investigate more or less whatever catches his fancy, for as long as he likes,
spending as much of the public's money as he deems necessary. The passing of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">petty</ENAMEX> scandal, the resignation of a target, even a change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> is
no obstacle, as we know from the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barnacle-encrusted investigators</ENAMEX> still
hanging on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, who has been poking into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>,
is the least of them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> is still deciding whether to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecute Henry Cisneros</ENAMEX>, the former housing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, for understating
payments to an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>. Another has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> trying to nail
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">long-departed Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX> for accepting free football
tickets from a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. There's even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, holed up somewhere in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, who is still on the verge of cracking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Housing and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Development</ENAMEX> scandal, which dates from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> and more than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX>.

            
Independent counsels go on forever because they can--no one has the power to
fire them--and because they have strong incentives to do so. An ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> may decide to forgo charges so that he can devote his energies to a
case that is more important and easier to win. But, for the independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, there is no other case. Were he to announce that his scandal didn't
justify criminal proceedings after all, he would be declaring himself a failure
who had wasted the public's time and money. After he returned to his law
practice in the sticks, no one would ever hear from him again. Much better to
keep digging, declare that indictments are just around the corner, and hold off
on releasing that final report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a few months</TIMEX> longer.

            In retrospect, it seems obvious that combining these
structural pressures with the lugubrious personality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Walsh</ENAMEX> was a
recipe for zombification. Coming out of semiretirement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 years old</TIMEX> when he was handed responsibility for bringing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> scandal. For an ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
had been frustrated in his career, the appointment was a heaven-sent extra
chance, and it appeared at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to be a bit of brilliant casting. In his
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-piece suits and high, starched collars, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> looked like a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, radiating an unflinching,
humorless rectitude. He was the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> cowboy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX>.
The problem is that the image was too close to reality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> was a maddening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plodder</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stickler</ENAMEX> for detail, with no ability to play politics or work the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>. Faced with a public-relations challenge that might have daunted the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">seasoned Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>, he responded the only way he knew how, by
trudging onward. Like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pit bull</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>, he clung to the trousers long after
the leg was gone.

            The leaden
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">account Walsh</ENAMEX> has produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade later</TIMEX> reflects in microcosm most
of the foibles that afflicted his investigation. As a piece of writing, it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repetitive</ENAMEX>, unfocused, and confusing. It feels like it goes on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>.
There are no surprises and no original ideas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>'s theory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>
scandal--that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> tried to do an end run
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>--is not very novel. But rather than presenting his case
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> remains obsessed with the minutiae of what went wrong when
he tried to make his case in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Matters of subdoctoral interest, such as
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s battle for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Hakim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX>-bank-account
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>, fill chapter upon chapter. In his litigious thickets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> loses
sight of the question of why anyone should still care.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> quite rightly points out that his
investigation was undermined at the outset by the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>'s decision to grant immunity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House National</ENAMEX>
Security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Poindexter</ENAMEX> who, along with the conveniently deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Casey</ENAMEX>, appear to have been the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> in the plot.
Despite the extraordinary efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to insulate themselves
from the immunized testimony, the unavoidable tainting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>'s
case provided a basis for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> to throw out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North's</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poindexter</ENAMEX>'s convictions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>'s first mistake, which he acknowledges, was not
pitching a fit to try to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> from granting immunity to the chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protagonists</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mistake, which he does not acknowledge, was failing to
admit defeat after the grants of immunity predictably ruined his case. Once the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poindexter</ENAMEX> convictions were thrown out, there was little point in his
trying to lock up other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> whose behavior, while far from exemplary, was
neither venal nor as outrageous as that of the ringleaders going free.

            It is at
the point when the initial convictions were reversed, around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>
seems to lose touch with his judiciousness, if not his deliberateness. Instead
of conceding, he redoubles his efforts. As he keeps missing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, he
takes aim at less and less compelling ones, desperate to convict someone,
anyone, of something. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> after the scandal broke--he
contemplates charging former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Shultz</ENAMEX> with lying to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. This was simply foolish. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shultz</ENAMEX>, who opposed the original
arms-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> deal, was the closest thing to a conscience inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
administration's foreign-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. Belatedly persuaded that he can't convict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shultz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> decides to go after former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caspar Weinberger</ENAMEX>
instead for concealing the existence of some of his personal notes. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shultz</ENAMEX>, was far from a black hat in the affair; he too had
opposed the arms-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> deal. Indicting him was an exercise in
prosecutorial pique, doomed to fail. After the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> election, when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame-duck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> pardons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> is truly overtaken by rage, and
considers going after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-president</ENAMEX> himself for obstructing justice. By the
end of his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> has unwittingly painted himself as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahab</ENAMEX> without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flailing</ENAMEX> after targets large and small in his attempt to vindicate his
effort.

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> never went after the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> of
all--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. Though he was still thinking about indicting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> in late
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> never found effective proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was lying when he testified
that he hadn't known about the diversion of profits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contras</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>'s
theory--again, not a novel one--is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> successfully
constructed a "firewall" to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> from being implicated in the
scandal. If this conspiracy worked the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> thinks it did, it has yet
to crack. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> must have known about the diversion
because he chose to persist with the policy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>, even though
most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> were not released in exchange for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> that were shipped to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. This is a pretty slim reed to hang <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
on; he was clearly obsessed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>, and clung to any hope of setting
them free. And indeed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> were released in apparent conjunction
with the arms sales, which does not constitute an overwhelming failure, however
wrongheaded the arms-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> policy may have been.

            With hindsight, the whole
issue of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> "knew" seems more a metaphysical question than a legal
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> may well have been informed of the diversion at some point,
he was probably sufficiently gaga by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987 and 1988</TIMEX> that he did not really hold
the information in his head in any meaningful way. Interviewed on videotape as
a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poindexter</ENAMEX> trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> presented a sorry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spectacle</ENAMEX>, unable to recall his own foreign policy beyond generalities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>
doesn't seem to grasp that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> is losing it. He clings to the maddening
inconsistencies in the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s answers as if they actually meant
something. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> flies to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> to grill him one more time.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> points at sights outside the window and tries to remember irrelevant
anecdotes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>. This is the only
poignant moment in the book; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> has evidently let go. Perhaps now that he's
set his frustrations down in a book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Walsh</ENAMEX> will be able to do the
same.

         
      
   
