
   
   
      
         
            Stuff and Nonsense

             

            Sometimes art's just not
enough. There's a new fashion in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> exhibitions: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accessorize</ENAMEX>. We're seeing
fewer shows like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cezanne</ENAMEX> retrospective at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, which
merely assemble great pictures, unembellished by catchy themes, related
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objects</ENAMEX>, documentary materials, or voluminous explanatory texts. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> increasingly feel the itch to interpret, not only with words but with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objects</ENAMEX> and illustrations that "explain" the art and give it "context."

            A few recent examples:

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of</ENAMEX>
Art's "Rembrandt/Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>," displaying drawing materials and printmaking
tools of the type used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rembrandt</ENAMEX>, as well as photos and bios of Rembrandt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and radiographs showing the underpainting in real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rembrandts</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wannabes</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine Arts</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Singleton Copley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>" (at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milwaukee Art Museum</ENAMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25</TIMEX>) intersperses the art with colonial furniture, silver
(including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX> teapot similar to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Copley</ENAMEX>'s famous
portrait), and costumed mannequins "suggesting the coherence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copley</ENAMEX>'s work
in the cultural environment of pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary Boston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Splendors of Ancient Egypt"</ENAMEX> (through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 7</TIMEX>), recreating a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pharaoh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial chamber</ENAMEX> and providing "a taste of the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Karnak</ENAMEX>
experience--using mirrors and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> massive columns to completely surround
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> with the magnificence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>." To add an authentic desert
touch, real sand was dumped on the floor along one wall.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> used to visit art
museums to look at art. Great paintings on the walls, superb sculptures on
their pedestals--what more could you ask? The thirst for detailed information
on the art's significance or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s life and times was best slaked before
or after. Outside intervention just interfered with the intimate communication
between artwork and art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>.

            Not any
more. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mississippi Arts Pavilion</ENAMEX>,
there's a growing sense that art can't communicate on its own. A new
buzzword--"interpretive design"--means that art exhibitions must be laden with
text and context. Curators divert us from art with an array of related
artifacts or documents from the period, as if too much aesthetic concentration
might tax our attention span. The creative process itself is demystified
through displays of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>' working tools and illustrations of artistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technique</ENAMEX>, as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winslow Homer</ENAMEX>
show. (The show has traveled to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>, where it will stay until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22</TIMEX>,
without these supplementary materials.)

            Is there a problem here? Not if you think an art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
should be like a history <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, treating art as a cultural artifact that
illustrates the story of a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, period, and place. But for those
of us who cherish art for art's sake, gussying it up with photos, paint
samples, and teapots merely trivializes and distracts.

            The trend
toward interpretive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">installation</ENAMEX>, aimed at broadening art's appeal by expanding
public understanding, paralleled the transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>-going from
serious cultural pursuit to highbrow entertainment. Efforts to make information
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> art (as well as art itself) more accessible were strongly encouraged by
exhibitions were distinguished by their elaborate wall panels--educational
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">maps</ENAMEX>, photomurals, stenciled treatises--which competed with the objects
themselves for space and attention. One early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of this trend, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, complained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEH</ENAMEX> "tends to lose sight of the fundamental purpose of an art exhibition, which
is not to illustrate history but to allow an art work to be understood and
enjoyed as a work of art."

            
Next came the burble of taped audio guides,
filling our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> with instructions on what to see and think, while inhibiting
personal response. This also suppressed civilized conversation with our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">companions</ENAMEX>, who were similarly encased in electronic earmuffs. The latest audio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guides</ENAMEX> have gone <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and digital: "Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>" electronically beamed
up by recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum-goers</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Nimoy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morgan Freeman</ENAMEX>. The newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX>-in-your-pocket are lightweight CD-ROM
based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can punch in the numbers on wall labels,
accessing commentary on whatever interests them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> enjoy these
cybertoys: Some exhibitions where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> tote around the latest electronic
gadgetry are beginning to resemble cellular-phone-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' conventions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
also enjoy shows that make them feel they are not just gazing at the products
of a distant culture but, for a brief time, are actually a part of that milieu,
roaming about an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pyramid</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. Such
cultural tourism has become the specialty of a new breed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insta-museum</ENAMEX>, built
solely to imbue foreign masterpieces with glitz and mystique. In addition to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida International Museum</ENAMEX>, other such blockbuster <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> include the
Wonders exhibition series in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mississippi Arts Pavilion</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>. Before the opening of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palaces</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>" exhibition
(through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> artisans painstakingly transformed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mississippi Arts Pavilion</ENAMEX> into lavishly appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> adapted from the homes
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czars</ENAMEX>, fitted out with authentic paintings and furnishings.

            Virtual-reality exhibitions
go <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step further: They attempt to create the you-are-there sensation without
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty Conservation Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> recently sponsored
a virtual-reality recreation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Nefertari</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, which purports
to let cyberexplorers "look at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3200-year-old</TIMEX> wall paintings ... without
fear of damaging the fragile artwork." This cartoonish cultural video game can
now be navigated at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum SoHo</ENAMEX>, and, perhaps more fittingly, at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Epcot Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virtual Pompeii</ENAMEX>" recently had a glitch-ridden
run at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.H. de Young Museum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>; and a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Networks</ENAMEX>, plans to work with major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> to produce a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great Civilizations</ENAMEX>"
series, which will display "the finest archaeological works of art, together
with reconstructions and virtual reality visits to ancient sites."

            All of this surely will draw
the curious hoards, a benefit that few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> can ignore given the
unreliability of outside funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Museums</ENAMEX> must rely increasingly on
self-generated income--the kind that comes from admissions, memberships,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. But as the seductive trappings gain prominence,
something else is obscured. It's the art.

             

             

         
      
   
