
   
   
      
         
            Deadbeat Dads

            "I had done this before,"
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Simpson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lost Father</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>), as she sets
off on her search for the mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who left home when she was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. "I was always doing things over again in my life," she reiterates, as if
to reassure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that she knows the territory looks familiar. It does. Like
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> is addicted to quests for lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>. Her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> book,
Anywhere But Here (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>), was the story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
unmoored by the absence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost Father</ENAMEX> , its sequel, had
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> seeking to rectify the situation, announcing, "I knew I hadn't
really done it right the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time." In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Regular Guy</ENAMEX> , her latest
novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> has yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> looking for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. The trouble is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> really did do it right the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time and, by now, she has gotten
rather tired.

            It's
fitting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> can't seem to stop herself, for what galvanized
Anywhere But Here was its obsession with obsessives. Upon her emergence
on the literary scene <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a decade ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> seemed like a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX> in reverse, a virtuosic ventriloquist for a compelling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Jewish</ENAMEX>,
nonurban, high-energy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> neurotic type. Her heroines were restless
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> absurdly full of optimism and fatally drawn to exoticism,
which presented itself in the form of an unreliable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX>. Abandoned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Atassi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Stevenson</ENAMEX> joined her magnificently deluded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Adele</ENAMEX>,
in a compensatory fantasy of escape and renewal. This pair of romantic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">provincials</ENAMEX> came from a hardscrabble rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gynocracy</ENAMEX>, and also from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">precincts</ENAMEX> of mythic caricature. An intense realist and a fierce satirist,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> turned this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> journey from small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> in
pursuit of fame and a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in the promised land (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>) into a
surreal odyssey of female frustration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adele</ENAMEX>, products of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">claustrophobic 1950s</ENAMEX>, fought and clung to each other and never found their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
With them, the classic search for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX> became a brilliantly
eccentric matrilineal comedy of no manners.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Regular Guy , Simpson</ENAMEX> apparently has concluded
that the time has come to be witheringly ironic, rather than comic, about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dream</ENAMEX>. No longer picaresque, the quest for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and fortune now aims
to be profound. So it is a famous <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>, rather than obscure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle American hicks</ENAMEX>, to whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> grants the chance to display a zealous
ambition born of delusory innocence. This elusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is no longer a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wanderer</ENAMEX> pursued by driven furies. He's the multimillionaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of a
biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter pair</ENAMEX> in pursuit of him are hippie
drifters, who whimper for their chance at legitimacy and reliable love where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adele</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX> howled and scratched.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Owens</ENAMEX>
is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year-old</TIMEX>, handsome, vegetarian, jean-clad driving force behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> that has become extremely successful extremely
quickly. He has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who is an obvious foil. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Kaskie</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cripple</ENAMEX> working slowly in comparative obscurity, trying to map a gene and
worrying about money and love. But otherwise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX> is surrounded mostly by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Chief among his many conquests is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olivia</ENAMEX>, his current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, a
beauty who enthralls him by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ramshackle mansion</ENAMEX> he's never bothered
to fix up and disappoints him by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> in her modest desire for a career no
greater than that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>.

            
And then out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX>' offbeat past appear his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary di Natali</ENAMEX>, whom he once urged
to get an abortion and has since done his best to forget. They've been living
truly on the fringe, in a succession of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">communes</ENAMEX> and finally alone in a tiny
cottage in the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> woods, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> has made sure never to
drop completely from sight. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX>, she sends a photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane to Owens</ENAMEX>,
who never acknowledges it. As the novel begins, she's preparing to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> by
herself in their rusty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, having laboriously and implausibly taught the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to drive.

            
Commenting on that nighttime drive over the mountains, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> perched
on a seat stacked with phone books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> writes, "The most terrible and
wondrous experience in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane di Natali</ENAMEX>'s life was over by the time she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>,
before she'd truly mastered the art of riding a bicycle." That's not what you
want to hear on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">336</NUMEX>-page novel in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>, a central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>,
will have many more experiences. And it's not as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> has expended much
effort on making the truck ride all that terrible or wondrous. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> here
plays omniscient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, and the poetic intensity and sure
rhythms that drove the monologues of her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel and still echoed in her
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> are gone. That vapid, sentimentalizing declaration about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>'s ride is
typical of the flaccid style she now favors, and what it says proves true: The
novel is all anticlimax.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> apparently meant to write an acerbic social
portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s post-postindustrial revolution, and of the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">countercultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> who lead it. But she can't summon up much
curiosity about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX>, who rarely rises above portentously ironic clichés. "He
was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX>," we learn early on, "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in the potential
accomplishments of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and, in a way he couldn't explain, proud." So we know
he's riding for a fall, professionally and personally (just as we know that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah</ENAMEX>--the most prominent of the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> whose roles in the book soon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peter</ENAMEX> out--will have a shot at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis</ENAMEX> might as well be, say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--you know, no neckties, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brainy employees</ENAMEX>, only the freshest fruit
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> in the machines. (Actually, the model for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX> is pretty clearly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>, who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.) It's hard even to figure out what the company
produces: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> gives us an acronym for a medically useful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LCSF</ENAMEX>, and
that's about it.

            Nor is it
clear why, exactly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX> gets ousted from power, except that that's what
happens to overconfident egotists even (or especially) when they flaunt a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX>, granola style. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX>' fate with his various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, it's
impossible to care--because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> doesn't. She indulges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX> the celebrity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> in endless narcissistic agonizing about who will be his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and gives
Owens the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> no emotional substance. His selfish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vacuity</ENAMEX> is, of course, the
point. Still, he's also supposed to have charisma and fascinating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">idiosyncrasies</ENAMEX>. (He drives fast, regularly runs out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, forgets
appointments, has lots of answering machines he ignores: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s idea of
big-shot oddity is not very odd.) But really, as the title warns, he comes
across as just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who's a jerk with chicks.

            
Why do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> put up with him? Since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> of this latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> isn't interesting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> might have found a story
in the social insecurity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are his hangers-on, and their
ambivalence about ambition. But the upward-mobility drama of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adele</ENAMEX> may
be a nearly impossible act to follow; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> don't even try. Again, that
seems to be the point. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adele</ENAMEX> brought the fiercest, most infantile needs
to maternity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> as mellow flower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. Where the steak- and
corn-fed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX> rushes down the road to rebellion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>, the wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">woods</ENAMEX>, becomes a conformist.

            Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
is made distinctive this time around, except in the most heavy-handed way.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> continues to eat her scabs, even as she's being civilized. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> takes up
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gentle bird</ENAMEX>-saving loser.) Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Olivia</ENAMEX> fits right into the role of
the beautiful-blonde-who-isn't-really-a-bimbo. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s dependence and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deference</ENAMEX> as they maneuver for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX>' attention (and money), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX>' domineering
response to his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olivia</ENAMEX>'s defiance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>--all are
presumably meant to suggest, with due irony, that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, plus ça

               change . ... But that is not a very original moral, and there aren't
nearly enough sharp fin-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-siècle observations to rejuvenate it. It is,
however, a motto that all too accurately applies to this novel itself.

         
      
   
