
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heaven</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giambattista Tiepolo</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1696-1770</TIMEX>), the last of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Venetian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>--those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> of color and
suave worldliness--was the supreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> of ceilings and skies. A proper
appreciation of his work can give you a pain in the neck. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and
palaces around his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, and then, as his fame spread, as far afield
as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dresden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> was without peer in executing the tricks that
make for a believable scene in the heavens: the figures foreshortened as if
seen from below, the sturdy cloudbanks, the shades of pink and blue that draw
the eye toward the infinite. Perched so often on scaffolding as he painted,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> rather naturally developed a fascination for things that hover and fly,
or flutter and fall.

            For the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next few months</TIMEX>, in celebration of the master's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">300 th</NUMEX> birthday, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX> will host <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no fewer than four</NUMEX> exhibitions devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s work
and to that of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>. Since ceilings and wall frescoes don't travel
well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> have had to rely on portable paintings and works on paper.
Fortunately, such was the zeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> that many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">finest</ENAMEX> works are in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">magnificent horde</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>. Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s larger works were destroyed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, so his vivid oil sketches (or modelli ), prized by
connoisseurs, are the best record we have of them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s holdings have been
augmented with masterpieces from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, and the result
is a dazzling and dizzying show.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> was not one to work, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>, in solitary
secrecy. Having grown up in a working-class <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">quarter</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> was
apprenticed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic painter</ENAMEX>. He seems to have thought of painting
as a trade like any other, surrounding himself with a workshop of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>,
including his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domenico</ENAMEX>. (The resulting issues of attribution are a
nightmare for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>.) When he worked on commissions all over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, he was
said to prefer the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workmen</ENAMEX> to that of the wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX>
who had hired him.

            The
interlocked worlds of above and below--in the realms of religion, myth, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>--were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s great subject. He lived in the stable prosperity of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian Republic</ENAMEX> and died before the revolutionary upheavals of the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter of the 18 th century</TIMEX> that toppled so many hierarchies.
Consequently, he has often been dismissed as a well-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">upholder</ENAMEX> of the status
quo. But while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s work has none of the dark premonitions of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Francisco de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goya</ENAMEX>, there is an intriguing precariousness that sets in from time to time in
his compositions, especially when high and low come unexpectedly into contact.
Paintings that seem at first sight to be sober treatments of an enduring order
turn out on closer inspection to have pockets of deep pathos or subtle
humor.

            
Though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> doubted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiepolo's</ENAMEX> spiritual conviction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> make a strong case that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> was not just a brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decorator</ENAMEX> of sumptuous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>. His
pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> are particularly moving, especially when their attention is
wrenched suddenly upward. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Francis Receiving the Stigmata</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1767-69</TIMEX>), the saint cranes his neck (as we do) to see the weird God hovering
above him: a round sun with a human face and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> that shoots
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX> laser beams down into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX>. Since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francis</ENAMEX>
narrative mentioned a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-winged seraph in the sky and another a crucified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>--a virtuoso in depicting wings--fudged and deployed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> in the shape of a cross.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> had a mischievous
wit--to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> of the lively catalog are particularly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attentive</ENAMEX>--and it is given free play in his secular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, such as the very
different joining of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">divine</ENAMEX> and human realms in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">The Rape of Europa</ENAMEX> (c.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1720-22</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Europa</ENAMEX> sits innocently on the back of a tame bull while a handmaiden
tends to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>'s unruly hair. Europa little suspects that the bull is
really <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>, about to run off and have his way with her. Meanwhile, from
high above, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cupid</ENAMEX> pisses from a passing cloud onto <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thunderbolts</ENAMEX>--surely a novel (if ineffectual) way to cool a god's ardor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>, by giving <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europa</ENAMEX> the features of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (whom he had furtively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wooed</ENAMEX> and married when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>), placed himself in the role of the divine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bull</ENAMEX>--a gesture worthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cupid</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX> shower is nothing compared to the literal shower of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Danaë</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1734-36</TIMEX>), one of the gems of the show. According to myth, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
Acrisius, hearing the prediction that he'd be killed by his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>,
locked up his only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Danaë</ENAMEX>, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>. But gods move in mysterious ways,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX> (at it again!) appeared on the scene and poured down a fructifying
flood of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> coins on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Danaë.</ENAMEX> As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> imagines him, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX> is a withered
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, hunched, goatlike, as the coins spew forth from his crotch. An old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crone</ENAMEX> who attends <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Danaë</ENAMEX> tries to catch some of the loot on a salver. The
histrionic scene, the stage effects of which might have arisen from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s
involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venetian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, suggests sex for pay, with the crone in the
role of procuress. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perseus</ENAMEX>, somehow conceived in that metallic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">torrent</ENAMEX>, accidentally felled his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather Acrisius</ENAMEX> with a discus.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">errant discus</ENAMEX>, as it happens, also killed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyacinth</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>, in his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of Hyacinth</ENAMEX> (c. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1752-53</TIMEX>), took his
cue from a contemporary retelling of the myth and updated the murderous missile
to a tennis ball. In the foreground of the huge painting, next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyacinth</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corpse</ENAMEX>, are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two innocuous</NUMEX>-looking balls and a racket, while the net hangs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slackly</ENAMEX> in the background. The appalled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX> makes an operatic gesture of
horror over his muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, while a satyr and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot</ENAMEX> (symbols of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">forbidden lust</ENAMEX>) stare sardonically down at the proceedings. Even if the picture
had a private meaning for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> (who had just lost his male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>), it's
obvious that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX> enjoyed toying with the tragicomic possibilities of a
fatal tennis match.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s
wit evidently found an echo in the popular commedia dell'arte <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> of
Venetian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street theater</ENAMEX>, a taste for the topsy-turvy he shared with his son
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domenico</ENAMEX>. They took particular pleasure in the antics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punchinello</ENAMEX>, a
long-nosed clown with white clothes and a cone hat. In a show largely devoted
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domenico</ENAMEX>'s work, one can see a host of Punchinellos
felling a tree (perhaps one of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Napoleonic</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that marked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>'s
progress through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>) or pompously burying one of their number. They also
populate a related show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pierpont Morgan Library</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tiepolo and His</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Circle: Drawings in American Collections</ENAMEX>," which showcases some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domenico</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punchinello</ENAMEX> with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punchinello</ENAMEX> riding a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">donkey</ENAMEX>). And at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> are, yes, even more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punchinellos</ENAMEX> (these being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giambattista's</ENAMEX>), such as the lively <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punchinellos Cooking</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gnocchi</ENAMEX> . These figures possess a magical, carnivalesque aura (despite their
unfortunate resemblance, when seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, to white-robed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klansmen</ENAMEX>). In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commedia dell'arte</ENAMEX>, where lowlife <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> mingled with aristocratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>, one's social position was no more secure than those tumbling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.

            
The sheer range of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giambattista Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s work
comes across in these multifaceted exhibitions at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>, and
no one could complain of the variety of the objects on view. I would like to
have seen a few more of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s portraits (the greatest of which, depicting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Venetian</ENAMEX> naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> with a mutilated hand, could not leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>), and not
quite so many sketches for ceilings. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>'s vision, like Rilke
contemplating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> leaves, was of a world where everything is falling: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And</ENAMEX>
yet, there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> who holds this falling with infinite softness in his hands."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> leaves these gravity-defying masterpieces with a lighter step,
expecting the sky to fill up momentarily with things that flutter and fly.

         
      
   
