
   
   
      
         
            Net Result

            Were it not
for a coin tossed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1962</TIMEX>, the Internet might not exist. The winner
of the toss, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Carl Robnett Licklider</ENAMEX> (or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lick</ENAMEX>,"
as he insisted on being called), got the top job at an obscure government
agency known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Command</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Research Division</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Research Projects Agency</ENAMEX> (ARPA), which was created after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sputnik</ENAMEX> to close the purported gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> science.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Licklider</ENAMEX> arrived, his
agency specialized in the sort of esoteric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> research that
could only be called "asinine" (his word, in fact). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> intelligence, for
instance, wanted to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s huge mainframe computers to detect
patterns of behavior among high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The idea was to feed
the computers bits of information like, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> drank two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">martinis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>," or, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kruschev</ENAMEX> isn't reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pravda</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX>,"
from which the computer was to deduce that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> were building a new
missile, or that some inner-circle coup was imminent, or whatever.

            This is a test
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word</ENAMEX>'s abilities.

            Licklider
got rid of the fanciful war games, substituting something that must have
sounded equally bizarre--the creation of an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergalactic Network</ENAMEX>." In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
short <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> on the job (he returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Licklider</ENAMEX> poured enough
money into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> to influence an entire generation of computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, of whom some would go on to invent video games, the mouse, the
metaphor of "windows" and "icons" and, of course, the Internet itself.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Licklider</ENAMEX>'s prescience stemmed from his pioneering research on
"time-sharing"--the then-unthinkable notion that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could
share a computer at the same time, through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>-sharing" had the
added benefit of letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get their hands on keyboards, which few of them
had ever done. Computer science up to that point had been dominated by
"batch-processing," a system believed to be maximally efficient, wherein
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">programmers</ENAMEX> wrote code at their desks, copied it onto stacks of cards with
holes punched into them, and handed them over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> who had a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priestlike</ENAMEX> say over who got to use the computer, and when.

            Considering his achievements, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C.R. Licklider</ENAMEX> may be the
most influential little-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the history of computer science. Katie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hafner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Lyon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where Wizards Stay</ENAMEX> 
               Up Late: The
Origins of the Internet , dedicate their book to him, although that,
unfortunately, is the grandest of their corrective gestures. The short <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> pages
they devote to his life do little more than summarize his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">résumé</ENAMEX>.

            This reflects a larger flaw
in the book. Hafner, a contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Markoff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cyberpunk: Outlaws and Hackers</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frontier</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and an assistant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX>, have written an epic technological history. Their story of
how the Internet was discovered is a blow-by-blow saga of how a single
engineering problem, in this case the construction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ARPANET</ENAMEX> (precursor to
the Internet), was solved. But the larger intellectual revolution undergirding
the Internet--the redefinition of the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
computers, which turned impersonal calculating machines into intimate tools for
everyday thought--earns only a few mentions in passing. There is merit to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hafner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX>'s narrowly focused approach. They've conducted extensive
interviews with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> involved, culled material from archives and
private collections, and revised the historical record where necessary.

            For
instance, they debunk the long-standing myth that the Internet was created as a
test to see if computer networks could be designed to survive a nuclear war.
Instead, as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hafner</ENAMEX> show, the Net was built because the federal
government needed a way for all the incompatible computers being used for
government research to communicate with each other. In a sense, the Internet
was the ultimate time-sharing project: a nationwide network capable of
connecting any sort of computer with another computer.

            
The logistics were daunting. How on earth were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to create connections between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX>, let alone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>, of
computers without running up a fortune in telephone bills? The answer, which
occupies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> of the book, is "packet switching," and it remains the
core of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s Internet. Instead of opening a direct connection with the
destination computer, messages are sent willy-nilly, chopped up into little
packets that are reassembled when they get to their destination.

            Hafner
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX> tell the story of how <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Baran</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, arrived independently at the notion of packet switching.
They trace the web of conversations that brought their ideas to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Taylor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Licklider</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> didn't have time to manage the
details of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ARPANET</ENAMEX> project, and hired one particularly brilliant graduate
student named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Roberts</ENAMEX> to do it for him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roberts</ENAMEX> assembled his fellow
graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, then gave them the
right to do more or less whatever they wanted. Perhaps the greatest mystery in
the history of the Internet is one about which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hafner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX> never bother to
speculate--how and why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, at the height of the backlash against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>, was persuaded to grant a bunch of longhaired, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tolkien</ENAMEX>-reading grad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> huge sums of money, without insisting on oversight. Whatever the
reason, it worked: The crucial design decisions were made at a series of
informal grad-student conferences, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1969</TIMEX>, a working connection
had been opened between a computer at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where Wizards Stay Up Late</ENAMEX>
describes the aftermath of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ARPANET</ENAMEX> project. We read about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
developed interactive games, created the first online discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, fought
over what technical standards to adopt, and ran headfirst into issues still
relevant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--privacy online, the appropriate use of computers, ownership of
software, how to govern the Internet. Once again, though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> don't
interpret the picture they're painting in such studious detail. The Internet,
barely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s hands in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, was hijacked by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, who seemed to be more interested in playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dungeons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dragons</ENAMEX> than
in using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> solely for research.

            How does the architecture of
the Internet reflect the strange counterculture these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> conjured up out
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> funds? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> who want a more complete picture should read two
other books: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Levy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>), which gives a still-fresh account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project MAC</ENAMEX> (not
coincidentally funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Licklider</ENAMEX>), an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> dominated by the "hacker
ethic"--the compulsive urge to explore and improve on things. (In that sense,
the Internet was the ultimate hack.) And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart Brand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> Cybernetic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frontiers</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>), which recounts how this generation of "computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>"
designed computer games based on science fiction and used the Internet to
fashion a universe of their own. Building the Internet was not simply about
building a better mousetrap; it was, for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX>, also about building a
better and smarter, and wildly utopian, world. That story remains to be
told.

         
      
   
