
   
   
      
         
            Lies the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doctor Told Us</ENAMEX>

            "We must live by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fictions</ENAMEX>--not just to find meaning in life but to make it bearable," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruno</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> once wrote. That idea inspired his most famous book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Uses</ENAMEX>
of 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enchantment</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>). In it, he celebrated the power of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tales
to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> handle the "inner conflicts" that confront us all on the road
to achieving a "unified personality." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> biographies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> have set
out to prove that he practiced what he preached to a degree no one dreamed.
First <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Sutton</ENAMEX> and now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Pollak</ENAMEX> expose the renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychoanalyst</ENAMEX> as a
compulsive teller of tall tales about his own life.

            The tale
of the untruthful therapist itself all but begs to be told as a didactic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">legend</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollak</ENAMEX> have eagerly obliged. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutton</ENAMEX>'s version is
sympathetic. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bettelheim: A Life and a Legacy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), she follows a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resourceful Hansel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> as he struggles to escape a dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viennese</ENAMEX> forest and
find fame in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, "dropping little white pebbles along his path." As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutton</ENAMEX>
carefully gathers up the pebbles, she explains how the trail of fabrications
helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> along his arduous way. Among the most important distortions
she exposes are: an invented psychology degree from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>;
pretended acquaintance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>; guardianship of an autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> whom his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in fact tended; unreliable accounts of his ordeals in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dachau</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buchenwald</ENAMEX>; and exaggerated claims of success as a benevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX> of
emotionally disturbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Shankman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthogenic School</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>. None of these prevents <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutton</ENAMEX> from honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>
as an unorthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudian</ENAMEX> whose creative relationship to facts was inseparable
from his intuitive genius and his great empathetic powers.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Pollak</ENAMEX>'s tale is nastier, more brutish, and
shorter. He was inspired to write his book by troubled curiosity about his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s experience under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s care at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthogenic School</ENAMEX>, an
experience that came to an end when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> died from a fall during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer</TIMEX>
vacation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> claimed that it had been suicide--"What is it about
these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollak</ENAMEX>?" he asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollak</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>--and a cloud
hung over the family thereafter. Not surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollak</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Bad Wolf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">huffing</ENAMEX> and puffing from the moment <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Creation of Dr.</ENAMEX> B begins. Pollak
seizes on the same central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fictions</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutton</ENAMEX> does, and itemizes every other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inaccuracy</ENAMEX>, or hint of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, that he is able to find--and he certainly looks
hard. Dr. B's slapping, punching, beating, and shaming of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> receive
especially thorough attention, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollak</ENAMEX> even accuses him of sexually abusing
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. (Where the brutality was overt, as it often was,
the evidence supports the charges, but where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollak</ENAMEX> relies on former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> of being fondled under the covers, who knows what to think?)
Interpretation is at a minimum throughout, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollak</ENAMEX> soon reduces his
all-powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">broth</ENAMEX> of pernicious, self-serving lies.

            Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutton</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollak's Bettelheim</ENAMEX> allegories--the renegade from the narrow
Freudian path and the total fraud--have obvious iconic appeal for our
post-psychoanalytic era. But both also miss his perplexing reality, the
ambiguity of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose life and work refuse to add up to a simple object
lesson. Again and again in his writings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> insisted that the daunting
task of "inner integration" was a developmental ordeal that could be mastered
with great struggle, and with the support of good stories. Yet, a "unified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">personality</ENAMEX>," whether admirable or despicable, is precisely what eluded him. As
for his writings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.W. Winnicott</ENAMEX> once commented in some exasperation that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> "is difficult to read simply because he says everything and there is
nothing to be said that one could be certain has not been said by him."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s made-up stories seem more
mysterious in their motivation than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollak</ENAMEX> cares to acknowledge. He believes
that each of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s enchantments had a self-aggrandizing public and
private use--as indeed many of them did. But what's puzzling is how often
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s stories about his past and about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthogenic School</ENAMEX> look like
subtle acts of self-sabotage. The wolf whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollak</ENAMEX> is so eager to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> had a
curious way of landing himself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX>.

            Thus, for
instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollak</ENAMEX> views <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s distorted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> credentials as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">megalomaniac</ENAMEX>'s forceful bid for authority in his new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s
bogus psychology degree neither did much to ingratiate him with the established
psychoanalytic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, nor was it meant to secure him the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthogenic School</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directorship</ENAMEX>, which he at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> refused. And the dubious account given by the
newly arrived ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">concentration-camp</ENAMEX> experiences--the article
that put him on the map in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--enmeshed him in controversy and
self-contradiction.

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Individual and Mass Behavior in Extreme Situations</ENAMEX>,"
published in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>,
Bettelheim suggested that his fellow camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> were soon reduced to "types
of behavior which are characteristic of infancy or early youth," playing into
the hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> rather than standing up to them. It was a sweeping
generalization, based on much less scientific observation than he claimed to
have done. (Pollak questions whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> could have sampled as many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> as he said he had, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> his anecdotes to be selective and
willfully misinterpreted.) Yet, even before the factual distortions were
suggested, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s argument was disconcerting on other grounds. His grim
message about a regressive human impulse to act childlike seemed to undermine
his simultaneous call for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>--especially since he emphasized that any
struggle by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis</ENAMEX> was pointless without outside help. As
debate about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> unfolded, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s initial renown as a heroic
witness gave way to cloudier repute as a blamer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pollak</ENAMEX> turns to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s career at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthogenic School</ENAMEX>, he indicts the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychoanalyst</ENAMEX> for wholesale abuse of power and implies a facile symmetry: This
camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> identified with the aggressors, and went on to become a Gestapo
figure in his own well-barricaded fortress. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> had quite a different
parallel in mind, which he outlined in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Schizophrenia as a Reaction to Extreme</ENAMEX>
Situations" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>). Severely disturbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, he
proposed, echoing his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> article; they were immured in "mortal anxiety"
and overwhelmed by hostile circumstances, above all by their rejecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>.
He then assumed the mantle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Is Not</ENAMEX>

               Enough (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Truants From Life</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>), The Empty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortress</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Home</ENAMEX> for 
               the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>), he painted
a portrait of an intense therapeutic milieu in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superhumanly</ENAMEX> dedicated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counselors</ENAMEX> used compassion and empathy to help such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> rejoin the world.
He announced remarkable rates of success with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">autistic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. But, as Pollak
proves on the basis of school records, reality didn't measure up. There were
far fewer demonstrably autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--or cures--than Bettelheim
advertised.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s penchant for heroic narrative
certainly did bolster his popular image, though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollak</ENAMEX> gives ample evidence
that his insistence on blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and claiming miracles also invited
skepticism from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX>. As one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> at the
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commented</ENAMEX>, "I felt like saying, 'You don't have to exaggerate, Dr. B, it
was dramatic enough.' " Inside the walls of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthogenic School</ENAMEX>, the effect
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s mythomania was clearly destructive. His fantasy of omnipotence
seems to have contributed to a loss of control. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had been the
charismatically <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> "superego" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> (as he called himself) during its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX> could be--and often was--a brutal id by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. The outside world
got a bewildering glimpse of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-sided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettelheim</ENAMEX>, too. At the very moment
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Empty Fortress</ENAMEX> was clinching his reputation as a nonauthoritarian
liberator of autistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--in other words, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX> era--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ranting Bettelheim</ENAMEX> seized the podium as an authoritarian castigator of
rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. His finger-wagging surprised many, especially his numerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left-leaning admirers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> committed suicide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, evidently having found life unbearable,
despite (or because of) his fictions. But making sense of his active, prolific
career as a therapist and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> was difficult, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnicott</ENAMEX> pointed out, even
before his career as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> was uncovered. Bettelheim was criticized for
reductive psychoanalytic thinking and applauded for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">psychoanalytic</ENAMEX> dogma. He was accused of lacking "a social psychology that
recognized the powerful influence of the social environment in changing the
individual," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Marcus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Rosenberg</ENAMEX> put it in an issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychoanalytic Review</ENAMEX> devoted to him; and he was celebrated for
introducing just such a perspective. He was attacked for being uniquely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsystematic</ENAMEX> in his methods; but he was praised for his one-of-a-kind clinical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powers</ENAMEX>. He was hailed for his "life-affirming" approach to the traumas of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>; he was condemned and commended for his emphasis on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mankind</ENAMEX>'s destructive impulses. In his insistent quest for "meaning in life,"
Bettelheim was nearly impossible to pin down, and the addition of so many
slippery stories certainly doesn't help.

            
"But one must read him because he can be
exactly right, or more nearly right than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnicott</ENAMEX> persisted,
and this lack of definitiveness seems fitting in summing up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose own
most interesting verdicts resisted definitiveness about human dilemmas.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> had no overarching theory, but he had an abiding preoccupation:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> and the ambivalence it inspires. His humanistic intuitions about the
difficulties and possibilities inherent in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX>' struggles with their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' struggles with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, a mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>'s struggle
with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, and the self's struggle with itself were perhaps not
profoundly original. But they spoke to widespread social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, and during
an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> marked by its unthinking reliance on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, he made a point of
speaking neither as an obfuscating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> nor as a simplifying self-help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bettelheim</ENAMEX> believed grandiosely in being a guide, but he had
fundamentally humble guidance to offer: that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, as in the beginning
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his favorite phrases), one can hope to grow only by endeavoring to be
one's own guide. He evidently found no well-marked route to follow himself.

         
      
   
