
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> Phooey

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Jack</ENAMEX> came down.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> played "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God Save the Queen</ENAMEX>" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last time--although, given the
occasion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lyrics ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Country 'Tis of Thee</ENAMEX>") seemed more
appropriate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> looked suitably dour, boarded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britannia</ENAMEX> , and
departed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. He shall not return.

            No one
throws a ceremony like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, but did the coverage of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>
"handover" have to be so breathless? Will the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
really be remembered as one of the great events of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>?
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A month later</TIMEX>, the event already seems forgotten. The death of colonialism
should be ranked among humanity's greatest accomplishments of the waning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, but the hard work was done at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>--an event that
seems secure in its place in the history books even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>
wasn't there to report it.

            In this atmosphere of hyperbole, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Theroux</ENAMEX>'s Kowloon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tong</ENAMEX>: A Novel of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> takes a refreshingly small-scale approach. The
novel is an unabashed attempt to capitalize on the hype surrounding the
handover, but it succeeds by steadfastly refusing to indulge in majesty.
Instead of princes and beefeaters, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theroux</ENAMEX> gives us a circumscribed tale about
the fleecing of a dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> by an unscrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>
from mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. It is a tonic for the cloying coverage of the event
itself.

            I admit to
having been suspicious of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kowloon Tong</ENAMEX> , a novel prepared for an event
rather than responding to it. The publishing world is fond of anniversaries,
but the notion of creating a novel to commemorate an event before it happens
seems especially fishy. Great novels are topical only in a subtler and grander
sense. Imagine if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Melville</ENAMEX>'s seafaring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1851</TIMEX> had focused on
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's Cup</ENAMEX> race <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, or if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implicated Gatsby</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teapot Dome</ENAMEX> scandal.

            
To my surprise, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kowloon Tong</ENAMEX>
works because the match of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and subject is so good. Though born in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theroux</ENAMEX> is a passionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissector</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> character, having
spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theroux</ENAMEX> finds the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> most hilarious when
indulging in the rituals of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> ("dark comedy and absurdity," he calls it).
He also delights in exploring the limits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> stiff upper lip,
relishing opportunities to see what indignities a subject of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> can
suffer and still say "mustn't grumble." And while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theroux</ENAMEX> has never been noted
for his celebration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> of human kindness--at his worst, he is so
unrelentingly peeved with others that one wonders why he bothered to write
about them--he does have an eye for the differences among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peoples</ENAMEX>, and a shrewd understanding of the irrational annoyance those
differences provoke.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> handover creates the ideal subject for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theroux</ENAMEX>. Clashes of race and
politics are exacerbated by the emotional intensity of a deadline that everyone
thinks historical, though for different reasons. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theroux</ENAMEX>'s own sympathy lies
with those who fled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> but are being denied a chance to rule
themselves in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. (In case his fiction leaves any ambiguity, Theroux
spelled out his support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> in a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> article.)

            It is impossible not to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kowloon Tong</ENAMEX> as an
allegory. The book focuses on Neville "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bunt</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mullard</ENAMEX> and his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of a stitching <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, on the eve of the handover. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX>'s brand of
capitalism is played by the outdated rules of imperialism. He spends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s "blue" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, making <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, deliberately mysterious appearances
on the factory floor in order to encourage productivity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX> is unprepared for
the ruthless capitalism of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hung</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Liberation Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who
appears in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bunt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> to make him an offer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> he simply cannot
refuse. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX>, struck by a belated attachment to his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, falls in
love with an employee named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mei</ENAMEX>-ping. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mei</ENAMEX>-ping begin to raise
uncomfortable questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hung</ENAMEX>'s connection to a murder, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hung</ENAMEX> decides he
must drive Bunt from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> altogether .
            

            As Theroux
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">describes Bunt</ENAMEX>'s speculations about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hung</ENAMEX>'s guilt, he succumbs to the urge to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">preach</ENAMEX>: "The evidence was not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, the evidence was missing--that stark
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neatness</ENAMEX> was the proof that a bloody crime had been committed. The same was
true of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The look of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> was the spare look of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, a place
that had been scoured and simplified by chaos--upheaval, terror, mass murder,
war. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> had a peaceable clutter, just an accumulation of worn or
out-of-date things, like a massive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happily</ENAMEX>, however, labored metaphors
like this are few, and the politics serve more as a backdrop than as a
message.

            
In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theroux</ENAMEX>'s sympathy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> is what gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kowloon Tong</ENAMEX> a moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center</ENAMEX> often absent from his
work. Mei-ping, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX>'s employee and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, suffers at the hands of both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">outgoing British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> and incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>; without her, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hung</ENAMEX>'s takeover of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Stitching</ENAMEX> might have seemed a victimless crime. The otherwise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repellent Bunt</ENAMEX> is redeemed by his somewhat ridiculous infatuation with
Mei-ping, and the at times heavy-handed tale of the factory sale gives way to a
more interesting story, a love triangle of sorts among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mei</ENAMEX>-ping, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX> are a
memorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX> is named for an elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> who died in infancy, and
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bunt</ENAMEX> seem to feel that he is only a stand-in for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunt</ENAMEX> remains a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> in his mother's eyes, and he too is
disturbingly comfortable in the relationship. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Each evening</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX> waits up for
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, aware of his vain attempts to create a secret life for himself with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>. "When he was late and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> stood waiting in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">doorway</ENAMEX>, she always seemed to swell, filling the doorframe, to obstruct and
delay him, so that she could bulk against his approaching face and scold him.
... She had the pathetic aggression of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>--to Bunt there was no
difference."

            It soon becomes clear that
it is not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hung</ENAMEX>'s connivance that's driving Bunt out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> and into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exile</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>'s will. She hears the sum offered for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> and refuses
to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bunt</ENAMEX>'s concern about the future of the business or his burgeoning
romance with Mei-ping to stand in the way of her plan to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and
live in comfortable solitude with him. This chilling story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
crushing love for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> will haunt me long after I've forgotten the details of
the handover ceremony.

         
      
   
