
   
   
      
         
            Objects of Beauty 

            Still life, that most humble
of the classical genres, traces its origins to a legendary painting contest.
Around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeuxis</ENAMEX> was said to have painted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> so
lifelike that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> came to peck at them. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parrhasios</ENAMEX>, secretly
painted a curtain over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeuxis</ENAMEX> tried to lift the curtain,
and lost the contest. Teasingly realistic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> and drapes have figured in
still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifes</ENAMEX> ever since. Some of the most spectacular examples of the genre,
which got its name in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>, depict great mounds of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fruit</ENAMEX> and fabric that fool the eye ( trompe l'oeil ) so completely that we
can practically smell them and feel them.

            Still
life--the portrayal of familiar inanimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>--is, as the name suggests, a
paradoxical genre. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> name, nature morte ("dead nature"), points
up the paradox even more acutely. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> "banquet pieces" suggest endless
beauty--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17 th century</TIMEX> was so rich it didn't know what
to do with its money--there's a darker side to still life that warns of the
brevity of earthly pleasures. The ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> painted images of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and
personal effects in their tombs, images that were to accompany the dead on
their last journey, and a rich tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> still-life painting slips
little reminders of mortality--skulls and flickering candles--among the apples
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pears</ENAMEX> and peeled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lemons</ENAMEX>.

            Still life, then, is caught between the timeless vision and
the ticking clock. When you enter the current show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>,
titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Objects of Desire: The Modern Still Life</ENAMEX>," you find yourself in a small
white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> painting on the wall, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CÃ©zanne's Still Life With a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginger Jar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eggplants</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890-94</TIMEX>). This is the timeless vision. The effect
is that of a hushed chapel, and on the altar is this gorgeous riddle of a
painting, with its tilted plate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">ripe pears</ENAMEX>, its pendulous eggplants, its
great blue-black bedspread draped across the lower <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the painting, and
its round, wicker-wound ginger jar, carefully placed in the middle. Every form
finds an echo elsewhere in the painting, and none of the depicted objects calls
attention to the historical moment.

            It's a
dazzling opening, this great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne</ENAMEX>, and much of the explosion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubist</ENAMEX> work
in the next <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> builds on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne</ENAMEX>'s achievement. The gravity-defying sepia
swirls of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso and Braque</ENAMEX>, with their fragments of guitars and violins--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fiddlehead</ENAMEX> here, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-curve</ENAMEX> there, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of quarter</TIMEX> notes waltzing off a
table edge somewhere else--have a kindred formal harmony.

            Then you turn a corner and enter a different world, where
the immediacy of modern life, of the ticking clock, is everywhere palpable.
Here in a glass case is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man Ray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gift</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX>):
a clothes iron painted black with a row of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> tacks glued headfirst into the
face. Next to it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel Duchamp</ENAMEX>'s bizarre Why Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sneeze Rose SÃ©lavy</ENAMEX>?
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX>): a metal bird cage, painted white, containing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">151</TIMEX> marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cubes</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thermometer</ENAMEX>, and a piece of cuttlebone--the internal shell of a squid-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>, used, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>, as "a dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supplement</ENAMEX> for caged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>." Such objects, with their elliptical wit, return us to the dark side of
still life; these bones and cages and tacks and thermometers offer a deadpan
answer to what life is: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C'est</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">la vie</ENAMEX>.
            

            These "ready-mades," as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchamp</ENAMEX> called them, pose in a new way the oldest still-life question: Is it
real or is it art? Instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> pecking at painted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX>, we have objects
that are real and art. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>'s carefully constructed and painted
Brillo 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boxes</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>) stacked on the floor look an awful lot like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brillo</ENAMEX> boxes stacked on the floor. Backtracking, I found myself wondering what
these things had to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne</ENAMEX>, and the answer is: not much.

            For,
alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne</ENAMEX>'s timeless forms in subtle harmony, another modern still-life
tradition has flourished, more in tune with pop culture, advertising, and the
disposable culture of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. MoMA, which does so well by
the scions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne</ENAMEX>, is less instructive about this hybrid line of
descent.

            There was space in that little white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chapel</ENAMEX> at the start of
the show to include an example of the trompe l'oeil <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> masters
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harnett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Peto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne's</ENAMEX>, who are just as much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> of modern still life as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne</ENAMEX>, and whose more playful spirit is just
as tangible in the works at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX>. After all, the title of the show perfectly
fits the objects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harnett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peto</ENAMEX> assembled: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> bills, snapshots of loved
ones, jewel-studded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistols</ENAMEX>.

            As one
ventures deeper into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dadaism</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surrealism</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Art</ENAMEX>, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harnett</ENAMEX> one thinks of more often than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harnett</ENAMEX>'s practice of inserting newspaper headlines among his
tacked-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> turns up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Braque</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Gris</ENAMEX>, their way of asserting both
the up-to-dateness of their art and the background noise of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> aim of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Objects of Desire</ENAMEX>" is to show how the same
objects in the limited repertory of still life--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> bottles and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX>, pipes
and shaving kits--take on very different meanings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private, over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. The show succeeds spectacularly in this regard. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Murphy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Razor</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>) is alert to consumerist art during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, the so-called
"golden age of advertising." The razor crossed with the fountain pen,
surmounted by a box of matches, reminds those in the know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>, the
model for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tender Is the Night</ENAMEX> , gave up
painting to run the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark Cross</ENAMEX> pens. When a trompe
l'oeil shaving brush and a match turn up later in the show in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Magritte</ENAMEX>'s
Personal Values (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>), they have an oneiric suggestiveness
quite in contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>'s flat factuality. Superimposed against a blue sky,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magritte</ENAMEX>'s comb seems to be lying on clouds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shaving cream</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>'s
dream--while the match lies asleep on the floor. Still-life objects that have
figured for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> as reminders of mortality can take on new urgency under
the pressure of history. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Max Beckmann's Still Life With Three</ENAMEX> Skulls
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>), the greenish skulls on the table look fresh--as indeed they were in
that harrowing year--like not-quite-ripe fruit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skull</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>)
now reads unavoidably as a premonition of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.

            Passing
through the final <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the show, one feels the pressure of an argument
beginning to emerge. Painting gives way increasingly to 3-D <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sculpted</ENAMEX> still
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifes</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jasper Johns</ENAMEX>' brace of cast bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballantine Ale</ENAMEX> cans (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Painted Bronze</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>), and found <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>. Those dueling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
painters return in a new guise, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Merz</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zeuxis</ENAMEX> role, covers a
glass table with an array of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>, changed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caterer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spiral Table</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>), while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christo</ENAMEX>, playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrhasios</ENAMEX>,
conceals the familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ</ENAMEX>©zannesque shapes--wine bottle, vase, etc.--under a
drapery of canvas ( Package on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>).

            We're meant to feel that we're coming to the end of the
line, an impression confirmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Domenico Gnoli</ENAMEX>'s painting of an empty table
covered with a lace tablecloth, Without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Still Life</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>), placed
toward the end of the show and chosen for the cover of the catalog. The
still-life objects have escaped, leaving the bare table, the bare canvas.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX>'s story of modern art,
beginning with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ©zanne</ENAMEX> and ending with abstraction, has been confirmed, but at
a cost. The final <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>, with lessons hammered home. The
show ends as it began, in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">white room</ENAMEX> holding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> object. This time the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">altarpiece</ENAMEX> is a plain white block of marble centered on the floor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfgang</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laib</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milkstone</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>). A wall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> explains that a film of milk
covers the top of the marble, so that a "living substance" (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>) has been
"stilled," thus "embodying the quintessential definition of the still life."
Such heavy-handed conceptual humor is a far cry from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchamp</ENAMEX>'s mercurial wit,
or from the visceral delight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meret Oppenheim's Object</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>), the
famous fur-lined teacup. Now that's a living object stilled.

             

         
      
   
