
   
   
      
         
            A Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slant of Light</ENAMEX>

            The visual drama of the
Impressionist breakthrough into color and light has sometimes been dimmed in
the frequent telling and retailing. As you walk through the early <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">sumptuous</ENAMEX> exhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX> portraits at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art Institute of Chicago</ENAMEX>, the
effect of following <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s career is like that of traveling through a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>.
You pause before the precocious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inn of MÃ</ENAMEX>¨re <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1866</TIMEX>), where dinner
guests modeled on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant</ENAMEX> forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courbet</ENAMEX> huddle around a
candle-lit table. Caricatures scrawled on the dim walls behind them echo their
dark shapes. We could be in the caves of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lascaux</ENAMEX>, so gloomy are the grays and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s early palette. Then, in a small, circular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, the first
flickers of daylight: In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Monet Painting</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s close
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> stands in a darkened <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in black hat and full bushy black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beard</ENAMEX>, but
there's a wet blob of vermilion on the tip of his paintbrush, and more of that
red smeared on the palette in his left hand. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renoir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX>, and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> in the Impressionist circle were beginning to find ways to leave
behind the shadowy chiaroscuro of earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> painting, which they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with a rural world now lost to modern experience.

            You follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> to the
next <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and all that was gray turns into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>; the heavy, leaden shapes
dissolve in a shower of light. The painting before you is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX>'s
huge <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Madame Charpentier and Her Children</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1878</TIMEX> and the work that made <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s reputation as a portrait <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>. Madame
Charpentier, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, reclines in her Japanese-style <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boudoir</ENAMEX>. Her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> sits on the long-suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> pet, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Newfoundland</ENAMEX> whose
black-and-white coat comically echoes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madame Charpentier</ENAMEX>'s elaborate dress. Her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>--dressed identically to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in pinafore and patent-leather
shoes--joins his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> on the sofa. The surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> screens and mats
are red and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. "Seen on the walls of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcel Proust</ENAMEX> wrote,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madame Charpentier</ENAMEX> "will give a greater impression of elegance than
anything since the great paintings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>."

            Of all the Impressionist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre-Auguste Renoir</ENAMEX>, alchemist of elegance, had the humblest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beginnings</ENAMEX>. Born in the porcelain manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limoges</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of an impoverished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tailor</ENAMEX> and a dressmaker, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX> was apprenticed at age
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> to a porcelain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> specialized in imitations of
Limoges ware. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> rococo scenes that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX> learned to
execute with great skill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> and picnics in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
were a major influence on his later work. Then, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 17</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX> was abruptly
laid off, his paintbrush replaced by a machine.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s dazzling career as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painter</ENAMEX> can be viewed as his effort to prove the factory wrong. As the art
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Robert Herbert</ENAMEX> has pointed out, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s famously feathery brushwork
(which, according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, left light "like grease spots on the
clothing of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>") was meant to show the mark of the hand rather than
the mechanical "finish" of academic and salon art. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renoir</ENAMEX> went so far as to
write a manifesto in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1884</TIMEX> for a society of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irregularists</ENAMEX>"--to include such
sworn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of mechanical perfection as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decorators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>,
goldsmiths, embroiderers, etc."--but he couldn't muster enough fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
A late painting like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Lerolle Embroidering</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX>), with its
complex weave of frames within frames, is a veritable catalog of the
craftsmanlike bric-a-brac <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX> admired: the embroidery frame constructed of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bamboo</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Morris</ENAMEX> wallpaper; a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> vase; the rough-hewed paintings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Degas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX> himself that the connoisseurs are inspecting in the
background.

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s well-off fellow Impressionists, the aristocrat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manet</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son Degas</ENAMEX>, strolled through the working-class neighborhoods of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montmartre</ENAMEX>, they
were consciously slumming. They could afford to disdain commissions for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portraits</ENAMEX> and to paint, instead, the class tensions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>--predatory males
and streetwalking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renoir</ENAMEX>, by contrast, had lived by necessity in the
slums of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. When he painted the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in his wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Acrobats</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cirque Fernando</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1879</TIMEX>), he was depicting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his own social
class. In the background one can just make out the binoculars of an eager male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> and the stripe on the trousers of an erect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, but all our
attention gravitates toward the innocent isolation of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>, one
of whom has gathered as many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX>, thrown as tokens from the appreciative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, as her small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> can hold.

            The harsh social vision of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acrobats</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s critical reputation has fared so
badly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, particularly at the hands of such leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.J. Clark</ENAMEX>, who contemptuously dismisses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">boulevard pastorals</ENAMEX>." On
the occasion of the last big <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX> show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Art in America</ENAMEX>
assembled a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hitters</ENAMEX> who took turns taking a swing at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Schjeldahl</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX> "the worst artist
ever to achieve canonical status"; art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Fried</ENAMEX> remarked that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> gift was perilously slight"; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rosenblum</ENAMEX>
worried about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> content" of his paintings.

            Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nochlin</ENAMEX> (whose contribution to the catalog of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> show is an overview
of Impressionist portraiture with almost nothing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>) used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> occasion to say something serious and illuminating about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s
art, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--in such idylls as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luncheon of the Boating</ENAMEX>
Party (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1881</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bougival</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1883</TIMEX>) (both great paintings,
which blur the distinction between portrait and genre painting, are in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> show)--offer a masculine ideal counter to the male <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Degas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manet</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tough</ENAMEX> and tender at once," these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> "are
luscious, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peachy-skinned</ENAMEX> and downy-haired, with heavy-lidded eyes and yearning
red mouths." That androgynous tenderness is evident in Lunch at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant Fournaise</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rowers' Lunch</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX>), where we can't tell if the
red daubs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> are ears or <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renoir</ENAMEX>'s
portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, which have a kindred prelapsarian innocence, now seem
the quintessence of cute. To his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>, however, such paintings as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Child</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Dress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lucie Berard</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1883</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> With a Watering
Can (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1879</TIMEX>; not in the show, but hanging in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>) were alarming. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucie Berard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> reported that the
portrait of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, with its unorthodox coloring and swirling purple
background, "simply frightens <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> away." In this regard as in others, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>
has been the victim of his own success. He banished the sentimental,
"penseroso" poses and the comforting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twilit</ENAMEX> faces favored by the fashionable
portrait <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> he competed with. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too have emerged from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tunnel</ENAMEX>, and they stare frankly out at us, uncompromising and alone.

             

         
      
   
