
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kuttner</ENAMEX>'s last
book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End of Laissez Faire</ENAMEX> , was published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, it set a new
standard in writing about economics for the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. It was so bad, and
bad in so many ways, that it demanded a kind of respect. To mention only its
most salient defect, here was a book announcing the failure of market economics
at a time when anybody with the slightest curiosity about the world was
transfixed by the sudden collapse of the main alternative to it: socialist
central planning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX> didn't so much as blink. He briefly noted the
interesting events in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> and observed, in passing, that they
confirmed his thesis. Then, with no more time for distractions, he resumed his
trudge through various learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> (mainly works by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>), denouncing "free markets" this way and that.

            Give the
man his due: Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have the dedication and single-mindedness to work so
hard and see so little. But are these qualities now on the wane? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX>'s new
book, Everything for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sale</ENAMEX> , suggests they might be.

            Note the subtitle, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Virtues and Limits of Markets</ENAMEX>." Is
there something to be said for markets after all? Not too much, it turns out.
Of the book's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX>-odd pages, at most <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> are about the virtues. And when Kuttner
recognizes them, it's usually with reluctance. "Consumption is doubtless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleasurable</ENAMEX>," he concedes, doubtfully, "and nobody minds a high material
standard of living." No indeed. Even in areas where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuttner</ENAMEX> thinks markets are
all right, he's sensitive to the drawbacks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Supermarkets</ENAMEX> work well on the
whole, he reckons, but what a burden on the economy that there should be so
many different kinds of breakfast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal</ENAMEX>: "At my local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX>, I counted
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 150</NUMEX> brands." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX> is also stern about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> food--although, in this
case, he provides no data on the number of brands.

            
Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX> does appear to be inching to the right. He admits as much
in his introduction: "In exploring different real-world markets, I come away
with increased respect for the power of markets and the complexity of the
story, yet with renewed conviction that the good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> requires a mixed
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>." Kuttner tirelessly proclaims his devotion to the "mixed economy," as
though this sets him apart. But almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> take the case for a mixed
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> for granted. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX> breaks with them is in judging the parts
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and market should have in the mix.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX>'s essential argument has been the same
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> in the virtues of markets rests on a theory whose
assumptions are not just untenable but patently absurd: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are rational and
perfectly informed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are too small to move prices single-handedly and seek
only to maximize profits, and so on--an error that, for some reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
have failed to spot. It follows that markets do not work as well as they're
supposed to, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> must play a large and active role in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. The properly functioning market economy exists only in the pages of
economics textbooks. In the real world, a heavy dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
needed.

            What is
wrong with this? To begin with, the purported contrast between the blinkered
maxims of economic theory and the penetrating insights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX>'s common
sense is a fraud. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> spend much of their time working out the
implications of "market failure" caused by departures from the assumptions of
the standard laissez-faire model. The textbooks are laden with theoretical
opportunities for efficiency-promoting interventions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: taxes,
public spending, tariffs, regulation--you name it.

            Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX> misrepresents what most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> think,
so he exaggerates what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> in the real world can achieve. In theory,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> may be selfless, competent, and adequately informed. In practice,
they aren't.

            In much of
his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Kuttner</ENAMEX> implicitly weighs imperfect markets against perfect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, thus evading the issue. He does not entirely ignore the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> (public-choice theory) that is most concerned with analyzing
government failure. He caricatures it briefly, calls it "banal" and
"tautological," and cites its influence on mainstream economics as further
evidence of the corruption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>. Be that as it may, the real choice
is not between imperfect markets and perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, but between markets
that fail and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> that fail.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX> would say that a good deal of his book
is addressed to this question. Certainly, many pages are devoted to case
studies of various kinds of regulation and deregulation: telecommunications,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, finance, health and safety, and more. As the cases pile up, a pattern
recurs: The standard method of study, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuttner</ENAMEX> writes, "usually finds that
the cost of regulation outweighs the benefit." Does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX> therefore revise
his view that more regulation is usually better than less? Not at all. These
findings only strengthen his conviction that economics is bunk. Again and
again, he deems the beneficial effects of heavy regulation to be self-evident.
Studies that come to the opposite conclusion only demonstrate the bankruptcy of
"ghoulish" techniques such as cost-benefit analysis and provide more proof in
general of the poverty of economics.

            The core
of the book, then, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuttner</ENAMEX>'s prejudice against economics. He is not an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>; he is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. That would be all right if he
could offer some other coherent way to think about these issues, or even if his
critique were arresting or persuasive. But he offers no alternative apart from
his own privileged sense of what is obvious, and his attacks on economic method
are mostly ill-informed or self-contradictory.

            When he attempts to lampoon what he sees as a silly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>, he often just gets it wrong. Satirizing the efficiency of financial
markets, he writes: "The market, again by definition, had to be right. If loans
to ski <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resorts</ENAMEX>, fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bolivian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> paid a slightly
higher return than loans to a local small business or housing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, then
they had to be the more deserving use of capital." As any semiconscious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> could tell you, a higher rate would not signal that the loan
in question is more deserving than another, but rather, the opposite: that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are being compensated for extra risk, leaving the marginal lender
indifferent among the alternatives.

            No doubt, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuttner</ENAMEX>, that
account is just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> as the one he mocks. But if he expects to have any
Kuttner plainly sees himself as a heretic. But a heretic comprehends the ideas
he is attacking. Someone who writes book after book to refute what he doesn't
understand is just a crank.

         
      
   
