
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohemian Rhapsody</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, but is it the capital, in addition, of something purely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abstract</ENAMEX>, a quality of mind perhaps--something that might fascinate a puzzled
world? Every great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is constructed around a principle all its own--a
principle of brute strength in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case, of sensuous delicacy in another, of
majesty somewhere else, and mad chaos elsewhere. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>, the principle
appears to be metaphysical. The entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> seems to have been laid out
according to the cosmologies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> myths. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crowds</ENAMEX> of humble mortals
stride the pavements down below while, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> stories above, on the
fa√ßades of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, a very different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of carved stone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>, the
Olympian gods and goddesses, throng the upper air, in clear illustration of the
dualistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of all existence: mortals below, immortals above, flesh
here, stone there; the ever-changing, the everlasting.

            The
Olympian sculpted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX> come in fantastic varieties. You see winged nymphs and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angels</ENAMEX>, arrow-bearing cupids, fabulously sensual and muscular naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, enslaved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titans</ENAMEX> bearing the weight of entire lofty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> on their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sinewy</ENAMEX> backs, bearded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>, heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proletarians</ENAMEX>, and famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX>. On a narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in the old <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish quarter</TIMEX> you gaze upward at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cornices</ENAMEX> and see, of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creatures</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Three Musketeers</ENAMEX>, direct from the pages
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexandre Dumas</ENAMEX>. Just when you were expecting Maimonides! Around the corner,
on the roof of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, a chariot and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> are frozen in
eternal petrifaction on the brink of hurtling suicidally off the roof, quite as
if the immortals, too, have their traffic problems. But what is the meaning of
this strange dualism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>? Are we to conclude that it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of
mysteries that will never be fathomed--a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of mysticism and the occult? Or
is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of reason and lucidity, of light and simplicity--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> to the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>?

            The mystic interpretation--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of Kabbalists
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Loew</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay android</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golem</ENAMEX>--arose in the late
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>. It was a bit of late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romanticism</ENAMEX>, which flourished in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> literature, then in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>, and reached an apogee of acceptance
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> in a stylish volume by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo Maria Ripellino</ENAMEX> called, after a phrase by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andr√© Breton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Magic Prague</ENAMEX> . But the mystic interpretation is exactly
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Demetz</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, wishes to counter in his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prague in Black and Gold: Scenes From the Life of a European City</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demetz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-16 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX> (a scientific-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, though he did go mad at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>) and the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">logician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Bolzano</ENAMEX>. And it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tom√</ENAMEX>°

         
      
   
