
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Wept</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years ago</TIMEX>, I attempted
to write a work of nonfiction that reconstructed the life of the historical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. I knew that it was an impossible task--and for that reason worth
attempting, since human curiosity can never satisfy itself about the identity
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose destiny it was to be hailed, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three centuries</TIMEX> after
his birth, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Light of Light</ENAMEX>, God of God, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Very God of Very God</ENAMEX>.

            
Discussing the purely technical problem of how such a book could be written,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Ackroyd</ENAMEX> asked me why I did not make mine a work of
fiction. As the discussion wore on during a long evening, we decided that it
would make a better novel if the traditional claims of theology--from virginal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conception to Resurrection</ENAMEX>, with all the miracles between--turned out to be
true. Then, with a great deal of laughter, we recollected that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> such books
had already been written, attributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>,
Luke, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> has now made that attempt. Fortuitously, he
has followed the plan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ackroyd</ENAMEX> and I considered, namely, writing a book that
accepts the traditional story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> that we were told in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. This is no <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Temptation</ENAMEX> . There are no troubling scenes of
lust with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Magdalene</ENAMEX> or, as in a notorious poem that was condemned for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blasphemy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years ago</TIMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> soldiery. The only new
difficulty that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> has made for himself is that he has decided to tell the
story in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. This is the autobiography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, written we know
not where, but in some eternal realm where he has been dwelling since his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ascension</ENAMEX>. Like a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chekhovian</ENAMEX> character, frustrated by his own redundancy and by
an unexplained absence of sympathy with his closest relation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> records:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Father ...</ENAMEX> does not often speak to me. Nonetheless, I honor Him. He sends
forth as much love as He can offer, but His love is not without limit."

            At the
beginning of the book, it would seem as if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesus/Mailer</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Bulgakov</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Master</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margarita</ENAMEX> , was going to make witty play of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelists</ENAMEX>' incomprehension of his message. But in spite of telling us that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospel of Luke</ENAMEX> is highly unreliable, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> accepts the basic evangelical
accounts of his own life, death, and teaching. It is obvious that, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heavenly</ENAMEX> places, he has not had access to any of the modern works of
scholarship that have urged caution on those who accept too readily the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospel</ENAMEX>
accounts of his trial.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> claims to have been an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Essene</ENAMEX>, a member
of that strict <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> sect whose puritanical customs and views of life it has
been the delight of modern fantasists to reconstruct. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gospel writers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> almost exonerates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontius Pilate</ENAMEX> from any guilt in his death. He either
has not read--or disbelieves--those modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> who believe that, far from
being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharisees</ENAMEX>, the historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was likely to have been
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, if not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pharisee</ENAMEX> himself. Pilate, who was in real life so cruel
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> had to remove him from the procuratorship of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Judea</ENAMEX>,
is, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' account of things, the detached Gentile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> who believes
that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>" has done no wrong, and should be released. (The
real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pilate</ENAMEX> crucified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharisees</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single day</TIMEX>.) Here, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>'
account, we read of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharisees</ENAMEX> improbably collaborating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> and
urging them to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. It remains the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, in the accounts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus/Mailer</ENAMEX>, who are guilty of crucifying the innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galilean</ENAMEX> prophet--a
fiction that has had an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">incomparably</ENAMEX> damaging historical effect, and which is
both the origin and supposed justification of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> anti-Semitism.

            But this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> has strange memory lapses. He was told as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, for instance, about
the annunciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Gabriel</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Virgin Mother</ENAMEX>, but then he forgot
about it until he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>, concentrating instead on the carpentry details that
form the least arresting part of his narrative.

            Reading these pages, one can see why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> has never chosen
to write a book before, since whenever he adds to the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>,
Luke, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, the results are less than happy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilate</ENAMEX> epigrammatically
offers the cynical question, "What is truth?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus' Pilate</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">windbag</ENAMEX> who
adds: "Where there is truth, there will be no peace. Where peace abides, you
will find no truth." (What does this mean? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> had ever read the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uneventful</ENAMEX> lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immanuel Kant</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludwig Wittgenstein</ENAMEX>, he might
have decided that peace was a precondition for the pursuit of truth.)

            But then,
the sad evidence presented by these pages is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is not merely rather
stupid, but also a very bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. "They drove a spike into each of my wrists
and another spike through each of my feet. I did not cry out. But I saw the
heavens divide. Within my skull, light glared at me until I knew the colors of
the rainbow: my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> was luminous with pain." Perhaps it sounds better in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aramaic</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> originally wrote it, but one can't help fearing, when he
sees his words in print, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> will think this sounds like a sadomasochist
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>.

            
His story ends rather lamely for one who has
been through so much. "There are many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in my name and in the name of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apostles</ENAMEX>. The greatest and holiest is named after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>; it is a place of great
splendor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. Nowhere can be found more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>." Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> should have
employed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> to tell him that, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> is not short of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>,
it can hardly rival the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is wistful, more than angry, at
the continued success of the devil, but he modestly hopes that he is himself
still of some use to the poor old human race. "It is even by way of my blessing
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> sends what love He can muster down to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> who is man
and that other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and I try to remain the source of that
love that is tender."

            If only there were creative
writing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in Heaven, or failing that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, we could hope that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
would learn how to improve on awful sentences like that. No doubt he will do
better in his next book. Perhaps the most surprising revelations are left to
the end when, in a passage of acknowledgements, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> reveals that he has a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norris</ENAMEX> and a literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Wylie</ENAMEX>. Maybe he should
get some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> to sign him up to write the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
