
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Z.</ENAMEX>

            For honesty's sake, any
early criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX>'s new novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason & Dixon</ENAMEX> , ought
to be labeled "provisional" or "tentative." The text of the book was released
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> as of this writing. And because it will take any normal human
being at least that long to read the galleys (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">773</NUMEX> pages), let alone reflect
upon their contents, it's a fair bet that anyone who reviews the novel has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
merely skimmed it, meaning his impressions are superficial; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) actually read
every page, but only by foregoing food and rest, meaning his impressions are
warped by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) not read the book at all, meaning his impressions are
just as worthy as those of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of other literate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> who will buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX>'s novel on reputation, read the jacket copy, put it down, and pronounce
it either another masterpiece or a disappointing falling off, though somewhat
better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vineland</ENAMEX> , his previous book. Indeed, I have already heard
the latter view bandied about at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> cocktail parties

            Here is
my own preliminary view, based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> pages read, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> skimmed, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foregone</ENAMEX>: Maybe, just maybe, minimalist fiction wasn't such a bad thing after
all.

            As I said, it should take any normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> at least
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> to get through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason & Dixon</ENAMEX> --but that begs the question
of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX>'s writings are intended for normal human beings. I don't
think they are. They partake of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabethans</ENAMEX> called "euphuism"--the
pursuit of linguistic complexity for its own sake. As such, they're intended
for literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monastics</ENAMEX>, for the tenured priesthood of paid interpreters that
sprang up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> with the help of massive public
funding from schemes such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pell</ENAMEX> grants. This professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for difficult "texts" created the demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX> first filled
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gravity's Rainbow</ENAMEX> , the semiotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monoliths</ENAMEX> whose mix
of scientific imagery, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> absurdity, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joycean</ENAMEX> allusion provided a kind
of full-employment program for a generation of rising postdocs. In academia,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> found his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pynchon</ENAMEX>, academia found its paychecks.

            The
problem is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> is performing for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that no longer exists. The
boom in subsidized <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">deconstruction</ENAMEX> is over. (What's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason & Dixon</ENAMEX>

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> ? I'll get to that.) Think about what's happened to the novel since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fecund days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gravity's Rainbow</ENAMEX> . It's grown thin and literal
and modest, so much so that the typical <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel isn't called a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel
anymore; it's called a memoir, just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step from journalism, and it's
immunized from conventional criticism by its traumatized sincerity. Even the
bright young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who imitate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> by fortifying their fashionably fractured
stories with math and science, myth and metafiction, can't really hold a candle
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>. They write <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Italian</TIMEX> compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>--perhaps
because they no longer have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> behind them, merely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> of secular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superstores</ENAMEX>.

            
Which brings me to the new novel itself.
Written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX> ("magical" is spelled "magickal,"
for example, and the predominant punctuation marks are the dash and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apostrophe</ENAMEX>), it tells the picaresque tale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> astronomers best known for
surveying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> line, which separates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and
the American cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> from the cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. We meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> as
they're setting off from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> for southern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, where they hope to
observe the transit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX> for purposes of mapping the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s longitude.
You'll learn a lot about shipping in this novel, and the main thing you'll
learn is how important it was to find a reliable way of measuring longitude.
National fortunes depended on the feat, making it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age of Reason</ENAMEX>'s
equivalent to finding the Holy Grail.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mason</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> travel, they have adventures. Rollicking, bawdy adventures. They
drink. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carouse</ENAMEX>. While staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape Town</ENAMEX> with a family of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> is set upon by its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, whose mission is to arouse him
to the point where he'll want to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> with their black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>, thereby producing
a light-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>. When the pair land in colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, they hook up
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin Franklin</ENAMEX>, finding not a parsimonious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> but a turned-on,
pre-psychedelic party <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> wears tinted glasses, consorts with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prostitutes</ENAMEX>, and stages <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">proto</ENAMEX>-raves at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>, wowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> with
electrical experiments and machine-made music. "The moment you've all been
waiting for ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saloon</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orchid Tavern</ENAMEX> is pleas'd to Present, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fam'd Leyden-Jar Danse Macabre</ENAMEX>! with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Euclid of the Electrick</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s own Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> , in the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death</ENAMEX>."

            Next, it's on to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>. He
greets the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> by lighting up a hemp pipe and getting them roundly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stoned</ENAMEX>. To curb the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s munchies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> serves muffins and doughnuts. The
comedy of anachronism is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX>'s favorite kind, and here, as elsewhere in his
work, it isn't very funny. Pynchon the verbal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, but Pynchon
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humorist</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> indeed and reminds one of a brainy college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sophomore</ENAMEX> who
studies joke books to make himself amusing. Worse, he's very big on language
humor, on purposely mismatching tone and topic and veering abruptly between
high-flown rhetoric and scatological bluntness. Again, not funny. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
once represented the future of literature--and, to some, still does--is bogged
down in Ivy League <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">revue</TIMEX>-style japery circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>. A farting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> who's quick
with learned puns is his idea of hilarity.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and the
surveyors pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX>, intrigues and conspiracies involving all sorts of
secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesuits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--are hinted at.
Everyone has a vital interest, it seems, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX>'s wilderness
survey, and it becomes clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> are really pawns in some obscure
sociocultural power struggle that may involve as-yet-unknown advanced
communication technologies. When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">explorers</ENAMEX> have
buried mysterious metal plates up and down the frontier, die-hard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> fans
will lick their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chops</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Playful</ENAMEX>, ingenious revisions of orthodox history based
on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, covert affiliations and strange secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> are the master's
trademark. At bottom, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pynchon</ENAMEX> writes mystery novels--symphonic, polymathic
detective stories that resolve themselves not in simple sums but in hip new
intellectual logarithms. And he pays his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> the ultimate compliment of
writing as though he knows they're capable of getting his erudite cosmic
jokes.

            That's the rub, and that's
why I'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> you have to "get," and I find no
activity less inspiring than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rubik's Cube</ENAMEX>-ing through a clue-strewn supertext
in search of a paradoxical Eureka! The low part of the higher mind that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX> so pyrotechnically appeals to (the same part that responds to Escher
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drawings</ENAMEX>, PDQ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX>, and perspective-switching holograms) is not a part of
myself I'm in touch with, nor do I particularly long to be. I admire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX>; I'm wowed by him at times; but the truth is I'm happy leaving him to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> whose academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> gave birth to him. They're the ones whose love
he seems to want, the ones who seem best equipped to give it to him. May their
funding never quite dry up.

         
      
   
