
   
   
      
         
            Living With <BR><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>

            It doesn't get much better
than this, unfortunately.

            
               By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
Alter
            

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1285</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 2</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 9</TIMEX>)
            

            This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> book by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>, and whenever I read a new one, I always have the same two
reactions. The first reaction is that it is not really a book. It doesn't have
a theme or an argument or even a coherent story line. Books are supposed to
have spines. They're supposed to have context. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> doesn't know from
context, though in recent books he has made feeble efforts to stipulate some.
His narrative is more like a series of scenes from a pulpy novel, only they
aren't fiction--at least most of the time.

            Which leads to a second
reaction: The reporting, if one defines reporting in its smallest-bore sense,
is sometimes breathtaking. Every time I begin to feel a bit guilty about my
part in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> hype machine ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> almost always excerpts his
books, often on the cover) I reflect on my paltry powers to find out what
happened at an unimportant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> meeting, much less a solarium seance.
The theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sirica</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX>, brought down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> isn't right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> is sui generis when it comes to getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
tell him stuff that is only supposed to come out under truth serum.

            This time I have a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
reaction. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, I've believed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perfectibility of Bob</ENAMEX>. Given his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvinist</ENAMEX> work habits, I held out hope that his devotion to self-improvement
would eventually take him to a new level (make that a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> level) of real
political analysis. In the same way that he knows to unearth the outtakes of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> film bio, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man From Hope</ENAMEX>, to mine it for details about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' relationship, I thought surely he would start to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
history seriously, so as to be able to mine it for historical perspective. If
he had, he would have learned, for instance, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> his holy-shit headlines, was in a rich tradition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spiritualists</ENAMEX> dating back through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first ladies</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Todd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>. Certainly her efforts to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX> to talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin Franklin</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Washington</ENAMEX> would have been considered "anecdote-rich." But now I've
given up on searching for sweep and subtext and I've decided to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>
on his own mechanical terms. By that standard, he does fine. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About half</NUMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> is a mindless Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Hillary</ENAMEX>: He climbs for the detail
because it is there, gettable by him, even if it tells us nothing. But the
other <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the scooplets are fresh, or at least flavorful. If they
don't always reveal the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the subject of the anecdotes, they are
invariably telling about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, and about the eternal
question of why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say things they shouldn't. Click here for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> possible
answer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s book may not be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">online</ENAMEX>, but it's on the frontier of publishing. No need to worry about
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-free pages for this one. The book, published a mere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> after it was
completed (a remarkably short lead time for a hardcover), was not written to
last much beyond the length of the ballyhoo book tour. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, no one
will want to read a book about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign that ends in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. It's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockbuster</ENAMEX> syndrome taken to its natural conclusion.

            Who talked for The
Choice ? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> didn't. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> imagines their dilemma. They knew that not
talking meant that they would take more of a beating. But their cooperation
would have given the green light to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Livingstone</ENAMEX> in the
administration to drop a dime on them. Having already been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodwardized</ENAMEX> once
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Agenda</ENAMEX> , they passed. The only good news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> chose not to write about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater</ENAMEX>, at least not yet.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> talked some. Among
the juiciest parts of the book are the accounts, partly from him, of the
acrimonious budget meetings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. "You have a chickenshit
operation here, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> as saying.
"You've been calling me an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX>," he roared at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.

            "At least we didn't accuse
you of drowning those little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> shot back, in
reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s comments blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Smith</ENAMEX> case.
Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Armey</ENAMEX> point
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fingers</ENAMEX>--literally--at each other, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> go nuts over what they
consider to be an unflattering picture the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> released to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> .
All in all, everyone in the budget talks looks petty and political, except for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> gave <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> of
formal interviews and lots more time informally, in part because, as his press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Warfield</ENAMEX> told me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, he likes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> personally. Dole
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loved Nixon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon hated Woodward</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole trusts Woodward</ENAMEX>. Go figure. Anyway, it
paid off for him. He comes across up close as the same solid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cramer</ENAMEX> found in his classic, What It Takes , the best campaign book of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> camp loves <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Choice</ENAMEX> , though to my mind, the book
makes him look as indecisive as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and too uncommunicative to be a good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>

            For instance, it turns out
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> had to make an office appointment with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to
discuss whether he should run or not, and that she wasn't informed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
was resigning from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> until after he had told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Helprin</ENAMEX>, a
supporter he barely knew. "In her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> with him, she had never once heard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> say, 'Here's what we're doing.' He never would come right out and say it,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> writes. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> had an inability to reach out fully or lay out
completely what was on his mind. He held things so close. He didn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">systematically</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> things with her or even regularly delegate to her."

            The other candidates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cooperated</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Mayhew</ENAMEX>,
who had originally planned a book about the primaries, mostly left the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> stories on the cutting-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> does
recount the decision-making process of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who decided not to
run. In every case, family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, who in an earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> would have been
enthusiastic, urged them to stay out.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s is the best
look we're likely to get at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>'s psyche. The retired general talks to
almost no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">other than Woodward</ENAMEX>, who helped make him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commanders</ENAMEX> . Besides his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, it turns out the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>'s
decision not to run was his laconic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-camp, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Smullen</ENAMEX>: He laid out all
the reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> gave later for why running would have been the wrong move
personally.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> obviously is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
first choice for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> uses reporting to make a good
case that if it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>, it may well be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baker</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cheney</ENAMEX> or
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Rumsfeld</ENAMEX>, instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
oft-mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>. Such details might not mean anything in the
long run, but they're delicious in a campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>. The conventional wisdom
among the wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> of the press has been that there are now so many reporters
around--and so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leakers</ENAMEX>--that campaign scoops are a thing of the past. The
new grail is the "conceptual scoop"--the fresh frame that some smart analyst
can put on events, not the events themselves. But now comes along <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>
to prove that a little shoe leather still works. He fails to make us understand
what the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign means for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. But he does pull back the curtain
more, just when we thought it had disintegrated. Who can resist a peek?

         
      
   
