
   
   
      
         
            Capture the Flag

            Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
appropriated motifs that swim in and out of the later work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jasper Johns</ENAMEX>,
whose career is the subject of a curatorially brilliant retrospective at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, is the face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Lisa</ENAMEX> . The reference is not
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX>. The reference is to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Lisa</ENAMEX> is the classic
instance of the image that becomes synonymous with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>. It is the
emblem of painterly emblems, the imprint on the ultimate tote bag of Western
art. It's the archetype for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel Duchamp</ENAMEX>'s urinal, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson Pollock</ENAMEX>'s drips,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> can, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jasper Johns</ENAMEX>' flag.

            The flag
was the outcome of a standard modernist ritual of self-launching. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>, when
he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> and an artistic unknown, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johns</ENAMEX> decided to destroy all his work, with
a view to purging himself of influence and beginning afresh with a blank
canvas. It was a sacrifice the gods seems to have found satisfactory (which is,
of course, why we know about it: If they hadn't found it satisfactory, the
story would have acquired a different beginning). For they sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns</ENAMEX> a dream,
in which he saw himself painting an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag, and the result was the work
with which his name will always be associated, an image he would produce many
renderings of--white flags, flags on orange backgrounds, flags with (by
mistake) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, flags drawn in pencil and graphite wash, flags in
superimposed triplicate.

            The original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flag</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954-1955</TIMEX>)--which is a
representation of the familiar red, white, and blue, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>-starred item--first
attracted attention in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, when it was displayed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castelli Gallery</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castelli</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johns</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man exhibition;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Barr</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, attended, and agreed to purchase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
works. Flag was among them, but the possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>'s
acquisitions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> would object to it as unpatriotic made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> nervous, so
he arranged for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Johnson</ENAMEX> to buy it (the price was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>),
with the promise that he would donate it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> later on (which he did,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, when it was worth a lot more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>).

            The
thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns' Flag</ENAMEX>, which seems so sweet and inoffensive in
comparison with the art that causes controversy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, would give anyone
political jitters seems a commentary on the oppressiveness of early <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. But it is really a commentary on the timidity of the art
establishment. For a version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White Flag</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955-1958</TIMEX>) had
already appeared in the window of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonwit Teller</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, as a background for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mannequins displaying the latest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>' suits, and no one seems to have
called in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> commercial culture, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1960s</TIMEX>,
was, in its lack of inhibition, way ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> high culture. It was this
friction between the agitators of appetite and the guardians of taste that gave
rise to pop.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> show figures in many stories of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in the turn away from abstract expressionism,
from the hot grandiloquence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Kooning</ENAMEX> toward the cool of pop,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">minimalism</ENAMEX>, and conceptual art--the art of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> and after. There is some
truth to this version, but not enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johns</ENAMEX> must have been happy to have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">displaced</ENAMEX>, in his understated way, the cultural dominance of the big action
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painters</ENAMEX>. The title of his sendup of abstract expressionism, Painting with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balls</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>)--and there they are, squeezed forlornly between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big
panels of drips and brushstrokes--is about as explicit as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johns</ENAMEX> ever gets. The
flags, targets, and twin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballantine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ale</ENAMEX> cans-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Painted Bronze</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>)--are
plausible prototypes for the art of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nauman</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns</ENAMEX> retrospective makes it clear that that to insist on
thinking of him as popist or a minimalist or a conceptualist is to miss out on
the pleasures of his work.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirk</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varnedoe</ENAMEX> has arranged the exhibition, and the excellent catalog that
accompanies it, to exemplify what has become a leading theme of his work as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief curator</ENAMEX> of painting and sculpture at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. This is the idea that
modern art is a song <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that never ends</TIMEX>--that what began with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cézanne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>
did not stop with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX> or with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnabel</ENAMEX>, but is an impulse that is
continually being renewed and revisited in Western culture. There may be no
better illustration of this thesis than the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jasper Johns</ENAMEX>.

            From <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point of view, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns'</ENAMEX> flags and targets derive
from the famous ready-mades of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel Duchamp</ENAMEX>--the urinal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX> wheel,
the snow shovel, all exhibited before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>. They are anti-art. They ask the
question asked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchamp</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX> wheel and, later, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> cans,
which is, if this is a work of art, then what is not? But from another point of
view, they derive from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monet</ENAMEX>'s haystacks. The flags and the targets and the
rest are, like the haystacks, simply subject matter for painterly treatment.
They are, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johns</ENAMEX> himself put it, "things the mind already knows," forms which
can be remade, over and over, and seen anew. This puts them about as squarely
in the artistic mainstream as anyone could wish.

            For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns</ENAMEX>' paintings and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sculptures</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ale</ENAMEX> cans, the sculp-metal shoes and flashlights, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">combines</ENAMEX>) lose exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> their point in reproduction. They retain their
intellectual aspect, but lose their sensual aspect. In reproduction, the flag
picture is a familiar dadaist conundrum: something that is neither a flag nor a
picture. On the wall, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flag</ENAMEX> is a magnificently variegated
surface, an intensely made thing, a dense amalgam of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>,
encaustic, and paint. It does not occur to you, when you encounter it in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flesh</ENAMEX>, to contemplate its metaphysics--any more than encountering a movie star
in the flesh inspires reflections on the nature of modern fame. You are too
busy soaking up the sense data.

            "Take an
object. Do something to it. Do something else to it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditto</ENAMEX>." The recipe is from
an early notebook of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns'</ENAMEX>, and it is the best explanation of his procedure.
It is why a list of the materials <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johns</ENAMEX> has used over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 40 years</TIMEX> of his
career includes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beeswax</ENAMEX>, lighter fluid, oil stain, plaster casts, crayon,
charcoal, chalk, cardboard, ink on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX>, and the impress of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> painting features his teeth marks. He doesn't want to represent or to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deconstruct</ENAMEX>. He wants to transform.

            
An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> who takes a bite out of his own
painting, and who derives his subject matter from a dream, is, in some sense, a
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>; and the later work, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varnedoe</ENAMEX> has organized it, suggests an
increasing absorption in a personal vocabulary composed of body parts;
crosshatching patterns (an overworked motif of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>); vases; clocks;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skulls</ENAMEX>; specific borrowings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchamp, Picassso, Holbein</ENAMEX>, and a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grünewald</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">altarpiece</ENAMEX>; little stick figures with bubble
heads; and, in the most recent work, the image of a spiral galaxy.

            Like the early flags, these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> got reworked in a variety of media and a range of combinations--as
though if the right combinations were found, the rebus might be decoded
(though, of course, it never is). There are periods in which the work fades
into hermeticism; there are periods when it aspires to a lyric summing up, as
in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seasons</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), in which the shadow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> is
projected onto a sequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnsian</ENAMEX> montages. Sometimes the desire to work
out an idea--as in the large-scale panel picture According to What
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>), which presents a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns</ENAMEX>' customary images in a deliberately
decentered composition--produces a flaccid surface. But mostly there is the
spectacle of technique brought to bear on form; and although this is a minimal
definition of art, there is nothing minimal about the results.

         
      
   
