
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Camp</ENAMEX>

            When you
hear the term "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Realism</ENAMEX>," you probably see in your mind's eye a large,
detailed canvas: A sweating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborer</ENAMEX>, goggles pushed back on his forehead,
stands by his red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX> and shakes hands with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>, in a white uniform, who
smirks under his mustache. Behind them is a chorus line of muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">babushkas</ENAMEX>; behind them, in turn, a rising sun. Or something like that. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, the genre is now referred to
primarily in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX> ads, as stock imagery of a comfortably camp sort. It is a
grotesque relic of a defused threat, and we can feel good knowing that we have
triumphed over its implications.

            So what could be the
purpose of this massive book? You pick it up expecting counterpropaganda run
rampant. But this is no mere coffee table decoration--although it weighs at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> pounds and contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">530 reproductions</NUMEX>, it is text-laden far beyond the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">norm</ENAMEX>. The next thing that makes an impression on leafing through it is the
unfamiliarity of the images. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tractors</ENAMEX> and babushkas and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> are accounted
for, but very few of the many pictures fit the conventional mold. The paintings
chosen as illustrations tend to be darker, less academic, more complicated. The
tone is very different from, for example, that of the show of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Realist</ENAMEX>
paintings I saw <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Museum of Fine Arts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>,
which approached the subject in the usual pop-camp way--nearly every picture
looked like a parody, and any of them could have been hung very nicely next to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> . But the paintings in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cullerne Bown</ENAMEX>'s book,
grave and dignified and often eager to claim descent from the likes of
Rembrandt, would be affronted by the pairing.

            As I continued second-guessing my way through my initial
encounter with the book, my next thought was that it must surely represent a
perverse but fascinating phenomenon: a defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Realism</ENAMEX> from the
position of aesthetic conservatism. After all, there exists a tendency these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> that is eager to reclaim the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norman Rockwell</ENAMEX> while consigning to
his former cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clement Greenberg</ENAMEX> and his exemplars. Since a loss of faith in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Modernist canon</ENAMEX> often seems to be paired with a disillusionment with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teleology</ENAMEX>, wouldn't championing the essential conservatism of all
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Zhdanovists</ENAMEX> make a dandy short circuit? Indeed, the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> who
most consistently comes to mind when you look at the pictures in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bown</ENAMEX>'s book is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Wyeth</ENAMEX>. But there are also a considerable number of works illustrated
that do not fit the bill, that refer neither to old masters nor to magazine
illustration. Again I was guilty of trying to boil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bown</ENAMEX>'s argument down to a
formula.

            His argument is not a
simplistic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>; in fact it is an argument against simplification. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bown</ENAMEX> proposes
that we in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> have ignored, if not actually betrayed, the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of
painting made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> in the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX>. We have chosen to
represent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Realism</ENAMEX> in terms of its most moronic and craven examples,
and we have instead upheld the banner of the "left" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Futurists</ENAMEX> and
Constructivists, who were marginal at best in their time and place.

            He does not dismiss the latter, recognizing the originality
and strength of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kazimir Malevich, Aleksandr Rodchenko</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Lisitski</ENAMEX>, and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, but he wants us to pay attention to those other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, many more
in number, who do not fall seamlessly into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modernist</ENAMEX> continuum but who
often had to pay as harsh a price for their independence as their better-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde counterparts</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonspecialist readers</ENAMEX>, the book is a journey into
the unknown.

            Bown, described in press
materials as an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>, has absorbed a vast history largely
unreported outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX>. It is seldom easy going. Acronyms
bristle on the page as he records internecine warfare in various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s mind throbs as he dissects minute shifts in
official thinking and individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">temper</ENAMEX>, and conducts tours of the diverse art
scenes in far-flung provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. But there is always a point. It is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fascinating</ENAMEX>, for example, to note the many swings of the official pendulum
between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> sins of "naturalism" (meaning grim subject matter) and
"formalism" (denoting any sort of aesthetic deviation). At various times in
various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, war or peace ruled as themes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were seen as strong or as
fragile, colors were to be bright or dun. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutions</ENAMEX> took place when,
say, failure was accepted as a subject or national costume permitted. There was
no single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Zhdanovist tank</ENAMEX> that rumbled down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> but a plethora of
day-to-day changes, both in official policy and in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>' decisions.

            For that matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Realism</ENAMEX> was no monolithic
invention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bown</ENAMEX> takes pains to point out, it descended
largely intact from the artistic currents of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> and
had its roots both in classic Western art and in much older local traditions,
including the work of such <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrei Rublev</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bown</ENAMEX> has unearthed a tremendous number of strong paintings,
largely from private collections, that defy all our notions of what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> art
looked like, even at the height of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinism</ENAMEX>. Who would have expected that in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petr V. Vilyams</ENAMEX> could have been making such a rarefied, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vuillard</ENAMEX>-like
canvas as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nana</ENAMEX> , with its profusion of sensuous patterns and textures, a
painting that just reeks of sex? Or that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Georgi I. Rublev</ENAMEX>, behind the
unpromising subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Factory Party Meeting</ENAMEX> , could have been up to
something that looks simultaneously back to rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">primitivism</ENAMEX> and forward to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Rivers</ENAMEX>? You get the sense, continually, of various fallen reins picked
up, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> in remote mining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> discovering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courbet</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whistler</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Léger</ENAMEX>, or reinventing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impressionism</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Expressionism</ENAMEX> as if they had never heard
of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>--as indeed they might not have.

            If there is a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">throbbing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> in this show it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleksandr A. Deineka</ENAMEX>, whose extraordinary
work really does not look like anyone else's. Building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Factories</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Female Textile Workers</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Defence of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petrograd</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>) take the conventional subjects their titles indicate and
make them new, setting human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>--which are somehow at once photographic
and icon-based--in fields of geometric patterns that are nevertheless
recognizable as industrial landscapes. Deineka, whose career endured into the
1950s despite intermittent castigation for "aestheticism," represents a missing
link, connecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Realism</ENAMEX> with the collages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constructivists</ENAMEX> and
them with the icons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rublev</ENAMEX>. He may be the major revelation here, but his
neglect in the West is just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> indication of the giant iceberg of unknown art
whose existence below the surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bown spotlights</ENAMEX>, explains, and places in
context.

         
      
   
