
   
   
      
         
            Microcosm

            Business writing bores me.
It tends to be drier, less passionate, and less accurate than other forms of
journalism. Business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are generally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> looking in: They lack the
access granted to political, sports, or even entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, since few
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> seek the kind of publicity the press wants to bestow upon them.

            
Sometimes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> of the genre can rise above its limitations; but you
can count on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fingers the number of books that have migrated from the
business-aisle ghetto to the mainstream: Barbarians at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Den of Thieves</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbarians</ENAMEX> succeeded because its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bryan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burrough</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Helyar</ENAMEX>, weren't seduced by the power of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. They
knew that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR Nabisco</ENAMEX>-leveraged buyout represented the nadir of that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>'s
financial engineering. They called a moron a moron, and damned the whole lot of
them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Den of Thieves</ENAMEX> required even more intelligence work, as well as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James B. Stewart</ENAMEX>'s master touch at cutting through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multimillion</ENAMEX>-dollar public-relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>--still ongoing--that tried to
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Milken</ENAMEX> look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Schweitzer</ENAMEX> pursued recklessly by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">jackbooted</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>.

            Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall E. Stross</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Microsoft Way</ENAMEX> ,
an inside look at the software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> that publishes this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, will not
match the gold standard set by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbarians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Thieves</ENAMEX> . The book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">succumbs</ENAMEX> to all the usual pitfalls of business writing. It shouldn't have.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stross</ENAMEX> had unparalleled access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, including the right to
stroll through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> without an apparatchik at his side. And the tale of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is certainly worth telling, if only because we can all learn from the
successes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the world's greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            To his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit, Stross</ENAMEX> does grasp what's right at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>: the hard-boiled
meritocracy that makes rich those who contribute to it; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' prediction
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, not just large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, would jump at the chance to own
computers; and his--and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s--driving desire to outsmart and outfox
the competition. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stross</ENAMEX> fails to see the larger context for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
dominance, and we know that from the get-go, when he begins his book with a
pretentious foreword that postulates the similarities between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, a comparison to which he alludes repeatedly over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 239</TIMEX>
pages.

            
In fact, the flawed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> analogy is a
perfect metaphor for what's wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stross</ENAMEX>' book. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> lay in mass
production, and in bringing down the cost of the product so that the consumer
could afford to purchase a one-time luxury item. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of computing,
that feat was accomplished not by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>--who has never fought to reduce the
price of computing power, lest his margins suffer unnecessarily--but by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Grove</ENAMEX>, and the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Noyce</ENAMEX>--who,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before his death, joked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> that computers in the future would
not only be more powerful than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> mainframes, but would be smaller, and much,
much cheaper.

            A better
comparison for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> would have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller</ENAMEX>, who sought to
monopolize the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> that went into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS-DOS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 95</ENAMEX>,
gasoline engines serve as the operating system of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, and to be the dominant
provider of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> for that operating system seems a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>-like.

            This hits on the larger flaw of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stross</ENAMEX>' analysis. Had the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> drawn the obvious parallels, he would have run the risk of endorsing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s case against the monopolist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, a case Stross
spends almost the entire book debunking. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX> is a benign, friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that succeeded in spite of itself. It
dominated the software industry because its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> were such lightweights and
buffoons, and because it hired the smartest and brightest software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>.
When it came up against serious competition, in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intuit</ENAMEX>, it was just
another bumbling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, hardly worth the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antitrust Division</ENAMEX>'s time. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
recap: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> vetoed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> attempt to purchase
Intuit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of the personal-finance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">program Quicken</ENAMEX>, on the grounds that it
was anti-competitive--a bid to corner the personal-finance-software market.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s aborted purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intuit</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stross</ENAMEX>, shows not only that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> does not dominate, it can't even shoot straight.

            Stross
could have written a fabulous book about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s meritocracy produced a
perfect monopoly, out of sheer grit and the love bestowed upon its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s mutual funds (their fondness for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock yielded
a price that allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, with its handsome stock-option compensation
program, to hold on to its best, most talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>). He could have written
about how severely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> was soon to be tested by the Internet, and by
its proselytizer, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Andreessen</ENAMEX>. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stross</ENAMEX> spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most of</TIMEX>
his time talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s attempts to produce consumer-software CDs,
which is only anecdotally interesting. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intriguing</ENAMEX>, though, to learn that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> only approached <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Funk & Wagnalls</ENAMEX> to collaborate on an encyclopedia
CD-ROM after being turned down by a haughty Encyclopedia

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britannica</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Funk & Wagnalls' Encarta</ENAMEX> is now the
leading encyclopedia in the multimedia market, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britannica</ENAMEX> is up
for sale.) And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stross</ENAMEX> skips almost entirely over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s chief strength,
the operating systems of both personal computers (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> MS-DOS and then Windows
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>) and big corporate machines (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows NT</ENAMEX>). Rather than find out how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
produced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encarta</ENAMEX> , I would really like to know how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> got every PC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to load its computers with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> software and not that of other--at
times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior</ENAMEX>--operating systems (the conventional wisdom that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> handed
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>' standards out to everyone while his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> kept their
standards proprietary doesn't begin to account for the enormity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>).

            
Don't get me wrong. I didn't agree with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s suit for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX>. I don't want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to be punished
simply because it dominates. Were it not for the monopolistic traits of both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, I believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> would have had a choke hold on
this industry and destroyed the comeback that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has enjoyed in the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>. But if you come at the industry with the perspective of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stross</ENAMEX> does, you won't ever learn--let alone be able to
explain--why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> succeeds the way it does.

            Had Stross written his book
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, he would have had a whole new story line: how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was or was
not able to translate its dominance in personal computers to the Internet. This
phenomenon happened so quickly, like much in the computer industry, that Stross
couldn't incorporate it cogently. Somehow I got the feeling, when reading
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Way</ENAMEX> , that I was reading about the greatness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
army and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maginot</ENAMEX> line in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> may not be waking up in the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">middle of the night</TIMEX> worried about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> has stormed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ardennes</ENAMEX> on
the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sedan</ENAMEX>, but I'm sure somebody at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is worried (probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
Ballmer, a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> of mine who would wake up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX>
if he bothered to sleep), and is working on a devastating counterattack this
very moment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> doesn't seem like the kind of place that would fight new
wars with old-war strategies, but it is insightful to see just how little of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stross</ENAMEX> saw was focused on the Net, and how much was focused
on old-fashioned software-delivery systems.

            Maybe we'll never know what
really goes on inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I've worked with there, including
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, certainly don't seem to know. Whether that's by design or
disinformation on the part of their nonjournalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>, I can't
tell. My conclusion after reading The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Way</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stross</ENAMEX> has plenty
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> when it comes to those who are clueless about this huge capitalist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> story.

         
      
   
