
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Thing We Expected</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Didion</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>
is a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in stories. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Didion</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> has a habit of
distrusting them. In her essays, she has confidently found narrative
everywhere--in the worship of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX>, in the empty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jogger</ENAMEX>'s fate. But in her fiction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> gets
the jitters at the mere thought of spinning out a tale. The anxious narrators
of her disjointedly elliptical novels are always interrupting, challenging,
undercutting themselves. By fits and starts: that is how they write, a stylized
stuttering that has become <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>'s trademark delivery. That is also how her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> live. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> protagonist is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> adrift in history, her own
and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's</ENAMEX>.

            Her new novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last</ENAMEX>
Thing He Wanted , is about--what else?--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> adrift in history, her own
and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena McMahon</ENAMEX>, given to "fast walks and clean starts," fits the
mold of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, sensitive yet impassive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> proficient at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forgetting</ENAMEX> and at never looking far ahead. She has learned how to evade her
past, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Wyeth</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Play It As It Lays</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Book of Common Prayer</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>), who cope with crisis by
living only "in the now," never risking "the backward glance." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena</ENAMEX>, a course
of radiation treatments for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> behind her, has distanced herself
from her dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, her rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-husband</ENAMEX>, her resentful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. Now
crisscrossing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> covering the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> presidential campaign for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , she feels "a fatigue near vertigo" at the daily
round of spin, counterspin, rumors, denials. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Inez Victor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a
vacuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>), she is quickly mastering a
"capacity for passive detachment." In fact, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when the action of the
novel begins, she walks off the campaign, without a clue as to what she plans
to do next.

            
               The
Last Thing He Wanted also features a self-consciously intrusive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>--nothing new here, either. This time, the uneasy voice is that of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">nameless California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who has written about administration policy in
Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> (she could, in other words, be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Didion</ENAMEX>
herself). The novel unfolds in the cinematic style that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> has made her
own: flashbacks, flash-forwards, crosscuts, staccato bursts of dialogue, now
and then "a montage, music over." The quest to assemble the shards of
experience, too, is by now familiar. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, cross-examines
the inscrutable life of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena McMahon</ENAMEX>, hoping but not really
expecting to find meaning in it.

            In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Thing</ENAMEX> He Wanted looks like proof
of what you may have suspected for some time: that for all its restlessness
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> form, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Didion</ENAMEX>'s fiction is formulaic--even contrived. The
exhilarating surprise of her new novel is that in it, she masters one of the
most contrived forms of all, the thriller. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Followers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>'s studiously
anticlimactic, fragmented fiction will find it hard to believe, but her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
novel has perfect pitch and pace, and is hauntingly hard to put down.

            The truth
is that suspense and plot, though never before part of the technique of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>'s fiction, have always been its subject. Novels are where she frets
about narrative, its possibilities and deceptions. Her protagonists are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enigmas</ENAMEX>--to themselves, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, and, not least, the
mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who hover at the edge of their lives, in love with them. These
male figures are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plotters</ENAMEX> in a dimly lit world where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, corporate powers,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, and small-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schemers</ENAMEX> do deals, stage coups, order up murders. To
what end they maneuver has never been clear, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who in their remote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> are drawn to them, can't bring themselves to care. The point has been that
the suspense is endless, that there is finally no meaningful plot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>'s
parables about anomie in post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>-era <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> have implied that once
history is forgotten, identity dissolves and conspiracy--and the suspicion of
it--is the only guide.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Thing He Wanted</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> gets
to the bottom of the mystery for once, and a parable that had long since begun
to seem world-weary becomes unexpectedly gripping. Cut loose from the scripted
charade of the campaign beat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena McMahon</ENAMEX> gets caught up in the machinations
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> in dangerous merchandise, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMahon</ENAMEX>. In fact, completely against type, she acquires an active role in the
operation.

            Another
"clean start" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena</ENAMEX>, this one is launched in a customary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> daze. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena</ENAMEX>
barely knows what she is doing when she buys a ticket to see her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, though then it dawns on her that she wants to persuade him of something
that he, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena</ENAMEX> herself, seems to be having trouble absorbing: that her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>--is now dead. When the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> gets sick soon after her
arrival, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who missed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> has a chance to make
amends for a lifelong habit of aloofness. (Finally, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> who makes a
motive clear!) Filling in for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> on his latest deal, she accompanies a
shipment of arms in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L-100</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> to somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX>,
where she has been told she will receive payment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>. "The
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million-dollar</NUMEX> score, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million-dollar</NUMEX> pop, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million-dollar</NUMEX> payday," is
the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick McMahon</ENAMEX> puts it to her in a febrile panic. This is the "major
deal" he has been awaiting all his life.

            Of course, that is only the beginning of the story--and by
the time you've pieced this much together, the plot has deepened to involve
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Treat Morrison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>-at-large, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> policy toward
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan contras</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena McMahon</ENAMEX> has been propelled into a demimonde
where, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> puts it in a knowing pastiche of official jargon, those
"trying to create a context for democracy" are "maybe getting [their] hands a
little dirty in the process or just opting out, letting the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> call it."
This is the realm where history--such as it is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> believes--gets made,
"exclusively and at random by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick McMahon</ENAMEX>" and his much more
ruthless higher-ups.

            
Scrutinized from the ground, which is where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena McMahon</ENAMEX> are,
this history is not as random as it might seem. It's an eerie blend of careful
planning and pure chance, impromptu schemes and long-running designs. As she
plays out the process of converting "humanitarian resupply" into "lethal
resupply," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> seems to allude (as she did in her book <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> ) to the
theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>-trained anti-Castro <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> have been at work in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a few</NUMEX>
dubious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> exploits. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> on an island near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>
prepares to bring in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Forces</ENAMEX> in case of a "full-scale effort,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadier men</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist friends</ENAMEX> and lots of experience in international
subterfuge are busy plotting with "the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>" to make such an "effort"
occur. So is a slick congressional foreign-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exiles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX>. The plot happens to be
an assassination, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena McMahon</ENAMEX> soon figures.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>, in other words, has written a
fast-paced story, not just her usual series of fractured "stories." As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX> explains: "Every moment could be seen to connect to every other
moment, every act to have logical if obscure consequences, an unbroken
narrative of vivid complexity." It is not overarching moral or political
meaning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> has suddenly discovered. No historically significant
struggle of good against evil has dawned in her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, where a frontier ethos
has long since declined into corruption and cynicism. It is emotional meaning
that she registers, with a vivid simplicity and in the unlikeliest of places.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> has always been an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on coolness, numbness, in hot climates. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, at the heart of a carefully constructed thriller is a romance, which is
no less tragic--in fact, is more tragic--for being oblique. It is born of
another of those fated yet fortuitous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>'s disorienting
world, this one between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena McMahon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treat Morrison</ENAMEX>) who "were
equally remote."

            As she
tries to decipher the convoluted course of her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central American</ENAMEX> adventure,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena McMahon</ENAMEX>, "not one of those who saw in a flash how every moment could
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">connect</ENAMEX>," discovers memory and imagination--faculties that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>'s previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heroines</ENAMEX> did their best to deny. She has exchanged a hollow life for a
"heightened life," and has tried to "comprehend all its turns, get its
possibilities." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who do that, the narrator observes, "are at heart
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">storytellers</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> should know, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX> of weaving her intricate
essays. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Thing He Wanted</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> finally gives
in to the narrative urge.

         
      
   
