
   
   
      
         
            Black Brainpower

            There's been a lot of talk
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> recently, in such places as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> . Much of it has
picked up on the even more considerable chat about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> in general and
the "public intellectual" in particular. Many of us got our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sense of that
term reading about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Left Bank</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartre</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Beauvoir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camus</ENAMEX> in dark
sweaters and a haze of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaulloises</ENAMEX>, quaffing rough red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and arguing about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Absolute</ENAMEX>--or the slightly less outre Partisan

               Review <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s and 1950s</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Given the
whiteness of those images and the long history of denying intellectual aptitude
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>, it's surely good news that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the word
"intellectual" is as likely to evoke <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sontag</ENAMEX>.

            The
reason for this is obvious. There's a longer list now than ever before of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, ensconced in the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prestige</ENAMEX>, producing scholarly works, and discussing with a popular audience
questions about race in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. In the past, the disciplinary heart of
this activity lay in the social sciences. Now, the rise of black studies has
produced a new wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> in the humanities, many of
whom share the engagement with the work of contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> that
characterized the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Left Bank</ENAMEX> milieu. Some, like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Adrian Piper</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellesley</ENAMEX> (a
philosophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and conceptual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, are
both serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and substantial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. So, it might seem that the time
has come for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Intellectuals</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William M. Banks</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African-American</ENAMEX> studies at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>), a book that claims to be the first
historical survey of its subject, from the colonial period to the present.

            Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banks</ENAMEX> discusses--bell hooks, or my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>, for example--are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> in
the stricter sense of the word. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Left Bankers</ENAMEX>, they had elite
educations; like them, they address questions about our public life. And they
write hard books--post-structuralist literary criticism, feminist theory,
post-analytic philosophy--as well as memoirs and essays for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> outside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banks</ENAMEX>
chooses to begin with the medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, who are, he
asserts, the ancestors of contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>. I am
leery of this desire to extend the category of "intellectual" in all sorts of
directions away from those with a vocation to scholarship or writing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX>'
choice of a starting point seems to invoke an expansive notion of the
intellectual that includes some (but not all) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, novelists,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, and poets--an idea I
think muddies more than it clarifies.

            
I've been at conferences where gangsta rappers
have been characterized as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, apparently on the theory that the
term is apt when celebrating anyone who ever had and expressed an idea some
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> liked. The problem here isn't that rappers don't
think--although sometimes that is a problem--but that only an academic
would suppose that calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>" is the best way to take them
seriously. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> nowadays use the term "intellectual" as an honorific,
and often as little more.

            More
important, all the different ways of using your intellect in different
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, for different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>, in different social circles, with
differing degrees of self-consciousness, do not, it seems to me, produce the
kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you can shoehorn into a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. There are societies, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, where such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> constitute a self-conscious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with a shared
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> life--what is called an "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX>." There are societies, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> speak to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, as Émile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zola</ENAMEX> did in the course of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreyfus</ENAMEX> affair (which is the context in which the
word "intellectual" was first used in its modern sense). But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
is not, in these ways, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. The current fashion for talk
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> will leave some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to expect a few clear definitions
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banks</ENAMEX>. But this is something <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banks</ENAMEX> avoids--wisely, in my view.

            In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banks</ENAMEX>' concession to this academic vogue is almost
entirely limited to the medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> of his first chapter. The
decision is a reflection, I think, not of his catering to fashion, but of the
problem facing anyone whose aim is to write the first full history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>: namely, that since the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>
were slaves introduced largely for manual labor, intellectual activity is
naturally not a large part of their record. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> had used slaves as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teachers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman Empire</ENAMEX>), but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
slaves were brought to the New World to use their muscles, not their minds.

            Still,
many of the slaves transplanted to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>,
and could read and write <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>. Their narratives, now translated, offer, along
with the medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> who cared about
the cultivation of knowledge. Does it matter that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banks</ENAMEX> omits them from his
story? That depends on whether your interest is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> or in the present.
The intellectual traditions encoded in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> religion and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> literacy
played little role in shaping the later intellectual life of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, black
or white; the great contribution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> inheritance to black, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, religion came from elsewhere. (Attempts to connect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
Christianity with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> traditions stem from the more recent ideas of black
power.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX>' heart, it seems to me, is in the present: He is tracing the
ancestry of contemporary black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> to claim for them the title to a
substantial tradition. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> slaves would be a distraction.

            
In discussing a time when black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and women
with an intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vocation</ENAMEX> were deprived of the chance to make a living
through the pen, there is a case for looking in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> black life for the
places to which those thwarted thinkers diverted their energies. But as black
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> developed after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, and increasingly since the
desegregation of elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, intellectual life for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>--as for
everyone--has come to be centered, for better and for worse, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>.
Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most important novelists, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>, are
now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>. It is not surprising, then, that as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Intellectuals</ENAMEX>
reaches into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, it is increasingly about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> does not, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, succumb to the desire to include everyone who ever
had an idea.

            Indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> has written a useful survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and
the ways in which they have worked throughout the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>. His
central themes are debates over the meaning of race and how black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>
(whoever they may be) have negotiated their relationship with "ordinary" black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. As the book discusses the fate of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>, or the participation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> in
government during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, it draws a sharp picture of the fate of blacks
with brains, forced, whatever their real interests, to deal with the question
of race. His later chapters ask whether, in a new world where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> are
present (if still in small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX>) in our society's most powerful intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinkers</ENAMEX> might be free to spend less time thinking about
what it means to be black.

            The book ends with a reflection on the argument between
"those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> who advocate an organic relationship with the black
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> and those who aspire to transcend ethnic considerations," suggesting,
affably, that the choice must be left, in our individualist culture, for each
of us to make for ourselves. This is a little too simple. These are not, after
all, the only options: Some of us who don't want to be the organic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> of the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> (or of anywhere else) are not disposed simply
to "transcend" our racial identities either. And, even if the choice were up to
each of us, it would be a choice we make in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that still places
strong constraints on what a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> can do. The individualist ideal in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> lives side by side with powerful notions of racial obligation.

            A survey of this sort allows
little time for mining the substantial debates among black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, but
the main ones get at least a mention. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> general issue is curiously
absent: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Afrocentrism</ENAMEX>. If, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> normally assumes, any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
academic who has an engagement with the fate of the race is part of the story,
I am not sure why he thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molefi K. Asante</ENAMEX>, who can make a
reasonable claim to having invented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Afrocentrism</ENAMEX> as an academic subject,
doesn't merit discussion. I suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX>' choice reflects his own commitment
to a sensibly conventional vision of the intellectual life, one that casts more
light--and less heat--than much of the heady verbiage in the current debates
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Intellectual</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
