
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keystone Nazis</ENAMEX>

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question that has
to be asked about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> is: Did it exist? A good case can be
made that it did not. To frame the question less contentiously: Did the
scattered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, and (in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case) ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX> who defied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> act more as isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> than as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concerted</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>? On the large stage of history, do these brave individuals
shrink to statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insignificance</ENAMEX>? And is the so-called resistance movement
therefore a kind of optical illusion, generated by a need to find some shred of
goodness or worth in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>? It has to be said that books
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> seem to greatly outnumber the resisters themselves. The
stack before me now includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore S. Hamerow</ENAMEX>'s On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s
Lair: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German Resistance</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim Fest</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan Stoltzfus' Resistance of the Heart</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intermarriage</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rosenstrasse Protest</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>); and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Hoffmann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stauffenberg: A Family History</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905-1944</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>).

            
Certainly, these books are not mythographies. They are sober, sometimes
skeptical historical accounts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fest</ENAMEX> surveys resistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, paying particular attention to the military plot, whose deficiencies he
chronicles mercilessly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamerow</ENAMEX> examines the motives of the resisters, both
civilian and military; he shows them weaving sinuously between self-interest
and idealism. Stoltzfus, writing of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who marched down
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosenstrasse</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> to protest the incarceration of their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>,
sees that his case is something less than a study in pure virtue: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> cared
nothing for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> unless self-interest intervened. And yet--with one
exception--I came away feeling these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> had exaggerated the significance
of their subject. The exception is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffmann</ENAMEX>'s book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claus von Stauffenberg</ENAMEX>,
who nearly killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> with a bomb on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20, 1944</TIMEX>. Stauffenberg was a very
strange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has to be considered as a phenomenon unto himself (and will be,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fest</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of perhaps the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> biography,
begins his book with a chapter titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Resistance That Never Was</ENAMEX>," which
covers the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933-37</TIMEX> period. His stage-setting narrative is a conventional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> cements his hold on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> through a combination of rhetoric, political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stratagems</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fest</ENAMEX> states that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> was the only organization able
to keep its structure intact, and therefore the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in a position to mount
a concerted resistance. He omits, however, certain successful--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un</ENAMEX>-military--protests in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s policies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> more
or less collectively decried <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s plan to kill off the mentally and
physically disabled. There were also protests against domestic austerities
during the armaments buildup of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935-36</TIMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Kershaw</ENAMEX> has
demonstrated, this kind of pinpoint, smaller-scale resistance was common in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX>. No general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> emerged because very few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> were
generally unhappy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>.

            As Fest
describes it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s first plot against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> came in the tense weeks
before the conclusion of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> agreement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> seemed determined to
lead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> into a war for which military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> felt neither ready nor
eager. Had he marched toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> at that time, they would have arrested
him--or assassinated him outright. The broader circle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX>--centering on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludwig Beck</ENAMEX>, who had resigned as army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of
staff in protest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s war plans--agreed to the idea of seizing and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imprisoning Hitler</ENAMEX>. It was even proposed that he be declared insane by a panel
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX>. An "inner" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> should be summarily
shot. This interesting debate became moot once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> abruptly changed his mind
and accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chamberlain</ENAMEX>'s peace offer at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX>. The conspiracy fell apart
because it depended too much on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s own plans.

            
After a long period of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disillusionment</ENAMEX>--uncomfortably mixed with exhilaration at the success of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blitzkrieg</ENAMEX>--and as soon as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> decreed the invasion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> began to plot again. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March of 1943</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henning von Tresckow</ENAMEX> concealed
a bomb in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cointreau</ENAMEX> and had them carried onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>.
The bottles mysteriously failed to explode. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that month</TIMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tresckow</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> had a bomb wired to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, and followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> through an
exhibition of military trophies; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> mysteriously exited through a side
door. Another attempt fell through when a scheduled presentation of military
uniforms never took place. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March of 1944</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eberhard von Breitenbuch</ENAMEX> announced
that he would shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> in the mouth at a briefing. He was pulled away from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FÃ</ENAMEX>¼hrer at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX> because of a change in agenda. The last
and most nearly effective of the plots was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stauffenberg's</ENAMEX>, which hinged not
only on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> he brought into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s Lair" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prussia</ENAMEX>, but also on coordinated strikes against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> power structure in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> and all across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            The
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> tended to defeat themselves at every turn. To begin with,
there was a high ratio of memorandum-writing to action. Much thought was given
to a new constitution, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s proper postwar borders, and other untimely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meditations</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading Fest</ENAMEX>'s book, I was often reminded of the scene in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty Python's Life</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> in which anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Front of Judaea</ENAMEX> respond to a new crisis by shouting out, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right</ENAMEX>! This
calls for immediate discussion!") As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fest</ENAMEX> notes, the plans were always
contingent; they were also needlessly intricate. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> plot fell apart when
a newfangled detonating mechanism proved too complicated for anyone in the high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">command</ENAMEX> to understand.

            Should the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plotters</ENAMEX> receive credit for their intentions,
rather than their actions? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamerow</ENAMEX> takes up this question. He asks whether the
resisters were driven by genuine dislike of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> and his ideas, or whether
they decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was superfluous only after his string of victories
turned into a string of defeats. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamerow</ENAMEX> comes up with a mass of contradictory
evidence. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX>, certainly, were cold-blooded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatists</ENAMEX>; others
were disaffected front-line <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> who had suffered on the Eastern front.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than a few</NUMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and monarchist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who deplored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s tendency toward self-deification. Almost all were devoted to the
traditions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> military and infuriated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s peremptory
directives from on high.

            Sometimes,
there was also a moral strain to their deliberations. Several of these men
seemed to sense the full dimensions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Axel von dem Bussche</ENAMEX>
reeled in shock from a mass execution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Yorck von</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wartenburg</ENAMEX> stated at his treason trial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> that the escalation of
anti-Semitism into genocide was the single cause of his "inner break" with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazism</ENAMEX> (a claim that gained him nothing before a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>); and Tresckow
understood the genocidal implications of the orders accompanying plans for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> invasion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamerow</ENAMEX> quotes a moving statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tresckow</ENAMEX>: "If God once
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">promised Abraham</ENAMEX> that he would destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sodom</ENAMEX> if only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> lived
there, then I hope that because of us God will also not destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>."
Departing dramatically from the cautious analysis that guides the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of
his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamerow</ENAMEX> names <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yorck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tresckow</ENAMEX> in just such a circle of the
righteous, "for whose sake God would spare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamerow</ENAMEX> is in dubious pursuit of a select
circle of absolutely "good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>," and his emphasis on intentions over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX> leads to strange choices. His pantheon also includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut von</ENAMEX>
Moltke, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kreisau Circle</ENAMEX>, a religious-philosophical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> that spent most of its time imagining an ideal future <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> society. But
Moltke was firmly opposed to the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>; when he was put on trial with
the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> plot, he was impressed--almost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heartened</ENAMEX>--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> gave him a death sentence simply for thinking about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>. (It testified, he thought, to the power of the mind!)
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamerow</ENAMEX> "demotes" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX> on the grounds that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berthold</ENAMEX> failed to dissociate himself completely from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> thinking at
his trial. To consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moltke</ENAMEX> more "righteous" than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX>--the one who
actually did something--borders on the perverse.

            History
sometimes tells simple stories. The fact that none of the various attempts,
plans, and general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspiratorial</ENAMEX> notions to assassinate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> succeeded--and
that all but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stauffenberg</ENAMEX>'s never seemed plausible--speaks for itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hitler</ENAMEX>
was an easy target; he liked to show himself in public and did not always
travel in conditions of airtight security. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> literature often
comments on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s "amazing luck," or his "uncanny" ability to sense danger;
but the failures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> might be better ascribed to the calculated
unluck of the resisters, their own ability to sense danger and step away from
it, and their overall minuscule number. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s death by his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX> cannot
be counted as one of history's accidents. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> could not imagine any other
death for him.

            

               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> : The mysterious motives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
