
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood Shuffle</ENAMEX>

            Soon
after taking over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guber</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Peters</ENAMEX> got
down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of establishing their importance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>: They
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redecorated</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> particularly wanted to impress the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Corp.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, so they redid their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> motif,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">importing Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to put up <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cedar</ENAMEX> paneling over a special kind of mud
used in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> construction. Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> humidity melted
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> buckled. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guber</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX> fled to new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> shortly
thereafter.

            
The marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> worked out
about the same way. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>, the electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> famous for inventing and
marketing products that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> never knew they wanted, shelled out what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> reported to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, a figure that included
the cost of severing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guber</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX>' existing contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>. Everyone
else in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> was flabbergasted and jealous, while the media dwelled on
fears that a cultural treasure was being gobbled up. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, though, it was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> who were swallowed whole. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years</TIMEX> after the purchase, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> had
to write off <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.2 billion</NUMEX> on its investment, one of the biggest losses in
industry history.

            In their book, Hit and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>: How <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Peters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guber Took Sony</ENAMEX> for a Ride in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Griffin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Masters</ENAMEX>
outline the colossal arrogance, excess, and self-delusion that led to the
debacle. Their steady stream of malicious, if clumsily written, anecdotes is
nothing if not entertaining. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Peters</ENAMEX>, everyone knows, began as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streisand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdresser</ENAMEX>. Here we learn that he also played a critical role in
her sexual awakening--that their marathon fights, followed by sex, freed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diva</ENAMEX> to experience a new "assertiveness" in bed. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, however, he was a
hot-tempered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, threatening at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point to break a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>'s jaw. On
another occasion, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streisand</ENAMEX> confessed that she had never seen an
uncircumcised penis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX> ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> to come over and drop
his pants. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX> also sent the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>, laden with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, to a model
he was courting, and ordered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> to call ahead to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> so someone
could be poised to open his car door when he arrived.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guber</ENAMEX>--a ponytailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buff</ENAMEX> who rose through the ranks at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>--refused to be interviewed for the book. Perhaps as a result, he comes
across even worse than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX>. Most damaging for his future job <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> is
the implicit suggestion that he cynically exploited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> to advance his own
movies and sybaritic lifestyle, never caring much about the parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
long-term interests. With a habit of disappearing during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> of crisis at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guber</ENAMEX> came across to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> as ambivalent, at best, about working
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. "They haven't bought me," he told a fellow studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>.
"They're only renting me for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> may be most amused by
lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Canton</ENAMEX>, the credit-hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of production at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, who pathetically asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Few Good Men to</ENAMEX>
thank him publicly at the premiere (they did) and implored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Nolte</ENAMEX> to thank
him if he got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Globe</ENAMEX> award for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tides</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte</ENAMEX> won, but
didn't).

            There are plenty of problems with the way Hit and
Run is told. It relies too heavily on anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, and the trade
press has begun complaining that some of its stories are bogus. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of
Variety , for instance, has indignantly denied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' assertion
that he suppressed publication of financial documents embarrassing to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
Pictures. The book's tone also is relentlessly caustic. Can there ever have
been a more loathsome collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">charlatans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sycophants</ENAMEX>, and back-stabbers?
Come to think of it, maybe not.

            But the book's value lies
less in the anecdotes than in what it has to tell us about how one of the
biggest entertainment deals went awry at a time when the industry was
consolidating everywhere, heading toward domination by a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or eight</NUMEX>
multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--all of which face the headache of competing fiefdoms.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony-Columbia</ENAMEX> deal is a cautionary tale, even though larger lessons are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX>' forte.

            One
does wish that they had more to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>' misplaced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> in "synergy," since the search for that elusive ideal has run so
spectacularly aground in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> deals. It was especially disastrous in the
acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA Inc.</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>'s electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matsushita</ENAMEX>, which took
place about the same time. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matsushita</ENAMEX> later sold the majority interest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.7 billion</NUMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX> sale did not involve the same level of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plunder</ENAMEX>. In both takeovers, though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> thought that by selling,
it could tap into a bottomless well of capital with which to buy television
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and the like. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, were
hoping for a new source of "software" (i.e., movies and television shows) for
their digital televisions, compact discs, and other new products. They counted
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> to produce it in a reliable way.

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> refused to cooperate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of
Hit and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX> , so we don't get much insight into the thought processes of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. Did they have a "mole" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> or not? How much did they
know about what they were getting into? We never find out. But we do get
snapshots of the mindset that allowed them to get sucked into the vortex of
financial losses. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norio Ohga</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>, joined a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> to tour the set of Who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s more successful television shows. All they did was look at the
cameras and ask who made the video tape and what kind of lead density it
had.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> may have been confused, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who supposedly represented
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> seem frankly guilty of misleading them. If anything, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffin</ENAMEX>
and Masters let these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> off too easily. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter G. Peterson</ENAMEX>, the
prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX>, then-head of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creative</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists Agency</ENAMEX>, would seem to have been more interested in making money out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> deal than in warning their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>, about the risks, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> are too polite to come right out and say so. Also treated kindly is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Schulhof</ENAMEX>, the miscast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> (he had no
background in the movie business). After backing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guber</ENAMEX> through a series of
disasters, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schulhof</ENAMEX> eventually admitted that he was unable to get the producer
to change his management style. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> do not hold Schulhof
accountable. They do not ask what changes he had in mind, other than getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guber</ENAMEX> to try harder to make better movies at lower cost.

            
               Hit and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX> is further undercut by parochialism,
especially evident in its constant use of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> jargon. This is a book in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> never approve a movie; they "greenlight" it. Even beyond the
klunky language, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> fail to transcend their narrow context and explore
what management success in the movie business might have entailed. The only
clear measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guber</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX>' misjudgment is their overspending for
antique furniture, yachts, slumber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aspen</ENAMEX>, and the like, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbing</ENAMEX> succession of box-office bombs. (Actually, some of the bombs were
pretty good movies, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Remains of the Day</ENAMEX>, while others, like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">much-maligned Last Action Hero</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>, were failures in an
interesting way.)

            With their
backgrounds--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffin</ENAMEX> is deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premiere</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masters</ENAMEX>, a
contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> --the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> should
have been able to tell us a little more about why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movies are so bad.
Instead, they have written the story of a failure, albeit one with important
consequences for the industry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Hopefully, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who read the story of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>'s less-than-excellent adventure in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> will look a little more
skeptically at the vaporous claims surrounding other megamergers in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> business. They will have less patience for optimistic talk about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synergy</ENAMEX> and the marriage of content with distribution. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Goldman</ENAMEX> put
it, when it comes to what works or doesn't in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, "nobody knows
anything."

         
      
   
