
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 Million</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bride</ENAMEX>?
            

            In the new movie 
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bachelor</ENAMEX>
               , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> leaves his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$100 million</ENAMEX>
in his will. The catch: To receive his inheritance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> must be
married before his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 th</NUMEX> birthday. Is this sort of restriction legal?
And are there any limits on the conditions one can place on a gift?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpa</ENAMEX> is well within his rights; conditional gifts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> are not uncommon. Although the laws vary from state to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have generally reasoned that since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> is free to decline
the gift, such conditions don't violate anyone's rights.

            So, wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are free to put virtually any restriction on their
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">estates</ENAMEX>. Inherited money is most frequently contingent upon the recipient's
getting a college education or staying out of legal trouble. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have
even upheld <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' right to condition gifts on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>'s abstaining from
smoking or marrying someone of a certain religion or ethnicity. And conditional
gifts to charities--such as the donation of a university <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with the
restriction that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> not be served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>--have long been made.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have made a only few exceptions:

            

               
                  The condition cannot require a violation of the law. This
principle has been used most frequently to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> from having to
uphold illegal racial restrictions in order to receive property. For instance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have overturned the proviso that donated parkland be available only to
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

               
                  The condition cannot run counter to "public policy."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> vary in their interpretation of this principle but have generally used
it to strike down requirements that prohibit marriage or encourage divorce.
(Most commonly, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will attempt to leave property to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> as long as she
never remarries.) It has also been used to repeal requirements that would cause
family strife--for example, the provision that inherited land can only be used
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. And it has prevented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> from being
required to change their religion or name.

               
                  The condition cannot last forever. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> consider it
undesirable for someone to control property or land for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after
his death. So in most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, restrictions on private inheritances are limited
to the lifetime of living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> plus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years</TIMEX> (conditions on bequests
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> can often last longer). After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, the property and decision
rights must be transferred to an individual or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            Next question?

         
      
   
