
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahir</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Diaper-Clad Chat-Room Denizens</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Todd</ENAMEX>,

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> in the letter you filed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about noon</TIMEX> you said, "I see that Mahir
has finally made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>." My first impulse was to write back,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's Mahir?</ENAMEX>" but I felt incredibly stupid for not knowing who Mahir was,
which lead me to assume that he had to be either a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> (pick a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sport</ENAMEX>, any sport) or someone connected to the opera or the ballet. Then, for a
second I thought there was a typo involved and you were actually speaking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maher</ENAMEX>, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Politically Incorrect</ENAMEX> . But I couldn't imagine
out why he mattered to you so much that you were gleefully remarking on his
inclusion in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . Not wanting to own up to being either ignorant or
unhip, I never said a word, even though I still wanted to in my first letter
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. Instead, I quietly typed his name into a search engine and found
out everything I needed to know. And I only mention this because I now realize
that no way was I the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who had no idea to whom you were referring
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. Which, of course, was kind of a relief.

            Moving on to weightier matters: Did you read that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> is set to
star as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Allen Poe</ENAMEX> in a new movie? The racial discrepancy of this casting
choice doesn't bother me nearly as much as the fact that portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Allen</ENAMEX>
Poe as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with a high-pitched, breathless voice who has had a ton of plastic
surgery would put such a completely different spin on what might have been the
psychological issues behind the writing of those scary twisted stories that it
just might be impossible to ever really enjoy them again. It's almost like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hiring Richard Simmons</ENAMEX> to play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Moveable Feast</ENAMEX> .
Although, now that I think about it more, I would do almost anything for a
chance to see that movie made.

            Apparently a new study of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s media habits just released by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Family Foundation</ENAMEX> reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 2 and 18</TIMEX> spend about
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five and a half hours</TIMEX> a day consuming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> ... mostly TV. But as I was
analyzing the figures, I noticed that the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 2</TIMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> who have a TV right in their very own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> watch an average of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours nine minutes</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>. In other words, as I see it, the more central the TV
is to their world, the less they want anything to do with it. This is something
I have long suspected, as I have found there is no more effective way to get
someone to cut back on their TV viewing than to put them front and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> on a
TV show. And if you give them a job in the writing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, they may just
decide to never even own TV again, period.

            I don't know how the statistics fall as far as the homeless and TV viewing,
but according to the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> , they are spending a
lot more time online. The article reports that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of homeless shelters
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have installed computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> that would be the envy of most
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>." I guess just because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> doesn't have a permanent address
is no reason they shouldn't be allowed to give themselves a wacky pseudonym and
log on to a chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> full of adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in diapers like everyone else. But I
have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who keep telling me that online dating is the answer. And as far
as I am concerned this is the final nail in the coffin of online dating for me
because I am not meeting anyone for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> at a homeless shelter. Period. I
don't care how single and sensitive they otherwise appear to be.

            You know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> when I was snooping around at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cyber-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">handbag emporium</ENAMEX> I found myself wondering how she had turned into a
handbag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> simply by sitting around eating fists full of éclairs at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX> and then making crosstown limo rides to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> for grand jury
appearances. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I noticed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomingdale's</ENAMEX> is running <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX>-page
ad in the front section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> that says "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet Designer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Shoshanna</ENAMEX>' at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomingdale's</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 20</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-4</NUMEX>." It features a photo of one-time
teen-age- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>-of<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-Jerry-Seinfeld's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoshanna Lonstein</ENAMEX>, posing in "her
own holiday creation--a garnet self striped strapless silk taffeta
dress--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$255</NUMEX>." What I conclude from this is that apparently surviving a
controversial and highly publicized affair with a famous male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> figure
confers upon a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> not just symptoms of post-traumatic-stress disorder, but
also a functioning set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> skills and abilities equivalent to a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX> of arts degree. Which means I think we can all look forward
to at least a line of whimsical scarves or belts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marla Maples</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duff</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>.

            Did you read that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> discovered a gene that exerts major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> over the life span of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>? This is considered a milestone in research
concerning anti-aging. And I suppose even if they never find the corresponding
gene in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, it will still make us all feel younger at heart to be around so
many younger looking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
