
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble's Gamble</ENAMEX>

Times all lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist party</ENAMEX>'s (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionists</ENAMEX>) vote to join the region's local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition government</ENAMEX>. This
body, established by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> Good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> agreement, aims to replace direct
rule from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> with an autonomous local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> representing both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">/nationalist</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">/Loyalist factions</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unionists</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>, had previously refused to take part in the
government until the IRA had disarmed. This reticence had rendered the
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">impotent</ENAMEX> since its initial meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>.

            What's the next step? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unionists</ENAMEX> now expect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> and the IRA to
begin disarming. All the papers quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trimble</ENAMEX>'s message to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>: "We've jumped. You follow." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> will appoint a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">delegate</ENAMEX> to a disarmament <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> convenes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX> has threatened to resign and pull his party out of the joint
government if the IRA hasn't handed over some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the LAT mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> was unhappy with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX>'s
remarks, but only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says why: such ultimatums, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>,
merely fuel the hopes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naysayers</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faiths</ENAMEX> who want the peace to
fail.

            In general, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> see the vote as a big step. Though the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>
percent support among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulster Unionists</ENAMEX> was less than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX> hoped for ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ), he managed to effect a major
change in policy without splintering his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and LAT
emphasize this "we've come a long way" angle, noting that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimble</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deputies</ENAMEX> helped derail the last attempt at a shared local government 25 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trimble</ENAMEX> was also involved). A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> editorial calls the vote "the equivalent of the fall of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX>," but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> claim the measure was "akin to turkeys voting
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the LAT front stories on the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Organization</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. The summit, and the protests raging
around it, will help shape the debate over the nature and aims of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalization</ENAMEX>, with many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> decrying the secretive, undemocratic nature
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> itself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also reports that union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> will
dump <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> steel into the harbor during a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Steel Party</ENAMEX>," but it
doesn't say why.

            A popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Kouri</ENAMEX>, was sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> in
prison and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> banishment from publishing for blasphemous statements,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s leading
pro-democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, was also shut down. Kouri was initially tried
openly, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> brought the process to a quick behind-the-scenes
conclusion after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kouri</ENAMEX> used the trial as a forum to vent his grievances with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>. Barring some unlikely <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last minute</TIMEX> intervention
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ayatollah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kouri</ENAMEX>'s conviction should serve to further increase tensions
between hard-liners and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>, making <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>'s parliamentary elections
all the more volatile.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also examines the link between childhood sexual abuse and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on welfare. According to rough estimates, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 35 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on
welfare roles claim they were sexually abused as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, compared with around
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The problem is cyclical--poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
live in dangerous neighborhoods and in single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother families</ENAMEX>, which expose
them to greater risk of abuse. Sexual abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are then more likely to
become teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abusers</ENAMEX>, increasing the chance that they'll
have to go on welfare, and making it harder to get off the rolls once they
do.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story reports that even while <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and monuments
increase public awareness of the event, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> themselves are being
forgotten. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pride</ENAMEX>, the pain of their memories, and red tape are making it
difficult for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> graying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> to obtain the
money and services to which they're entitled. For example, to obtain a share of
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.25 billion</NUMEX> in assets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> may pay to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>,
they must fill out forms asking them to: "Please describe, in as much detail as
you can, where the Subject was from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934 to 1945</TIMEX>."

            The WP fronts a profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>'s general councilor, who is largely
responsible for policing the site. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX>, he's intervened to
prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from selling human organs, tombstones, and even their virginity
on the site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eBay</ENAMEX> maintains that fraud is still very rare, with only "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX>"
of auctions being halted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>. The chief problem from an enforcement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> is that you can't just lock up the perps and throw away the
key--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> can simply come back with a new username when their accounts are
suspended. One repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX> has done so <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 157</NUMEX> times.

         
      
   
