
   
   
      
         
            Triumph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middlebrow</ENAMEX>?
            

            This book comes with a triumphant blaring of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>' trumpets, and one
supposes that it is a signal sort of triumph for black studies or Africana
studies (take your pick of names). The field has arrived to such an extent that
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> thinks that it can make money, significant money, publishing such a
work. Assignments in black studies have filtered down to the high-school,
junior-high, and even elementary<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-school</ENAMEX> level (and remember the black
liturgical occasions we now have on the calendar that beg for special
schoolchild reports of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sort</ENAMEX> or another: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black History</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Music Month, Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm X</ENAMEX>'s birthday, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juneteenth</ENAMEX>), and while
not every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> does all of this, most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> must do some of this. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>
this, of course, has nothing to do with the occasional racial killing or major
protest that took place or may be taking place somewhere that require a report
and discussion in a current-events or social-studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>.) Moreover, blacks
cannot be left out of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Women's History Month or Veteran's Day or</ENAMEX>, for the truly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">daring</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay Appreciation Month</ENAMEX>. So, a book like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africana</ENAMEX> is bound to get
a great deal of use, to be sold to virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, and
university <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, as well as to a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, to say
nothing of the private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that will have a copy right next to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britannica</ENAMEX> . (In some more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afrocentric</ENAMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, it may replace the
Britannica entirely, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eurocentric</ENAMEX> collection of lies, although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britannica</ENAMEX> has become as multicultural as everyone else <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.)
Those of us who have labored in the field of black studies (politically
incorrectly such as the present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> or very much politically correctly like
a good many very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>) are heartened by this commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>.
Indeed, it would be disheartening, as well as entirely untrue, if one were to
think that this book was published as an act of philanthropy, as something that
ought to be done. (It is so tiresome as a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to be the recipient of
charity all the time, to be the object of the moral imperative.)

            It is good to know that, partly through the energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, black studies can, as it were, pay its way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and not be
dependent for its existence on a kind of political and cultural moralism on the
part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and a kind of fetishlike piety on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. It can be,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alas</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of an entirely good sort or needful sort, justifying itself in
the marketplace. But I would think that most black-studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> are only
partly heartened by this; for this rather triumphalist book (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is
important in black studies, in part, for the promotion of a triumphalist view
of black history and black culture--globally speaking--which is why he is hated
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Afrocentrists</ENAMEX> who take a somewhat different view of the long-term meaning of
"the coming of the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>") is nothing less than the middlebrow arrival of
black studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture. Encyclopedias, after all, are middlebrow,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bourgeois</ENAMEX> books that tend, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, not to promote intellectual inquiry on
the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who use them but rather to stifle it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> tend to
copy verbatim from such books without ever reading what they are copying.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adults</ENAMEX>, with far too much deference for the printed word, tend to consult such
a book in much the way they consult the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary or the Bible</ENAMEX> (or in the way
baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fanatics</ENAMEX> consult the official record books): as the final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arbiter</ENAMEX>, as
that which settles all arguments. Why, for goodness' sake, would anyone
actually read a book like this? Knowledge, in the instance of the definitive
reference book, becomes entombed and sanctified, very much serving the
anti-intellectual ends of the middlebrow, who want not to encounter knowledge
and to wrestle with it but to store it as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> on the bookshelf.

            But I suppose it is something of a triumph, which the publication of this
book is meant to acknowledge, that black studies has achieved middlebrow status
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, that bourgeois <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, both white and black, feel bad if
they don't know something about the history and culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX>-descended
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, in much the same way they feel bad, inadequate, if they don't know
something about opera or a bit about Impressionist painting or if they have
never seen a film by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. W. Griffith</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fritz Lang</ENAMEX>. How terrible at a party to
discover that one has never seen The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Illusion</ENAMEX> --one of the all-time
great films--or that one has not read, alas, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX> novel or one does
not own a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wynton Marsalis album</ENAMEX>. (The truly knowing coves own albums by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelonious Monk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coltrane</ENAMEX>, no less, and do reports for their book clubs
on the blues.) What most thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in black studies find dangerous about
the middlebrow apotheosis of the field is that it usually leads to the
enshrinement of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Barzun</ENAMEX> calls thought-clichés, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-truths or
non-truths that are accepted as the truth because someone said so in some
reference book like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africana</ENAMEX> . Thought-clichés are like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX>; people
love them because they relieve them of the very thing they do not wish to do in
any case, that is, think, think hard, and think critically and against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grain</ENAMEX> of their own beliefs or psychological needs or neurotic fantasy
projections. Thought-clichés confirm one's stupidity and one's laziness. With
all the goodwill in the world, a book like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africana</ENAMEX> cannot help but
produce thought-clichés; it is, indeed, why most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will consult such a
work, to find them and be comforted by them. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> can,
therefore, be fully at ease with a work of this sort, no matter his or her
ideological stripe. Such a book as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africana</ENAMEX> simply washes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> in the field in a sea of ambivalence, with a sense of lost faith,
as we all stand before it a bit as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Arnold</ENAMEX> stood before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dover Beach</ENAMEX>.

            Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appiah</ENAMEX> published a multicultural dictionary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nellie McKay</ENAMEX> published the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton Anthology of African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Literature</ENAMEX> shortly before that. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appiah</ENAMEX>, rather sentimentally and opportunistically, see themselves as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX>, whose unfilled dream was to produce such a book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
seems to have cornered the market on black reference books that shape the canon
of black studies, that define the field and its major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. Building a canon
is very important to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, and it is, without question, an important
pedagogical pursuit. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> must have order and it must have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>. It is also a power pursuit. He who defines the field controls it, in a
manner of speaking. Some are jealous that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> wants this sort of power.
Others find it unseemly. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is wasting his considerable talents in
the pursuit of it, but that is another issue for another type of review. It is
amazing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> has done this volume so successfully and so quickly, that he
has flooded the market with first-rate black reference books in such short
order. It took him and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Appiah</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only four years</TIMEX> to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Africana</ENAMEX> . Even
with modern technology, that is an astonishing feat, so astonishing that some
will dismiss the book (I have heard some comments of this sort even before the
book was published) as some half-baked enterprise. That would be a mistake, for
this is an incredibly polished work. This is a beautiful book, one of the most
striking reference works I have ever seen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appiah</ENAMEX> must be quite the
field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshals</ENAMEX> to have hustled together this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and to have
gotten the work from them on time or nearly so. They deserve much credit for
this. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> would have felt lucky to have finished this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX>--who exists in the field of black studies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> as rather
the black equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> (wordsmith), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerson</ENAMEX>
(humanist), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kant</ENAMEX> (moral philosopher), separately and together, as it
were--is evoked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> in their introduction provides this volume with
a pedigree that I suppose they thought it needed, making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and Appiah our
intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX> who have given us the Holy Grail. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quest</ENAMEX> for producing a black encyclopedia "a Holy Grail." More triumphalist
history!) The introduction offers a good and useful account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX>' attempt
to produce an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africana</ENAMEX> encyclopedia, the professional jealousy he
encountered, the racism that sometimes thwarted his efforts. It should be read
by all who purchase the book.

            But the history of the publication of this book is only incompletely told by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, when black studies was established on the white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> campus, a number of reference books about the black experience were
published and continue to be published. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> make no attempt to place
their book within that particular context, a more accurate historical context
for understanding the appearance of this book, as it was made possible not by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX>' dream in any respect but by the rise of multiculturalism and black
studies as intellectual industries in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. The
increasing professionalization of black studies made this book possible, more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> in the field, both black and white, being produced since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, more
scholarship being produced. This book was also made possible by the rise of
professionalism among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> and the rise of a black
middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that has demanded more artifacts and objects, more "education"
about its experience (more institutionalization of it, in other words, and more
orthodoxy about its significance), that are all meant to reinforce its sense of
identity, its psychological well-being, its sense of race mission, all
important reasons for the existence of black studies, but all clearly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-intellectual</ENAMEX>. In other words, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> that brought this book into
existence had little enough to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX>--although evoking him is of
critical importance to the book's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> as a kind of typology about the
struggle of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to gain self-knowledge, a story that black people
never tire of reciting, even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with a plethora of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bookshops</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX> grinding out books on black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> or with a black point of view
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">ever-increasing</ENAMEX> regularity--and a great deal to do with the shift that has
taken place within the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and the dramatic change in its status. This book is the product of both a
strong movement toward the intellectualization of black experience among an
elite and the anti-intellectualization of black experience by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at
large (earnest and respectful of black experience as it has now generally
become) and those who cater to the public's access to intellectual material by
rounding off the rough edges and making it thoroughly anti-intellectual by
designing and evoking certain emotional markers about "struggle" and
"resistance."

            I shall begin my next entry with a discussion of a set of entries in
Africana , those dealing with aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>, and a
response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Nicholson</ENAMEX>'s impressions of the book.

         
      
   
