
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picture-Perfect Fed</ENAMEX>
            

            So now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> has taken all the rate cuts back. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX> and fall, when
it sometimes felt as if the global economy were on the verge of a massive
nervous breakdown, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> cut interest rates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three consecutive</TIMEX>
times--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one between</NUMEX>-meetings rate cut--to ensure that suddenly panicky
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> didn't strangle access to credit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy, perhaps as a
result, didn't even hiccup, while the stock market, which had plummeted in the
wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> turmoil, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> devaluation, and the collapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Management</ENAMEX>, came roaring back. But after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>-basis-point rate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hike</ENAMEX>, the federal funds rate now stands at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.50 percent</NUMEX>, exactly where it was
before the chaos of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>.

            To me, this looks like nearly picture-perfect central banking, especially
since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy continues to grow at a fast pace, unemployment continues
to shrink, and inflation at the consumer level remains in check. There are
voices of dissent who think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> is paying too much attention to
Wall Street and that the continued rise in stock prices is entirely the product
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s distribution of easy money. But that case has been weakened not
only by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s own rate hikes but also by the powerful rally in the bond
market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty-year</TIMEX> interest rates are back down near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
percent, after trading close to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.5 percent</NUMEX>, and they would not be there if
bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>--for whom vigilance about inflation is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> law--thought the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> was letting us all live high on the hog by printing lots of greenbacks.

            In any case, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed-watching</ENAMEX> has become so ubiquitous that it's harder to say
something new about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> than about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>. But there are two
important things to keep in mind about this most recent hike. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that
even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s performance over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> looks perfect, we
don't actually know if it was. By this I mean something more than just the
obvious point, which is that history has no control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. I also mean that the
most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> of non-inflationary growth--business
productivity--remains something of a mystery to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>.

            Productivity growth remains very strong, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.1 percent</NUMEX> in the most recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>, though the rate of that growth has slowed slightly (very slightly).
And it seems increasingly clear that the effects on productivity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">computerization</ENAMEX> and the Internet are real and not temporary blips. But why
those effects are being felt now, how long they will last, how much of
productivity growth is being driven by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> running leaner than they once
did: These questions don't have firm answers. Nor, for that matter, do we
really understand why productivity growth slowed so rapidly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. So
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> deserves credit for its performance, most of what's going on in
this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Goldilocks</ENAMEX> economy is out of its control.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thing worth noticing is that the popular understanding of the
role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> seems to have shifted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year and a half</TIMEX>, arguably as
a result of its quick action <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The conventional wisdom was that it
took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> to a year for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> rate hike to work its way into the economy,
which makes sense since raising or lowering interest rates generally isn't like
slamming a door open or shut. It's more like easing it open or closed. But what
we've seen more recently is the idea that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s key roles is
psychological. It wasn't the literal opening of the taps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> that
mattered but rather the symbolic message the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX>, which was that
it was OK to take on a little risk at a time when the only thing anyone wanted
to do was buy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bonds. Similarly, no one really believes that
raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> funds rate from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.25 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.50 percent</NUMEX> is going to put
the brakes on economic growth (although the gradual rise from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.75 percent</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.50 percent</NUMEX> has to have had some effect). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do believe that it will
send the right message to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX>. To be sure, ultimately the
message carries weight because it's backed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s actions. But in
concrete terms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s actions probably won't have an effect for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to a year. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s message, though, is already at work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
