
   
   
      
         
            Why <i>Who <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wants To Be a Millionaire</ENAMEX></i> Is a Hit
            

            The most important thing that's changed about the major TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX>, aside from their steadily shrinking share of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, is
that more and more of their programming is "reality-based." On the one hand,
you have the continued proliferation of the too-scary-to-be-fictional genre,
which was pioneered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> and exemplified by When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animals</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Attack</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scariest Car Chases</ENAMEX> . At the same time, more and more of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>' schedules are occupied by news shows--which generally have at least a
loose connection to reality--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dateline</ENAMEX> . And although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funniest Home Videos</ENAMEX> is no longer provoking belly laughs across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">variants</ENAMEX> thereof air regularly as specials.

            The great virtue of reality-based programming is that it's relatively
inexpensive to produce, since very little of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> needs to be paid for.
And for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are supposedly obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> seem
remarkably interested in what other "real" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing--as long as what
they're doing involves either being chased down with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> vials of crack,
fighting a long illness, driving the wrong way on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX>, or getting upended
off a ladder by an overly friendly springer spaniel. (Wasn't that a great
segment?)

            Perhaps as a result of its success, though, "reality-based programming" is
now being used as a label to cover shows that are, well, not real, like the
huge hit game show <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Wants To Be a Millionaire</ENAMEX> and its recent
successful competitor <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greed</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millionaire</ENAMEX> has picked up where it
left off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>, dominating its time slot and actually casting a slight
halo effect on its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> peers, while <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greed</ENAMEX> has been one of the only--OK,
the only--bright spot in a disappointing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> season. It's their success
that prompted a recent headline in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> proclaiming "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nets Reap</ENAMEX>
Ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Reality Shows</ENAMEX>."

            What's odd about this is that game shows--even if they're not fixed like
they were in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>--are real only in a very tenuous sense. Thoroughly staged
and stage-managed, they're dramatic, or perhaps melodramatic, precisely because
of the artificial structure of their formats. We don't, it's true, know how any
given episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millionaire</ENAMEX> is going to turn out, and even though one
might say the same about a forthcoming episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> , the fact that in
theory no one knows how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Millionaire</ENAMEX> episode is going to turn
out may make it more real.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millionaire and Greed are to Cops and When</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> Attack as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> is to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Serengeti Plain</ENAMEX>, offering a kind of
semblance of uncertainty (and, therefore, reality) instead of the actual thing,
whatever that might be. In part, the actual thing is just the possibility that
something genuinely unexpected is going to happen--who knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> could
beat down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> with their front hooves?--but in part, especially with a show
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cops</ENAMEX> , it's the possibility that nothing especially important is
going to happen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millionaire</ENAMEX> , by contrast, is circumscribed in both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directions</ENAMEX>. You know it'll be exciting but not too surprising, and you know it
won't be too surprising but also not dull.

            Game shows do have many of the same advantages as true reality-based
programming--relatively low production cost, endless supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>--and
some others in addition, including the ability to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Woolery</ENAMEX> off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dole</ENAMEX>. And the fact that TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> would rather spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">prime time</TIMEX> watching a
not-so-great-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> answer questions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Lakes</ENAMEX> than watching
gorgeous twentysomethings pretend to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> has to count for something.
But only in a world as totally hermetic as that of TV production would game
shows count as real . Next we'll probably hear that Felicity
counts as real, too, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying their lines on the show are actual
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX> who are actually saying the words.

            Sounds good to me.

         
      
   
