
   
   
      
         
            See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Run</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> race. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential
campaign.

            Interviews: On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> compliments current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, for being a better dealmaker than he was.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> says he prefers his current life on the lecture circuit to being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> because lecturing better suits his idealistic temperament and doesn't
require day-to-day detail work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> should stick to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
campaign themes in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the rescue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> through
Personal Savings Accounts (a type of privatization); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the establishment of a
"global missile defense"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the limitation of taxes in peacetime to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX>
of income; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) the abolition of the inheritance tax; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) the securing of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' rights through health-care reform. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> says he would personally spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> if
he ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (in addition to spending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $12</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in federal funds).

            Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s pointed announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that she "intends
to run" for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> )
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> )--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy</ENAMEX>
Molinari, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> (both on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> )--think she has left some
wiggle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and may yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the 11th hour</TIMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> supporters
point to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX>' remark in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Sheehy</ENAMEX> book that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
run will be about personal "redemption" (to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillary's Choice</ENAMEX> ,
click here). Asked about this on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , Ickes
doesn't own up to the statement, but he doesn't deny it either. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) notes that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have negative ratings topping <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 8 percent to 9 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are undecided, an unusually low number with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year</TIMEX> until
Election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) says that a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> TV ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">questioning Hillary</ENAMEX>'s devotion to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is smart, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are one of
the few swing votes left.

            Several programs cite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time /CNN</ENAMEX> poll showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> in a statistical dead
heat in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent to 35 percent</NUMEX>, respectively, with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX>
percent margin of error. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press ], <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ], and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ]
assert that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is ahead in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granite State</ENAMEX>; only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> [ This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ] points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-point lead is statistically
meaningless.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) notes that even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
wins <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> still leads by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 40</NUMEX> points in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> points out that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mondale</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>'s polls suddenly rose by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> points nationally (left unspoken: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart</ENAMEX>
lost the nomination anyway). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) argues that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> showing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> poll (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX>), despite his
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of dollars, should give pause to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of campaign-finance reform.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> could still hurt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, which would add to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s momentum should he win <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
numbers will improve once he spends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some time</TIMEX> there, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Rees</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ) thinks that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> numbers have peaked.

            
               And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Thought Buchanan and Fulani Made an Odd Couple</ENAMEX>
...
            

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> ticks off
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his ideal presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rangel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>
State: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ret</ENAMEX>.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Welch</ENAMEX>, outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>

            
               Last Word
            

            

               I think that it would be a very, very bad thing to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He's almost <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> in his leanings.

               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>] stays in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump Tower</ENAMEX> when she's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. ... At least she has
great taste.

               I do shake hands, [but] I think it's a terrible custom. ... It's almost
barbaric in a certain way.

               I don't take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--I've never had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in my life--I've never had a glass
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, I've never had a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, I've never had a cigarette. I do
love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. But I'm single, [so] I'm allowed to do that, I guess. But I respect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, I admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and if that's supposed to be bad, then I'm guilty.

                     --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> )

            

         
      
   
