
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Is</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like, Cool</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>:

            I think you're right that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> (and I'm using
"ideologue" here as a euphemism for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of principle," rather than
"wild-eyed nut cases") are going to wake up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> early into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
presidency with a terrible hangover. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is considerably less conservative
than many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> believe, not that he's ever made any secret of it. He's
run so far as an out-of-the-closet moderate, someone who genuinely cares about
bipartisan compromise, or the appearance of it anyway. He brags about his
friendships with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. He hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McKinnon</ENAMEX>, who's not only an excellent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> but also an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandy Grunwald</ENAMEX> (not
to mention a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">songwriter</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kris Kristofferson</ENAMEX> and by far the coolest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>).

            The message of all this is unmistakable: I'm no winger. It's been a terribly
effective strategy so far--and it leaves no messy pandering to clean up during
the general--but I think it has consequences for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, as you
point out, is in some ways a Reagan-like figure. But here's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> difference:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> came to office in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> with a large outstanding debt to the right,
particularly evangelicals. He rewarded them by giving them jobs and access, and
in many cases real power. It was the ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who worked for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, to name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> who are still very much
around--who pulled his domestic policy to the right and kept it there.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> in memory who owes no such debt to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> squandered their leverage over him
almost immediately. They threw their endorsements to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> at the very beginning
of the cycle, and without demanding anything in return. They shouldn't have
been surprised when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> repaid the favor by casting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Hastert</ENAMEX> as Sista
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soulja</ENAMEX>.

            But they were. And wounded, too. But by that point there was nothing they
could do. My guess is, they'll be every bit as shocked when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>
strikes up a warm personal friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephart</ENAMEX>, doubles the budget of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX>, and appoints several more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Souters</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> never learn.

            Though I must say they've been pretty good about the drug thing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has
all but admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> use (or admitted that it would be a bad idea to admit
it, which strikes me as roughly the same thing), and nobody apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> has thrown a fit. Good for everyone involved, I say. Admittedly, I hold
the minority view on the drug question--pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> but anti-legalization--but I'm
convinced a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> must feel the way I do: Who'd want a 53-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who'd never done a line? A dork, in other words. Not me.

            Then again, maybe a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't feel the way I do about it. I'm
taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s loudmouth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frat-boy</ENAMEX> shtick, for instance. Just about everyone
else I know thinks it's odd, even "troubling" to see a serious presidential
candidate run around punching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> and giving nicknames to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strangers</ENAMEX>. They use the phrase "towel-snapper" as an epithet, like there's
something hideous about being mildly boorish with your male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

            I don't get it. I don't have my finger on the pulse of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>. I'm
not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to figure out who buys <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Monthly</ENAMEX> and why. Sorry.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
