
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coming Year of Gush-Bore</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>:

            If I lean back in my chair ever so slightly and look out my window, I can
see the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Texas Capitol</ENAMEX> and, just to the southwest, the top of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>. It's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 a.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, do you think the light in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>'s study is
on? Part of me really wants to believe that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turd</ENAMEX> and the ghost
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bully</ENAMEX> are already up cramming for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s debate, but why should he
bother? Much as I fantasized about the temper-tantrum possibilities of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Bradley</ENAMEX> race <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few weeks ago</TIMEX>, it's getting to be something
approaching inevitable that we're in for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gush-Bore</ENAMEX>.

            There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time /CNN</ENAMEX> poll out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> a few points ahead
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. I worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> had peaked too early, and maybe I was I
right. If he doesn't win in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, I don't care what the laptop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> say: The race is over. The apparatus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-presidency</ENAMEX> is too
much to overcome, even this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-presidency</ENAMEX>. The main argument
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--the bathtub ring of scandal--is more effectively made in the
general election than the primary. Who wants to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>? By and large, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">independents</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. The same poll
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shows McCain</ENAMEX> actually leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, which didn't get the
wide play I thought it would. My suspicion is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, much like those of us in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, don't really believe it. Who are the
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> saying they'll go for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> part of the sample? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.W.</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> hurts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s chances,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">independents</ENAMEX> can go this way or that and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> needs them all, but I
think the reverse is true: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is a drain on the potential pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, who needs every single <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to orchestrate an upset. I'd be shocked
if he didn't fall short. By the way, how 'bout <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stockdale</ENAMEX> defending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s sanity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ? Next up: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>'s potty mouth.

            Speaking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Apple Polisher</ENAMEX>'s piece over
the weekend marveling at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s facile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frat-boy</ENAMEX> geniality? What surprised me
the most wasn't that I'd read this before in, oh, I don't know, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> and Talk . It's that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has been so hostile to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> up to this point. I can't explain the shift in thinking other than to
speculate that the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> is finally giving up and accepting his
inevitability the way the political establishment long ago did. (By the way,
did you hear that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.--Will</ENAMEX>--has made up with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>? Another sign.)
But I have a theory about what came before: More than just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, the
Times hates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. On the whole, the national press has a sneering
stereotypical view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, which you'd think was overrun with oil-slicked
bumpkins, tyrannical high-school football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>, mechanical-bull-riding
smoothies, and the odd computer geek, but no one sneers with more relish than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . Maybe it dates back to the trouble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ivins</ENAMEX> had as the
paper's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legend</ENAMEX> has it that she walked around the office
barefoot, brought her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shit</ENAMEX>, to work, and offended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Rosenthal</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensibilities</ENAMEX> (who doesn't <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>?) by referring to the goings-on at a
chicken-processing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> pluck." Whatever the reason, you don't see
that great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Herbert</ENAMEX> holing up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> to
write column after column about the barbarism of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. He's our
burden. My burden. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ugh</ENAMEX>.
I'm out of space--and I haven't even said a word about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>, whose candidacy
is deader than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hsing-Hsing</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> manages to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> look good.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Evan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
