
   
   
      
         
            My Visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>

            I've just walked into the 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an</TIMEX> hour-long free-form discussion with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. I
loved the discussion. There was obviously tension in the air, because my
visit--though long-scheduled--came on the heels of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Findings of Fact</ENAMEX>" by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> presiding over the anti-trust case brought against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>.

            Even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> makes its own
independent decisions in such matters without input from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Klein</ENAMEX>--are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.
For that reason, I couldn't comment on the decision that was clearly on many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s minds on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> campus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I did make clear that there is a
fundamental <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> value in making sure that neither heavy-handed government
nor unfair business practices stamp out competition.

            But then the meeting moved on to other topics, and I
wasn't surprised to find that, as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are interested
in technology and the Internet, they are also interested in the same issues as
all hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--how they can give their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>; how we can make our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> safer; and how we can reach
across our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> to bring this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> together.

            And even though national security policy didn't come up,
I suggested that one crucial issue for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to ponder is this: whose finger
do you want on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALT-CONTROL-DELETE</ENAMEX> button? 

            The
issue of payment of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> dues came up (in the context of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s
feeling that no inappropriate compromise on the issue of choice should be
accepted), but no other foreign policy issues arose. So I obviously spent too
much time in advance preparing for a pop quiz about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s of software companies
from hot spots around the world.

            But in
truth, the questions were wide-ranging. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> asked me my position on hate
crimes legislation. And to me, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX> was crucified on
a split rail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX> because of his sexual orientation; when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Byrd</ENAMEX> was
dragged to his death because of his skin color; and both a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Filipino</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate student</ENAMEX> were murdered because of the shape of their
eyes--I cannot comprehend how some can argue that hate crimes are no different
from all other crimes. That is why we need tougher laws to prevent and punish
them. 

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> asked me how we can make our schools
safer in the aftermath of tragedies such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>. I said that I believe
the solutions range from tough measures to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, to more discipline and values in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, to more self-restraint
in the use of gratuitous violence in the entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, to more parental
involvement in the lives of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--which of course means we need to give
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> more help in balancing work and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.  

            I was certainly impressed by the discussion, and the
quality and range of the questions. I could see right away that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to a great deal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and creative drive. That may be why, according
to certain projections, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> may be worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a trillion dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some day</TIMEX>. Of
course, I feel it's important to point out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
had not dropped out of college, he'd have a chance at being worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion dollars</NUMEX>.

            After the discussion, I got a chance to visit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home of the Future</ENAMEX>--where I got a chance to see technology that was
definitely impressive. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> were features of Windows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>:
magnification for the vision-impaired, and a voice that reads the screen to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blind</ENAMEX>.

            Finally, I stopped over here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of

                  Slate
               , where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karenna</ENAMEX> worked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'96 and '97</TIMEX>. Actually,
while I started this piece at 
                  Slate
               , I am finishing it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
and e-mailing it. (And all this time, I thought you actually had to be
physically present at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> in order to write for it.) It was terrific to
meet some of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>--and also to try my hand at
journalism for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a quarter of a century</TIMEX>.

            Instead of my trusty old typewriter from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my days</TIMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nashville Tennessean</ENAMEX> , I did get to write this article on a state-of
the-art, ergonometric keyboard. And, true to my old profession, as I write this
I'm crashing to meet the deadline I was assigned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>.


            All told, it was a wonderful visit. The entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
campus is just bubbling with energy and ideas. I certainly hope to spend even
more time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> area. And who knows? If I work at it, I might even be
able to pick up some endorsements from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonics</ENAMEX>. ...

         
      
   
