
   
   
      
         
            Living <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With It, Warts and All</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>:

            It is more than a little distressing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James McPherson</ENAMEX> is not included in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> . I admire him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and like him greatly as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. He
is, I think, a very significant post-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, someone who I think took up
the mantle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX>. Plus, he has won a major literary prize, something that
means a lot to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who put together this book. Why would McPherson not
be included here? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gracious</ENAMEX>, that's as bad as not having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Flood</ENAMEX>.

            The omissions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africana</ENAMEX> , some of which I pointed in my previous
message, are glaring and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for serious thought. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> is making a
statement about what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and the advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> feel is important.
Those who have been consigned to the dustbin of irrelevancy, where the evidence
clearly does not support such a judgement, only deepen one's uneasy about the
purpose of this book.

            The role of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> is difficult to discern. Clearly, I do
not think the role of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> is to churn out books of this
sort. First, I have never had the occasion of seeing a reference book marketed
on the strength of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. I have no idea who edited the
reference books I used. I couldn't tell you who edited my dictionaries or my
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> books. I think this is true with most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It is not especially
important to know this. Already, the idea of the black reference book with
glamorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> is something of a real problem and should make the public a
bit suspicious because it seems so much like a marketing ploy. It is, perhaps,
this sense of opportunism, and of blowing up ordinary jobs like creating a
black reference book of this sort as if one were announcing the return of the
monarchy to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, that makes you feel uneasy about many of the black public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>. They are talented, but are they principled? They are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">well-trained</ENAMEX>, but are they courageous? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell West</ENAMEX>, the conscience of the
current generation of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>--or at least, so he is advertised--is
portrayed as courageous, but how much courage does it take to pocket fat fees
for giving lectures spiked with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> socialist bromides to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> who
adore you?)

            To whom much is given, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> said, much is expected. And much has been
given to this generation of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, far more than any earlier
generation ever dreamed of having. And is the product that has been generated
the best that can be done with all that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> has at its disposal?
This is a fair question. I feel deeply inadequate myself when I think about it
and feel that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Brawley or J. Saunders Reddings</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sterling Brown</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alain Locke</ENAMEX> or any of the earlier black literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> had been in my
position, they would have produced so much more and so much better. (I must
admit that I did not aspire to be any of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> when I was in graduate
school and I do aspire to be them now. In graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, I aspired to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Wilson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patriotic Gore</ENAMEX> is still the best title for an
intellectual book that I have come across), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Barzun</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Wyck</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>. I still aspire to be them, and their work has most influenced me. But
can a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> ever get to talk about something like that when white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">literary</ENAMEX> and intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> would rather have him or her write
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm X</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> or some such stuff as that?
Most black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, if they are truly reflective, with a few exceptions
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Levering Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Murray</ENAMEX> and some others I deeply deeply
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">admire</ENAMEX>, cannot help but think they might be a bit fraudulent.

            So, if a book like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africana</ENAMEX> is an indication of the fraudulence of
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, or a suggestion of its possibility, then we must ask the
question, How has this come to pass? What set of conditions exist that keep
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> from being incisive and as honest and as courageous and as
productive as they should be? Some of the compromises from the realm of
political correctness I have already discussed. Some of the compromises spring
from the need of racial solidarity, either as opportunism or misplaced loyalty.
I do not speak and never have spoken for black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and do not want to. Some
of the compromises are the normal sorts of difficulties that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>
face--from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-edited writing meant to make easy any difficult idea to the
need for excessive conflict in order to make the work "interesting." Some are
the result of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> who box <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> into a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX> as public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>.

            You raise a good question about who is reviewing this book. (I have been
asked to review every book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> has written. I feel as if I am his personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reviewer</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> go into black studies for a number of complex reasons, some
good, some not so good; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> respond with opportunities and enticements
that are bound to keep them there. The niche becomes a trap. The various white
intellectual establishments, moreover, tend to buy the kind of black that best
suits them ideologically, which means they buy the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> they themselves think they would be if they were black. And most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, they never buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>, and so black opinion-making tends to become
reduced, funneled, constrained, and strained, either in its liberal or its
conservative manifestations, in ways that are not especially useful either to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> or black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> but are very useful to the white intellectual
establishments as they distribute their spoils. I don't say this to suggest
anything sinister or racist about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. (Although racism and conspiracy
cannot entirely be discounted, either.) The pressures of commercialism and
prestige combine to make this rather unpleasant situation, both of
which--commercialism and prestige--are condemned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> as they lust
for what they can offer. And black opinon-making, I think, becomes, as a
result, highly distorted, and black intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> do not help as
they are even more restrictive about the kind of commentary and judgments they
will tolerate. They are usually even more anti-intellectual in their insistence
that the black experience must have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX> and that all intellectual
matters must be subordinate to social do-goodism and political protest--the
more shrill and demagogic, the more heroic.

            All of this, I think, explains why black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public intellectuals</ENAMEX> are the way
they are and why so few have said much that really matters in intellectual
circles. Moreover, even more so than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> tend to give
in to the worst sorts of anti-intellectual impulses because of social
do-goodism and political protest. Even the most sober-minded black thinkers
indulge in a bit of racial hectoring and demagogic posturing to remind the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> whose side they are on.

            I know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and West get your dander up. I like them and admire them
to some degree, although I do not think they have worked up to their capacity.
I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> particularly is a very smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, if he were to
give himself the time to write the way he can. I like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appiah</ENAMEX>, too, and think
him very smart. What is curious about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africana</ENAMEX> is that they both--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appiah</ENAMEX>--are doing a book that I think, in its current manifestation, is
beneath them. Another type of encyclopedia, one that might have taken <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 or 15</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to do but would have been far more intensive, and far more usefully
selective, might have been much more worth the effort. For you, I know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
is a hustler and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>, worse still, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sanctimonious hustler</ENAMEX>, which means,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dangerously</ENAMEX>, he actually takes what he says seriously and takes himself very
seriously, to boot. But I think the real problem is over-exposure and too
little to say. I think your impatience stems from that. There is far too much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> and there is far too little in what they are saying to justify
their demand for your attention or for the culture's attention. This is a fair
enough criticism, if I read you rightly, and one I would agree with. I think
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> need to stop churning out work and think about a kind of settled
obscurity in working long and hard on some project that would absorb them
completely and passionately, and simply quit producing for public consumption a
series of well-financed distractions.

            But even when I find myself frustrated by their work, I find that I would
rather have them doing what they do than doing nothing at all, and if it is
not, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, greatly advancing black intellectualism or not advancing it as
much as they think it is, it is probably not doing the cause of black
intellectualism any harm, either, or any more harm than I or any of the rest
are doing in our bumbling way. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s essay on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> in Africana
seemed a re-working of his essay on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Future of the Race</ENAMEX> .
There is nothing new said in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> essay, and his presentism, his
insistence on judging a historical figure by current moral standards, I find
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fatuous</ENAMEX>, just poor scholarship. I agree with you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> should have done
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> essay and not West. (Any one of a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> could have done
a good job with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlem Renaissance</ENAMEX>.) I would have preferred having West
discuss something more on the order of the impact of pragmatism on black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> or an essay on the whole black philosophy movement.

            Don't throw the book at your television. Televisions are expensive these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monday Night Football</ENAMEX> is one of the reasons to have a
television. (The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">baseball season</TIMEX> is another and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMC</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.) If you really
can't stand the book, probably someone on your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> list would appreciate
it as a gift. It is a great-looking book despite its shortcomings, and there is
a lot of good information in it. My bottom line is that I would recommend the
book to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and I hope it does well, despite its
anti-intellectual p.c.-isms and its contempt for opinions it does not favor.
Probably this book could be done better, but no one is going to get an
opportunity to do that, so you might as well live with what you've got, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">warts</ENAMEX>
and all. Besides, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 or 20 years from now</TIMEX>, when it needs to be done again, it
might very well be better. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appiah</ENAMEX> would have to be thanked for
opening the door. Maybe black stuff is still so suspect that we need
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> to get reference books. I hope things aren't that bad!

            I agree with you about book-reviewing. It is not a glamorous job at all, but
someone has to do it. Besides, when I was boy, I dreamed, as all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> do, of
running off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the things that stopped me was that I was
afraid I would wind up shoveling dung. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task</ENAMEX> has caught up with me anyway
and at last. Be Well.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Early</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
