
   
   
      
         
            <i>The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sopranos</ENAMEX></i>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s Only High Note
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>:

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> thing sounds reprehensible--I agree. If, I don't know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX> sent around a mass e-mail with dirty jokes about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
executioners, do you think he'd get fired?

            I want to move away from all this witty banter about politics and media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethics</ENAMEX> and move on to something more serious: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>. I noticed in several papers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> plans to rerun all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> starting
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a holiday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Marchand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, Livia
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soprano</ENAMEX>, would no doubt say is a racket for the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>). I don't know about
you, but I love television. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have sports; other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
politics. I have digital cable: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> channels of bliss. Watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sopranos</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX> was like gazing at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothko</ENAMEX> or eating at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chez Panisse</ENAMEX>.
It was art, pure and simple, and it was immensely nourishing--and if you don't
believe me, ask the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half-dozen or so</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> I play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>. They're
not your average beer-bellied slackers (well, only one is), and they're not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alpha</ENAMEX>-wave-overdosed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX>. They're sophisticates, and to a one they savored
every episode, every frame, every line. It's all we talked about then, and
again all we talked about when the series was rerun for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. What makes it so good? All the usual things: wonderful writing, great
casting (the co-casting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Walken</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>), and a very
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contemporary</ENAMEX> story line that has already been copied to ill effect by other
movies and TV shows. What The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ally</ENAMEX>
McBeal was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>: A masterpiece
fraudulently imitated by lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--the sort who wouldn't be let into the Bada
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bing Club</ENAMEX>. (Don't ask.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason I think <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> is so far superior to everything else
on the tube is that everything else on the tube is dreadful. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wing</ENAMEX> , a shabby small-screen version of every big-screen movie about the
inner workings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (which are themselves shabby versions of the real
thing, which is itself a shabby version of what the real thing should be), is a
hit; it ought to be canceled, if only to send a message to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capped Martin Sheen</ENAMEX>'s teeth. Only a little while ago, it seems, everyone was
marveling at how TV had eclipsed the movies in terms of quality, which led to
an exodus of film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> for the friendlier confines of the blue glow. This
season, I think, the tide has turned back. It's been a banner year for the
movies, at least in my opinion. I really liked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Beauty , Three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kings</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sixth Sense</ENAMEX> , The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project , and Being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> , to name but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the very solid flicks that lived up to
and even exceeded my expectations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX>. Whereas, except for
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Practice</ENAMEX>, there are no TV shows worth
watching regularly anymore. This is probably the reason for the rise of the
magazine shows on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VH-1</ENAMEX>, E!, and the like. Not that I need to rationalize the
existence of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behind the Music</ENAMEX> . The minute I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leif Garrett</ENAMEX> in his
bandanna hopefully talking about a comeback in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, I was hooked. He had me at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>, you have little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, right? I have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-old</TIMEX>, and she is much
more optimistic about the future of television than I am. Not a day goes by
when she doesn't ask to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> or the new hip <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoom</ENAMEX> , whose
cast is as diverse ethnically and, for all I know, in its sexual orientation as
the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>. Lately, though, our favorite--hers and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>--is the
animated series based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> books. The main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hippos, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, and I've always suspected that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
is gay--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> homosexual lead, as it were, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s entertainment.
(I'm not counting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bednobs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broomsticks</ENAMEX> . The Brits
are simply effete.) And, wouldn't you know, I'm right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Lane</ENAMEX> does the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice of George</ENAMEX> with such flamboyance and relish that it puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> on
Will and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace</ENAMEX> to shame.

            What's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace</ENAMEX> ? Uhh, maybe we should go back to talking about
politics.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Evan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
