
   
   
      
         
            Trending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buck</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX>'s upward
revision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-quarter</TIMEX> growth, to an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annualized</TIMEX> rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.5 percent</NUMEX>, signifying even more prosperity than had been
predicted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> puts that story on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> of its business
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> and goes instead with the announcement of a sweeping free-trade
agreement between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> that would (if given final
approval by the participating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>) eliminate most trade barriers
between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>, a development that, the paper observes, should help
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> expand its already booming exports and reduce its economic dependence on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that the latest numbers mean
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy is flirting with record-setting prosperity, but the
Times is clearer on this: it's now becoming likely that with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>,
the economy will see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">107</NUMEX> consecutive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of growth, which would break the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mark</ENAMEX> set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1961 and 1969</TIMEX>.

            Both papers appeal to the now-familiar productivity revolution to explain
various aspects of the boom. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that spectacular
productivity growth has more than offset <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' increases in labor costs
(brought about by a more competitive pay-and-benefits environment), thus
insulating prices from lockstep increases. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that
productivity gains have meant better compensation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> than they
anticipated, leaving them feeling more satisfied, which in turn encourages them
to buy more consumer goods. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> financial crises get some credit for braking inflation because of all
the overseas money they drove into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> financial markets, helping to
keep interest rates low. (For a 
                  Slate
                take on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>
should do about all this, click here.)

            The LAT fronts a story that only deepens the sense of national
well-being: about the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX>'s increasing participation in the
bull market. The technology-intensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq exchange</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, which
has had its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> biggest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">trading days</TIMEX> ever in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, is seeing an increasing
percentage of small block trades. And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third quarter</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brokerages</ENAMEX> added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> new accounts.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front weighs in with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of its series airing
charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Smile</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> that sends plastic surgeons to poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to do pro bono facial operations on deformed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, is guilty of
shoddy medical practices due to an emphasis on volume and publicity. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
installment focuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s activities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, which have resulted in
"complications," "faulty operations," and "some angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>." Although cleft
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lip</ENAMEX> and palate surgeries are considered low-risk, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Operation Smile</ENAMEX> has had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> deaths doing them since it started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of
them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch reporting that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> transportation
official suggested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> Flight 990 wasn't brought down by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suicidal co-pilot</ENAMEX> but by an explosion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s tail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
passes this theory along but spends most of its EgyptAir ink reporting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> crash <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have been drawn to the role of the relief pilot
not just for the reference he made to God shortly before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> went down,
but also because of the abrupt way he took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX>'s seat just minutes
before the catastrophe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> relies on the interpretation of three
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> for this, who spoke to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> under a guarantee of
anonymity. It's a mistake for the paper not to mention that just such nameless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> were also behind now-discredited press reports in the
Times and elsewhere that the black box tapes had the relief co-pilot
saying, "I've made my decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>," shortly before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s terminal
dive.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> states that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> has finally
officially confirmed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117 stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> shot down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX> over
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> was hit by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The paper reminds that immediately after the
loss (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> was rescued), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> suggested that the cause was
mechanical malfunction. The way-afterward news came as a result of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom of</ENAMEX>
Information Act request filed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Paso Times</ENAMEX> , the paper in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-117</ENAMEX> was based. Question: Why didn't the big-time papers this
column covers use their considerable resources to also pursue this
question?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, this space erred in referring to ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX> as a convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX>. What was meant was that he is an ex-convict
(he was sent up the river on a misdemeanor). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers apologizes to</ENAMEX>
anyone--including convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX>--who was offended by this mistake.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving holiday</TIMEX> clearly inspires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. There is for instance,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> saluting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for being so thanksworthy.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jedediah Purdy</ENAMEX> commending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> for its
encouragement of "scrupulous memory" of all "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of our pleasures,
privileges and obligations." But by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>' lights, there's a more
prosaic truth communicated by the practice of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX>. This after all, is
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> enters the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Garden</ENAMEX> and in a public ceremony
pardons a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX>, but then later on in the utter privacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Camp David</ENAMEX> sits
down to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> dinner.

         
      
   
