
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad Ayres Day</ENAMEX>

            How spun was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Drummond Ayres Jr.</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
when he wrote about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s special election in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to fill the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
seat of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Brown</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayres</ENAMEX>' line was that the seat had been a "sure
bet" for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to pick up. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> once "confidently
predict[ed] victory by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Pirozzi</ENAMEX>," he wrote, because they
"had been steadily nibbling away at [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s] winning margins as the district
... grew more and more conservative." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> couldn't have set the
stage better: If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Baca</ENAMEX> wins, it now looks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
like a stunning upset that foreshadows a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> collapse. If
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pirozzi</ENAMEX> wins, it looks like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> barely hung on to take a
seat that should have been a gimme.

            So what's wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayres</ENAMEX>' take? A lot:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. It's factually inaccurate. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> hadn't been
"steadily nibbling away" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>'s margins. They came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a few hundred</TIMEX>
votes of beating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years later</TIMEX> Pirozzi "lost to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> percentage points," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayres</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Purdum</ENAMEX> noted in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
piece on this very race <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district</ENAMEX> hasn't been growing "more and more
conservative." As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdum</ENAMEX> also reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> registration has "dropped
from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 39 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in the district to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 33 percent</NUMEX> now,
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, fueled by newly registered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, picking up the
difference." Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayres</ENAMEX> read his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> hadn't "confidently" predicted victory by
"their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pirozzi</ENAMEX>." In fact, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>,
State <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Brulte</ENAMEX>, decided not to run, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been
desperately lowering expectations, something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayres</ENAMEX> himself noted in an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 4</TIMEX>
piece. Since "no other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brulte</ENAMEX>'s] political stature has
indicated a desire to get into [the] contest," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayres</ENAMEX> wrote back then,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> ... may not be such an easy target." Why
is the stature-challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirozzi</ENAMEX> now suddenly a former "sure bet" of these
same unnamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>"?

            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayres</ENAMEX> read his own copy?

         
      
   
