
   
   
      
         
            Trading Insults

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second straight day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> meetings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> is everybody's
lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's lead focuses entirely on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-level protests and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> response to them, while the others split their attention between that
and the actual issues confronting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.

            In discussing the situation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, where a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk-to-dawn</TIMEX> curfew
stayed in effect last night, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> now believe
their initial handling of the situation was too permissive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reveals some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cops</ENAMEX>' most effective techniques after they decided to get tougher: confiscating
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas masks</ENAMEX> and cell phones from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX>. (But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>
are still using cell phones, as well as laptop computers and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palm Pilots</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regroup</ENAMEX> and alert <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> about their activities.) What a difference from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 1</TIMEX>, when, according to "several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cabinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>" quoted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , there hadn't even been any police barricades in place.

            A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front pager, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Egan</ENAMEX>, offers the best you-are-there account of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mayhem</ENAMEX>. The piece has an unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in black saying that anarchists
had planned all along to incite the rampage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times passes along unconfirmed reports of violent altercations on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> and also reports that when the
presidential limousine came through downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> it was
occasionally met by raised middle fingers. The WP front runs a profile
on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Dolan</ENAMEX>, who it claims was the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> protest, a
claim brought a bit into question because none of the other papers' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
coverage even mentions him.

            Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> really clearly says what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>
are actually trying to do: forging an agreement on what should be on the table
for the next round of trade liberalization talks. Everybody reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was much in evidence at the meetings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, addressing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> types, meeting privately with enviros, and closeting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>. The coverage makes it clear what the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> item is on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> agenda: getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to apply higher standards
regarding working conditions and environmental damage. And that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who
condemned the violent protests but welcomed the peaceful ones, in effect
endorsed one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>' key complaints: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is far too
secretive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also chastised <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> to the importation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-produced genetically engineered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> plays this latter
point higher than anybody else.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on a more specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposal--his advocacy of
relaxing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> trade rules to make anti-AIDS <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> more affordable in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>. This, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes, is a reversal of recent administration
policy, which had favored the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' stance of strict
distribution controls that kept prices high. (But there is no mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s history of having taken a pro-drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> position in this matter.) The
paper also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would support ending tariffs on all exports
from the poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-leads and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes bottom front with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviation Administration</ENAMEX>'s revelation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> who set out
to test security at major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> repeatedly found it could be easily
breached. They broke through checkpoints <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117</NUMEX> times in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">173</NUMEX> attempts. Some of
them, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, even managed to get themselves comfortably seated aboard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">airliners</ENAMEX> at departure time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX> used such techniques as piggybacking
through locked doors behind properly credentialed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and driving
through unmanned gates.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts report that after a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decade</ENAMEX> of work, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have decoded the information in a human chromosome.
The chromosome in question is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-smallest of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> pairs in a human
cell. Mapping all the information in all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> is the ultimate goal being
undertaken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Genome Project</ENAMEX> as well as by a competing
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stuffs the story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports inside that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> since the federal government
required background checks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to pawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, the gun inventory of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s pawn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> has fallen from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 million to 3 million</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial page comes down hard on those class-action suits
filed against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in the wake of the rather harsh finding of fact handed
down against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">DOJ</ENAMEX> antitrust trial. Such lawsuits are, opines
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "particularly troubling in cases such as these, in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plaintiff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, who are not elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> after all, seek to take in
their own hands significant public policy questions." Excuse, but couldn't
segregationists have said the same thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown vs. Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> ?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Business Bulletin" has a fact that
dramatizes how profoundly well-off this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> throw out
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 12 percent</NUMEX> of the stuff they buy at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the implementation of various energy-efficient
measures has saved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $1.4 million</NUMEX> in the operation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. Guess having the lights down low in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> all those
times really paid off ...

         
      
   
