
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batouti Bashing</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with an agreement between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">.38-percent</NUMEX> across-the-board spending cut, a story fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and
reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> tops its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box with the arrests
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">debtors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> by the new military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">junta</ENAMEX>, a story
fronted by no other paper. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EgyptAir 990</ENAMEX> investigation, a story fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with a decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azerbaijan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipeline</ENAMEX> from the landlocked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caspian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Basin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> had been lobbying to have the pipeline
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross Chechnya</ENAMEX>, and the West's demurral may cause friction at a meeting today
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pipeline</ENAMEX> will "tap rich oil fields in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>," but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on the deal says that no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> has yet been found; the pipeline is more
about political alliances than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>.

will give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> to convince it that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> should
not take over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir 990</ENAMEX> investigation. Although not much new evidence
surrounding the crash has come to light since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> run dispatches from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>
quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s suspected saboteur, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gamil al-Batouti</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> spelling). (All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> continue to spell the name
differently; see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Batouti</ENAMEX> was faithful enough not to condone suicide, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> argue, but
not zealous enough to believe in extreme political causes. And while he had
never been promoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>, as he had wanted, he was still quite
wealthy--so much so that he held no life insurance.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> chronicles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s journalism career. After brief stints
as a copy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> in college and as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> took a job at the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessean</ENAMEX> --which was then a
popular stop-off for the idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sirica</ENAMEX> had worked there). But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> surprised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scribblers</ENAMEX> by staying there
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. His biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> involved teaming up with the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.A.</ENAMEX> to
lure a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">councilman</ENAMEX> into taking a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> bribe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">councilman</ENAMEX> was defeated at the
polls as a result, but he was acquitted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The acquittal disillusioned
the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> with the power of the pen, and he decided to change
careers. He entered law school and shortly thereafter ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> when a
seat opened up. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">councilman</ENAMEX>--who has since been re-elected--has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> sign in his window. "His qualifications [for the presidency] outweigh
anything that happened between us," he says.

            The LAT highlights some unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of the Internet: the
homeless. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a half-dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> shelters have computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labs</ENAMEX>, which help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> learn everything from remedial math to job-searching
techniques. Free e-mail access has allowed the homeless to receive messages and
interact with potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> in ways they could not before. But since
computer time in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX> in highly structured, most of the truly dedicated
homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">techies</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>--use the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, where time is
virtually unlimited (and where, in large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 75 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are
homeless). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX>, it turns out, make money on the Web in much the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> they do on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>--by finding value in things discarded by others. One
homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> set up a site to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX> parts that he bought cheap from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> that
went out of business. Another made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few thousand dollars</NUMEX> by selling obscure
videos; he simply found the videos elsewhere on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and sold them at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">markup</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> began by charging others <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> to teach them how to acquire free
e-mail accounts. Now he runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Drudge</ENAMEX>-like tech industry gossip site, which has a mailing list
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,700</NUMEX>. On the Web, "it doesn't show if you haven't showered for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>,"
says a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless woman</ENAMEX> who now runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> writing workshop.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the M6</TIMEX>, was terrorized
by a carload of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> look-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alikes</ENAMEX> wielding toy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. The
velvet-clad pranksters were caught by a roadblock and given a warning by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
