
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kill People; Olympic Athletes Do</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wrote an item
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">praising Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> for turning the tables on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX>
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , whether he'd ever used
any illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. (For a full transcript of the broadcast, click here.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> continues to admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> for firing
back, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have you ?</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have you , Cokie?</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George [Will</ENAMEX>]? Who
wants to know?" And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> continues to find amusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>' desperate
attempts to change the subject ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and violence" and "Can we get
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and violence?" and "The--you wrote an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Op-Ed on guns"</ENAMEX>) after she gave
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> the ridiculous non-answer that "I was so pregnant during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX>."
(As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> observed in the earlier item,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.)

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was too beguiled by this little operetta to notice at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> that once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> finally permitted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> to change the subject, it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> who gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> a nonsensical answer. Let's pick the
dialogue up where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s previous
item left off.

            At first, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> more than held his own:

            

               
                  COKIE: The--you wrote an Op-Ed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>.
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX>: Yes.

               COKIE: Why not ban all handguns? Why just leave it to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-night</TIMEX>
specials?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">BRADLEY: Well</ENAMEX> I would ban <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-night</TIMEX> specials.

               COKIE: I know.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX>: And ever since I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX> in a pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> on the floor
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambassador Hotel</ENAMEX>, the picture of it, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, I thought any president
should ban <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-night</TIMEX> specials. I think that with regard to all handguns,
we should have system of registration and licensing, just like we do for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX>. If we can do it for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX>, we ought to be able to do it to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handguns</ENAMEX>. We ought to take gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> out of residential neighborhoods. We
ought to make it a felony, not a misdemeanor, if you sell a gun to somebody who
is underage or who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> himself. And I think that we ought to put trigger
locks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. And I think, finally, that we ought to have background checks
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> at the gun shows.

            

            But then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> came up with a very good question:

            

               
                  COKIE: But why not just get rid of them?
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX>: Get rid of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>? I think that getting rid of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COKIE</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nice</ENAMEX> try, slick ] : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handguns</ENAMEX>.
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX> [ Uh oh ] : Getting rid of all handguns. Well, I mean, what
are we going to [do] with the pentathlon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>? [ You may have heard
that I captained the gold-medal-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>
... ] They've got to have handguns. That's an event in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> . There are several other exceptions. So I
believe that we can have commonsense ...
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROBERTS</ENAMEX> [ I'm ready for ya! ] : <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> got rid of handguns after the
shootings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, and they participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>.
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> to try a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bluster</ENAMEX> ] : Well the point is, then
they haven't gotten rid of all the handguns , have they?
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SAM</ENAMEX> [ Teach you to ask me bullying questions about my past
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beanpole</ENAMEX> ] : How many angels can dance on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a pin,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>?
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yo Sam</ENAMEX>, thanks for overplaying your hand, as usual, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rudeness</ENAMEX> ] : Well enough to answer this question the way I want to answer
it.
               

            

            By then, time had run out on the interview, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> no chance to ask
the logical follow-up: "Do you favor a handgun ban that would allow an
exception for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> pentathlon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, like they apparently have
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>?" To which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> would almost certainly have answered, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>" Which
would have undercut (though, of course, not eliminated) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s status as
Bravest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gun Control</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pedant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> might also have pointed out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> pentathlon are air
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pistols</ENAMEX>, not exactly at the top of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Brady</ENAMEX>'s wish list of firearms to
ban.

         
      
   
