
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Suckers</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the angry reaction from many in business to the
government's just-proposed guidelines for fighting workplace repetitive stress
injuries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead covers essentially the same ground,
while also explaining the difference between the new rules and current
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> law. Both stories report that the rules, which mandate various
corrective actions at the first sign of injury, will cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> an
aggregate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.2 billion</NUMEX> per year. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the imminent release of the
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> study ever of racial attitudes within the uniformed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>.
The results are somewhat bracing for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> that portrays itself as
remarkably colorblind: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some three-quarters</NUMEX> of minority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> members
responding say they've experienced racism, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> doubted that
discrimination complaints are thoroughly investigated. And the survey shows
that military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> have a drastically more positive view. The paper quotes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> as saying the study was actually concluded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>,
but release was delayed while the brass debated how to portray the results. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> fronts the
survey--adding that a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> DOD report shows that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> get promoted
at a much lower rate than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>--but leads instead with the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New York</ENAMEX> has approved a plan that would bar remedial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> from a vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>, who apparently was once told to give
every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> something unique. He tells the former that trying to implement
the new workplace safety regs will be like getting your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> around a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marshmallow</ENAMEX>," and he tells the latter it will be like getting your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> around
a bowl of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jell-O</ENAMEX>." But the coverage itself suggests the squishiness of the
subject matter. The number of relevant workplace injuries mentioned (by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s coverage was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600,000</NUMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> (in an inside story) up the ante
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.8 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead's headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA Scales Back Its New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workplace Safety Plan</ENAMEX>"--and its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
quickly caved in to the protesting business world, whereas the story itself
explains that the rules were softened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last February</TIMEX>, not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> flagged in the WSJ front-page
business news box report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial was motivated to
bring in an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> by his worries about a rift over possible remedies developing between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and
those representing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The rift--with the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> favoring more
aggressive actions against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, such as carving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> up or forcing
it to share its operating system code--has been previously reported on in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s speech
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in which he charged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> had little interest in campaign-finance
reform because the current money-raising system favors <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX>. The
Times calls the speech one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s strongest efforts yet to portray
himself as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>, but also notes that with it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> risks
offending many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in that he is mirroring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> raised
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fund-raising apparatus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>.

            An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story by veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis X. Clines</ENAMEX> tells of a
new growth industry--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> specializing in cleaning up the messes left by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">homicides</ENAMEX> and suicides. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 200</NUMEX> such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX> have started up in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, creating concern that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should establish public health
standards for the field, like it has already for funeral <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parlors</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quick Quiz</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Today</ENAMEX>'s WSJ front page features a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,140</NUMEX>-word article
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s a) criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign-finance stance; b)
health-care plan; c) Web site as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> outreach tool; or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) lozenges. The
answer is d). This kind of drivel is the direct result of a presidential
campaign that started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> too early. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX> aren't saying much of
substance yet but are still out there working the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and the press feels
they still have to cover them.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> query prompts <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> to wonder about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s
obituaries for longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amintore Fanfani</ENAMEX>. Turns out that
there's a virtually identical <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>-word passage appearing in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obit</ENAMEX>, running over the byline of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alessandra Stanley</ENAMEX>, and in the WP obit,
credited to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Services</ENAMEX>." Who took from whom? And does this smidgeon of
theft still count as full-blown plagiarism?

         
      
   
