
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Salad Day</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Todd</ENAMEX>,

            I think what you are describing are those free concerts they hold outside of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> show. Particularly the ones by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Martin or Hansen</ENAMEX>.

            We have switched places <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I am groggy and having a hard time waking up.
I'm not sure if I ate too many waffles or too few. I saw An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Movie <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, which is a funny documentary about an obsessed young
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmaker</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>. Maybe prolonged exposure of any kind to your state
makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sleep later.

            So now, according to this morning's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> , they think that
maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> flight was responsible for the crash. They
are saying he was burdened by a lot of medical bills from a sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>. That he
made a few ominous "in case anything might happen to me" remarks to family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. You know, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX> I keep reading reports about all the
controversial "profiling" they are doing at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>, trying to predict the
behavior of suspicious ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX>. Now it turns out it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> they
should have be profiling, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>.

            It's been fun reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. But it's so weird
how full of odd bits of gossip these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> is widely
accepted as the less sophisticated of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, yet there are no parallel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> here. The other <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> there was a lengthy item in either the
Post or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> about what the newly slimmer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> eats for lunch (a chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesar</ENAMEX>). And I thought to myself, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, how
sad that we in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Los Angeles</ENAMEX> have virtually no idea what's in the
meals of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Riordan</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
