
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge Done</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>,

            Let me choose my words carefully: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> is the single most repulsive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the planet. Not since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Nicole Smith</ENAMEX> has such an extraordinarily
big boob been mistaken for a celebrity. For me, the problem is only partly his
hair, which is absolutely a toupee. (Trust me. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have gaydar; I have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rugdar</ENAMEX>). And it's a terrible toupee. Can't he pay someone to tell him how bad
it looks? If I left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> looking like that, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> would change the
locks. But even worse is the slit-eyed, phony-baloney pout, the one he
presumably thinks makes him look serious-minded. I've spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last eight</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> watching one middle-aged lothario manipulate his lower lip for emotional
effect in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Garden</ENAMEX>; I don't need to see another. Both problems, of
course, pale by comparison to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Issue</ENAMEX>, as in: What the hell is a girl
like her doing with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> like him? How does he get supermodels to spend more
than a minute with him? Not that I really want to know the answer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dating</ENAMEX>--and other unmentionable gerunds--is more than I care to
contemplate.

            But I'm happy to contemplate the sorry state of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>. Other than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>, not a peep from those quarters lately, huh? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> has dropped out
of sight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> has remained out of sight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> is watching Out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sight</ENAMEX> (OK, a stretch, but work with me). And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is probably out
buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> gifts. The undoing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>, whom you wrote about quite nicely in
the last Talk , is arguably the most interesting story of this campaign.
He's incredibly smart and telegenic--it's always fun to watch him spar on TV,
even if I disagree with him--but he's shown himself to be a helpless captive of
another era, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-prong outlet in a world of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-prong plugs. His tin ear on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> stuff--his inability to recognize that it wasn't what he said but
what he seemed to say--was baffling; imagine what he'd have said if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> had
played footsie with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commies</ENAMEX>. And his cozying up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenora Fulani</ENAMEX>, whose
great contribution to society is to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX> seem statesmanlike, is
nuts. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> hugs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> and calls it compassionate conservatism, we
all think: OK, this is who he is; he's credible. But any time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s in a room
with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>, you wonder: When's he gonna call <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX>? The shame is
that the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> is buried beneath all that. I just saw an early cut of a great
documentary on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX> that will play <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sundance</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> and then air
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Experience</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s on camera defending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>, sort of, but his energy and intelligence and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> are
unmistakable. You walk away just plain liking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            Apropos of not liking someone and not having any authority to speak of: Do
you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>'s days are numbered? First he goes all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Terry</ENAMEX> on
us and gets bounced from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartford Courant</ENAMEX> says he's
irrelevant. (Yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartford Courant</ENAMEX> . Aren't you surfing the Web site
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>'s finest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>?) The essence of the story, which I found on the
hidden gem of the Internet, mediagossip.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, is that he hasn't broken any stories since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
and has seen his unique selling proposition usurped by other would-be Web
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winchells</ENAMEX>. That sounds about right. But damned if I don't look at the Drudge
Report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Evan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
