
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reckless Gossip Merchants</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Hand</ENAMEX>-Wringers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>:

            I'd love to add something even meaner to your description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>--he's the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> I want to keep kicking once he's down--but I
don't think I can. You've said it all: He is the single most repulsive person
on the planet. What a wonderfully pithy, accurate sentence.
Congratulations.

            That said, I still plan to write about him some time. I don't think I'll be
able to help it. Horrible as he is (or perhaps because he is so horrible),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> is interesting, or at least more so than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>
took a lot of crap from more serious-minded political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">devoting</ENAMEX> so much ink to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morry Taylor</ENAMEX>, the drunken tire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
who made a brief, self-financed run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> nomination. The idea
was, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morry Taylor</ENAMEX> is irrelevant. Why waste <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' time writing about him?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> part of me agrees: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morry Taylor</ENAMEX> barely rose to the level of sideshow.
And there's no reason to feed the ego of every rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who decides to inflict
his mid-life crisis on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. That's the sober, responsible part of
me speaking. The much larger part--the part that once wrote a piece about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s sex therapist--feels differently. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, following
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> around would likely be amusing as hell. I plan to start the interview by
sneezing repeatedly into my palm, then trying to shake his hand. Guaranteed
lede right there. (I can already see it in print: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> is afraid of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cooties</ENAMEX>.") For another, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>'s candidacy, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> generally,
reflects a larger, important trend in politics, and may be the surest sign yet
that ideology as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in national elections is dead.

            Wow. Did I just write that last sentence? Pardon me. Let me take that back:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> isn't a reflection of anything. They're just a bunch of wackos
with a Web site and federal matching funds. But that doesn't mean we can't have
a good time covering them.

            Now that I've revealed myself as essentially shallow and self-interested,
let's talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>. Has his time passed? I don't know. I must admit I'm a
bit torn here. I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> is obsessed with accuracy, and I never
thought that giving him a television show sounded like a great idea. On the
other hand, if there's one thing that annoys me more than a reckless Internet
gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>, it's self-appointed media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchdog hand-wringers</ENAMEX> who whine
about reckless Internet gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX>. As if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to be protected
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>. As if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> don't know the difference between the Drudge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . As if anyone cares what a bunch of
tight-assed media-studies dorks who work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX> nobody's ever heard of
and haven't filed a story since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Administration</ENAMEX> think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Journalism Today</ENAMEX>. As if ... I could go on, and on. But I'll spare you.
Just remind me not to get started on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX>.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
