
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weapons of Mass Destruction Ain't Rocket Science</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Merrill</ENAMEX>--

            OK, I bought new copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, and I'm wearing the right pants.
Here's a headline from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> again: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. Thinks Iraq Is Rebuilding</ENAMEX>
Ruined <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Military Sites</ENAMEX>." As we used to say in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade, back when I was
wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keds</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> and a Star Wars T-shirt and sobbing on the
playground because the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were all pelting me with dodge balls, "well,
ah- doy... " Since when has the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> there done anything
else? I mean, that's literally all they do, they've got all their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> in one
basket, so to speak. Amass <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, subjugate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> into obeisance with
weapons, and when somebody comes along and blows up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, well, one just
has to keep one's chin up, look on the bright side, and start over again from
the top. Get right back on the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> there, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX>, and keep at it. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hussein</ENAMEX>
decided long ago to sort of put the various other subtle, more nuanced aspects
of running a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on the back burner, if you will, and just kind of focus on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> specific area of approach. Do what you're good at (kind of like the way the
Markoe family <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> focus their energies on eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>). And why is he so good
at it? Because, like many evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>, he learned from the absolute best:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">los Federales de Los Estados Unidos</ENAMEX>, as the good ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in the expertly
trained death squads of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> like to affectionately call them.
Again, hardly a brilliant observation on my part, but then again, how smart do
you really need to be to get the general gist of this sort of thing? After all,
this is chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction, not rocket science.

            Of course gay weddings should be legal. After all, gay luxury tropical
cruises are, and although I've never experienced either of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, luxury
tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cruises</ENAMEX> must be at least as difficult to endure as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of
marriage is. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lesbians</ENAMEX> in particular, from what I've observed, seem to have a
particular knack for it (staying married, I mean, not enduring ocean-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX>
dream vacations). And of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moesha</ENAMEX> was taking diuretics. I may live in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, but that much was obvious immediately, hence my anecdote about how
she was worried that she wasn't pretty enough. News flash to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX>: There may
be many things that you are not, but pretty isn't one of them. So stop taking
the diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>. I want to propose something (all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> freaking out about
gay marriage in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fray</ENAMEX>" section should particularly consider redirecting
your energies into this one): Let's start a national e-mailing campaign,
spearheaded by 
                  Slate
               , into letting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> know that, yes, she is
indeed pretty enough. Here's a suggested sample wording:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Moesha</ENAMEX>--

               I think you are pretty. So does everybody else. In fact, you are an
internationally famous <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pretty</ENAMEX>-Person. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may not like your show, or
your singing, or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psycho-murderer</ENAMEX> horror movie, but nobody, anywhere in the
whole world, doesn't think you are pretty. Therefore, please never think that
you aren't pretty enough ever again.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
(your name).

               P.S.: I loved the episode wear you learned the important lesson about not
being afraid to wear glasses.

            

            What do you say? Think we can get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> to bankroll this? It's for a good
cause, and he needs some good P.R. right now.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
