
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan Pork Chops</ENAMEX>

Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s berating, at a conference in
Istanbul, of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military's
assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>--a story fronted (below the fold) by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>'s decision to boost enlistment benefits.
It nearly doubled the signing bonus for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX>--from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX>--and decreased the minimum enlistment period needed to receive a bonus
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. Total benefits can now reach <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85,000</NUMEX>. No other paper
carries this story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">296-135</ENAMEX> passage of a final budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven weeks</TIMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fiscal year</TIMEX>--a story off-leaded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> continued to bicker over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> renewed an
emergency-spending bill for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another two weeks</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bill increases
spending on health and education, pays <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> debts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, and
restores <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 billion</NUMEX> worth of cuts to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> notes
high up that spending will increase by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of billions of dollars</NUMEX> from last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and will break appropriations caps set by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> balanced budged
agreement.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> decried the "sermonizing" by the West over his attack on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">rebellious</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. Although speaking immediately after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> noted the heavy civilian casualties inflicted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and
made an analogy: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> had been jailed (instead of elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>)
after standing on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> in defiance of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> coup, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> argued,
"I would hope that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> around this table would have
stood up for you and for freedom in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and not said, 'Well, that is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal Russian</ENAMEX> affair that we cannot be part of.' " Many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> at the
summit spoke in support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> agreed to an external review by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSCE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> do not make much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s leaving the
conference <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a day</TIMEX> early, but the news summary in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's
"Woldwide" box claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "walked out" of the conference
(the corresponding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's Web site
makes no such characterization). The papers do not mention a possible political
motive for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is expected to launch a similar attack
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechnya</ENAMEX> campaign in a foreign-policy speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, a
position that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has now triangulated.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diagrams</ENAMEX> of a miniaturized nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warhead</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the W88</TIMEX>, designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--contain a telltale measurement error
that can be traced back to several weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">manufacterers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> The
anonymously sourced, front-page story reports that these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> include
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandia National Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>--but probably not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos National Labratory</ENAMEX>, where an employee, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>, had been targeted
by a much-criticized espionage investigation.

            An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> documents declassified <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> reveal that in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '80s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '90s</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> was more aware of impending <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> collapse
than previously thought. Although it continued to stress the likelihood of a
hard-line revolt against perestroika, it did conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX>'s
reformist inclinations were sincere.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says that an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> has retracted an
earlier assertion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX> suspected of sabotaging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir 990</ENAMEX> said,
"I have made my decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>," before uttering the widely reported phrase, "I
put my faith in God's hands." (The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phrase has been mentioned by some, but
not all, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> now. Suspecting that this first
phrase was spurious, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> now regrets not having mentioned this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anomaly</ENAMEX>.) This is not, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes, a petty detail: If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">co-pilot</ENAMEX> had actually said, "I have made my decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>," that would seem to
rule out the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s theory that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX>'s "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>" phrase,
"I put my faith in God's hands," was a reaction to an as-yet-undiscovered
mechanical problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , which ran both phrases in a top-front
pull-quote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, does not make a similar retraction; in fact, it
repeats both phrases in an inside story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, an
anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in a story run inside, that a
re-examination of the flight data recorder shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> to be "rock steady,"
with no hint of mechanical failure, before its fatal dive.

            The LAT fronts an appraisal of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.5 million</NUMEX> to dredge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marina del Rey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> to remove burros
from the desert, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> for a mural in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Twentynine Palms</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to build an
international trade <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulare County</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> to reinforce
levees on the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Los Angeles River</ENAMEX> and relieve nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of a federal
mandate to buy flood insurance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> profiles the goodies secured by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Stevens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>,
including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Alaska</ENAMEX> to study the aurora
borealis, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to conduct a census of walruses, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> to help stranded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> to build a parking ramp for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-130</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> is so legendary, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , that a recent
episode of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Wing</ENAMEX> features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
joking about a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> outlay to monitor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> skies for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">volcanic ash</ENAMEX>--an
appropriation that, unlike the rest of the sitcom, is not fictional.

         
      
   
