
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Murphy's Law</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox Investigation</ENAMEX>

            The death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul Stapp</ENAMEX>, who during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX> and '50s
allowed his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to be used in various experiments testing the effects of
high-speed transportation, provides an occasion to consider how <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy's Law</ENAMEX>
came into being. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' obituary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stapp</ENAMEX>, who died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13</TIMEX> at the ripe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 89</TIMEX>, tells
it this way:

            

               
                  Stapp, who was known for his razor-sharp wit, suffered an injury in the
experiment that inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy's Law</ENAMEX>, after a ... rapid sled ride in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>.
               

               An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Murphy Jr.</ENAMEX>, had designed a harness to strap the
rider in. The harness held <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> sensors to measure the acceleration, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>,
on different parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. There were exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways each sensor could
be installed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> did each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the wrong way.

               The result was that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stapp</ENAMEX> staggered off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket sled</ENAMEX> with bloodshot
eyes and bleeding sores, all the sensors registered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. He had been
restrained in vain.

               A distraught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> proclaimed the original version of the famous maxim: "If
there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more ways to do something and one of those results in a
catastrophe, then someone will do it that way."

            

            But a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Bear</ENAMEX>, then a flight-center <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Edwards Air Force Base</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, where the experiment in question took
place, tells it this way:

            

               
                  [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Murphy's Law</ENAMEX>] was named after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward A. Murphy</ENAMEX>, an engineer
working on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Project</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MX981</ENAMEX>, [a project] designed to see how much sudden
deceleration a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can stand in a crash.
               

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX>, after finding that a transducer was wired wrong, he cursed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> responsible and said, "If there is any way to do it wrong, he'll
find it."

            

            Both versions of the story have the same basic theme, which is that it's
always good to be prepared for lots of things going wrong. But in the
Times version, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>'s comment seems to be an exercise in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evading</ENAMEX> blame . Rather than saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gosh</ENAMEX>, I'm sorry," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> is
attributing his 
               own screw-up to some larger cosmic tendency for
all things to get screwed up. It's the engineering equivalent of the
familiar political dodge, "mistakes were made." By contrast, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX>'s version,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capt. Murphy</ENAMEX> is attaching blame to someone else . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> is more or less
calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> said to be responsible (we never get the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technician</ENAMEX>'s version) a schmuck . In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX>'s version, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> is not
stating any broad philosophical principle of any kind. If this is the
real version--for what it's worth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah M. Bryant</ENAMEX> told the story
the same way in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1997</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Edge</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> organ of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Materiel Command</ENAMEX>--then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law</ENAMEX> was completely misconstrued.
In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX> is itself an illustration of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy's Law</ENAMEX>.
(Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> version nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear/Bryant</ENAMEX> version is particularly
flattering to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>.)

            To make matters even more confusing, there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> version of the
story involving an entirely different <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>--not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX> (later Admiral ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph M. "Murph</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>. Chatterbox was unable to obtain details of this story, but "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murph</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward H. Heinemann</ENAMEX>, an aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Douglas Aircraft</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s and '50s</TIMEX>, attributes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy's Law</ENAMEX> in
his (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heinemann</ENAMEX>'s) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> autobiography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Heinemann</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combat Aircraft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Designer</ENAMEX> . Chatterbox
got the poop on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murph</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Johnsen</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edwards</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> Flight <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Test Center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnsen</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heinemann</ENAMEX> once
showed him "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murph</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>'s photograph and said, "That's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who invented
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Murphy's Law</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnsen</ENAMEX> said that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heinemann</ENAMEX> spent a lot of time at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX>, he has no reason to think that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murph</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> had any connection to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX> at all.

            "There are several reputable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the aeronautic industry who claim to
have known <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>, and it's a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> in each case," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnsen</ENAMEX> told
Chatterbox regretfully. At least, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnsen</ENAMEX>
said ...

         
      
   
