
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX>?

            Chatterbox, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> who has a somewhat limited
understanding of how they do things in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, is baffled by the
commentary coming out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> concerning the future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX>. As was widely publicized, the
Labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> evicted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">666</NUMEX> very Monty Python-ish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hereditary</ENAMEX> peers ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Binkies</ENAMEX>") from the upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>, temporarily leaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX> and
otherwise putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX> in the hands of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 500</NUMEX> politically
appointed life peers ("day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>"), whose title and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> dies with them. A
lively discussion has now begun about how to complete the reform of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX>, which for most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> has had the power only to delay
legislation. The scenarios under consideration tend to emphasize making
membership entirely or partially elective, which would make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX>
more democratic, and then giving the upper chamber greater power than it
currently enjoys. If nothing is done, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX> will persist as a
patronage tool for whichever party happens to control the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Commons</ENAMEX>.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't understand is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britons</ENAMEX> don't kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX> outright. From this side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> has long appeared to
be ruled by an essentially unicameral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>. Making it unequivocally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unicameral</ENAMEX> would seem to be a small and eminently sensible step--one that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
embraced throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s and 1980s</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX>' own compendium of major
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> proposals to reform or abolish the chamber.) Instead,
the talk is drifting in the direction of turning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX> into an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anglified U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>. Wouldn't this give the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> a government far less
streamlined than what it enjoys <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? Chatterbox can't imagine why any country
that didn't already have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> could possibly want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read an excellent recent column by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary McGrory</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Byrd</ENAMEX>'s nearly
successful attempt to use his power to filibuster to promote the decapitation
by mining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>. See also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Geoghegan</ENAMEX>'s
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Secret Lives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens</ENAMEX> [click here to buy the book], which makes an excellent case for
abolishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>.)

            Seeking guidance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox queried Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, who is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> by birth and an admirably
uncompromising small-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">r republican</ENAMEX>. In an e-mail, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchens</ENAMEX> likened the ejection
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binkies</ENAMEX> to building a bridge "from the middle of the river."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> ought to come the point of principle: do you want a hereditary head
of state or inherited seats in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX>? Then and only then does one have a
constitutional discussion about which alternative to adopt. Brilliant as they
are at avoiding anything that smacks of principle, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blairites</ENAMEX> now have a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a hundred</NUMEX> "chosen" hereditary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>, and the
remainder a bunch of party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX>. Nobody could conceivably have designed
such an outcome if they were writing a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. And so of course this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pre-empts</ENAMEX> (as it may be meant to) the persistent argument over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
ought to have a written document with an appended <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>. It also
avoids the ticklish subject of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windsors</ENAMEX>, who are now the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with political power by right of birth.
            

            Concerning unicameralism, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitchens</ENAMEX> seemed unenthusiastic. He said it
was "fine by me, but most big decisions in modern history have been taken
without reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> and so I suppose that one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> is as easy to
bypass as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>."

            Chatterbox next queried <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hendrik Hertzberg</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , who not
long ago wrote a compelling "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>" piece endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s plan to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> unicameral. (At present, the
only unicameral state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>'s.) Chatterbox
will give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertzberg</ENAMEX> the last word:

            
               There was a lot of sentiment for abolition back in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd George</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>,
the last time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX> reform really had traction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd George</ENAMEX> himself wanted to
get rid of the thing, but he had to settle for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Parliament Act of 1911</ENAMEX>,
which scaled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX>' power down from being able to kill legislation outright
to being able to delay it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> (reduced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> in, I think,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>). [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, actually.]

            
               Several things have happened since then. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, the relatively
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toothless</ENAMEX> post-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1911</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lulled people</ENAMEX> into thinking it was a good
idea to have a delaying or amending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> as a safeguard against overhasty
legislation. For another, a certain amount of bicameral delusion has seeped
over from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> constitutionalism at the moment is away
from absolute parliamentary (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Commons</ENAMEX>) sovereignty and toward
divided sovereignty of various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinds</ENAMEX>--parliaments for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>,
stronger local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> with elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>.
Abolishing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>-wide chamber outright would go against what a lot
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> assume to be the spirit of the times.
            

            Personally, I'd like to see them abolish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX> and I bet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>
would, too. The idea of an elected <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> sounds all nicey-nice and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX>, but the more democratic legitimacy a second <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> has, the
stronger the possibility of gridlock. An appointed <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> would have
less legitimacy, therefore less power, therefore less likelihood of gumming up
the works.

         
      
   
