
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hack Work, Pandering</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omissions</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>:

            I would not see myself as being easy on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> There are
those who frankly think him fraudulent, some of whom are very prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
I think this might be a bit unfair. What I find fascinating about him is not
the work, which may or may not be remembered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come, but rather the
driving ambition so directed at what seems to me to be small causes writ large
by advertising and the sheer claims he can make for them. In this regard, he is
an incredible intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> and an incredible public presence. I think it
is a waste of time for a major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> to create an encyclopedia, despite the
efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diderot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> in the past. I think it is a waste of time for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">major scholar</ENAMEX> to do such hack work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, even if one could make a great deal
of money doing it. It is this obsession, which far exceeds anything I have ever
encountered in any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> have no little ego
and no little ambition), this need to have his fingerprints everywhere, that I
find curious but that I also think, ultimately for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, is destructive of the
very end he probably wants to achieve. He wants, I assume, to be taken
seriously, but is he, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>? And will he be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 or 20 years from now</TIMEX>?

            Yes, I do agree that he has taken advantage of the practice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> have
of wanting one prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> at a time in a field. He is a very shrewd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
and I cannot blame him for taking the world as it has been given to him. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Whites</ENAMEX>
find him agreeable for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons that they find any black intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">agreeable</ENAMEX>: he makes what he knows about Negroes interesting but not
threatening; he knows a great deal of white intellectual stuff, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>
always find amusing and entertaining in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX>. But while he is a singular
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual figure</ENAMEX>, his position is simply, to some large degree, that
of any hustling black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who knows that the rewards worth having in
this culture for his professional pursuits are all controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.

            Now, your comments about the politically correct nature of Africana
are right and point up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the serious flaws with this book. It is far too
trendy, almost whimsically so, to be of great value to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years from now</TIMEX>. This book aspires to be not only an encyclopedia but also
an almanac, a biographical dictionary, a historical monument in and of itself.
Here is an intellectual effort that is greatly compromised by anti-intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of compelling strength: the need to give emphasis to homosexuality all
out of proportion to its importance in black life, the need to mention people
such as rappers like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tupac Shakur</ENAMEX> and the like when the art and significance of
such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> remain to be proved worthy of attention, the need for personalities
generally like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rupaul</ENAMEX> whose inclusion is an embarrassment. Then, there are the
thought-clichés such as the inclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX> even though all the credible
scholarship shows that it was extremely unlikely that she was of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
descent.

            It is this sort of pandering to the popular and to notions that many black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hold dear even though they are wrong that works against this book and
against black intellectual efforts generally. That is because, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> finds him or herself engaged in a propagandistic defense of
the race, instead of a true, objective exploration of the meaning of the race's
experience, good, bad, and indifferent. This makes the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> not
only a propagandist but also an apologist, at times, of the most hypocritical
sort, blowing up trivialities while ignoring profundities because of their
ambiguous nature, all the while operating with the urges of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX>,
discarding merit in the name of equality of space or for "educating" the public
in favor of a good cause. This, more than anything, makes the public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intellectual</ENAMEX>, black or white, fraudulent, dangerous in both his or her snobbery
and his or her political moralism. And this has particularly sapped the vigor
and strength of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>, his or her incisiveness swallowed in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX> of bathetic race promoting. It is telling, indeed, about the
anti-intellectual nature of this book that the blurbs on the back do not come
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> at all but from popular black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX> for causes. Nothing corrupts good intellectual work more thoroughly
that the righteous malice of a cause.

            I do not particularly like to engage what is not in a book, but, of course,
it cannot be avoided in this sort of work, as its scheme is meant to make a
statement about what is important about the black experience and what isn't. To
ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelby Steele</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Crouch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Loury</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Wortham</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Sowell</ENAMEX> is irresponsible. They deserve to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objectively</ENAMEX> presented whether one agrees with their positions or not. But there
are other absences here that, given the p.c. nature of the work, are very
surprising. There are no entries on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamza El-Din</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Abdul-Malik</ENAMEX>, the two
most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> ever to play in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Adbul-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malik</ENAMEX> played with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monk</ENAMEX>, for instance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamza El-Din</ENAMEX> has made the oud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, as Ravi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shankar</ENAMEX> did the sitar. Since the book is trying so hard to promote a global
black culture and "world music," (whatever that is), their omission is just
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bewildering</ENAMEX>. There is no entry for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Flood</ENAMEX>. How can the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who challenged
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s reserve clause in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--who gave up his career as a professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> rather than submit to going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for whom he did
not wish to play (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>)--how can such mighty resistance, which this
book and all black political correctness greatly prizes, be ignored!? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Curt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flood</ENAMEX> was probably second only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Robinson</ENAMEX> as the most important
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th- century</TIMEX> baseball. Yet nothing on him in
this book. His omission outraged me. Snoop Doggy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikki Giovanni</ENAMEX> or Queen
Latifah are more important than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flood</ENAMEX>!

            This brings me to the entries that are connected in some way or another to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>. I was heartened to see entries for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Pace Alexander</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sadie Mossell Alexander</ENAMEX>. I was disappointed that there was no entry for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson Goode</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, or for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Allen</ENAMEX>, the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX>, who was traded to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX> in the deal that was to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Flood</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, the deal that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flood</ENAMEX> used as a pretext for challenging the reserve clause. So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> was
important in several ways, but not to have him in the book was understandable.
What was less understandable was the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil Moore</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the
Alexanders, as black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, cannot be understood without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil Moore</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiery ex-Marine</ENAMEX> who became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> and proceeded to turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> upside-down with his militant protests. The
Alexanders, middle-class black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who were uncomfortable with street
protest, detested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>. Indeed, most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> did.
Also, the entries on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexanders</ENAMEX> did not mention her role as the president
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Relations Commission</ENAMEX>, a city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that was started when
the reform <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> swept the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> out of power in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX> and
changed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> charter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Relations Commission</ENAMEX> was very important in
the history of race relations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s and 1960s</TIMEX>, although it
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> without strong enforcement abilities. It was not mentioned in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Pace Alexander</ENAMEX>'s piece how he worked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> to try to desegregate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girard College</ENAMEX> (he failed) and how he tried to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mummers</ENAMEX> in their annual
parade to stop using blackface makeup (he failed there, too). In the entry on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> itself, there is no mention of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> riot that changed the city
dramatically. No mention in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chubby Checker</ENAMEX> entry that his marriage to a
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathrina Lodders</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1963</TIMEX>, adversely
affected his career.

            I mention all of this to say that to me, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphian</ENAMEX>, what is said
collectively about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> in the book is not terribly useful. And that is
precisely the problem with these sorts of catch-all books, with entries often
written as hack work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who are not terribly familiar with the subject.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> try to emphasize what makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> a national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> without
concentrating very much on the local context of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s importance, which
is often far more valuable and meaningful to understanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s
historical standing than what can be said about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as a national
figure. This I find enormously frustrating about a book like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africana</ENAMEX> .
This is why I am puzzled that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' abilities wants to do such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsatisfying</ENAMEX> and such compromised intellectual work as this. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> is
a very self-conscious monument. But to what?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Early</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
