
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Paid His Accountants $4 Million</ENAMEX>
            

            Of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign will raise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX>--or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>--will go toward "the legal and accounting costs of meeting
federal campaign finance regulations," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> estimates.
Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s bill so high?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s bills are par for the course for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who participate in the
government's "matching-fund program." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> aren't
participating in the matching-fund program because it comes with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33 million</NUMEX>
spending limit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> is.) The matching-fund program disburses one
dollar for every dollar donated by an individual to a campaign <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $250</NUMEX>. If
an individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> gives the legal limit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $250</NUMEX> qualifies for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> matching funds.

            To qualify for matching funds, campaigns must verify the addresses, phone
numbers, signatures, and occupations of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>--and constructing this paper
trail can be costly. For example, if a campaign requests matching funds for a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> donation from a joint checking account, it must obtain a letter verifying
that each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> contributed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>; otherwise the campaign will receive only
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> of the matching funds. Similarly, the campaign's expenditures must be
exhaustively documented to demonstrate that they comply with the campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> laws.

            Monster accounting and legal bills like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s are so common that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX> allows presidential campaigns to automatically
deduct <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the money they raise against the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33 million</NUMEX> spending cap.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> often spend more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> on legal and accounting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX>, but they must document that fact to the satisfaction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX>.

            Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> adds new rules after each election cycle, the complexity and
costs of reporting continue to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushroom</ENAMEX>. Most large campaigns outsource their
regulatory accounting, and since there are only a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that
specialize in this area, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> can be quite expensive. Are they worth
the bother and expense? In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s case, he spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> to receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $13</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in matching dollars.

            Next question?

         
      
   
