
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lighten Up</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>:

            Ooh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX>. Do I really want to say what I think about him and then
have to read a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>-page analysis of my various journalistic indiscretions in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Con Job</ENAMEX> ? Including a discography of all the free copies of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beastie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> CDs I received in the mail and kept?!? Even though we never
actually ran a review?!?

            The trouble with him and his self-police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> is they have no sense of
humor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ombudsmen</ENAMEX>? Agate-type footnotes? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geez</ENAMEX>. My heart aches for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of
the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spy</ENAMEX> , when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> hid behind pseudonyms, skewered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX> "I'm
Writing as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad as I Can</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and recounted
delicious personal details about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> I'd never heard of who left the
bathroom without washing their hands, etc. Instead, we get pots calling kettles
black; and not just pots but rich and powerful pots with rich and powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Lighten up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>. Let he who is without synergy cast the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX>.

            For what it's worth, my somewhat obvious street-corner view is that the
conflicts of interests that drive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> nuts are inevitable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> mergers and
gobblings-up and the like have made it impossible for us to do our jobs if
we're obligated to disqualify ourselves from covering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a) we
do business with, b) we have a personal relationship or history with, or c) are
in competition with. I'm not saying I like it; I'm just saying there it is.
Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> goes wrong is in failing to distinguish between the most innocuous
and naturally occurring conflicts from those lipstick-smeared ones that could
have and should have been avoided. In the former category, I put, say,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's decision to review the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pokémon</ENAMEX> movie, which was
released by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>; what's it gonna do--not run a review? In the latter,
I put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' decision to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie Weinraub</ENAMEX> on the movie business
beat all that time after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> ascended to the ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> muckety-muck.
And I won't even mention the sort of logrolling that routinely goes on in the
book-review biz, the most recent example of which involves a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>-based
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that shall remain nameless. But not shameless.

            Into the latter category, alas, I must also put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of your current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> (which each seem to be piece of a big, honking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX>, as is
mine). Can you tell that I'm dying to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Unpronounceable Last</ENAMEX>
Name's Talk piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ? In a way I admire what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> is doing (he said respectfully, protecting his future job
prospects). Rather than mincing around on the edges of the conflict-of-interest
minefield, she's charging down the middle, ignoring the explosions to her left
and right. What I don't admire is her pretending, however energetically, that
she's doing something other than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">shilling</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weinsteins</ENAMEX>. Knowing that
[insert blonde <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starlet</ENAMEX> here] appears on the cover because she's got a movie
coming out doesn't make me want to read the story less--or more. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>'s
insisting that she put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Hurley</ENAMEX> in an extraterrestrial fashion spread
because it was a cute idea and not because she starred in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Favorite</ENAMEX>
Martian , a film available right now on video from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>'s parent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, totally and completely strains credibility. My advice: Out
yourself. Come clean. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tattoo</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob"</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of knuckles and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harv</ENAMEX>" on the
other, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belushi</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blues Brothers</ENAMEX> . It's not as if we'll stop reading
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>--or start.

            Before I sign off, I must point out my favorite wire story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> tourist has filed a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> lawsuit because his penis was allegedly crushed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX>.
No, not in a roaster--he was in the bathroom making, as they say, a
grande , when he reached back for the toilet paper and inadvertently got
himself caught between the seat and bowl.

            But did he wash his hands? Brill, get me rewrite.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Evan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
