
   
   
      
         
            The Trouble With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German Nationalism</ENAMEX>
            

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecom giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vodafone</ENAMEX> succeeds in its attempted hostile takeover
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecom giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann</ENAMEX>, the deal will be, by some measures, the
biggest deal in history (non-inflation, non-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">bull-market-</TIMEX>adjusted, that is). And
it will also be a crucial step in turning <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> into what it's supposedly well
on its way to becoming: a unified economic region.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Britain</ENAMEX> has refused to become part of the euro currency zone, so
there's something ironic about a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> serving as the avatar of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalization</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-style. Nonetheless, it is as precisely that kind of
avatar that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann</ENAMEX>'s management and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are treating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vodafone</ENAMEX>. Even
allowing for the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> trying to resist hostile takeovers will
say and do almost anything to make their would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">acquirers</ENAMEX> look bad, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> reaction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vodafone</ENAMEX> offer has been striking for its vehemence and
the nakedness of its nationalism. Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> alike have all publicly attacked the deal as effectively
British imperialism.

            This is not, on some level, exactly surprising. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, after all,
nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> had regulations requiring pension funds to invest
most of their assets in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> based in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olivetti</ENAMEX>'s
successful takeover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecom Italia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> was made possible in part by
the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecom Italia</ENAMEX>'s attempted defense against the takeover involved
a prospective merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Telekom</ENAMEX>, a merger that would have been
unacceptable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In any case, it's not as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> has no experience with this sort of thing, as evidenced by the hysteria
occasioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' acquisitions of properties like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX>. (Of course,
since only huge inflows of foreign capital now allow us to fund our
current-accounts deficit, we should be thankful, not angry, that foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> want to put their money here.)

            Still, the fight over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann</ENAMEX> seems especially ironic. In the first
place, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have been among the most aggressive of global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">acquirers</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, both in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> has bought
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bertelsmann</ENAMEX> has acquired a host of media and publishing properties,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Bank</ENAMEX> bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bankers Trust</ENAMEX>, and the list goes on. That's why, for all
the bluster, you probably won't see the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> actually taking any
political action to block the deal. And it's also why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> should get over
the knee-jerk reaction that any foreign takeover necessarily means terrible
things for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            The other factor that should be at play here, but doesn't seem to be, is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> that foreign competition, whether in the direct form of competition
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> or the more indirect form of competition for corporate control,
is a very good thing, at least if we can take any lessons from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
experience. Most of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> acquisitions were complete bombs, but then
most acquisitions fail. The pressure created by those acquisitions, though, was
a good thing (as, in retrospect, the pressure created by the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">raiders</ENAMEX>
of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> was).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann</ENAMEX> is not exactly a fat and happy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> run by sleepy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. It has turned in a strong performance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>. But when Vodafone
offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX> euros a share for a stock that had been trading at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX> euros a share
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> say that the offer is an insult, it makes you wonder
whether those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> really understand what shareholder value means. And it
also makes you think that they may be looking after their own interests more
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s. The impulse to rally to the flag may be understandable in
the face of an offer like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vodafone's</ENAMEX>. But from an economic perspective, it's an
impulse that should be resisted.

         
      
   
