
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impresario Gates</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Gerald</ENAMEX>:

            We're probably more in accord on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Africana</ENAMEX> than not, but I think you
were too easy on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years ago</TIMEX>, before blackness became really marketable,
it used to be said that the publishing industry would admit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at a time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langston Hughes</ENAMEX> was succeeded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Wright</ENAMEX>, who in turn
was succeeded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baldwin</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, we thought that notion was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disproved</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Walker</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry McMillan</ENAMEX> were
simultaneously on the bestseller list. Then along came <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis "Skip" Gates</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>

            He's the modern-day impresario of black culture, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Carol Oates</ENAMEX> of
black studies, producing with daunting regularity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brown</ENAMEX> used to be
called the hardest-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in show business, but he ain't got nothing on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>.

            Would somebody puh-leeze stop him before he writes again?

            Unlike you, I don't labor in the fields of black culture, and I'm
glad--though as a fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who keeps hearing rumors that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is working
on a novel, I'm constantly checking my rear-view mirror for his headlights. You
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are in an unenviable place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> must seem like he's everywhere. Still
and all, I wonder how much of his work will survive, and whether, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, say, anyone will read anything by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, in the same way we still read
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Souls of Black Folk</ENAMEX> .

            Oh, well. At least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> had the decency not to include himself in his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">encyclopedia</ENAMEX>. Or did I miss that entry?

            I wish he'd left out bell hooks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX>, though, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> prominent
public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> (that's what they call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get paid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of dollars to lecture the rest of us about what we're doing wrong).
There are biographies of both, though, thankfully, we only have to read
about hooks. Not so with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>. He writes a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-page "interpretation" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.E.B. Du Bois</ENAMEX>. (I think what "interpretation" really means is that, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> wants to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> when he grows up.) But why <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levering Lewis</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is an award-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> (not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher manqu√</ENAMEX>©),
and though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> volume has been published, his is already the standard
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX>.

            I suppose the explanation is that when you get to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNIC</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> has, you
reward your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and ignore everyone else. Which would explain why there's
nothing here on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Crouch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Loury</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Sowell</ENAMEX>. I
couldn't even find anything on black conservatism.

            Of course, I'd rather have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africana</ENAMEX> than not, but did they have to be
so slavishly politically correct and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX>? There are at least three
articles on homosexuality, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homosexuality</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>: An
Interpretation" (there's that word again!), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">popularization</ENAMEX> begins on
the box with a blurb from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>. (And I thought he was just a
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and TV huckster.)

            There's an entry on rap music (what an oxymoron!). I suppose you could make
an argument that it's a significant enough phenomenon, so that it deserves to
be here. But what's the rationale for separate biographical entries on Queen
Latifah, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snoop Doggy Dog</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tupac Shakur</ENAMEX>, and a host of other dubious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>? And
what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rupaul</ENAMEX>? Why is he here? I thought he'd already used up his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of fame.

            And what would <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> have made of that ?

            You think black studies has achieved middlebrow status. I'm less sanguine
that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> feel bad when they don't know something about black history
and culture. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years ago</TIMEX>, a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> told me about how her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> let
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> dance to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> record for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> to celebrate Black
History <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Month</TIMEX>. And I wonder whether the choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> here--we're both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX>--doesn't say something that makes me uncomfortable and, well, a little
bit angry.

            We'll be closer when we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>.
Black history--in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, at least--is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. There ought to be
room in the retelling of it for the letters <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Twain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Douglass</ENAMEX>
exchanged, for the similarities between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Invisible Man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben Franklin</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autobiography</ENAMEX> , for the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Chesnutt</ENAMEX> at the banquet to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honor Twain</ENAMEX> shortly before the latter's death, and for the monument in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> who rode with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> irregulars.

            Sadly, I don't find that here,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
