
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Is it OK to stop saying: "Big week in the markets"? But it was. Spurred,
oddly enough, by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> rate hike--it used to be programmatic that stock prices
fell when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> raised rates--the Dow reached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> set new record after new record. Price-to-earnings ratios
are fairly meaningless statistics--since they don't take into account how much
capital <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are using to get their earnings--but if we can use a
meaningless stat, the market's current P/E ratio puts all those that came
before it to shame. Or, alternatively, the market's current P/E ratio makes all
those that came before it look sane. (Those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sentences sound so much alike,
and yet mean such different things.) Of course, the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> reached a deal on a wide-ranging trade agreement is a nice symbolic
statement of part of the reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stocks are so much more valuable today
than they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>. The world, at least in the economic sense, is just
a much bigger and more profitable place. Which doesn't mean you need to eat,
drink, and be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">merry</ENAMEX> tonight. But at the very least, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chat</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> reached a landmark trade
agreement . As part of the deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> agreed to import up to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> films <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> now. An unwritten side
deal ensured that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Message in a Bottle nor Random Hearts</ENAMEX>
would be included in the list."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci</ENAMEX> announced that it won a quiet bidding war for
luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yves Saint Laurent</ENAMEX>. Soon there will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> major
fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the world --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gucci</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LVMH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prada</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armani</ENAMEX>--and
they'll still be competing for the exact same tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard & Poor's</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> had effectively defaulted on
its bonds when it asked current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to swap their old bonds for
new ones. The world's markets returned a unanimous verdict of 'Who
cares?' Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> would have had a
comment, but he decided to wait until he figured out exactly where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
was, and what 'a bond' meant."

            3a. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard & Poor's</ENAMEX> also announced that it was downgrading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National City Corp .</ENAMEX> from a 'hold' to an 'avoid.' Next
for the stock: 'avoid at all costs.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Kinzius</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> phone company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann</ENAMEX> who
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> testified that he was at a meeting where a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman Sachs</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman</ENAMEX> would not help <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vodafone</ENAMEX> launch a
hostile bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannesmann</ENAMEX> , filed a new affidavit saying that
he hadn't been at the meeting. 'I have now had an opportunity to
refresh my memory ,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinzius</ENAMEX> said. 'I was lying the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinzius</ENAMEX> did not add."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> spinoff <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agilent</ENAMEX> went public on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and watched its
stock price jump better than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>. Surprisingly,
Agilent, although a high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, is profitable and has been profitable
for quite some time, and yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> flocked to it . A breath
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sanity</ENAMEX> arrives."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rite-Aid</ENAMEX>, whose stock price has been crushed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX> because of
concerns about accounting irregularities , announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
that long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KPMG</ENAMEX> had resigned as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> because it could
not rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rite-Aid</ENAMEX>'s management to provide accurate numbers .
Let's face it. Here's where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rite-Aid</ENAMEX>'s corporate communications and investor
relations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get a chance to earn their salaries. 'KPMG left because of:
Personality conflict? Health reasons? Utter disgust? ... No, cancel that last
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "Boring headline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'Corning</ENAMEX> said it agreed to
acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Industries</ENAMEX> in a stock transaction valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.8 billion</NUMEX>.'
The really sad thing is that I'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Industries</ENAMEX>' revenue is close to the
price of the transaction. If it were a Net <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> , it'd be,
oh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 or 40</NUMEX> times less."

         
      
   
