
   
   
      
         
            Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatigue Syndrome</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Squeegee Guys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leprous Beggars for Hillary</ENAMEX>! What a campaign slogan. And
the bumper-sticker possibilities. ... It's going to be a great race.

            That's my desperate hope, anyway. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the problems with a presidential
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> is that it starts so early. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Twelve</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to go and I'm already finding
myself blowing past the political stories in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and heading for
the pointless wire roundups at the back. I've always liked the weird stuff
anyway--I probably should have become a night-beat police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>--but
increasingly I've come to see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rockville Teen Set Ablaze</ENAMEX>" as my reward for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slogging</ENAMEX> through "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley Unveils Medicare</ENAMEX> Plan."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s news is a great example. Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is
crowded with eat-your-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peas</ENAMEX>-type stories: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s tax-cut plan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Corning</ENAMEX>
settlement, an earnest feature on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> who work in
chicken-processing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> on the Eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shore</ENAMEX>. There are also pieces on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> riots and the mass graves in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juarez</ENAMEX>--unusually interesting stories for the
A section--but for the really compelling copy you've got to venture inside
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Style</ENAMEX>," where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howie Kurtz</ENAMEX> has an account of a group firing at the New York
Times . The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> tossed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> from one of
its clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norfolk</ENAMEX> for sending "inappropriate and offensive"
e-mails. None of the e-mails in question is reproduced in the story, so it's
not clear precisely what was inappropriate or offensive about them. But there
are a couple of incredibly creepy quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. "If you
receive e-mail that violates our policy," wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> in
a company-wide memo, "please notify your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources</ENAMEX>
in your business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>. We will take prompt action to address the situation."
Translation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rat</ENAMEX> out your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and we'll fire them.

            Or some of them. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine pointed out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, if a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">well-known Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> was caught forwarding an obscene picture to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX>, would he lose his job? No way. But when some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX>-an-hour
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mope</ENAMEX> in the payroll <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norfolk</ENAMEX> does it, he's walking down the road
talking to his lunch box inside of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>.

            Under most circumstances, I wouldn't have a problem with this. Generally, I
think private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> ought to be able to hire and fire whomever they want at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for any reason. And I accept that there is a meaningful difference between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Berke</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who files <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workman</ENAMEX>'s comp forms. On the other hand, the
Times came up with its policy against offensive e-mail as a way to
shield its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> from discrimination and harassment--in other words, as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Guy</ENAMEX> from the abuses of the powerful. And yet here we
have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Guy</ENAMEX> getting shafted for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> that a) in all likelihood
hurt no one, and b) that the powerful could almost certainly commit without
getting fired.

            What we have here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>, is your classic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irony Story</ENAMEX>. And that's what I
really want from my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
