
   
   
      
         
            Who Stole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX>'s <I>Cojones</I>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan Motor Corporation</ENAMEX>, which recently announced a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-month</TIMEX> loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, has been trying to pull itself out of near-bankruptcy with TV ads
featuring its handsome, smooth-talking design <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Hirshberg</ENAMEX>. In a spot
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan Altima</ENAMEX> that's on the air now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> boasts, "Technically
speaking, we gave the car some cojones ." The word "cojones " is
partially bleeped out to emphasize that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> is bravely violating a taboo.
Fleeting images of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Altimas</ENAMEX> go by. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgy</ENAMEX>!

Here's the problem with this ad: Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> has managed
the difficult feat of going broke while making some of the best mass-market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in the world. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About a decade ago</TIMEX>, if I remember right, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> made the
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>, in terms of quality and performance, in practically every
category: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sentra</ENAMEX> was the best small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maxima</ENAMEX> the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX>, the
Pathfinder the best <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SUV</ENAMEX>. Then, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX>'s quality stayed high, sales and
profits somehow plummeted. How did they do it? One word: ugly .*

Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirshberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> produced many of those loser designs, it's odd that he
even kept his job, much less wound up as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> face. It's as if the
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> hired the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> congressional defeat to run his campaign! OK, bad example. But
you get the point.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> has managed to dodge blame for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX>'s decline by letting it be
shifted to his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit News</ENAMEX> recently reported that
"in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, product plans and designs would go from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
and return watered down, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> said." That may have been true for some
models. But for others, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> can't deny paternity. In his own book, The
Creative Priority , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> boasts of producing the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infiniti</ENAMEX>
J30, a car whose massively round, sagging rear end (based, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> says,
on the bottom of a toilet bowl) was like nothing on the road, and nothing many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> wanted to buy. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">J30</NUMEX> was a car desperately trying to make a
pretentious fashion statement, but it galumphed awkwardly in the real world of
tires and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asphalt</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.J. O'Rourke</ENAMEX> once said of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda Prelude</ENAMEX>: It looks good
from the front, it looks good from the back, it looks good from the top and the
sides. It just doesn't look good.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> also claims paternity for the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Altima</ENAMEX>, another radical, droopy-assed design that
performed weakly in the marketplace. "Every time I see somebody driving one of
those," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine, "I feel sorry for them." The current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altima</ENAMEX> retains the original's basic downcast shape--which is why those
images in the current TV ad are so fleeting. This is a vehicle designed to
instantly lower your serotonin level by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>.** The reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> now
has to add "cojones " is that he cut them off in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

P.S.: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirshberg</ENAMEX> was recently hired to help redesign the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times. How will he (to quote his book) "break through the stereotypes and
freely access the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and imagery ... needed for inspiration"? When
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> designed the ill-fated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">J30</TIMEX>, they thought about toilet bowls and
conceived their target <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> as "the perfect asshole!" Times readers
may be in for a special treat.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.P.S.</ENAMEX>: In fairness, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirshberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> did produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> brilliant
design, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gobi</ENAMEX>" pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, which married a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX>-pod <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> to a
simple corrugated-steel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> bin. On the other hand, his recent proposed
revival of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Z</ENAMEX>" sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was a shapeless blob.

            
               * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> also failed to anticipate consumer demand for airbags; for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, many of its best <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were available only with those annoying motorized
seat belts.

               ** I don't want to speculate on the psychosexual meaning of "high-butt"
versus "low-butt" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX>, except to note that a) it's pretty darn obvious;
b) in keeping with a), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> seem to uniformly like the high-rear designs, while
those who like the low-rear look tend to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; c) the low-rear look has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abjectly</ENAMEX> failed in the market--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altima</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the J30</TIMEX>, and the disastrous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
redesign of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> being the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most obvious flops. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> has now
reissued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> with a higher butt, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> probably can't wait to redo
the sad-sack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altima</ENAMEX>. The high-rear form is also functional, improving both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aerodynamics</ENAMEX> and luggage space. The final collapse of the low-rear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was
probably signaled recently when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audi</ENAMEX> was forced to add a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spoiler</ENAMEX>--a raised
wing--to the round, drooping rear of its high-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TT Coupe</ENAMEX>. Without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> tended to become unstable at very high speeds.
            

         
      
   
