
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica Speaks to Today's Woman</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Todd</ENAMEX>:

            OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> is wacky and maybe a little too proud of it. But only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> would even dream of running an item like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in "Page
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX> (the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> )
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Brinkley</ENAMEX> were both seen at the grand opening of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX> in the
Hamptons, "loading up on bargains." I'm keeping my fingers crossed that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> they'll tell us what some of those bargains were. (The smart money is
on giant containers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cheese fish</ENAMEX>.) But the bottom line is that it is nice
just to realize, in a kind of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Are the World</ENAMEX>" sense, as we come upon another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, that there are things that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX> can enjoy doing together.

            There's a great local story on the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> today
that is sure to hit all the big newscasts and the radio talk shows by this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. The female <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year</TIMEX> marriage, "a relationship so close that
they shared an electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">toothbrush</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yuck</ENAMEX>. I hope they only mean the handle
part), apparently filed for a quickie divorce from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 days</TIMEX>
after she was so busy that she forgot to tell him that she won <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">California Lottery</ENAMEX>. Cut to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years later</TIMEX> when her puzzled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, who had no clue as to her motives for leaving the marriage so hastily
(but if he had asked me I would have said "Give a little thought to the area of
dental hygiene"), accidentally intercepted a piece of her mail that mentioned a
few of the lottery details. The upshot is that he took her to court and now a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has ruled that because she "acted out of fraud and malice" when she
"violated state asset disclosure laws" during the divorce proceedings, she must
turn the entire lottery win over to her ex. Ouch, that must sting. She is
claiming the only reason she never mentioned the big lotto win to her once
beloved was due to an "ignorance of the law." You're probably scoffing now, but
I, for one, believe her. There are so many painful emotional and logistical
details surrounding the nightmare of a divorce--the search for good counseling,
the brouhaha about how it will affect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--that no one ever really talks
publicly about the ways in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are often forced to part with a lot of
their money. Now it's out in the open, I guess.

            Elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> ' "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern California Living</ENAMEX>" section,
there was a brief review by "fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s new handbag
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX>. It gave the Web site address, so I couldn't resist spending a little time
there examining photos of her "purses and totes," each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> "adorned with the
unique rose-bordered label that says 'Made especially for you by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>.' "
(Wear it with pride!) Come with me now as we revel in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Garden Patch</ENAMEX>": "a
deep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX> green velvet bag with its outer avocado patch pocket," priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90</NUMEX>. Or luxuriate in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bohemian Baroque</ENAMEX>": "terracotta, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX>, and
maroon chenille tapestry that is reminiscent of an earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>" (I wonder
if she knows which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>). Cost to you the consumer? <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110 and $130</NUMEX>. (But sorry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ladies</ENAMEX>, all sold out!) Apparently, we learn in the Web site text, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> was
breathing life into these masterpieces as she underwent a "reawakening of my
creative senses" during "an almost undendurable time." Which brings us to her
wish for us. "I hope that you recognize the importance of being free spirited
with your creativity," she writes. Making me think that she may have learned
nothing at all from her big ordeal. I'm not sure if the "being free spirited"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angle</ENAMEX> has really worked all that well for her so far.

            Actually my favorite part of the Web site is where she writes (under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Product</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Description</ENAMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> needs both practicality and durability en vogue."
En vogue? Who talks like that? I think what we have here is a rare glimpse of
the "more mature <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>," the one that she used to exercise when she would
offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> her ideas concerning educational reform. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sadly</ENAMEX>, I can't
recall whether those more enlightened policy discussions took place before or
after the usual free-spirited stuff.) And since she brought up the issue of
"practicality," from a practicality standpoint alone it surprised me that all
of her purses are "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dry Clean Only</ENAMEX>." She of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be endorsing a
line of fully washable products. If ever there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who has learned
firsthand about the difficulties of having to drag things to the dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX>,
it would certainly be she. In fact, the least she could do is throw in a bottle
of free stain remover for your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> bucks.

            I'm back to reading more string theory now.

         
      
   
