
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Generals</ENAMEX> and Their Privates

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post leads with a report that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and marijuana seizures in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southwestern U.S.</ENAMEX> and along <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> coast have escalated dramatically
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>. The story states that the increase reflects more
smuggling into this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and also increased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> production in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will sign a bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> permitting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to provide food to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> who've been fighting
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moslem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX>. This would be, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, a
reversal of current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law that prohibits food assistance to combatants
before they demobilize. The move is stirring up fears in and out of government
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is becoming more interventionist and that it is violating a
fundamental principle of international humanitarian assistance--that food
should not be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. The story makes it clear that there is heartfelt
disagreement about this within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> by quoting by name government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> on both sides. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the uncovering by state and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> of "a giant rip-off" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s state-federal program
providing health care to the poor. The scam involved phony storefront medical
supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> being reimbursed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for providing supplies that
never were purchased for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who didn't exist. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the false
claims paid may total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 billion</NUMEX>. So far, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>
have pleaded guilty. Most of those charged, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surnames</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a bullish report on retail sales over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving weekend</TIMEX>. The
Internet sales figures the paper passes along for the period include:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX>--orders up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> times over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads</ENAMEX> is
even fronted by anybody else.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is consistently buttressed by appeal to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, but it could sorely use some independent expert
voices, because it never really comes to grip with the seeming indeterminism of
its data. In other words, the piece suggests that more seizures equals more
production. But it's just as easy to imagine that more seizures equals better
law enforcement vs. the same level of production. And indeed, the WP
further confuses on this point by also claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> opium and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>
production are way up while seizures of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> opium and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> are way
down.

            And does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead really have the current law about food aid
right? If so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> should have explained how it squares with past <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> and for contras against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, or for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> against various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, etc. Are
we to understand that these aid packages didn't include <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>? And is it really
true that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are OK, but not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>? When did this law go into effect?

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the
military, but look at the topic differently. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> emphasizes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> consistently leave the service at higher rates than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
focuses on the difficulties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> have getting to the highest rank--general
and admiral. The closest the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> comes to mentioning the latter is its
26th paragraph, about the special obstacles for women's' military careers posed
by their "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> issues." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> doesn't get to the problem of
asymmetrical attrition until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 21st</TIMEX> graph.

            It seems that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has got hold of a national problem, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story, while interesting, is more of a curio. After all, according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> the difference in the attrition rates for men
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX>, while by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's own lights, there are only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women generals</ENAMEX> or admirals. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story still has some
problems. It waits till its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> paragraph to notice that across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, the gender difference in attrition is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5 percent</NUMEX> and till the
24th paragraph to mention that unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can get pregnant and still get
out of the service with an honorable discharge, and even then never pauses to
wonder how closing this loophole might change the situation.

            Challenge to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> doing stories about trends in the military: Try
doing your next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> without quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Moskos</ENAMEX>, military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern University</ENAMEX>. This is apparently impossible.

            An editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>'s harboring of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX> exemplifies some of the pointlessness of this hidebound genre.
The editorial wraps up thus: "Now that they control most of the national
territory and are responsible for affairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have
to take more seriously their responsibility to rein in terrorism. The new
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has to reevaluate, too. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> has supported the Taliban
as part of its military's longtime reach for an active regional foreign policy.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> needs a quiet policy that will allow it to rebuild at home. So
does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>." Who exactly is this editorial directed at? Does anyone at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, or perhaps bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> himself
will just put down this sterling prose and change?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> has fired a music critic
for lifting a paragraph from a music reference book. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX> recalls
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> also fired an obituary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> for making up
quotes. Which makes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> wonder--Why no official reaction to its item
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> noticing an identical paragraph in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
obituaries of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>? Why are these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> willing to let the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> be the most ethical paper in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
