
   
   
      
         
            <i>Toy Story</i> vs. the Internet

            Did one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toy</ENAMEX>
Story <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> have a bad experience on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>? The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> film articulates a provocative and
long-overdue critique of what is possibly the worst thing about the Internet:
Its tendency to turn everything in meatspace--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> editions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie Babies</ENAMEX>, unopened cans of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Coke</ENAMEX>--into a "collectible." In the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff Woody</ENAMEX>, the cowboy action
figure (voice supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>), turns out to be a valuable relic of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1950s</TIMEX>; he is stolen by an unsavory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX>/toy-store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Knight</ENAMEX>) and sold to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. The other toys from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>'s
room--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz Lightyear</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Allen</ENAMEX>), Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potato Head</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Rickles</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>--arrive
to rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX> before he's shipped overseas. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX> is by then uncertain
whether he prefers a necessarily short shelf life as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s toy to
immortality as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> piece. The dilemma is fairly complex. Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>'s toy
= being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Tom</ENAMEX>. You devote yourself to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> (well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child</ENAMEX>) and for
your troubles end up being outgrown and cast aside. Existentially, though, it's
more satisfying than being an artifact. Being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> piece = reveling in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> identity. That's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX> would be joined in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> by various <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
accessories of which he was previously unaware--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bullseye</ENAMEX>, a
female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sidekick</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Cusack</ENAMEX>), a prospector named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stinky Pete</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelsey Grammar</ENAMEX>) who's never even been out of the box. But are toys really
meant to be gazed at behind glass? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> fudge on the
ethnic-identity question (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX> chooses to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>'s toy and gets the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX> accessories to come with him), but reject unequivocally the creepy
culture of collectibles.

            I don't recall seeing any computers in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toy Story 2</ENAMEX> , and of course the
movie was made with computers. Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of
Pixar, the animation studio
that made both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toy Story</ENAMEX> movies, is quite obviously very fond of computers. Still,
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in our culture is driving the growing obsession with collectibles?
What technology is globalizing the collectibles market--is making it
possible for, say, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to obtain cast-off vintage toys from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>! (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pedants</ENAMEX> will observe that in the movie, the evil toy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thief Al</ENAMEX> actually conducts his communications with the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> via cell
phone and fax machine, but that's just because the filmmakers don't want to be
too overt in challenging the mightiest phenomenon in capitalism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.)

            In a sprightly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> essay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> about collecting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX> noted that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16 th century</TIMEX>
there proliferated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kunst- und Wunderkammern</ENAMEX> , "art and wonder cabinets"
containing curiosities of all kinds:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonderment</ENAMEX> came to be perceived as a kind of middle state between
ignorance and knowledge, and wonder cabinets were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> of the marvelous,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">museums</ENAMEX> of accumulated curiosities, proving God's ingenuity. They contained
whatever was the biggest, the smallest, the rarest, the most exquisite, the
most bizarre, the most grotesque.
               

               Art, astrolabes, armor--man-made wonders--were cheek by jowl with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX>'
teeth and pathological anomalies like human horns. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> had a typical Kunst- und <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wunderkammer</ENAMEX> : he owned paintings by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Durer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cranach</ENAMEX>, a skeleton of a newborn, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> miniature spoons hidden
within a cherry pit, an armband made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elks</ENAMEX>' hoofs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mummies</ENAMEX> and various rare
musical instruments.

            

            Broadly speaking, the Internet is itself a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kunst</ENAMEX>- und
Wunderkammern , but it is also very efficient at helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fill
whatever non-virtual wonder cabinets they have lying around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. This is
in many ways a blessing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is delighted that used-book sites like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bibliofind</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alibris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Book Exchange</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell's Books</ENAMEX> make it possible to retrieve almost any
out-of-print book one might want--usually for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than one</NUMEX> would pay to buy it
in paperback. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is always surprised to see the wares presented in
such artifact-y fashion. On searching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bibliofind</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pappy Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s first
novel, All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right Answers</ENAMEX> , for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> learns that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX>
Mail, a used bookstore in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Mesa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, is ready to sell it to for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX>, provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> doesn't take
offense that it has "writing on front fly." Why would Chatterbox care about a
little writing on the front flyleaf? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pappy Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> novel,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man Who Stole the Mona Lisa</ENAMEX> , can be had for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cousin</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">White Plains</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> It's priced that high
because it's a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> edition and wrapped in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeez, Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can
get a fresh hardcover (it's still in print) for a mere <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22.95</NUMEX>. The point, after
all, is to read the thing, not hang it on the wall. Indeed, first
editions in pristine condition ought to be less valuable than most
books, because it's almost impossible to use them for their intended
purpose--i.e., read them. Who wants to crack the binding of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> piece?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff Woody</ENAMEX> would understand. The Internet doesn't.

         
      
   
