
   
   
      
         
            Every <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LIttle Baby Is a Miracle Straight From God</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Merrill</ENAMEX>,

            Yeah, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> you can get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken waffles</ENAMEX>.

            Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think they have the right to demand that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX> movie
not be seen? It's like some misbegotten bastard stepchild of the civil rights
movement, I guess, but for some reason, everybody's forgetting that just
because you're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> doesn't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX> doesn't have the right to make
fun of you as much as he damn well pleases. As in, he could've made a movie
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fuck You</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX> if he wanted. But since I was recently called a
"callow, superficial, self-obsessed bunny" by one of 
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> (I didn't mind the adjectives, but "bunny" kind of hurt), I guess I
should skip the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moesha</ENAMEX> ruminations and get on to the "grown-up"
news (damn, that means I have to skip the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> feature on the @
symbol!).

            After my psychotic outburst of HMO-vitriol, I almost hesitate to comment on
your remark about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher H. Smith</ENAMEX>, because regarding the deal that was
worked out to impose "anti-abortion" restrictions on international Third World
family planning aid programs as a condition of paying our long-overdue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
debt, I'm on the verge of spinning out into berzerker mode again. Look, its a
free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> (OK, so actually, its a really expensive and not to mention
debt-ridden <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but I digress), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can believe what they want. But
while I respect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right of Iowa Gun-Lobbyists and Southern Fundamentalists</ENAMEX>
Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Respect a Woman's Right To Choose</ENAMEX>, when it comes to global
overpopulation, it's not a matter of some domestic political disagreement, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s sake, you're talking about the whole world.

            The same goes for (speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>) all the medieval doctrinists in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican</ENAMEX> who seem bent on imposing a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-world fertility program on every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underdeveloped</ENAMEX> and uneducated native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> under heaven. As a genuine
honest-to-goodness <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Son of a Preacher Man</ENAMEX>, I feel qualified to say that I don't
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is standing at the gates of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> shouting down "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Send More Dead</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Babies</ENAMEX>!" As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> pointed out simply and clearly in his great
(and much-hated, and banned) book (and film, too, though I haven't seen it) on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Theresa</ENAMEX>, it's one thing to say you have this long-standing religious
belief and tradition and you want to stick to it out of devotion to your faith,
but when you are not only a) blindly encouraging poverty-stricken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> like rabbits, but also b) actively stopping, I mean, going out of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to directly oppose, the efforts of those courageous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who are trying to
make sure those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can get a handful or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> and maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few ounces</NUMEX>
of clean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to wash the parasites out of their underwear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. Then
it's no longer a question of how Every <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Baby Is a Miracle Straight From</ENAMEX>
God. And if your spiritual traditions can't handle such an obvious fact (note:
not religious opinion, but science fact, like as in, you know, math), then you
must be stopped. And, yeah, that goes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, too.

            And I eagerly await your thoughts on the string theory article. I'm not
sure, but I worry that it may conflict with the biblical account of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis</ENAMEX>.

            I love you, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
