
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brainless</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> clashes between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> that delayed the opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> summit and resulted in an
all-night curfew and the calling out of some unarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> to
keep the peace for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s arrival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. The
fronts all feature photos of the cops firing tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>, reminding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>' central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> problem in such
situations: Regardless of the merits, there's no way to look good when you're
armored from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> to toe and shooting stuff at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who are unarmored and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unarmed</ENAMEX>.

            The coverage explains that what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> calls a "guerrilla <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of anti-trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>trade?) started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">massing early in the day</TIMEX>, prompting the
lock-down of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> housing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> and of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">convention center</ENAMEX> where the meetings were supposed to be held. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Stores</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX> then shut down and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> filled the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. The papers
say that most of the protest was nonviolent noncompliance, but also pass along
eyewitness accounts of destruction of property, including that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sacrilege</ENAMEX>, the looting and vandalizing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
shows a moronic dirtball doing just that.) It's reported that much of the
violence was committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in black clothes and ski masks.

            The papers grapple with the sheer diversity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>: people
dressed as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Superman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX>,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> spots <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> First! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> chaining
themselves together and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> calling themselves "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vegan Dykes</ENAMEX>" marching
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">topless</ENAMEX>. Also present were some top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> labor, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honcho</ENAMEX>, and a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX>. The only common thread seemed to be,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> puts it, the view
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is a "handmaiden of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> whose rulings undermine
health, labor and environmental protections around the world." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX>, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , have columns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ridiculing this view.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> protests are undoubtedly an important, perhaps even watershed,
event, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> overshoots when it states: "Not since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> and the civil rights movement has the entire downtown core of a
major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> been seized by a popular political uprising." Well, no ...
actually there was this thing called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> riots. Remember,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ?--your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> got trashed.

            The LAT fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> go inside with new
research uncovering brain damage in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> complaining of the myriad
symptoms collectively known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War Syndrome</ENAMEX>." The finding means,
according to a lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vets</ENAMEX>'
complaints are not the result of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">battlefield stress</ENAMEX>, the conclusion of a
presidential advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Findings</ENAMEX>" section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says secondhand
cigarette smoke may be more dangerous than previously believed: A new study
found that a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with a certain genetic mutation who live
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6 to six</NUMEX> times more likely to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX>. Another
piece of research--based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">366,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (!)--in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Findings</ENAMEX>" is that not
smoking and watching your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> and blood pressure is worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
extra years of life.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> auto business
will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> break a total vehicle sales record that's stood for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX>.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says some auto industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> think the new car market has
broadened permanently. Reasons? The enormous wealth caused by the boom means
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more three</NUMEX>-car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX>. The intersection of rising median income and flat or
falling new car prices hasn't been this favorable since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>
are entering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their 50s</TIMEX>, which are the peak <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>-buying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            The WP profiles a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who took a problem where he
lives--dead deer on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>--and turned it into a solution to a problem
everywhere--poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not having enough to eat. His idea: pick up the road
kill and turn it into venison for the hungry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>, the project has produced <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than 100,000 pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> for
the poor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s business card reads "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Whack 'Em, I Pack 'Em</ENAMEX>." Now, if he
could only make a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> from spent pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray shells</ENAMEX> ...

         
      
   
