
   
   
      
         
            Doesn't Anyone <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Want To Be Famous</ENAMEX>?

            Why doesn't some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> run against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> U.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> primary? After all, a sizable chunk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>, even the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>, can't stand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, and that number is growing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. (In a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siena College</ENAMEX> poll, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 49 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> thought
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was their party's best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. About the same number, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX>,
thought she wasn't.) There is a swarming press corps ready to give an
international platform to whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who does it with some wit and humor will become the repository of
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' hopes and fears and reap a huge bonanza of favorable
publicity.

            You wouldn't even have to raise money for campaign ads: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> will do
most of the work for free. You could even make a point of running a shoestring
campaign against the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> leviathan. Since Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
herself appears to have no sense of humor, plus an intense sense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entitlement</ENAMEX>, plus a ham-handed campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, she'll make an ideal
target--big, slow-moving, profusely bleeding.

            True, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s absurd election laws, it's hard to get on the
ballot unless you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX> of the party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. But that issue
could easily be turned against the anointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>
want to keep poor candidate <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> off the ballot," etc. It's also true that whoever
runs against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> would infuriate that same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party establishment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gregg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birnbaum</ENAMEX>, a well-informed political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ,
knows of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who was thinking of running
but was then "leaned on by powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX>."

            Maybe a career <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX> would not want to risk angering party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
not to mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> (though he'll be out of office in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>). But if there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assemblyman</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> ready to
become an instant household name, what about everyone else? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Businessmen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>--even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>! Who wants to be famous? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Siegel</ENAMEX>--think of the
boost this will give your lecture fees! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Shapiro</ENAMEX>, come on down! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Silver</ENAMEX>--here's your big part! An obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Unz</ENAMEX> is now a
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> because (in part) he ran against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of his
party, then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Wilson</ENAMEX>.

            And think of the upside: While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> would probably beat any primary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unz</ENAMEX>, there's a chance she'll abandon the race
entirely if she doesn't have a clear field (something she may do anyway). That
would leave you, Mr. or Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambitious Democrat</ENAMEX>, as the giant-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>. Then, if
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>, deprived of the chance to beat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> himself, opts out of the race, it would leave you with a clear shot at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>!

            The worst that happens is you get a ton of name recognition. This is, as
they say, low-hanging fruit. Who will grab it?

         
      
   
