
   
   
      
         
            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Censor</ENAMEX> <i>The Insider</i>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Insider</ENAMEX> , the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Al Pacino</ENAMEX> film about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> , is a pretty good movie. Much of the story is
fictionalized, of course--intentionally in most instances, unintentionally in a
few others, like when a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> played by Debi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazar</ENAMEX> makes a terrible hash of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milo Geyelin</ENAMEX>," the name of a Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> on the tobacco beat.*

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is willing to believe that the deliberate changes made to
the tobacco story in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Insider</ENAMEX> were done in the interest of making it
a better movie. (Whether fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> should be permitted to keep the
names of real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX>," or real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, like "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX>," is another matter, but one
that has been amply discussed elsewhere.) Still, there's one change to
the story that left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wondering whether the pressures were more
corporate than dramatic : the omission of any mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day One</ENAMEX> broadcast alleging that cigarette
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> were spiking their products with additional nicotine, the stuff
that makes cigarettes addictive.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> things ought to be remembered about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day One</ENAMEX> broadcast:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Bogdanich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Martin</ENAMEX> became the first
to break the important story that tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were manipulating the
degree to which cigarettes pumped nicotine into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>' bloodstreams. In
addition to making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> look even more corrupt than was previously
believed, this made it more difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> to say that it wasn't in
the drug business--a claim it was using to avoid regulation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>.

               The term "spiking" turned out to be ever-so-slightly inaccurate, because
the nicotine put into the cigarettes had been taken out earlier in the
manufacturing process; the way tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were boosting the nicotine hit
was actually more complicated than that and involved the addition of ammonia.
(If you want to know more, click here to
read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s findings on the matter.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> filed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> libel suit-- the biggest libel suit in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history --against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> over the broadcast. Despite the essential
triviality of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day One</ENAMEX> 's error, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>--possibly under pressure
connected to its pending takeover by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>--chose to settle the libel suit for
a reported <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> and to issue an apology.* * This prompted widespread
disgust among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, who viewed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s move as a sellout. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogdanich</ENAMEX>, who
never conceded that his broadcast was in error at all about "spiking,"
refused to sign the apology.)

            

            
               The Insider leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> with the impression that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wigand</ENAMEX> who
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that the tobacco industry was fine-tuning the way cigarettes
delivered nicotine to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. In fact, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogdanich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>. ( The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alix Freedman</ENAMEX> subsequently published a fuller account
that also predated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX>.) In the scenes in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX>
agonize over whether to cave in to corporate pressure not to broadcast their
Wigand piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Insider</ENAMEX> neglects to alert <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to the likelihood
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> lawsuit is weighing heavily on their minds. (At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, as at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>,
the pressure to surrender seemed linked to a pending sale of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>.) And
The Insider never shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wigand</ENAMEX> himself became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> on the libel suit.

            It's certainly possible these omissions were made because including them
would have made the plot less tidy. But <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Insider</ENAMEX> is a movie that asks
you to think hard about how corporate interests affect what media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do. As it happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Insider</ENAMEX> was made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Touchstone</ENAMEX>, which
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disney</ENAMEX>! Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> demand the film not
include any material that might remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s cheesy surrender to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> posed the question to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell Bergman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>
producer (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacino</ENAMEX> in the film) who fought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s initial decision not
to air the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX> interview for fear of being sued. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX> (who now
works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frontline</ENAMEX> and teaches journalism at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>) was a paid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to the film. "As far as I know, there was no pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
of any kind," he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX> said that an early version of the
script did allude to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day One</ENAMEX> broadcast, but it was cut out.
"If you look closer in the credits," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergman</ENAMEX> said, "you will see there is a set
of acknowledgements that includes all the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day One</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergman</ENAMEX> says
he was the one who urged the film's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Mann</ENAMEX>, to include this tip
of the hat to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogdanich and Co.</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford Douglas</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>, has lately
published letters in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Science Monitor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> touting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogdanich</ENAMEX>-- not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergman</ENAMEX>--as the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who "lit the fuse
of public outrage" over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. As it happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogdanich</ENAMEX> is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> for
... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> ! <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX>' letters appeared, a
pronouncement quite similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX>' emanated from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archerd</ENAMEX>'s column in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> (click here to read the whole thing):

            

               
                  The real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> of "the tobacco wars" is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell Bergman</ENAMEX>, but
it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Bogdanich</ENAMEX>, now of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> , who did the "tobacco wars"
work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> news. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogdanich</ENAMEX> refused to apologize--and came to work for
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> .
               

            

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewitt</ENAMEX> neglected to point out, of course, is that apologizing for a
perfectly good piece of journalism is not so great a sin as preventing that
piece of journalism from coming to light in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. But the question
of why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s movie eliminated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogdanich</ENAMEX> from its narrative remains an
intriguing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was himself at the time a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
on the tobacco beat, and could gripe about how <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Insider</ENAMEX> didn't even
trouble itself to mis pronounce his own name. But the narrative doesn't
really dwell on the tobacco rulemaking process at the 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>
               , which was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s
piece of the story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will simply observe that the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> film
epic derived from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> 's fine print has yet to be realized.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">**</ENAMEX> "We now agree that we should not have reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX> [which had also sued] add significant amounts of nicotine from
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. That was a mistake that was not deliberate on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
but for which we accept responsibility and which requires correction. We
apologize to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX>.''
            

         
      
   
