
   
   
      
         
            Dubya, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the budget agreement. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> race. Issue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>.

            In his first weekend talk show appearance--on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> touches on foreign policy, health care, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, and sex education, among other issues. On foreign policy, he says
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> invasions would not have happened under his watch.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> reminds him that his father initiated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>
intervention, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX> simply reasserts that he will not intervene on humanitarian
grounds, except in rare circumstances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> goes out of his way to emphasize the
need for a "theater anti-missile defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>"--both for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>.
He downplays the importance of arms control, stressing instead the need for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">non-proliferation</ENAMEX>, anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>, and the safe storage of existing
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. He pledges to increase military salaries and military R&D
budgets. Asked if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is too supportive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> replies cryptically, "That's going to be an
interesting debate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> campaign if I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>, let me just put it
to you that way. We'll find out about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> and the [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and the relationship they have."

            On health care, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> supports allowing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> to sue her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> if an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review board</ENAMEX> has decided that she has a reasonable dispute. (This
position is more lawsuit-friendly than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.) Asked about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX> indicates a willingness to raise the current
benefit-receiving age. (Responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> transforming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> into
"personal savings accounts," which would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to choose their own
retirement age.) When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX> reads a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> quote advocating that sex
education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> promote fondling and mutual masturbation as an
alternative to sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s advice is "pathetic," says condom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promotion</ENAMEX> hasn't decreased teen pregnancy rates, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> teaching
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abstinence</ENAMEX>.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> )--think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> caved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on important budget
issues, like tax cuts and across-the-board spending cuts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) notes that spending in this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s budget has grown at twice the rate of inflation since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. But
some, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reined</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s spending requests, kept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
funds intact, and prevented the subsidization of international abortion
providers through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> continue to be pessimistic about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s chances
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) says
her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> needs a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Carville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> to rev things up, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) says she has an uphill battle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) says that focus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> show that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> wish
there were different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> running. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> will
drop out of the race and wonders how she'll ever be able to run for president
if she can't win <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. But several shows flash the results of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> poll
showing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> points behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> )
notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> points behind--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> before the election in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
state--is not exactly the kiss of death. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Torricelli</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> has "raised more funds than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in the nation
other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week and Late Edition</ENAMEX> review a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> campaign
commercial in which W. pledges to "restore dignity" to the presidency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> notes that the message is not just anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but also aimed at
stealing some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s patriotic thunder. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late</ENAMEX>
Edition ) thinks that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is alluding to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s history of honorable
public service.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pseudo</ENAMEX>-Events
            

            Television news conventions are already silly enough--the intrepid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correspondent</ENAMEX> shouting into the camera from underneath swaying <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> during a
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">hurricane</ENAMEX>, the sober <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> standing in front of a coastline after a plane
crashes at sea, and so on. But location-specific reporting reached a new high
(or low) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> . After mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>
interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> announces, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correspondent Kelly Wallace</ENAMEX> was watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, and she joins us now."
Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> hiding in the shadows of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>, hoping that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> wouldn't notice her intruding on their exclusive? Of course not. She,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blitzer</ENAMEX> and every other armchair pundit, watched the interview on
television. This "on-location" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> read her story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
interview from ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> briefing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Late Edition</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> are also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, but never mind.)

            

               Last Word
            

            

               Oh, probably not, [because] it would create a huge political scene. I am
someone who is a uniter, not a divider. I don't believe in group
thinking--pitting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> against another. All that does is create
a huge political nightmare for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

               

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ), asked if he would follow in the
footsteps of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and visit a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gay-rights group</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Log Cabin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>

               

            

         
      
   
