
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teflon Candidate</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>:

            If you figure out who buys which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> for what reason, I will pay you
cash money to tell me. This is a question I mull over and over because it's
part of my job to answer it--to try and figure out how to please the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX> or
so kind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who (hopefully) buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Monthly</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX> each
month without mortally offending the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275,000 or so</NUMEX> who subscribe. It's no easy
task. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Bird Johnson</ENAMEX> sells, the next she doesn't; or rather, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> we spin a story about her (icon in repose) works, but another way
(long-suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a serial philanderer) doesn't. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Authentic Texan Matthew</ENAMEX>
McConaughey on the cusp of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunkdom</ENAMEX> dies an agonizing newsstand death, but
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> transplant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bullock</ENAMEX> is huge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Aikman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armani</ENAMEX> scores,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> in a cowboy hat whiffs. Not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, the Ricky
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> of presidential politics, is a guaranteed winner. When he was running
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, he sold OK (a nice cover line, though: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Son of a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>"). When he was first exploring the possibility of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> bid in the
summer of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'98</NUMEX>, he did worse, actually, than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past June</TIMEX>,
when we did our comprehensive, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-segment story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, it was one of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best sellers. Most of those extra copies were probably sold to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Fineman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Balz</ENAMEX>, and their national press corps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX>, but we'll
take it. Their money's green.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is apparently a hot ticket on TV, too. The ratings for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91 percent</NUMEX> higher than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie 's</ENAMEX> on the day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Russert</ENAMEX> flew to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and interviewed the guv at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>. A cynical part
of me wants to believe that one of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> tuned in hoping to see a
gaffe, but not even the now-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> pop quiz--the You're No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kennedy</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign--has slowed the juggernaut. (I'm duty-bound to point out, by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s answers--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>--may inadvertently tell us something
about him: He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dukes of Hazzard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>.) Everyone covering the race is
looking for a comparison point for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, and I've decided it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>: amiable,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genial</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of broad principles instead of specific policies, and
blessed with good fortune and an utter coating of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teflon</ENAMEX>. For instance: Thanks
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay H. Hatfield</ENAMEX>, no one talks about his druggie past anymore. The story was
always going to be hard to prove, but the burden got damn near impossible when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortunate Son</ENAMEX> 's thoroughly implausible afterword withered under the
slightest cross-examination. Now anyone who hopes to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> stands for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasted</ENAMEX> is going to have to invent a time machine, take
us back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chateau Bijon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, and put us in the physical presence of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bombastic Bushkin</ENAMEX> with a spoon up his nose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotsa Ruck</ENAMEX>.

            I don't know about you, but I've always thought the potential peril for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
wasn't "younger, wilder" but "older, milder"--that is, he's not nearly as
conservative as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> would like to believe. Everything to this point had
confirmed that sense: his softish stance on abortion, his attacks on the
congressional right, his compassion rap. And then he goes to refuses to meet
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Log Cabin Republicans</ENAMEX>. I thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX> had him dead to rights
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . Why shouldn't he meet with them? What's the harm?
Maybe, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> says, he'd do it if they called it a fund-raiser. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> we know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> I know--has too much class to snub anybody,
ideology aside. A longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confrere</ENAMEX> of his from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>, a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, called me
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in despair, dumbstruck by the decision. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bullock</ENAMEX>--who as state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comptroller</ENAMEX> and lieutenant governor brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">browns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> into the white-male <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--were alive,
he'd give him hell. The rest of us should too.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Evan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
