
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gay Friends</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>:

            I think you need to take another look at the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>. If they're "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>" it's only because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s
holding out on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>. He wants to seal the deal. Badly. It's obvious. I admit
I've never seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan Lane TV</ENAMEX> version, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and I just finished the
unabridged, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300-plus</NUMEX>-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> collection <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. After a deep
reading of the text I can tell you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> is one of the more aggressively
hetero hippos in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> literature.

            Take the scene (I believe it's in Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> gets
caught peeping in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s window as she takes a bath. Or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> establishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Fan Club</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> is forever
giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Martha flowers</ENAMEX>, holding her hand, gazing into her eyes. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point he
has his missing front tooth replaced with a gold one in tribute to her. There
is, I concede, a somewhat confusing interlude where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> takes up modern
dance. But it is only as a means to woo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>. And as I recall he wears a
sombrero with his leotard.

            In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> isn't gay (not that there's anything wrong with that). But
if it's gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> you're searching for, look no further
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babar</ENAMEX> series. I, for one, am convinced that there's a good reason the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Lady</ENAMEX> is a lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spinster</ENAMEX>. Others (my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>) disagree, so let's not even
argue that point. Instead, I suggest you get to know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bouver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picardee</ENAMEX>, the
unmarried middle-aged male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babar</ENAMEX>'s who rescue his youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
when she becomes lost on a family picnic. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> live together in a
suspiciously well-decorated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> on a lake outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celesteville</ENAMEX>. They're into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">yoga</ENAMEX>. They wear turtlenecks. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them may even have a trim mustache.
(Unfortunately, the book is in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and she's asleep, so I can't
check.) They look like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> versions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village People</ENAMEX>. They're very,
very gay.

            I suspect they'd be ever gayer in a television version, but I wouldn't know
because--here's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bombshell</ENAMEX>--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have never watched TV. Every time I
admit that (which isn't very often), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> give me the "Oh, so you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davidian</ENAMEX>" look, like it's deeply weird to shield your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from television.
Maybe it is, but they don't know it yet (our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 and 6 months</TIMEX>; our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son</ENAMEX> is almost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), and we plan to keep the streak going until they do. At some
point some nasty little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is going to mock them for not knowing
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pok√</ENAMEX>©mon is and we'll have to crumble and introduce them to cartoons and
action-figure ads and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School House Rock</ENAMEX>" and all the rest. But I don't want
to. They're so happy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Scarry</ENAMEX> and crayons. I don't want them to join
the consumer culture. That will mean they're getting older. And that makes me
sad.

            Also--and here I'm going to sound like a real crank--I don't want them to
develop the same distorted attitudes about television that everyone else seems
to have. Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> example: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> ran an obit with the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel Frederick</ENAMEX> Dies at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>." I saw it and thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hmmm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel Frederick</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel Frederick</ENAMEX>. The name sounds familiar. Must be some long-forgotten civil
rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Bates</ENAMEX>' perhaps. Then I read the story.

            As it turns out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel Frederick</ENAMEX>'s obituary had nothing to do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orval</ENAMEX> Faubus
and everything to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>. According to the story, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day in 1969</TIMEX>, while
shopping in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX> accidentally walked into the view
of a camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> shooting the opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mary Tyler Moore Show</ENAMEX> and
was captured on film. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years after</TIMEX>, she could be seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> looking
confused as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Tyler Moore</ENAMEX> tossed her beret into the air.

            That was it, the whole reason for the obit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> never even mentioned what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel Frederick</ENAMEX> had done with her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">91 years</TIMEX>, only that for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second and a half</TIMEX>
she was seen in the background of the opening scene of a television show
(wearing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> noted, "a green coat with fur collar and matching scarf.") Her
life was significant only to the extent it had been televised. "She never got a
big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> about it," said her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. I'm surprised she didn't.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
