
   
   
      
         
            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Orthodontist Immortalized</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Simpson</ENAMEX>!

            
               "Open a little wider, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spritzer</ENAMEX> said. He looked even better
than he had at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> sale. His good face seemed to pop out of the
tight-necked green smock.
            

            "So, how did you survive your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>?" he asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> over my head.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ours</ENAMEX> was very tasty, actually."

            "Let's see here." He moved something suspiciously like a pliers in my mouth.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, it looks like she's going to need some braces for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da</ENAMEX> teef, I'm
afraid."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Simpson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anywhere But Here</ENAMEX>
               

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three decades</TIMEX> after enduring one of the more agonizing rituals of
adolescence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has no difficulty recognizing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Spritzer</ENAMEX>--the
vaguely caddish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodontist</ENAMEX> who seduces and abandons Adele
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX> in the just-released
movie)--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s own orthodontist. By this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't mean
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s novel captures certain universal truths about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hills</ENAMEX> orthodontists. Rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> captures one
specific <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> orthodontist, named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Seltzer</ENAMEX>, who straightened
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s teeth during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            
               Anywhere But Here is, of course, a novel (and a very good one; the
movie is only so-so). That said, it should be noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>, like most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who create works of the imagination, has been suspected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> of
drawing on the lives of real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Her mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanne Simpson</ENAMEX>, is widely
assumed to be a prototype for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Adele August</TIMEX>, the exuberantly selfish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in
Anywhere But Here ; her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX>, is
similarly thought to be a prototype for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Owens</ENAMEX>, the biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> in her
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Regular Guy</ENAMEX> . (To read an ambivalent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
Advocate article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s niece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Brennan-Jobs</ENAMEX>, about her own
story's being appropriated in the latter work, click here.)

            Not even the tiniest of the small literary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, however, has likely
given any consideration to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s apparent use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Seltzer</ENAMEX> as a
prototype for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Spritzer</ENAMEX>. Here is how, in the novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adele August</ENAMEX>
describes to her teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX> her first date with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spritzer</ENAMEX> (the
scene in the movie is nearly identical):

            

               
                  "He did something last night that grown-ups do sometimes that show you
really, really care about someone."
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What?</ENAMEX>"

               "Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, it's something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> do in bed. But not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ever do it.
It means you really, really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. You'll know when you're older. It
just means they're really, really serious about you. They wouldn't do it with
just any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>."

            

            But a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann</ENAMEX> overhears her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> talking on the phone to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spritzer</ENAMEX>, and

            

               
                  I could tell from the way her voice rose in waves of enthusiasm--too much
music, nerve and light--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Spritzer</ENAMEX> didn't want to be listening. Her
breath gathered as she began each sentence.
               

            

            A few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> after that, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adele</ENAMEX> is taking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann</ENAMEX> on rides past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spritzer</ENAMEX>'s
apartment and saying things like "I'd like to tell his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> a thing or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>." A few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> after that, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann</ENAMEX> observes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Spritzer</ENAMEX> seemed to be
dropping my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>." And a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> after that, he does. (In the movie, Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Spritzer</ENAMEX> hangs up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adele</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> after their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> because she tells
him she loves him.)

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spritzer</ENAMEX>'s reluctance to get enmeshed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Adele</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>'s life is
presented in both book and movie as entirely rational, given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adele</ENAMEX>'s extreme
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neediness</ENAMEX>, both emotional and financial--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann</ENAMEX> can't wait to be old enough to
leave home--there is also the sense, in both the book and the movie, that Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spritzer</ENAMEX> is a little bit of a jerk. Since first encountering the novel a dozen
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has assumed the sexual relationship in the book was
entirely made up, but nevertheless has wondered how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seltzer</ENAMEX> felt about
being portrayed as a love-'em-and-leave-'em '70s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swinger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> figured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seltzer</ENAMEX> would be flattered to be described in the book as handsome, and
even more flattered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunky</ENAMEX> portrayal of him in the movie by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart Bochner</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> also figured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seltzer</ENAMEX> would
consider the moral dimension of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spritzer</ENAMEX> character somewhat wanting.
Here was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who'd devoted his life to making crooked things
straight . Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> taking something straight --the uprightness
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Seltzer</ENAMEX>--and making it crooked ? The more he thought about
it, the more it seemed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seltzer</ENAMEX>, no less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brennan-Jobs</ENAMEX>, had a right to tell his side of the story.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after seeing the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> excitedly rang up Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seltzer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, where, according to the phone book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seltzer</ENAMEX> was still
straightening teeth on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wilshire Boulevard</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receptionist</ENAMEX> who answered
announced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> as that of another orthodontist named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph Cannon</ENAMEX>. Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seltzer</ENAMEX>, she explained, had passed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine years ago</TIMEX>--possibly not
even aware of the literary fame that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> had foisted upon him.

         
      
   
