
   
   
      
         
            Carpal Diem

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s expected
introduction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of safety rules designed to counter repetitive stress
injuries in the workplace, like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carpal tunnel syndrome</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
lead notes how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will be spending the first installment of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$206</NUMEX>
billion they'll receive in settlements with the tobacco industry. Most of the
initial <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 billion</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, will be going to health care, but much
will also be spent on completely unrelated areas, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX>, farm
aid, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. The story quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of state legal
action against tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX>,
as deploring this diversion of funds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a snapshot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s current political
sentiment, based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> (including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">370</NUMEX> who aren't registered to
vote--who cares what they think?). The polling's takeaway: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voters</ENAMEX> would prefer
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">survey</ENAMEX>'s presidential tally is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent to 40 percent</NUMEX>), a
stance the paper summarizes as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> are good, so throw the bums out."

            The big type over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA OFFERS STANDARD</ENAMEX> TO FIGHT
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">INJURIES IN WORKPLACE"</ENAMEX>--is clearer than the big type over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">AFTER LONG DELAY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S</ENAMEX> PLANS TO ISSUE ERGONOMIC RULES." But with
that exception, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> effort is the better story. For instance, what does the WP mean with this first
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to require many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to provide work spaces and equipment
to support the physical makeup of each individual doing his job."? And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> uses its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> paragraph to cite bottom-line-based business
resistance to the rules as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> cause in their delay, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> doesn't get to this until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 13th</TIMEX>. And while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> quotes
somebody from something called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Distributors International</ENAMEX> as its source
for the bottom-line worry, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> goes instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Administration</ENAMEX>, which the paper explains, is an independent government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>.

            Moreover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has the clearest statement of the dimension of
the problem being addressed: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> injured this way on the job each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. (A puzzle arising from reading the stories together: Although the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> doesn't give the injury total, it says the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> would prevent
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> injuries. Can it really be true that fully half of these injuries are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unpreventable</ENAMEX>?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is alone in fronting the news that according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>,
serious crime continues to plummet--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of 1999</TIMEX>. The story
makes the point that the falling crime rate helps police fight crime: lighter
caseloads mean more cops on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that a class action lawsuit will be filed today
on behalf of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> used its monopoly
on operating systems to overcharge for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Windows 95 and Windows 98</ENAMEX>. The paper
says that this sort of lawsuit could ultimately be more of a threat to the
company than suits brought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, potentially costing it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>,
even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> gave a live interview on TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press ) and what is most important about what he said depends on which
paper you read. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> emphasizes his praise for what the paper calls
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most consistently conservative and antiabortion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jurists</ENAMEX>," while refusing to say what he thought about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David H. Souter</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> starts off with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s profession of opposition to most
abortions but then immediately cites his remark that in his presidency an
anti-abortion stance would not be the principal consideration for appointment
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> leads instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GWB</ENAMEX>'s statement of
his commitment to an overhaul of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
story doesn't mention abortion.

            The WP passes along the results of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> online poll
soliciting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' opinions about the most evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of all time: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> had to write him in), after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX> but
ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josef Mengele</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, also a write-in,
finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>.

            Evidence of just how overpaid college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> are at even "legitimate"
programs can be garnered from this straight-faced item in the real estate
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s LAT : "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Lavin</ENAMEX> has
purchased a newly built custom <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marina del Rey</ENAMEX> for close to its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5</NUMEX>
million asking price."

         
      
   
