
   
   
      
         
            Advertising for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dummies</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the more remarked-upon trends in modern (actually, postmodern ,
I guess) advertising is the reliance upon anti-ads, those commercials that
acknowledge the basic insincerity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adman</ENAMEX>'s project and which presumably
please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> by nudge-nudge, wink-winking them in a way that recognizes how
phenomenally aware we are of advertising's attempts to ensnare us. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprite</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thirst Is Everything</ENAMEX>" campaign, with its faux pop songs touting the drink's
magical powers, is the most obvious example, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> it feels as if we're
all living in the world The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monkees</ENAMEX> made.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The past few months</TIMEX>, though, have given us an entirely new--and relatively
unremarked-upon--advertising trend, which might be called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are
dumb as a post" phenomenon. The campaign for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Single One Rate</ENAMEX>" plan
thus features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Reiser</ENAMEX> going around talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about how now every
long-distance call they make with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just 7 cents</NUMEX> a minute,
while those he talks to react with a mix of befuddlement and incredulity,
peppering him with questions that show that they just don't get what
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7-cents</NUMEX>-a<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX> really means.

            Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX>'s new radio campaign for its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cini-Minis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> on an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX> trying to explain that Cini-Minis cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just 99 cents</NUMEX> to a group of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ask questions like, "If I had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 cents</NUMEX>, could I get a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cini-Mini?</ENAMEX>"
And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX>'s utterly bizarre television ads for its new pricing
structure/Internet strategy all feature <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> who just can't quite
understand what this whole newfangled approach is going to mean, like the guy
who tells his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> how much he'll miss her, even as she assures him that
she'll still be around.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> campaign is by far the strangest exemplar of the trend, since
what the ads--which include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in which confused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> quiz a panel of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> at a kind of town meeting--actually point out is both how dubious
the whole brokerage business was to begin with and how potentially
damaging the new pricing structure (which includes much lower commissions) will
be to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>'s bottom line. But the principle in all these campaigns is the
same: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is offering something incredibly simple and straightforward,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> just can't see it.

            I think it makes sense to ask whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really like being told how
obtuse they are, because even if the ads work on some level to inculcate a
sense of superiority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>--as in "These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> don't know what
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7-cents</NUMEX>-a<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every-day</TIMEX> means, but I sure do! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha, ha</NUMEX>!"--on a deeper
level we are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> Reiser and those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are talking to, and think
of how troubling it is to be told that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Reiser</ENAMEX> understands something you
don't. So this aspect of the ads is genuinely perplexing. Usually, aspirational
advertising doesn't include not being stupid as one of the aspirations it's
meant to inspire.

            But there is something else going on in these ads, which is that they're
essentially a kind of reaction against data smog. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in these ads have
been confused by complicated pricing plans and service agreements with strange
restrictions. They've been trained to think that everything will be difficult
and tricky. They're unable to see the purity of "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7 cents</NUMEX> a minute" even when
it's right in front of them. And in some way the ads are saying that simplicity
is disorienting because we're too comfortable with complexity. It's like
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Morning in America</ENAMEX>" all over again.

            The problem is that this message is so simple that you can only hear it a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of times before it becomes intolerable. I'm happy to watch ads that
remind me of my knowingness, if they're clever. But there's no way to do the
"It's so simple it's baffling" ads cleverly, because the whole point of the ads
is that cleverness itself is bad. (This is partly why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> ads, which
seem to want to be clever, end up seeming weirdly self-defeating.) And that
would seem to mean that this trend will be short-lived. Then again, Touched
by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angel</ENAMEX> is a Top-10 show. So who knows?

         
      
   
