
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revenge of the Elderly Black Grandmother-Tang Clan</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Merrill</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greetings</ENAMEX> and salutations once again from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s (after
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tex.</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">City of Slack</ENAMEX>. As difficult as this may be for you to
believe, I'm actually finding myself jealous of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winkie, et al.</ENAMEX>, and
wishing I had my own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-dog-strong <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:15</TIMEX> wake-up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> of bounding,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tail</ENAMEX>-wagging <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">quadrupeds</ENAMEX> to help me out here. A creeping fear worries me that,
being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who normally thinks of breakfast as something you get at a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> waffle place after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> close, perhaps I'm just not cut out for the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">whole pithy-morning</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">punditry</NUMEX>-duties thing. Now I feel like I know firsthand
just how awful it must be for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to greet each new dawn with the
heart-wrenching realization that they are neoconservative MSNBC talk-show host
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Ingraham</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Llama</ENAMEX> must be feeling particularly serene <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> with the
news that, after a marathon negotiation session of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 th -hour</TIMEX>
meetings, the way is finally paved for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>. Everybody seems really happy about this, since it came through at
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last minute</TIMEX> despite longtime stumbling blocks in the way of such an
agreement. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> threatened to electrocute their testicles and beat
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> black and blue if they couldn't push the agreement through?
Let's hear it for effective diplomacy.

            You mentioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about being filled with repellent hatred and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loathing</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> again the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-page</ENAMEX> pieces on how utterly stupid and pathetic and evil and beneath the
dignity of any halfway civilized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> (OK, so they didn't necessarily
use those exact words) the whole "managed" health-care system is. To me, this
is like running a front-page article on how "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everybody's Breathing Air This</ENAMEX>
Fall TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Season</TIMEX>," or the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Still Following Day</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Record</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Umpteenth Gazillion Straight Week</ENAMEX>." I realize this is hardly an insightful
observation on my part; after all, the same point has been made by any number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> before me, including my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who works at the liquor
store down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, and virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> who lives in an even
remotely <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but nonetheless whenever I think about this I
just want to hit an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with a rock until it dies.
Then there's the added insult to untreated <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> waiting-room injury of having to
watch these Satanic sentimental TV spots for various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, featuring grainy
handheld pseudo-documentary sepia-tone footage of some hypothetical
multi-ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer base</ENAMEX> (elderly black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> on rocking chairs with
blankets draped over their knees and beaming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Asian-American 6-year-olds</TIMEX> on
swing sets always seem to make an appearance) while muted piano music plays and
some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> faux-gospel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vocalist</ENAMEX> breathily intones the company
slogan/musical sound bite, informing us all "(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insert Name</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> here) ... We
care about yooouuu ..." I mean, why not just come right out and sing, "We're
lying ... and we're not even trying to hide that fact from yooouuu ..." and be
done with it? Who are they fooling, do they think? It's like the spots were
produced by some Orwellian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of Information</ENAMEX>. I wish that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Dirty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bastard</ENAMEX> and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wu-Tang Clan</ENAMEX> had celebrated his birthday by
mobilizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of all those elderly black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> to start
snapping some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> ad-exec necks.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I'm becoming consumed by bile here, so I think I'd better go hose myself
down or something. Oh, and regarding your last letter's comment about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pinning Bradley</ENAMEX> to the floor and lying on top of him, its a good idea, but
somehow I don't think it'd work, because that's obviously what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper</ENAMEX>'s been
doing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX> herself since their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> teen-age (but presumably non-rock 'n'
roll concert) date.

            From hell,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
