
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> POW Wow

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with how business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> view the
just-concluded session of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Very enthusiastically, says the paper, in a
story running under a brutal headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONGRESS LEAVES BUSINESS LOBBIES ALMOST</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALL SMILES</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with a sum-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
investigation into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">990</ENAMEX>--an effort that by now involves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a mushrooming source of medical inflation--the rising cost of
prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> advertised on television--which are typically at least
twice as expensive as older, over-the-counter, unadvertised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. The
paper explains that since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> decision to permit prescription drug
TV commercials, average prescription costs have climbed at more than double the
general inflation rate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with a nonpartisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s
recently compiled figures indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> has a fund-raising lead
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, and is also
leading the money race in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, the two earliest primary
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , congressional victories for the business
lobby <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX> included: repeal of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX> laws preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>,
securities <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> from entering one another's line of
business, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> extension of the business R&D tax credit, no increase
in the minimum wage, no regulation of health-care plans, no campaign finance
reform, and no ban on agribusiness mergers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says business's
"knockout"legislative feat was a triumph over the trial lawyers: passage of a
law limiting Y2K lawsuits.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s willingness to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX>
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s accident investigation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>) remain for the time being in
charge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> investigation, rather than officially ratcheting it up
into an up-front criminal probe, has a payoff: It placates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, who therefore have been more cooperative in sharing flight and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personnel</ENAMEX> records with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>, which outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has no power to seize
evidence. Also, shades of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> who didn't bark, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reveals
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are paying close attention to what the praying co-pilot
didn't say: "There was no shocked expletive or puzzled comment, as pilots
typically make in an emergency or when highly computerized aircraft suddenly
take action without pilot input."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front stories about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">self-proclaimed Republic of Somaliland</ENAMEX>, which broke off from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> to escape the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> fighting between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlords</ENAMEX> there. The papers report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Somaliland</ENAMEX> has indeed accomplished its goal of becoming a peaceful enclave, but
needs foreign cash if it is to actually become an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. This at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> when the developed world is spending less and less on foreign aid.

            An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> item by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> reports that in an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> radio
ad making the rounds, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> chatting about health care are not the
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> they seem to be, but are actresses reading from a script. Why is
this news? Hasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> ever heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>?

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed, retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James B. Stockdale</ENAMEX> responds to recent
allegations that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> think he was rendered
unbalanced by his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. Stockdale vouches
for the rock-solid temperament of his fellow former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi Hilton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX>.
That's to be expected--but what's really newsy here is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stockdale</ENAMEX> reports
that an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> he describes as close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> campaign
recently called him soliciting comments on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s "weaknesses." This is the
first solid link between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> whispering campaign.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> features a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> memoir by
active-duty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Welsh</ENAMEX> that was originally delivered to cadets
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Academy</ENAMEX>. The talk contains the following compelling and
reassuring passage, about a transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>, who came up on the
radio volunteering to go pick up a fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> shot down over a heavy
concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>: "You need to remember a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinook</ENAMEX> is about the
size of a double-decker <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> bus with props, and it doesn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. We kid
around a lot about interservice rivalries, but I guarantee that I would follow
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> helicopter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> into combat. I'll never forget her voice."

         
      
   
