
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drop Everything</ENAMEX>

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s announcement
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that she will definitely run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> against
likely opponent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>. Somewhat surprisingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , although fronting
the announcement, does not lead with it, opting instead for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, which included get-togethers with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanians</ENAMEX> (he urged
them to forgive the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>) and with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> (he reminded
them that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is an excellent example of how different ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> can get along). The tops of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> feature pictures of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a bit lower. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> versions look like a campaign meet-and-greet, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times shot evokes the more intimate feeling of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>: It's good to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> can only find a
below-the-fold reefer for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and goes with a story nobody else
fronts--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> report on the worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> situation. Among the grim
numbers, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>: By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>, the cumulative toll from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease</ENAMEX> will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.3 million</NUMEX> deaths and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> infections. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 70</NUMEX>
percent of all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> cases live in sub-Saharan <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, which contains but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> continues, the region where
the disease is growing the fastest is the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, largely due to
the rise there of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intravenous drug</ENAMEX> use.

            According to the coverage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s announcement came at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> meeting of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says it had the feel of an orchestrated performance, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes even further, saying that union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> said it was
"scripted." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said that she would move into her new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westchester County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> as soon as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> said she could and that after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, she would scale back her activities as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
observes this will mark the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has lived
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sans first lady</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> is alone in commenting up high
on an even more remarkable fact: For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is
running for office.

            The main coverage takes a what-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>-in-the-parlor? approach to the
domestic implications of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s announcement. Although it is reported
that she said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> she had not told her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of her
decision, nobody notes how this contrasts with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly</NUMEX> universal tradition
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> announcing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> in tow. And there is no
speculation in the leads about whether the coming physical distance between the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> represents a psychical one as well. (An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> inside story, does briefly indulge, however.) This silence, which
might even be mistaken for good taste, can't possibly last.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is alone in fronting the filing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of class-action
lawsuits against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest HMOs. The suits, the paper
reports, were filed by one of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in the cases against the
tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that led to that industry's lavish financial settlement with
many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> claim that the health plans have violated their
obligations to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and even allege that they've engaged in
racketeering.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> report that a JAMA study
published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> suggests that despite widespread fears among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to the
contrary, the frequency of sexual activity and the pleasure derived from it
remain the same or even increase after having a hysterectomy.

            A front page WSJ feature looks past such arcana as pricing structures
and inventory management to find a simpler reason why discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>
consistently outperform traditional department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>: The former, but not the
latter, provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> with shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX>. Very simply, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX>--no, duh!--enable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> to
buy more stuff.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source</ENAMEX>" has great fun reporting that yesterday
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX> was on jury duty in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. But
the column never stops to wonder how an ex-convict like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> could serve on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. Indeed, although the column points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> in
the past, it never mentions that he's done time.

         
      
   
