
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Policy</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a commendable follow-up to a
story that it broke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 29, 1999</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eighteen-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Gelsinger</ENAMEX>, who suffered from a rare liver disorder,
died from a blood reaction caused during a gene therapy experiment administered
little question that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gelsinger</ENAMEX> was a willing and eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>" and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> remains supportive of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's investigation reveals a number of
variables--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wilson</ENAMEX> had financial interests in seeing the
therapy succeed; "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX> study experimented with the healthiest rather than
the sickest" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and more--that raise serious questions about whether the
experiment should have occurred.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> off-lead and an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times front piece all reflect on what the 106th <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has
accomplished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> which began with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> acquittal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 106th</TIMEX> "was notable more for what it
did not do than for what it did"; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> concur. Failures include the inability to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restructure Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and pass gun control legislation or
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> tax cut; and the rejection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban</ENAMEX>
Treaty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> cite the overhaul of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX> laws limiting the
interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, securities <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> as the 106th's
most significant feat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes it, but says "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s most striking
accomplishment" was promising "to end the long-standing practice of using
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> revenues to finance other parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
backed them up on their pledge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> emphasizes the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>'
post-impeachment resentment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, an idea echoed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece points
out that "Despite their minority status, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have largely set the agenda
for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> piece anticipates that, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> is less divisive than ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 106th</TIMEX> might have a
tough time resolving unfinished business as it heads into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> acknowledged "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government's support for the widely despised military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">junta</ENAMEX> that ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>
more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years ago</TIMEX>" during a speech to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> business and community
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has readily owned up to "mistakes--even
horrors--in official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> conduct." This latest admission should help his
efforts to get <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> to resolve their differences over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-leads a
piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> pesidential hopeful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989-91</TIMEX> "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-month</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> ethics investigation that ended with his exoneration." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>
wishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> web
site had links to related articles from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was accused, with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, of having attempted to improperly influence federal
banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Keating</ENAMEX>, from whom they'd accepted
legal but large campaign contributions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politicos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> say the
ordeal made him into a "crusader for changing campaign finance and ... a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
says his "strategy for surviving ... was candor, especially with the press"
which "gained him admirers in the news media, if not among his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> also praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s honesty--and his bravery--in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">refreshing NYT</ENAMEX> 
               Magazine piece that bemoans the dominance of
adversarial political journalism.

            In her piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Op-Ed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd lets McCain</ENAMEX> stick up for
himself against "whispered insinuations from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, including some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietcong</ENAMEX> dungeons, which included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
suicide attempts, drove him <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cuckoo</ENAMEX>." He says his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> spent in solitary gave
him confidence, self-knowledge, and prepared him for life's difficulties. Dowd
notes that wannabe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> are now getting "questioned for serving, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dodging</ENAMEX>" and thinks that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> might be worried about how they'll
compare to "inspiring war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>.

            Inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs news that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Governors' Association</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGA</ENAMEX>) offered an institutional endorsement" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>,
symbolizing their willingness "to use their muscle and prestige to help him win
the nomination."

            Under the fold, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calls a foul on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> for reneging on his
promise to play a chivalrous campaign game; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> has taken
verbal jabs at his competitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> recently. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> has
emphasized his disdain for campaign tactics like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>-bashing and building
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> around focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> research, he seems to be increasingly relying on
such conventions as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary approaches; it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 10 weeks</TIMEX>
away.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> poll shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> percentage point over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> though he's got an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>-point advantage nationally.
Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times the support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> does nationally, but only
leads him by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> points in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX> The poll also shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> by
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent to 40 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> would still choose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, but by a
smaller margin: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent to 41 percent</NUMEX>.

            Leaning on anecdotal evidence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says in a
front piece that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s most severely ill mental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> get sufficient
care only after actual or near catastrophes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example: A paranoid
schizophrenic who had been briefly hospitalized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 15</NUMEX> times killed a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
