
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slander Patrol: Saving Private Gore</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> and in particular its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> -style program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hannity</ENAMEX> and
Colmes have been hyping the allegation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> had a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX>" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. If true, this would cast a different light on the campaign ads that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tout Gore</ENAMEX>'s voluntary wartime service (in unstated contrast with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, both of whom avoided the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam-</ENAMEX>era draft). Should it turn
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, had a kind of safe-conduct pass through
the war zone, it would call into doubt just how courageous and self-sacrificing
his decision to volunteer was.

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX>" charge first surfaced in a long story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
experience that ran in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. The story, by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Serrano</ENAMEX>, quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Leo</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> assigned to the engineering
unit to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was also attached. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> says that he was ordered to keep the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> out of harm's way. "It blew me away," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .
"I was to make sure he didn't get into a situation he could not get out of.
They didn't want him to get into trouble. So we went into the field after the
fact after combat actions, and that limited his exposure to any hazards."

            This quote leaves the impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was treated specially by not
being sent into combat situations, and possibly that he or his politically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">connected</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> sought such favoritism. But other comments by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX> dispel these
implications. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> is both more specific and less incendiary in quotations that
appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, as part of an excerpt from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Turque</ENAMEX>'s
forthcoming biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turque</ENAMEX> that the request to watch over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brig.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.B. Cooper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineer Brigade</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> also told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turque</ENAMEX> that he never disclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>'s
request to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> himself, and that he does not believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was ever aware of
the arrangement.

            When I reached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX> by phone at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, he said some other
interesting things. He told me that the flap was "much ado about nothing" and
that he thinks the use of the term "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX>" is inaccurate. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, not visiting a battlefield until the battle was over
was standard operating procedure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> himself was more daring--or "stupid" in
his words--because he was single and addicted to adrenaline. He says he had
mixed feelings about being asked to serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s "security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX>." On the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, he resented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s special treatment. On the other hand, he felt
honored to be chosen. And while he at first thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was privileged and out
of touch with the real world, "after I'd been around him for a while, I kind of
changed my attitude--I found him to be a straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turque</ENAMEX> that he had no memory of asking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX> to watch over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. But whether or not the conversation occurred, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> clearly was not
specially protected for much of the time he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">20 th Engineer Brigade</ENAMEX> would often go into the field in pairs on
reporting assignments that were in practice largely voluntary.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> went on many such trips, where he and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> caught a
whiff of combat without participating in it. And often he went not with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX> but
with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> assigned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigade</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> says he has
no reason to believe these other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> got the request he did to keep
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> out of danger.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> who says he was never asked to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike O'Hara</ENAMEX>, a fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> attached to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> who became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Hara</ENAMEX>, who is now a sportswriter for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit News</ENAMEX> , calls
the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was specially protected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> "a pile of shit." He
recalls that he spoke to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> soon after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O'Hara</ENAMEX>
explained to him that he would have to choose between hanging around the base
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bien Hoa</ENAMEX> in relative safety or venturing out into the field to report on
stories. "That's a decision I'm going to have to make," he remembers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
telling him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s decision was to go and see the war for himself, often in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Hara</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. "Never once did I notice he was treated differently or asked
to be treated differently from anybody else," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Hara</ENAMEX> says. "We all would have
known it. If you're not pulling your weight, you're an outcast. [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>] was one
of the best-liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>."

            The field trips <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> made with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Hara</ENAMEX> were not highly dangerous forays--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX>
says he can't remember a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualty</ENAMEX> in the public-information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> he was stationed there. But they
clearly did expose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to hazards he wouldn't have faced had he stayed back at
the base writing up press releases. Riding on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>, sleeping in foxholes
within range of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">artillery</ENAMEX>, and even playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> were all things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> did that involved a degree of
avoidable risk.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has alleged in the past that he was protected in a different way at an
earlier stage, but not out of a benign motive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> enlisted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 1969</TIMEX>. With his anti-war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore Sr.</ENAMEX>, fighting a bitter
re-election battle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Jr</ENAMEX>'s orders for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> were mysteriously
delayed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>, until after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had lost the election in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1970</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> family has speculated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> administration
wanted to make sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Al</ENAMEX> didn't create good publicity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Al</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>--possibly by getting injured. But there's no actual evidence to support
the suspicion that politics was what kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> stateside for so long.

            The worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can be accused of on the basis of existing evidence is being
protected to a minor degree without his own knowledge or consent. Even that
much may not be true. But even if someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> did give an order to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protect Gore</ENAMEX>, this should hardly count as a mark against him. It doesn't
diminish the credit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> deserves for volunteering to participate in a war that
he personally opposed, and that nearly all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> did their
utmost to avoid.

         
      
   
