
   
   
      
         
            On a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wing and a Prayer</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trade agreement (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
goes with a three-row, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-column headline)--a story off-leaded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fronted</ENAMEX> (below the fold) by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . The papers run packages of stories covering
all the angles--the diplomatic intrigue, the technical details, etc.--of the
breakthrough accord, which effectively lets <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>. One detail: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will let <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> buy stakes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telecom companies</ENAMEX>, but only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 50 percent</NUMEX>  ("The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of darkness in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecom bureaucracies</ENAMEX> are going to have to slink under the rocks
again," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exultant pro-trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must
now shepherd the pact through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>; passage is likely but not certain. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moneybox</ENAMEX>'s take on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> accord means for the Internet--and what
the Internet might mean for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--click here.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Transportation Safety</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX>'s announcement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">990</ENAMEX>'s cockpit voice recorder indicates foul
play, a story fronted (above the fold) by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> did not give any specifics about the contents of the cockpit voice
recorder, but the papers publish leaked details: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Just</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autopilot</ENAMEX> is turned off, the cockpit door apparently opens and shuts several
times and then a pilot utters what appears to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Islamic prayer</ENAMEX>--whether as
an expression of alarm or of suicide is unknown. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Seconds later</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> goes
into what appears to be a pilot-induced dive, and soon it appears that another
pilot has re-entered the cockpit and is working at "cross purposes" with the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Eventually, someone apparently shuts off the engines. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
story implies that this sequence of events is certain rather than merely
apparent.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> translators did
not notice the religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">utterance</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that
when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX>-dialect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> were brought in, they spotted it right away.
All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX>'s announcement that it might surrender the
investigation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> offered to step
down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> demurred; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the LAT
quote anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> predicting that the transfer will happen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> tightened security at its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>.
Conspiracy theories abounded in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> crash of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, partly because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> effectively took control of the investigation and
ran it secretively.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts an anonymously sourced report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is near agreement on a resolution that would suspend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nine-year-old</TIMEX>
sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in exchange for its compliance with international arms
inspections. The proposal would require the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> to reaffirm the
suspension policy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 100 days</TIMEX>, and any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> would, as usual, have a
unilateral veto.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts a long feature on the backlash against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> fees, which took
form most concretely in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s ATM-fee prohibition by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX>. (In response, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells Fargo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of America</ENAMEX>--denied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> access to non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.)
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fails to report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> district court
issued a preliminary injunction against the fee prohibitions--a story off-leaded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> (this same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story
runs inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> in abbreviated form).

            On the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> opinion page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">think-tank scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Bartlett</ENAMEX> mocks would-be
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s proposal to eliminate the federal debt by
imposing a one-time, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.25 percent</NUMEX> tax on the net wealth of every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> with
over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX>. To pay off our <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.7 trillion</NUMEX> debt at a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.25 percent</NUMEX> rate,
you'd need a tax base of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 trillion</NUMEX>. This, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX> notes, is approximately
the net worth of every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> they own) and every
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Even if the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.25 percent</NUMEX> tax was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> universally--as the numbers would seem to require in order to raise
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.7 trillion</NUMEX>--this would mean taxing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> endowments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX>, and even the smallest bank accounts. It would force the sale of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trillions</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> of stock, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> either paid the tax or hid their
assets. And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX> writes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would likely replace the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$229</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in annual interest payments with new spending.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
received an interrogation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> upon visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. Peppered with hostile questions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> defended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>'s lawsuit and insisted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s antitrust laws represent a
"basic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> value." "Throughout the session," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> attempted to defuse tension by making jokes, mentioning obscure
scientific theories and repeatedly announcing his Web site address." Only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> nonetheless received a
standing ovation when he left. Afterwards, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> dropped in on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>.
Well, that's not entirely correct, but he did stop by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of

                  Slate
               --where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karenna</ENAMEX> worked several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>--to write a diary of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. To read it, click here.
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, it should be noted, missed his deadline.)

            From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> story:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> also stressed that they had not yet
synchronized the voice tape with the flight data recorder tape, which would
record events occurring on the airplane and could put the statements in
context. For instance, a prayer being said after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> began plummeting so
fast that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were rendered weightless would not be suspicious.

            

            From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> story:

            

               The key to understanding the sequence of events was that the safety board
laboratory was able to correlate the exact timing on the cockpit voice recorder
and the flight data recorder. They therefore knew exactly when the troubling
words were uttered and when the door was opened, in relation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s
dive.

            

         
      
   
