
   
   
      
         
            Area <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man Admits to Lack of Interest in Football</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Merrill</ENAMEX>,

            Wow. I think I might finally be getting the hang of this
getting-up-before<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-midafternoon</TIMEX> concept, and with absolutely no dog-assistance
whatsoever. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just a short</TIMEX> note to get the ball rolling <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>: I know this
is a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> and all, but since the other <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
I've read seemed to have no qualms about discussing what was in their local
news (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> politics, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> race, etc.), I figured I'd
follow suit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Leuders</ENAMEX> is really hopping mad about the zoning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>! OK, so maybe that one doesn't work, but I thought I'd be remiss if
I didn't mention the biggest local news of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> (all right, who am I trying
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>) here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> is going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rose Bowl</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayne Badger</ENAMEX> football kicks ass! <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WHEEEEEEOOOOOO</ENAMEX>!

            Everybody here is soiling themselves over this development. Actually,
though, I have to admit that I've never really had any much interest in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>. At least, I don't think I have ... is that the one where the people
all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> out of the backs of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickups</ENAMEX> for like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours</TIMEX>, and then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> runs out to like kettle drums and blaring brass bands, and the crowd
stomps on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bleachers</ENAMEX> and they chant fascist propaganda really loud in
unison, and paint themselves and scream like apes and dislocate each others
knees and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get crushed and everybody pees on each other and throws their
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">feces like in Gorillas In the Mist</ENAMEX> and then they all go home and get
date-raped? Because if it is, then I don't really know much about it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yours</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
