
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spliff Shocker</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>:

            I spent much of the latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> bound for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>, which is where I am as I write this. We hovered above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for
more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> before landing--a combination of bad weather and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> taking off from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.F.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. I didn't find out until much later
that he'd been here, and I didn't find out why he was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>, or
rather one of the reasons he was supposed to be on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>, until I
picked up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. Riots? What <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> is this? (And over trade
issues? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> trying to jump-start his campaign?) I don't know about
the coverage back east, but it's quite something out here. If you covered the
headline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> --"Turmoil in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
Streets"--and just looked at the picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> with clubs
and helmets and prole-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in heavy coats and scarves, you'd think it
was some <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> war zone.

            Also on the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> , a story about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>'s tax plan
(is there no escaping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>?), which I gather he'll detail <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in that
hotbed of economic-policy analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX>. Tax breaks for the working poor
and no reduction in capital gains taxes ... hmmm. I'm sure the conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> will fall right in line. Here's my favorite part of
the article: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Response</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> tax plan was swift. Even before knowing the
details, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> criticized it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>." Even before knowing
the details. Sheesh, couldn't he have waited <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five seconds</TIMEX> before attacking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>? I can see it now: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX> is the sexiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> alive. Even before knowing the details, Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s choice as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'hog</NUMEX>.' " Actually, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
quote is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s plan is a "truly reckless tax scheme." The new bogeyword
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics: scheme. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX> hates something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, it's never
a proposal; it's a scheme, as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snidely Wiplash</ENAMEX> cooked it up in his evil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lair</ENAMEX>.

            And then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>'s plan for the homeless in the
Times and elsewhere. Let's put aside the relative merits of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>'s
treated everyone but Christyne Lategano <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> has
cleaned up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, made it liveable again--made it visitable again. Even
if he's been cruel to the squeegee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>--and, c'mon, he has--this is not an
issue with legs for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>. There are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">libs</ENAMEX> who
will publicly nod at her in assent but privately want the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> free of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moochers</ENAMEX> and hookers and the like. I had hopes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, who seems senator
material to me: smart and pompous and possessed with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">regal</ENAMEX> bearing totally
out of proportion to her dime-store roots. I've been saying for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> that she
can win--I've even got a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> bet on the race with one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>'s media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Stevens</ENAMEX>--and I still think her chances improve if your favorite
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX>, gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
presidential nod and brings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> and into the
polling place. But she's shown absolutely no traction so far, and if the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 months</TIMEX> go the way I expect for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, she's gonna have to pull a rabbit
out of her hat to win.

            Or a joint. For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a fleeting moment late last night</TIMEX>, I thought I saw a
reference on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> to some story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> having acknowledged smoking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pot</ENAMEX>. (Oh, do you think?) Sadly, it did not carry the typical
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">inflamed/outraged/engorged Drudge</ENAMEX> headline -- "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Lady in Spliff Shocker</ENAMEX>!"
I'm with you on this: I think I'd respect her more knowing she spilled her
share of bong water way back when. Maybe she even bongoes naked.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary-McConaughey</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>: Talk about your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> par-tay.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Evan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
