
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Split Screens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> Screeds

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> all lead with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' approval of the fiercely contended spending bill. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74-24</NUMEX> vote in
favor was the last piece of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 trillion</NUMEX> federal budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, and it
allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to adjourn for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that although
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> had to make significant compromises to pass the bill, both
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are touting their local victories within the bill:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to hire more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> will receive its requisite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are assured of more money for medical
research.

            The LAT highlights the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> claim that passage of the bill
could mean that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> trust fund will remain untouched for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>, an assertion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> treats with deep
skepticism. In addressing the individual parts of the spending package, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that the budget still exceeds the set spending limits for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX>. Whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> address the
provisions of the bill in terms of the dollar amount assigned to them, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> tends to foreground the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> who backed or opposed particular
provisions. The WP account also includes more of the behind-the-scenes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wheeling</ENAMEX> and dealing that took place in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the final hours</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> piece examines a regionally motivated disagreement over dairy
subsidies that very nearly incited a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX>, all-night filibuster. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> both include the threatened filibuster, but less
prominently. A sense of grateful relief that the filibuster never materialized
and that the budget was finally sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> pervades <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>
papers--they seem to be as glad to be done writing about it as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> are
to be done haggling over it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that after the agreement
was reached, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of both parties emptied silently out of the chamber.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-leads and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>'s appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Posner</ENAMEX> to act as non-binding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. Both sides
welcomed the appointment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> centers its coverage on the present
status of the suit and whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> can help bring about a settlement.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes with a close scrutiny of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s record as a conservative
jurist skeptical of government-regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> companion piece,
though, warns that it's impossible to pigeonhole <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posner</ENAMEX>'s views and
proclivities, and that neither side in the case should feel as though it's been
appointed an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> security summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, where new
limits on conventional armaments, and simplifications of the procedures for
their inspection, were adopted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> war against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechnya</ENAMEX> stood in stark
contrast to the goals of the security talks, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> said that despite the
mass of criticism it was receiving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, its conduct toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> would
remain unchanged. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with a local off-lead that could
eventually have national significance: a federal appeals court ruled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> that state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> cannot ban outdoor tobacco
advertising. But such bans have been upheld in other regions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
The matter will likely go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.

            The WP fronts the protests that met <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> upon his
arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> expressed their lasting outrage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-led
bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. The story is slugged, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thousands Protest Visit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Policy; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shielded</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence</ENAMEX>," and the article develops more fully
that juxtaposition between the fury in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and the tranquility in which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was able to conduct his visit. In its live coverage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s
events, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> television split the screen between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX> and images of marauding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> hurling rocks and firebombs.
Mimicking that split-screen strategy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> places the article, in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is quoted to say that "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to protest, they ought to
have a chance to do it," under a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-column photo of riot police confronting
angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> they had set on fire. Reefering the
story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also contrasts the violence of the protests with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">placidity Clinton</ENAMEX> enjoyed while in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also offers
more specific details of the protests: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> assembled; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
injured and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> detained by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> front <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s speech in which he outlined his foreign
policy agenda: in short, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> internationalism. He would treat China
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>; and he wouldn't allow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> brutality in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> to go unpunished. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> assert that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> made the get-tough
speech to answer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of his foreign policy abilities, but each paper draws
different conclusions about the speech's effectiveness. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> heads its
story with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Urges Engagement</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Opposes Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX>," suggesting a
certain reckless bluster. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> hints that it was merely a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">well-rehearsed</ENAMEX> set-piece that will crumble when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> debuts it live at the
upcoming debates with his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stands alone in
reporting that the speech received endorsements from some prominent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lugar</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> Flight 990 receives less and less front page space <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. It
doesn't make the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> relegates it to a
reefer on the safety board <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s statement that media leaks have "clouded"
investigations into the disaster

         
      
   
