
   
   
      
         
            Who Cares Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> (Maybe<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">) Smoked Dope</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 29</TIMEX> interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone Phillips</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s Dateline
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alerted Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that the big scoop in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillary's Choice</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s new psychobiography of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> might have smoked some dope in college,
but her ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> isn't saying for sure .

            Stunned by this new revelation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> ran to the nearest bookstore and
purchased a copy. Sure enough on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>, we meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rupert</ENAMEX>, a

            

               
                  ruthlessly handsome 'black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irishman</ENAMEX>' with dark eyes that he used to his
advantage. He would become her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real love. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX> says he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>
pounds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pulsing hormones</ENAMEX>. Their relationship was a tempestuous one.
               

            

            This brooding hunk of manly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sinew</ENAMEX> seized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s heaving shoulders at a
mixer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> interns during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1968</TIMEX> and murmured ... that
he was working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Goodell</ENAMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. She
fluttered her eyes downward and whispered ... that she was working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laird</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> who would later be defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>. Their loins ached with passion.

            

               
                  "We always used birth control," offers [!] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>. [This is on
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">69</NUMEX>; by now they're both back at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>.] "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstinence</ENAMEX> is the absolute
remedy here, but a fear of getting pregnant did not deter us in our
relationship." He often stayed over with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> she shared with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellesley</ENAMEX> and knew her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roommates well</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            Mesmerized by the narrative rush of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s bodice-ripper, Chatterbox
almost forgot to look up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> about smoking dope. Here it is (Page
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>):

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX> discovered something unexpected about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>: get her away on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, and she could be playful. He vaguely remembers them joining a march on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> there together. "Some of us were inhaling,"
he says with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">you-know-what</TIMEX>-I-mean smirk. The obvious question is, did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">inhale too?</ENAMEX> "I don't have to go there," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>, "but you can read between
the lines."
               

            

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dateline</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> repeatedly
"has denied ever trying marijuana." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dateline</ENAMEX> , "I wasn't
aware of that" and that she hasn't "asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> herself.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillips</ENAMEX>
then intoned, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> told us Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stands by her
previous statements that she has never taken illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>." Surprisingly,
nobody pitched a question about this to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> when
he gave some remarks about a new proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> rule allowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to use unemployment insurance to fund parental work leave.

            In case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> isn't being snide enough to get his point across:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't care whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> ever smoked dope with
her college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, even if she's lying about it now. He brings the matter
up only to demonstrate the exhausted state of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
scandalmongering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven long years</TIMEX> into this national soap opera. By now we've
heard nearly every conceivable accusation about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>, true or
false, that could possibly be leveled. What's left? A loutish college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>
who says maybe when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was in college she engaged in a popular
illegal national pastime of that period. He'd rather not say for sure .
In response, the creaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> press office shudders and throws off a
spark or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and issues <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more unconvincing denial. Can't anybody make it
stop from both ends? Chatterbox can't take it any more !

         
      
   
