
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy Sue</ENAMEX>?

            On Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">138</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premiere</ENAMEX> , senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Millea</ENAMEX>
tells her side of a heated encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Kaufman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s upcoming movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quills</ENAMEX> . In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millea</ENAMEX>'s account, she was scheduled to interview <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quill s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winslet</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winslet</ENAMEX> was being driven home from the set after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>'s work.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millea</ENAMEX> pulled up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winslet's</ENAMEX> hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> confronted her and
(according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millea</ENAMEX>) ordered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew member</ENAMEX> to "Get her out of here. Now!"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millea</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winslet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> as saying, afterwards, "I wanted to slug him.
... That's wee-<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">willy syndrome</ENAMEX>, there." Take that, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Son-of-Sexy-Yet-Classy</ENAMEX>-but-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Commercially-Disappointing-Film-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>! Millea
also notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winslet</ENAMEX> later defended the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> as "just fiercely
protective of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>."

            Imagine the hilarity in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premiere</ENAMEX> 's legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> when the magazine
received a letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> objecting to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">wee-willy</ENAMEX>"
passage and hinting at legal action. Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> charging that the description
was false, and that his willy was not, in fact, wee? Would he submit to a
discovery on the matter? Can't you have "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">wee-willy syndrome</ENAMEX> " without
actually having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wee willy</ENAMEX>? Think of the potential for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> TV sweeps-week
special! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premiere</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Meigs</ENAMEX>, acknowledges receiving a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>-letter, and says, "We stand by our story." But surely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Kaufman</ENAMEX>
wouldn't be stupid enough to let himself become known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who brought
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wee-Willy Lawsuit</ENAMEX>, would he?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, he's probably not. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kausfiles</ENAMEX> contacted him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> seemed
in an affable, non-litigious mood. The letter, he said, was "just a thing that
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> do. It's pretty well over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> did contend that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millea</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> was "pretty vicious" and "not accurate," and offered his side of the
confrontation, which was basically that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millea</ENAMEX> "kept coming" when he asked her
to stay away. But will he sue<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "I have no plans. I just don't want to comment
on that." A subsequent call to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Tyerman</ENAMEX>, went unreturned.

            The only hope now is that this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> itself will somehow goad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> into
bringing his suit ...

         
      
   
