
   
   
      
         
            Roll Over, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Todd</ENAMEX>,

            I love the airplane mystery idea. Almost as much as I hate that song about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who wear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abercrombie & Fitch</ENAMEX>. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> need to be a great
deal cuter to get away with such horrible lyric writing.

            And a last comment on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie Brinkley</ENAMEX>. I once read a beauty book by her in
which she confessed that her biggest beauty secret was <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> it, bathe
in it, use it to moisturize <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX>. It's just that simple. But she apparently
forgot to add, "And get some better-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boy oh boy</ENAMEX>, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> ever full of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> space-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> features
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. They could certainly print the same ones verbatim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, but
instead they assign some poor beleaguered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to dress them up by adding a
few expressions from rap records. Of course, my favorite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> media
tradition is the one they air on all the TV newscasts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thanksgiving</ENAMEX>. It is called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Busiest Shopping Day of the Year</ENAMEX>" and is the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> where they send lifestyle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to the local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> to coerce
unsuspecting randomly selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> into speaking the exact same seasonal
cliches that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> came up with the last time they did the report. They
could definitely run this same report verbatim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX> were it not for
the slight difference in haircuts from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade to decade</TIMEX>. Of course, now with
all the sophisticated computer graphics and so forth, maybe they will finally
be able to produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that can run in perpetuity.

            I am not sure why I feel so driven to read through this multi-part article
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> is running on string theory. I hope it's not just because
I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Greene</ENAMEX> is a babe. OK. That is the reason. But shallow
motives aside, here is what I picked up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. As you may recall from my
incisive analysis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the string <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> have gone ahead and thrown
out that old saw, that antiquated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">buggy</NUMEX>-era concept of space and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. But , before you start going all nostalgic on me, you will be happy
to know that they have replaced it with the infinitely hipper and more
contemporary <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-dimensional strings. Yes, I realize it is a little hard to warm
up to at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. But I think we're all going to get to like it better as--oops,
I was going to say as time goes by but now that we've eliminated time--as we
get to know the strings on a more personal basis. Which is all well and good.
There's only just so many times that can eat in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, so to
speak. Space and time have had more than their share of the spotlight. Move
over and let a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> have a chance. But I wonder if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> behind
this important philosophical shift have really considered all the consequences
of their actions. Because, as the article points out, if there is no clear
difference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between now</TIMEX> and the instant after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> , then "how can
we say if the gunshot caused the death or if the death caused the gunshot<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" And
you thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> were incomprehensible morally compromised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bullshit artists</ENAMEX>
in love with the sound of their own voices before . Just imagine being
selected to sit on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that has to listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Cochran</ENAMEX> appeal the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> case on the grounds of factual inconsistencies due to string theory. Oh
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.

            And speaking of gunshots, let's move right on to the rage-filled portion of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s letter: Apparently they held "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take a Kid Pheasant Hunting Day</ENAMEX>"
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> has a lovely photo of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
sweet little grad-school-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> smiling as they hold up an assortment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lifeless corpses</ENAMEX>. At last, a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> steps in to help provide a
much-needed opportunity for the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> hidden
anywhere in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> to make firsthand contact with the pleasures of gun
violence. There really aren't enough opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to come in to
contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> or to kill helpless creatures nowadays, especially during the
all-important elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. So it's nice that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
Division of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fish, Game</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildlife</ENAMEX> was willing to co-sponsor the event with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX>. Their goal is "to shore up hunting's
popularity," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Poole</ENAMEX>, the moron in charge (who I would love to make
the first target of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brand-new</ENAMEX> still-untested self-defense fighting
skills--particularly one I just learned that they call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axe</ENAMEX>, which involves
bringing the heel of my foot right down between his eyes several times). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Poole</ENAMEX>
is also quoted as saying, "The shooting sports are like any other endeavor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youth</ENAMEX> is our future." Yeah. Like any other endeavor where helpless <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are
placed at a disadvantage (in this case, they spin the pheasants <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to make
them dizzy) in order to provide adorable little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with the joy of
inflicting pain and causing death. There really aren't enough other forms of
recreation and entertainment available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today. Of course, I guess
I'm not taking into account the fact that it does give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a chance to
help out with the household expenses by bringing home enough of that family
dinner favorite, pheasant, to keep everyone in pheasant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>.

            Now I need to go check my blood pressure. Talk to you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
