
   
   
      
         
            No <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Relation No. 6: Moore Than Meets the Eye</ENAMEX>
            

            By the looks of it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX> has had a busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> won critical acclaim for his documentary films. Then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX> led
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in their lawsuit against big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. And now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX> is
heading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> as it meets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. How does he do it all?

            Quite easily: There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moores</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX> , the documentary filmmaker, has made a name for himself
as a "professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gadfly</ENAMEX>." His breakthrough film, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX> ,
tracked his <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Â</NUMEX>½<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year</TIMEX> effort to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Smith</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flint</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>,
to view the effects of plant closings. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other films, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> television
shows, a Web
site , and a book ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Downsize This</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> has continued to promote
his left-leaning political views. Among his irreverent made-for-TV stunts:
driving a pink "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sodomobile</ENAMEX>" filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that
ban sodomy, and presenting an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> with a giant <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80-cent</NUMEX> check to pay for
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>'s labor. Corporate greed being one of his
favorite targets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX> has come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> to protest the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director-general</ENAMEX>, is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>. He has long been involved in international trade, serving as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>'s trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, and working to launch both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APEC</ENAMEX>. He took
the helm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>, filed the first
state lawsuit charging that cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> were liable for the health
costs of smoking. He helped lead <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in negotiations with tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that resulted in a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$206 billion</NUMEX> settlement. His role in the dispute
landed him a small part--as himself--in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Insider</ENAMEX> .

            
               Previously in this series, the 
               Explainer sorted out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cohens</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephens</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richards</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rays</ENAMEX>

               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeths</ENAMEX>), the Hirschfelds
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>), the Strausses
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert and R. Peter</ENAMEX>), and the Broders
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John M.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>).
            

            
               Have you noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the news with confusingly similar names? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> welcomes your
suggestions for future installments.
            

         
      
   
