
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Age</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Todd</ENAMEX>:

            The way you describe your life is starting to sound glamorous to me. We
don't even have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> waffle places out here. If we want waffles, we have
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a 12-hour</TIMEX> window of opportunity, and after that, tough luck, you're on
your own.

            I have never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>, but this day-and<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-night</TIMEX> access to waffles
may be all the reason I need to start planning a trip. The last time I visited
your general part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, I learned a different but equally interesting
regional dietary lesson: Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> around there do not feel that
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> is really a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> unless it has first been deep fried and then soaked
in a heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream sauce</ENAMEX>. I went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>" where not only did I not see
anything that reminded me of a vegetable (and by the way, I'm intentionally
going to skip the reflexive but pointlessly callous joke I could make about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, who I'm sure upon closer examination were lovely and admirable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>), but among the "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad ingredients</ENAMEX>" being offered was a dish of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate pudding</ENAMEX>. I thought to myself, "God bless the dietician behind this
menu who deserves a nomination for a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> just for getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate pudding</ENAMEX> reclassified as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX>."

            I guess you must be relieved that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moesha</ENAMEX> has rehydrated and her
show is back in production in time for it to be considered as a possible export
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> under the new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Trade Pact</ENAMEX>. I wonder what the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> products to
hit our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> will be? If things work the way they usually do in commerce,
when they find out our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are already glutted with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, my
guess is that they will begin to make and export enchiladas. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sweeney</ENAMEX>, "said it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'disgustingly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocritical</ENAMEX>' of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to claim to be keeping the
interests of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in mind as it negotiates with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> that
routinely violates human rights." Which got me to thinking about how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> continues to arrest and jail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group/</ENAMEX>sect<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">/cult</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>, which, from what I understand, sounds like
kind of a cross between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chi</ENAMEX>, yoga, and the kind of New Age philosophy about
controlling your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s energy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that would make it not only a beloved
spiritual staple but also a marketing bonanza at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> (and
eventually the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>). Maybe when they realize that their social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irritants</ENAMEX> might well be their most profitable exports, it will be the kick in
the butt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will need to start respecting the rights of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.

            On the furious-with-rage front, how about that creepy anti-abortion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dunderhead Christopher H. Smith</ENAMEX> keeping us from paying our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> dues because
part of the money supports women's health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that have pro-abortion
ties? It's good of him to be putting energy into making sure that the unwanted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the future will be born into to a world without a functioning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>.

            And while I'm in the anger section of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s events, I loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s
comments as he campaigns in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily</ENAMEX> news quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>
as having looked the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> over and come up with this incisive
statement: "Let me ask you, did they make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in a very short
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>? I don't think so." Since that is his criterion for excellence in
government, I hope he will remember to review the résumés of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>,
lotto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>, sitcom stars, and successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Wants To Be</ENAMEX>
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Millionaire</ENAMEX>? when he is picking out his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>. I also love the way he
brings his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> to press conferences to dress things up. I hope in the
future he will also bring a blowup of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> statement and a wheelbarrow full
of cash and precious gems.

            Now I am on to reading about string theory.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
