
   
   
      
         
            The Role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Intellectual</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Gerald</ENAMEX>:

            I'm enjoying this more than I thought I would, though it does remind me why,
when I quit reviewing books for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, I swore
I'd review no more. Book-reviewing bears about the same resemblance to
literature as cleaning up after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> does to being in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX>,
except that you're more likely to be useful pushing a broom behind the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>. Who, after all, really wants to step in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant dung</ENAMEX>?

            This question has been implicit in our conversation: Just what, as we
approach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>, is the responsibility of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>? I
don't claim to have any answers, but I can't help thinking about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris Rock</ENAMEX>'s
routine comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm X</ENAMEX>, and his conclusion that, while in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, now we
have substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.

            When I consider the inclusion in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana of Tupac Shakur</ENAMEX> and his
cohort of the rappers, I wonder whether black academia has been hijacked by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirtysomething</TIMEX> know-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nothings</ENAMEX> who actually think this stuff is
important. The truth, though, is that this fascination (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really
ought to know better) with violence and outlaw behavior is a long-standing
phenomenon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Crouch</ENAMEX> (or was it someone else?) calls it "the romance of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> nigger," and he's absolutely right. It crosses the color line, of
course--think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Henry Abbott</ENAMEX>. But it's a particularly
dangerous foolishness for black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, because it leads us to take
seriously <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Panthers</ENAMEX>, and to glorify the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kody Scotts</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan McCalls</ENAMEX> we ought to condemn instead.

            What I'm really puzzled <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about this morning</TIMEX> is the omission of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Alan McPherson</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africana</ENAMEX> . McPherson was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa</ENAMEX>; in fact, I went to the writing
program there to study with him.

            I'd first encountered his work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 20 years before</TIMEX>, when I was one of
perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. His Hue
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cry</ENAMEX> and, later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elbow Room</ENAMEX> , spoke directly to that
integrationist experience, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX> (and confusions) of inhabiting
an environment where, say, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> valued aspects of black culture, like
the blues, that my own firmly middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had long since discarded.
McPherson grappled with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX> and contradictions that plague us as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX> and white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in a way that no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> I know of has done.

            But I looked all through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> , hoping vainly they'd spelled his
name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MacPherson</ENAMEX>" or that there was a list of black <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize winners</ENAMEX>.
(That last isn't all that unreasonable, given the unremittingly cheerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebony</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>-like achievement accounting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> .)

            I returned <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX>'s essay on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.E.B. Du Bois</ENAMEX> and almost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">threw Africana</ENAMEX> at my television. I didn't--the book's too heavy, and
besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monday Night Football</ENAMEX> was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>. I've never met West.
Perhaps he's a genuinely nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. But so much of his writing is smug and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sanctimonious</ENAMEX>--he knows all the answers, and if the rest of us would just
listen and follow his advice, the world would be a better place.

            Much of the essay takes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> to task for his "inadequate interpretation
of the human condition"--translation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> didn't fight hard enough for the
rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>, and other oppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and doesn't seem
to have thought much about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolstoy or Kafka</ENAMEX>--and his "inability to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immerse</ENAMEX> himself fully in the rich cultural currents of black everyday life." As
near as I can figure, that last means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.E.B. Du Bois</ENAMEX> wasn't black enough.

            The essay's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost nearly 20</NUMEX> pages of small-point, narrow-leaded type, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
at his insufferable, pontificating worst. In my last message, I observed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, wants to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> when he grows up. I wonder now if his
problem isn't that he realizes he can't be and so--to paraphrase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baldwin</ENAMEX>'s
famous, if apocryphal, observation--this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> must kill his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">West</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX>--with no sense of irony--to the effect
that "we must have honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or we die. We must have unselfish, far-seeing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> or we fail." And that, to return to the question I posed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, is
just the problem. So-called public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>, bell hooks, and,
yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> himself, seem to me both dishonest and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">selfish</ENAMEX>--they're in it for the money and the power as much as out of any sense
of obligation or responsibility to the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.

            I don't know what they--unlike, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>--stand for. Either
they've never made it clear (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>) or, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>, because they stand for
so much, appealing to, and appeasing, so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>, after all,
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's managed the not-unenviable feat of sharing stages with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharpton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lerner</ENAMEX>, though not (as far as I know) at the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

            I'm suspicious of giving too much credit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>, but maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> is on to something.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
