
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empire Strikes Back</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s fiercest attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> yet, a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
puts inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> goes instead with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade</ENAMEX>
Commission <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have OKed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> merger.

            The papers announce that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is pummeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechnya</ENAMEX> and environs with new
intensity and new equipment and quote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> threats to finish off the Chechen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reads the statements the most savvily, saying they
provide the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> indication that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> wants to annihilate, not merely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">isolate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> have faced only
light resistance so far from their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>, but now Chechen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> are threatening a counterattack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reminds readers
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> were able to seize back their capital from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, and that this humiliating defeat is fueling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
current ferocity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> emphasizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s decision to use
scary-sounding "incendiary" bombs. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> hasn't explained how these differ
from ones employed previously, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to know either.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX> assented to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$81 billion</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil-Exxon</ENAMEX> merger, the largest in history, after the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> agreed to the
largest divestiture the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has ever seen. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will have to sell
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2,400</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>, of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. Things don't look as rosy for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP Amoco</ENAMEX>'s proposed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29 billion</NUMEX> purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Richfield</ENAMEX>. Since both
dominate exploration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, federal and state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are worried that a
merger might deflate competition and raise prices in the area. The story notes
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> that was broken
up by trustbusters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>. Competition for new oil reserves is much more
robust <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, which is why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are being allowed to rejoin.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts a fascinating examination of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the faith-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> programs supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and now touted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. A small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is running a pilot
project called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Change</ENAMEX> that aims to convert <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> into better
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizens</ENAMEX>--that is, better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who are fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>. The
program's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Colson</ENAMEX>, found God while serving time for involvement
in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, and has since devoted his life to helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> do the same.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> claims that overtly religious programs work better than their more secular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> because they use "the transforming power of faith." The program is
too young for a verdict on its effectiveness, but its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> are notably
more serene and cheerful than other convicts. 

            Recent polls have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> running neck-and-neck in some Northern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. But an LAT front-pager puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> hype in perspective by
describing his deep unpopularity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Barnes</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supporter</ENAMEX>--calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northeastern</ENAMEX>, elitist, old-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>." Even more
insultingly, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Emory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political scientist</ENAMEX> shuns him as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mondale</ENAMEX>." Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> credentials don't mean much in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie</ENAMEX>: "The
sport in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> that borders on being a religion is football," another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> points out. As the story admits, it's impossible to isolate the source
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s unpopularity: does he really rub <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> the wrong way, or are
they just intensely loyal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>?

            Lachrymose stories in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> chronicle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20-16</NUMEX> football
win by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stories, on the front pages of their respective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, are written
in prose much purpler than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> account. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that
the game drew the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> history. None says
the obvious--that it would have been heartless for UT not to let the Aggies
win.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, says an LAT front-pager, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was killed in a
shootout with police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> after he lead them on a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-hour</TIMEX> freeway car
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chase</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> hovered overhead and broadcast the shooting live.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> defended themselves by arguing that they could have showed
close-ups of the killing but refrained from doing so. "It is not our policy to
show graphic violence. We have to be cautious," said one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
