
   
   
      
         
            Hair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>:

            Nice analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley-McCain</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire Independents</ENAMEX> dynamic. You
left out just one thing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can't win. Under any circumstances. He could
be inducted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX>
other tiny but reputedly important primary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--and still have no chance of
becoming the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>, much less <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. He's a terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, the worst since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, maybe the
worst of all time.

            Ever watch him on the stump? He can't give a speech. He has precisely no
sense of humor. A lot of his ideas about policy sound like they were thought up
in the shower <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. At appearances, he often looks like he's about to
fall asleep. He answers questions like he'd rather be having hemorrhoid
surgery. Worst of all, he has total disdain for everything about politics, down
to and including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> carefully and you can actually see him exuding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contempt</ENAMEX>, like the oily haze that rises off airplane engines on a hot day.)
This sort of thing may be appealing to some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and others who
mistake ineptitude for integrity, but how do you think it'll play in the rest
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>? In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>? Or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>? No way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. He's got no chance.

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, I like your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> -hates-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> theory, and I agree
it's possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ivins</ENAMEX> single-handedly poisoned the relationship
between your state and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World's Most Important Newspaper</ENAMEX>. On the other hand,
what does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> care? It's not like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are
acutely aware that the rest of the world is laughing at them. I remember being
amazed when I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> by how seriously <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>---even the
relatively worldly, cynical newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I worked with--took the usual
attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> (that it's corrupt, politically incestuous, culturally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">backward</ENAMEX>, etc.). They were genuinely wounded. In other words, they half
believed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> are in no danger of that. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> really
did consider <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> to be, as you put it, overrun with oil-slicked bumpkins,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">tyrannical</ENAMEX> high-school football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>, mechanical-bull-riding smoothies, and
the odd computer geek--and let's be honest here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>, that's not an entirely
inaccurate depiction--I'm still not sure many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> would even notice. These
are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with a self-esteem problem.

            Sadly, I too have run out of space to talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>. But perhaps in
your reply you can answer the most pressing question about his candidacy:
What's with his hair? I've wondered for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, but now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> is back on
television a lot I'm haunted by it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plugs</ENAMEX>? That's what I'd always assumed, and
yet I've never spotted the telltale <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>-like implant clusters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rug</ENAMEX>? Maybe,
except the whole effect strikes me as too tussled to be a toupee. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a million</NUMEX> questions--have you
overcome your hand-shaking phobia? Who will be your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>?--but,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tragically</ENAMEX>, never broached the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hair Issue</ENAMEX>. I don't think we ought to elect him
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> before getting to the bottom of this.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
