
   
   
      
         
            Going <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bananas Over Stock Splits</ENAMEX>
            

            If you're looking for signs of irrationality in the current stock market,
and you're not one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think that every Internet stock out
there is necessarily overvalued, the best place to look is probably the
investor craze for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that announce stock splits. When a company splits
its stock, it does so by offering its current shareholders <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (or sometimes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>) shares for every one they currently own. The value of the company
as a whole stays unchanged, although its stock price is cut in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> (or in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thirds</ENAMEX> or fourths). In essence, a stock split divides up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> into
more slices, without changing the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> at all.

            Stock splits are a legacy of the time when it was difficult for individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to buy shares in anything other than round (that is, multiples of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>) lots. If your stock got too expensive, it was hard for individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to buy it, but if you split your stock, you could bring those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in. That rationale has evolved--or devolved--into a vague idea that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> would rather own more shares at a lower price rather than fewer
shares at a higher price, even though the value of each holding is the same
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> shares at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> shares at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX>).

            Vague and inexplicable as this idea is--all an investor needs to care about
is the percentage return on his or her investment--there is a grain of truth in
it. Take, for instance, the difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, which routinely
splits its stock when the price climbs comfortably above <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> a share, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshire Hathaway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which has never done a stock
split.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshire Hathaway</ENAMEX>'s Class A shares now trade at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $80,000</NUMEX> a share,
while its Class B shares trade at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $2,000</NUMEX>. That means there are millions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who will never consider buying the stock and, in the case of the
Class A shares, probably couldn't buy the stock. And, since stock prices
do reflect supply and demand to a certain degree, that's kept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hathaway</ENAMEX>'s stock price lower than if it had split as often as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s.
Conversely, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s stock price is almost certainly higher than it would
have been had it rejected stock splits (in which case its stock price would be
even more stratospheric than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshire's</ENAMEX>).

            So, all other things being equal, stock splits do exert a slight upward pull
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock price. But slight is the key word here. Academic
studies suggest that the shares of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that announce stock splits don't
do significantly better than the market, which makes sense, since in the long
run a stock's price is determined far more by the underlying value of the
company than by any other factor. And a stock split has nothing to do with
underlying value.

            You often hear that splits are important because they're a way for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to signal that it's confident in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, but this is a non
sequitur, unless not splitting the stock is a way of saying, "We don't believe
in our future, so we don't want small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to be hurt." And in any case,
splits have become so routine, and in some sense so expected, that any
signaling function they might have had has been vaporized.

            Despite all this, the announcement of a split now regularly drives up a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock price. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half ago</TIMEX>, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juniper</ENAMEX>, one of the
hottest back-end Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, announced a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3-for-1</NUMEX> stock split, and its
shares, which were already remarkably expensive, rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX>. There was no
other news. This was it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s future prospects were no better at the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> than they had been at the beginning. But the market thought the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.3 billion</NUMEX> more valuable.

            What we're seeing here is a classic recursive loop, in which meaningless
news becomes meaningful because the market has established a pattern of
treating similarly meaningless news as meaningful. More than that, an entire
cottage industry has sprung up around stock splits, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are now
able to receive e-mails and beeper messages telling them that a given stock has
split. And the existence of that industry itself conveys the message that
splits are important, even though they aren't.

            Any time you have a phenomenon like this one, it's better to look for the
underlying economic rationality rather than just write it off as hysteria. But
in this case, the market really isn't recognizing hidden value by rewarding
stock splits. It's just shuffling money from one pocket to another. And the
really weird thing is this: When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juniper</ENAMEX> announced its stock split, its shares
were trading at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$284</NUMEX>, and they then leapt to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$328</NUMEX>. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
don't seem to be deterred anymore by high stock prices. They're happy to pile
in, whether the stock costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>. In their reaction to the stock split,
then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> demonstrated that splitting isn't really necessary to bring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> in. And so the world turns. On its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
