
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Rights Becomes a Second-Day Story</ENAMEX>

            Despite the saturation coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trade deal in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , not
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sidebar</ENAMEX> could be found examining its implications for human rights. It
isn't as though the issue of human-rights abuses has gone away; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
crackdown on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> continues (click here to
read a summary of a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX> report, and here to read a pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Post Op-Ed</ENAMEX> column by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne</ENAMEX>), and several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> made (admittedly
partisan) noises about human rights when the deal was announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The
Times reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Rights Watch</ENAMEX> endorsed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> deal, but failed to point out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is conditioning
its support in the following way:

            

               
                  Before giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Normal Trade Relations</ENAMEX>) status, we
hope <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will insist on limited, meaningful steps to improve human rights.
For example, within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> of getting permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> should ratify one
or both of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> human rights treaties it has signed, and take other
steps.
               

            

            This may or may not be an ineffectual gesture on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Rights Watch</ENAMEX>'s part;
what's significant is that the news coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> deal presented the
human-rights issue as so negligible that such questions didn't even need to be
answered. (Presumably they will in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming days</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> scramble for
fresh angles.) As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Rights Watch</ENAMEX> observed in a statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Foreign Relations</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, human-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> have loomed smaller
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s other major trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> "even as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s restrictions on freedom of expression and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> grew
tighter." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the whole thing.) It may be that, contrary to
recent experience, greater trade ties will now foster greater freedom in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
Or it may be that they won't. There seems a growing consensus that attempting
to withhold admission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> as a means to advance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX> is futile and will only hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests. What's striking is the
lack of interest in examining whether this premise is correct.

         
      
   
