
   
   
      
         
            Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> Report: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charge To Keep</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Morrow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">243</NUMEX> pages, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$23</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to buy the book.)

            There was a bit of fuss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> back about who was going to write this
book. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Herskowitz</ENAMEX>, a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Chronicle</ENAMEX>
originally hired for the job, was fired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> following a dispute about what
the book should contain. At that point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Hughes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>'s
communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, stepped in as pinch-ghostwriter, reportedly working up
the text in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a month</TIMEX>. There hasn't been any pretense, as there often
is with these kinds of books, that the nominal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> actually wielded the pen.
But let's be realistic. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, the question isn't whether he
writes his own book. It's whether he reads it.

            Though there is probably not much danger that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> will claim, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barkley</ENAMEX> did, to have been misquoted in his autobiography, he might convincingly
do so. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> is supposedly as close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as any of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, yet the
book reads as if it were written by someone who barely knows him. Much of it is
boilerplate that could appear under the byline of any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in the
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>--or any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> walking down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> for that matter. Here
are some passages I found especially insightful:

            

               I always want to know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s backgrounds and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. I like people
and priorities are rooted in their upbringing.

               I enjoy meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and shaking their hands and listening to their
stories about their lives.

               Politics, like life, is a strange endeavor. Things are sometimes not what
they seem. I try to get facts and weigh both sides. And I remain confident that
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, most of the time, can see beyond the sound bites to appreciate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who try to do the right things for the right reasons.

               We are a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. I love my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and count them among
the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in my life.

               No discussion of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would be complete without mentioning our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>.

            

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wrote any of this, it must have been as part of his application to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog Millie</ENAMEX> came across as a more complex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--and a better
prose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX>.

            I suppose it's an accomplishment, in a way, to have achieved a tone so
utterly insipid. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> has accomplished this in part by the unusual technique
of double ghosting. She quotes long, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mattress-stuffing extracts</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
speeches ghostwritten by others. In other places, she describes events by
reprinting reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. In the biographical sections, which
occur at random, she repeats the familiar stories, though in a highly sanitized
form. Here, for instance, is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>" on his college career:

            

               I took my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> seriously and worked hard. ... And I made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and
played hard. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> came from all different backgrounds and all
parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, I knew many of them.

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> himself couldn't utter these words with a straight face. It is well
known that he hated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, which he thought was full of intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snobs</ENAMEX>, and
also that he did poorly there in academic terms. But rather than explore any of
this interesting territory, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> opts for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> encyclopedia approach,
removing any possible blemish from the face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.

            In the very few places where the book goes into any detail about anything,
the political purpose is transparent. In describing his time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says he wanted to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> to relieve active-duty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>, but hadn't logged enough flying time to qualify for the program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
spends a full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> attempting to defuse a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> issue by
explaining why he vetoed an HMO reform bill in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. He tries to disarm the
accusation that he was callous about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">executing Karla Fay Tucker</ENAMEX> by portraying his decision as an anguished
crisis of conscience. But by quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>'s eloquent letter to him, he
actually makes himself seem even more heartless. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sincerely</ENAMEX> penitent and that she wanted to escape execution in order to help set
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> straight. Then he killed her anyway.

            Autobiography can't help revealing something about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and even this
worthless placeholder of a book is telling in its way. What it indicates is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubya</ENAMEX> is not only the lightest of intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lightweights</ENAMEX>, but a
fundamentally cavalier and unserious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. He has no policy views, only vague
aspirations for a better <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. He believes that reading is important, but
fails to mention anything he has ever read other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>. Personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">quirks?</ENAMEX> "I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stickler</ENAMEX> for being on time," he writes, because "late is rude."
His faith is sincere but shallow. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> describes his surrender to forces
greater than himself as something that makes it possible for him to do his job
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>.

            Compare this with the books written by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other serious contenders
for the presidency: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s
book, the best of the bunch, is not only personally revealing and
insightful, but an affecting story, superbly told. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s books are dull but commendable efforts to explain themselves and
their views. It's clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> all put huge amounts of
personal effort into their respective books, being the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could
not really do otherwise. They are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who take themselves seriously.
They have respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might take the trouble to read what they
write. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, by contrast, sees a book as a campaign poster with words. His
tells you a lot about him, even as it tells you nothing at all.

         
      
   
