
   
   
      
         
            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have Us Over a Barrel Again</ENAMEX>?
            

            It may not be the greatest comeback in business history, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-ascendance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> is certainly one of the more surprising turnarounds in
recent memory. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, the benchmark price of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West Texas Intermediate</ENAMEX>
crude oil was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13</NUMEX> a barrel, and it seemed to be a foregone conclusion that the
ability of the world's key oil-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> to keep prices high had
forever vanished. In an earlier
incarnation of this column, in fact, I argued that the combination of new
oil-discovery and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>-recovery technology with the advent of the spot futures
market in oil meant that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s glory days were long gone. So why are oil
prices now at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27</NUMEX> a barrel, with consumption actually outpacing production, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>?

            The simplest answer--and the simplest excuse for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that earlier</TIMEX> column--is
that no one ever suggested that transformations in the oil industry were going
to have the effect of repealing the laws of supply and demand. Oil prices have
doubled because the global economy has made a powerful recovery in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 12</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy has grown faster than it did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humming</ENAMEX> along nicely, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> has crawled out of recession (at least for the
moment), and much of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> is now moving again. (Some predictions call for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, for instance, to grow at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.) Since oil prices are
prospective, the markets do not anticipate a global slowdown any time soon. And
the more oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> want, the more expensive it will become.

            Until, that is, more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> becomes available, either through expanded
production by the leading oil-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> or expanded exploitation of
existing reserves by the giant oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">multinationals</ENAMEX>. And here's where the
"foregone conclusion" looks a little less foregone, primarily because both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>
and non-member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>, have shown restraint in
the face of rising prices. The history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>, at least since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>,
has been one of massive cheating on the part of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, who have regularly
violated their production quotas in order to reap as much profit as possible.
That, of course, has sent prices tumbling. At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> has had an
impossible time dealing with its non-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, who were prone to
flood the market at any time.

            Prices have also stayed high because the major oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, having been
burned in the past, have been temperate in expanding their exploration and
production budgets. Although most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> will do more capital spending
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 and 2001</TIMEX> than they did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budgets for the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years</TIMEX> will probably not equal what they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as 1996</TIMEX>.
That's what a few of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13-</NUMEX>a-barrel prices will do for you.

            Still, there's another way to look at the relatively tempered way the oil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giants</ENAMEX> are expanding those budgets, and that is that they do not see prices
going, as some have suggested, to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> a barrel. In fact, the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
appear to be planning on prices between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 and $25</NUMEX> a barrel, which would mean
that while filling up your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> is going to be more expensive than it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, any inflationary impact from oil prices will be seriously
muted.

            There's no guarantee that the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are right. But there's an
excellent chance that they are, because the structural transformations in the
world oil market are real, and so too is the fact that running a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cartel</ENAMEX> has not
gotten any easier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX>. Price-fixing cartels can work
quite well in the short term. But over the long run the incentive to cheat is
simply too high, and the measures of coercion and punishment simply too weak,
to keep everyone in line. At the moment, the memories of what low oil prices
were like are probably strong enough to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>, for instance, from
pumping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> as fast as it can. But memories fade, and cash in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> can
sometimes look like forever.

         
      
   
