
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Malpractice Makes Perfect</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> all lead with a
prestigious independent medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s call for a new federal agency
dedicated to minimizing medical mistakes, which, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, are now
killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 44,000 and 98,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times reefers this to a Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> story, leading instead with the naming
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> power-sharing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>,
which could mean the true end of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Troubles</ENAMEX>" in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            The papers explain the basic point of the medical error recommendations:
most slip-ups occur not from individual ineptness but from structural flaws in
the ways <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and caregivers function. An example both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> cite is prescribing the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> because its name is very
similar to the right one. Systematically noting and disseminating such possible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confusions</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> would reduce risk. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> leads make the point that
medicine could benefit from following the tracking and notification procedures
of other risky fields like aviation and nuclear power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes
that establishing such a system is thought to cost only slightly more than 1
percent of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.8 billion</NUMEX> in health-care costs attributable to preventable
medical injuries.

            The biggest unclarity in the medical error coverage has to do with who would
get to see the results of the proposed systematic error tracking. Just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>,
or potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> too? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> refers to reporting "without fear of
punishment," which suggests a pretty tight lid. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> suggest that the system envisioned would allow serious medical errors
to be made known to the public but keep less serious ones confidential. But
there's no discussion of whether this makes sense from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s point of
view. A related point: There's already a data bank for sharing information
about incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. Surely it would be relevant to know if it functions
similarly to what's being proposed now and to know if it has indeed helped make
medicine safer.

            The other significant wiggle room in the stories relates to the dimension of
the medical error problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> suggests it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth</TIMEX>. How do the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> get
different results off the very same press release? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes with
the low end estimate of error-based fatalities and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes with
the high end.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> go high on their fronts with reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have begun excavating sites in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> very near
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> border believed to be a dumping ground for scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> killed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>. The LAT
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are expecting to find <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 100 and 300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX>. Both papers
say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> law enforcement are suspects in some of these
murders. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> blurbs the story inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-lead and the top story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> business news index is that later this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, on the heels of a spate of problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> will
start a thorough safety inspection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>,
focusing on quality control procedures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says the field audit
comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">after months</TIMEX> of increasing tension between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT fronts, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stuff, the
developing saga of that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee boy</ENAMEX> plucked from the ocean
near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, who saw his mother drown and then
spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> adrift in an inner tube, is the object of an international tug
of war. He is staying with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and has become, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , a poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for anti-Castro exiles there, but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, back
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, wants him returned. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is said to want to remain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> The
matter will probably end up in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wrestling Federation</ENAMEX>, faced with
advertiser pullouts, may be toning down its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. It quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWF</ENAMEX> minor domo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince McMahon</ENAMEX> as saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will soon see less aggression, less colorful
language, and less sexuality. The biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertiser</ENAMEX> to pull out over content
is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>, which has a wait-and-see attitude about coming back. Another refugee
from the sex and violence: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
