
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trouble With Summaries</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Gerald</ENAMEX>:

            You're absolutely right--it may be a long time until we see anything like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> again. Even if I'd been able to throw it at my television--just
lifting it violates the instructions my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthopedist</ENAMEX> gave me last week
concerning my arthritic shoulder--I wouldn't have, and not just because I like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> is as least as good as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other encyclopedias of black history and culture that sit in storage
while I wait for my shoulder to heal enough so I can build bookshelves.

            At the same time, though, admitting that I need to keep Africana
because it's all we have right now is too much like how some older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> I know
feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebony and BET</ENAMEX> (which, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX> I know quips, stands for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers' Excuse for Television</ENAMEX>). In their heart of hearts, they know neither
is really very good, but they nonetheless can't resist claiming pride of
ownership.

            Still, in the spirit of fairness, before I get back to beating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, I
have to list a few things I like about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> . The brief essay on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Conwell</ENAMEX>--also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Collins</ENAMEX>--acknowledges a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX> who
deserves wider recognition. She was also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>, but I
like best her film <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Losing Ground</ENAMEX> . When I was still editing <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black Film</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> I founded (shameless plug!), I spent a wonderful two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> with her at a film festival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>. When she died, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, we
published a special issue about her. I didn't know her well, of course, but I
often think about the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> we spent talking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that afternoon</TIMEX> so long
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.

            It's also good to see documentary filmmaker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Clair Bourne</ENAMEX> here, though I
wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Bogle</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> in black film studies--isn't. (That's
another one of those glaring omissions that make you wonder whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> didn't really have an agenda after all.) And I like the
entries on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Diaspora</ENAMEX> and the accompanying
"ready references" summarizing demographic and economic data about those
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. I spent much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> tutoring one of my godsons--if we'd had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> then, we wouldn't have had to leave my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to walk around to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>.

            That's both the strength and the weakness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> , that it
provides so much information in such a truncated form. Like you, I wish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appiah</ENAMEX> had taken the time to compile a truly comprehensive encyclopedia. If
you must have monuments to validate your worth as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, then build lasting
ones.

            At the heart of my criticism, though, is my conviction that our experience
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--like any human experience--is just too complex to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summarized</ENAMEX>. More and more, since I quit reviewing books, I think that's the job
of fiction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Schwartz-Bart</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last of the Just</ENAMEX> (for example) is
a far more moving evocation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> than any account in any reference
work, because it focuses on the experiences of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who, if he
continues to deny his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewishness</ENAMEX>, has a reasonable chance of escaping the death
camps. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McPherson</ENAMEX>'s stories have something of the same power. They, too,
bring representative individual experience alive, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX> confronts the
places where things intersect, then reports on what he finds.

            When I look at our place in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history, though, what intrigues me are
the missed opportunities--as when, for example, legal and societal distinctions
were first made between white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indentured servants</ENAMEX> and black slaves. I'm also
intrigued by the contradictions. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months</TIMEX> back, black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>
at a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conference</ENAMEX> took each other to task over the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> in the opening of the West. I'd like to have been there for that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>!

            I'd like to have seen some evidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> of our humanity and
resourcefulness, the kind of thing you find in the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Murray</ENAMEX>, both of whom were, if memory serves correctly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX>. Remember how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Penn Warren</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Murray</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
to a Very Old Place that slavery "was also a human thing ... not to say
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humane</ENAMEX>" and so "every possible, every imaginable combination of human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> relationships is likely to exist. And did exist ." [Italics
original.] Where is that kind of insightful and original thinking in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> ?

            Which isn't at all to excuse or make apologies for slavery, of course, but
only to argue that our collective memory needs to include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Harlan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">half-brother</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, depending on which biographer
you believe), who was educated by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>, escaped to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, made a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fortune</ENAMEX> in the gold <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX>, returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and bought his freedom, then
moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> to race <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>. Or the mulatto barber and real estate magnate
of antebellum <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Natchez</ENAMEX> (I can't remember his name, but remember, my books are in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">storage</ENAMEX>). He was freed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, then became wealthy enough to lend money
to prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. He was killed in a dispute over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">timber</ENAMEX> by a Pamunkey
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> who would have been considered black in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> but
escaped prosecution because he was considered white in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>.

            I feel like I'm rambling here, and with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 800</NUMEX> words written, I
haven't even gotten round to responding to your points about the responsibility
of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>. Like you, I wish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX> would take
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sabbaticals</ENAMEX> and embark on the kind of lasting work they're both capable of. And
there's an interesting paradox here with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africana</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is probably the
only black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> with the charisma and clout to get it
published. The work itself, alas!, is solid and workmanlike, nothing like what
I think we have the right to expect from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>.

            Take care. It was a pleasure working with you.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
