
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moesha Rehydrates</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Coleman</ENAMEX> Liquidates
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Todd</ENAMEX>,

            I guess the lesson that is to be learned from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> article you
mention on Page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A12</TIMEX> is that if you're going to get involved negotiating with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>-era slaves, you're just going to have to expect them to be a little grumpy
and that is all there is to it.

            I'm terribly sorry to hear about the horrible coffee incident. Nothing
remotely as dramatic happened here with the exception of a particular moment
that takes place many times a week during the dog breakfast period, usually at
about the halfway point. Suddenly all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them seem overcome with the idea
that someone else got a better breakfast, even though they all get the same
thing. So they freeze. And then, in a move not totally dissimilar to musical
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">chairs</ENAMEX>, they all change places and grab a different bowl. It's kind of Joffrey
Ballet moment and it's very, very beautiful, as you can imagine. Particularly
at this time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            They're reporting in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastor</ENAMEX> was
defrocked for officiating at the wedding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. I can not for the life of
me understand why so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so upset at the idea of gay marriages.
It's not as if the heterosexuals have been doing such a great job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keepers</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX>. I mean, the heterosexuals could not have made a bigger mess of the
whole marriage thing if they had intentionally set out to do so. In fact, it
often occurs to me that it would be a very good idea to just give the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> of marriage exclusively to the gay community for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8 years</TIMEX> and
let them refurbish it, like they do with rundown neighborhoods. Then, once
they've fixed it all up and made it cute and appealing again, we can have it
back to defile and degrade.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> is reporting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> is reporting (and now
I am reporting) that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moesha</ENAMEX> wound up dehydrated because of diet
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>. I suspected as much from the start. I thought to myself "Aha! I bet
she's taking diuretics." But I didn't say anything because I didn't want to
upset you. You are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>. You don't know about these things. But we
here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> know that although it doesn't happen often, every now again one of
our TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> is not as stable as we supposed they were. And I guess that is
what happened here because not only was our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandy/Moesha</ENAMEX> apparently
upset that she "had put on weight in her bust and thighs"; she also revealed
that she did indeed have a very tenuous grasp on reality when, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, she threw her script at the show's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>'s on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX> and screamed,
"This is a bunch of crap and I'm not doing it anymore!" Plus , to add
insult to injury, she then went on to drop to the floor screaming, "I just
can't do it anymore." Can you imagine? Apparently those diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> affected the
way her brain was working because, as I certainly don't have to remind you,
we're talking about the script for Moesha ! I trust that her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> will
see to it that she gets some counseling.

            OK, I'm going to sit down and read the real part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> now. But I do
want to add that after I saw the piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> about the Web site
where the newly bankrupt former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Coleman</ENAMEX> is auctioning off,
among other things, his spatula, his ice scraper, his gray leather couch
(current bid is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$307.50</NUMEX>, but there are still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX> left), and "the shirt off
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>'s back" (opening bid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>, and it says, "We'll even let you take it off
him") in order to raise money "to be able to pay my rent, electricity, car
insurance and water bill" I went snooping around to see if there was something
special I might send to a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>-stained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>. That's
all I'm going to reveal at this point.

         
      
   
