
   
   
      
         
            How Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget Cuts Work</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passed a massive budget bill that included a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.38</NUMEX>
percent "across-the-board" budget cut. How will this cut be applied?

            Although the cut is billed as across-the-board, it affects only
"discretionary" spending, which is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the estimated $1.7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trillion</ENAMEX> budget. Nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 trillion</NUMEX> in spending is deemed "mandatory," so it's
exempt from the cuts. This includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>,
unemployment benefits, government pensions, the earned income tax credit, and
other programs that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is obligated to fund. Although it is not
considered a mandatory expense, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> also exempted military salaries from
the cut--as well as its own.

            To achieve the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.38 percent</NUMEX> reduction, cabinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> will have to cut
that amount from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>' total discretionary spending.
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had originally proposed that the reduction be applied
equally to each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 1,000</NUMEX> discretionary programs listed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appropriation</ENAMEX> bills--that is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> allocation for aircraft
acquisitions and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> budget of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Product Safety</ENAMEX>
Commission would each have been reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.38 percent</NUMEX>. But the final measure
allows the cabinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> to allocate the cut as they see fit. They will
be able to reduce the spending of individual programs by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 15 percent</NUMEX>,
while leaving other programs' budgets alone. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> not granted
this flexibility is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, which is required to distribute the reduction
proportionally among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, procurement, and research programs.

            Next question?

         
      
   
