
   
   
      
         
            Save Our Aging Hardbodies
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Merrill</ENAMEX>,

            It's nice to know that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamptons</ENAMEX> need to cut
costs occasionally. I guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s exercise-machine infomercial
career must not be pulling in as much as revenue as expected. This is
surprising to me, because when I saw it at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three in the morning</TIMEX> the other
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, she looked like she was doing a great job: looked directly into the
camera, smiled broadly and evenly, even turned her head to make eye contact
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> when delivering the line "You're right, it really does
tone the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">calves</ENAMEX>!" The plight of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is an
interesting one. Where do they go after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> is done with them and has
moved on to weightier matters, like running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or opening tacky
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> or dating the next supermodel in line? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie</ENAMEX> at least has her
painting to keep her occupied, apparently having already learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s
lesson about the importance of being free-spirited with her creativity years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, without the benefit of the fashion world's fastest-rising new
purse-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>. (I know about this aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkley</ENAMEX>'s creative life because I
recall she did a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> album cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years back</TIMEX> when they were still
married. Not that I had the record; I saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> about it on Hour
Magazine or something. If I remember right, it had some sort of watercolor
waterfall or river or something, and she explained that the idea "came to [her]
in a dream.") The time is right for a brand-new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Save Our Aging</ENAMEX>
Hardbodies, which would set up a home to provide care for all the
now-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">slightly</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less</NUMEX>-beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> society is no longer interested in.

            And while we're on the topic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really know how to work it for
the camera lens, I see on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> 's front page that the
ever-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photogenic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> went and got his bad self arrested again, this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisenhower High School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Decatur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX> I'm sure his cause was a noble
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and everything, and I don't want to go on and on about this simply because
the good reverend's noted skills at making love to the camera have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhaustively</ENAMEX> remarked upon elsewhere, but it sounds like this incident was
notable even by his standards. Get this: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>] jockeyed for position so frantically that they almost knocked over
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly woman</ENAMEX> in a wheelchair who had come to watch." It goes on to say that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of press was so voluminous that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> had to actually come to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s aid in order to clear a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> so he could get arrested by them. The
photo accompanying the piece looked good, though. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> is biting his lower
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lip</ENAMEX> sternly, looking earnest and rugged like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sometimes chooses to.

            Regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> crash, they say they still don't know if it was
really a deliberate suicide thing or what, but it gives me an idea. Plane
crashes are one of those terrible things, like that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Like Girls Who Wear</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abercrombie & Fitch</ENAMEX>" song or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cervical cancer</ENAMEX>, that just happen without any
exciting drama or justification to explain them away. So, maybe we'd all feel a
little better if every time a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jetliner</ENAMEX> went down, the press concocted a big
exciting international-intrigue murder-mystery plot to go along with it? Later,
after a newer, different disaster had occupied the national attention afresh,
they could announce that subsequent investigations had ruled out the theory.
Meanwhile, everyone would have the comfort of pretending that, in this sad
life, all the tragedy and death wasn't simply meaningless. What do you think?
Will it play in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peoria</ENAMEX>?

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
