
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Castoffs of the Rich and Famous</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Todd</ENAMEX>:

            Thanks so much for the compliments. Although since I was only one of many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX> show, God only knows whose jokes you were
repeating.

            Well, I guess this it. Our last e-mail. Which makes me a little sad, but I
guess my sadness will be offset by the celebration being thrown by our
hate-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>. And their feelings matter, too. To someone. Even if not to
me or you.

            I was holding off buying your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Coleman</ENAMEX> gift after reading in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Barrymore</ENAMEX>'s estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jaid</ENAMEX>, also has a Web site on
which she is auctioning off several collections of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> clothes
(including an undershirt decorated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby chicks</ENAMEX> ). OK, yes, this seems like
a shockingly lowbrow, sociopathically self-serving, egomaniacal betrayal and
perversion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> bond until after you hear how touchingly Jaid
explains it: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew</ENAMEX> is such a special amazing magical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>" she says," that I
decided to put some of her things up on the Web site to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be a
part of her life." And you know, if there is a better way to become a part of
the life of a complete stranger than to own their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> clothing, it can only be
to own their spatula. So I think I have made my gift decision. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>, go buy
yourself some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and sit by the mailbox. Better cooking is on it's way.

            This has been a lot of fun. Thanks.

            
               
                  
Coming in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Smith</ENAMEX> go out to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
