



A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Preliminary Version</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX> was Presented at
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evolving Structure</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Industries June</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-14, 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Helsingør</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>
Sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Research</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulated Industries</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers University</ENAMEX>


AN ANALYSIS OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POTENTIAL FOR CREAM SKIMMING</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
RESIDENTIAL DELIVERY MARKET
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H. Cohen William W. Ferguson John D. Waller Spyros S.</ENAMEX>
Xenakis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of Rates, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1998</TIMEX>
Published in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Emerging Competition</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> and Delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.A. Crew</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis of the Potential for Cream Skimming</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Residential Delivery Market</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Introduction</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> often claim that without a legal
monopoly1 to protect them from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX>, they would not be
able to continue providing universal service at uniform and
affordable prices. Because they serve delivery points with a range
of profitability, postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> fear that without monopoly
protection cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX> would capture their high profit routes,
leaving them with their less profitable routes. The question is,
would cream skimming divert so much volume that universal service
at affordable prices becomes infeasible?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden</ENAMEX> is the only industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> which actually has had
competition in its letter mail market after abolishing its
monopoly<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Mail</ENAMEX>, has served selected portions of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but was twice forced into bankruptcy<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Mail</ENAMEX> has
again emerged from bankruptcy and is competing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden Post</ENAMEX>.
Perhaps on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Mail</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> attempt, we will finally have a valid
test of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden Post</ENAMEX> actually needs monopoly protection in
order to provide universal service at reasonable prices. As far as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> know, the economics of the competition between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> has not been studied. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Mail</ENAMEX> finally
succeeds in avoiding bankruptcy, such a study might determine the
reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden Post</ENAMEX> was vulnerable to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX>. In
addition, it might describe the impact that a viable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> has
had on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, as in most industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, the postal monopoly
extends only to letter mail (including addressed advertising).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finland</ENAMEX> has abolished its monopoly and in so doing created a
licensing system for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finland Post</ENAMEX>. No other operator
has yet begun to offer service in competition with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finland Post</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> has also just recently abolished its monopoly, but it
is too early to know if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> will emerge and be
successful.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
A recent study found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish Postal Service</ENAMEX> had engaged
in a variety of anti-competitive practices with respect to its
competitor. See "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deregulation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s Market;
report on the abuse by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Office</ENAMEX> of Its dominant market
position and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Competition Authority</ENAMEX>'s handling of the
question of competition in relation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Professor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Nerep</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stockholm School of Economics</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1995</TIMEX>.
the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>. It should be noted that the presence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Mail</ENAMEX> has already prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden Post</ENAMEX> to lower prices for
large volume mailers in areas served by its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>.4
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cream skimmers</ENAMEX> take advantage of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX>'s price when it is
based on an average of heterogeneous costs. They serve the low cost
portion of the market and price below the incumbent. Conceptually
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic dimensions - product and geography.
Product <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX> is where a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> tries to capture the
most profitable portion of the market for a product with
heterogeneous costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Geographic cream skimming</ENAMEX> is where a
competitor tries to provide a service only to selected, low cost
areas<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Mail</ENAMEX> is an example of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">geographic cream skimming</ENAMEX>. Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> provide twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> delivery to various areas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>
for large volume <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.6 This paper addresses only geographic
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
Postal monopolies, like most other legal monopolies, are thought
by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) to be technically inefficient, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) to
have delivery functions which exhibit economies of scale<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> This
paper addresses several questions which arise from these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points
under the assumption that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> and any other barriers to
entry were to be removed. It asks how much more efficient would a
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> have to be to overcome the scale economies of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>? Assuming potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> are able to
achieve the necessary level of efficiency, it then asks how much
volume might they be able to capture and in which markets? Finally,
it asks what effect
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
It would be interesting to learn: How much it cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden Post</ENAMEX>
to serve the areas where it lowered prices relative to its average
cost, how important the abandonment of universal pricing is to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden Post</ENAMEX>'s competitive position, and are the circumstances in
Sweden applicable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section J</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> examines
this issue further.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cream skimming</ENAMEX> may have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> dimension having to do with
transactions costs. In practice cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX> may restrict
themselves to large volume <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> since the transaction costs of
dealing with smaller volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prohibitive</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden Post</ENAMEX> delivers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> per week.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
A report by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>) at least
partially analyzed the effect <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimming</ENAMEX> would have on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>. Its assessment was as follows: Priority
Mail (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 11 ounces</NUMEX>) - high risk of loss of
significant volumes, but a low financial impact, if it did occur;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Class</ENAMEX> - low risk of loss of significant volumes, but a high
financial impact, if it did occur; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising Mail</ENAMEX> low risk of
loss and a medium financial impact, if it did occur. See "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reform; Issues Relevant to Changing Restrictions on Private</ENAMEX>
Letter Delivery," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1996</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> include the local delivery of
electricity, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, water and until recently telephone.
would the loss of volume to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> have on the resulting
prices the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would have to charge in order to maintain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> service?
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
would serve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and leave rural areas to the universal service
provider because they assume that the cost of delivery to rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> is much higher than the cost of delivery to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. An
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier study9</TIMEX> challenged that assumption. It estimated that in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> city delivery cost per piece was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 8 percent</NUMEX> lower than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> delivery, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery cost per delivery point was
actually <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> higher than rural delivery cost. It concluded
that there was no cross subsidy of rural delivery by city delivery.
In theory, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimming</ENAMEX> of residential service could occur in
either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or rural areas. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> focuses on city delivery
because of the more detailed data available on this type of
delivery.
We first provide a brief description of the current competition
in delivery. We then describe the data used in our analysis and the
costs and profitability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s city residential
delivery routes. We next examine the volume vulnerable to capture
by potential cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX>. We describe characteristics of routes
most likely to be profitable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> and provide a range of
estimates for the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>. After examining the
consequences of successful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> skimming on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> rates,
we explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX> is not likely to be successful on
business routes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S. Finally</ENAMEX>, we provide some observations
on the relevance this analysis may have for other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">B. Current Competition In Delivery</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Competitors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> may legally deliver only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">periodicals</ENAMEX>, catalogues over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> pages, parcels, and unaddressed
letters<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> Alternative delivery is particularly difficult because
of the so called mail box law which prohibits any one but the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen, Ferguson & Xenakis</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rural Delivery and the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Service Obligation</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantitative Investigation</ENAMEX>."
Regulation and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Delivery Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Kleindorfer, Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.
Technically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> is primarily a revenue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX>.
A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> may deliver a letter if proper postage is affixed and
canceled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> also has an urgent mail exception for
letters which are charged twice normal First-Class postage with a
minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.00</NUMEX>. Unlike most industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, there is no
exemption from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> based on weight or price.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> from accessing a private mail box<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> broadly interprets "letter" to include any addressed
information recorded on a physical object. Thus, for example, it
considers an addressed grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> advertisement to be a
letter.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Express</ENAMEX> was founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meredith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express Publishing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror Co.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. R. Donnelley</ENAMEX>, among others, to provide
alternative delivery<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> In spite of its prestigious sponsorship,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> ceased operations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Many other small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> provide alternative delivery, but they have a very
small share of the market. They are scattered around the country
and mostly deliver unaddressed "saturation" advertisements and
small quantities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> and small parcels.
The real alternative delivery system in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is the
newspaper industry which delivers advertising preprints or
inserts<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> has the advantage of being able to
deliver these advertisements to all addresses, while newspapers
usually (but not always) deliver inserts just to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>.
A typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 50 percent</NUMEX> coverage
in its service area. This puts it at a disadvantage vis a vis the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>, which delivers to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX>, on
the other hand, have the advantage of charging lower prices.
Because marginal costs are very low, a newspaper price for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preprints</ENAMEX> might be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as low as 5</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 cents</NUMEX> per piece. The lowest
rate currently charged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.0</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11.4 cents</NUMEX>
for saturation mail weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 3.3 ounces</NUMEX> and drop shipped at
the delivery office<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspapers</ENAMEX> deliver <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 86 billion</NUMEX> inserts
annually<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,15</NUMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> delivers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 11</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> competing items<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX>
11
As far as we know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that has a mail
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">box</ENAMEX> rule.
12
For a more comprehensive discussion of alternative delivery in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office Study</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">n. 7,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supra</ENAMEX>.
13
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> also deliver <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product samples</ENAMEX>.
14
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> has an additional disadvantage because city
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> deliver only addressed advertising mail. This requires the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailer</ENAMEX> to have an address list kept in delivery sequence and to
have address labels for each piece.
15
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspaper Association of America's WEB Site</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">naa</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/marketscope/databank/preppriyr.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm.</ENAMEX>
16
This was the saturation and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX>-piece walk sequence Enhanced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrier Route</ENAMEX> mail volume in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Many of these items are so
called "marriage mail" pieces which contain several individual
advertisements combined into a single piece. These individual
advertisements could each be a stand-alone insert. Thus, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11 billion</NUMEX>
pieces is an extreme lower bound on the number of preprints carried
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. City Carrier Data</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> conducts a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Carrier Survey</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCS</ENAMEX>) of delivered mail volume by route. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1993 and 1996</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> conducted the survey using a relatively small panel
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 400</NUMEX> routes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> Prior to that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> randomly
sampled a much larger cross section of its routes over the course
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. The last set of cross sectional data filed with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> consisted of a sample of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,092</NUMEX>
different routes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.18</NUMEX> Because of the large sample size, these data
are far more useful for our analysis than the subsequent panel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>.19
Each record in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CCS</ENAMEX> contains the date of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5-Digit ZIP Code</ENAMEX> in which the route is located,
the route type<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,20</NUMEX> the number of pieces (by subclass and by shape)
per stop, the number of possible deliveries and actual deliveries
per stop, and the stop type ("single delivery residential,"
"multi-delivery residential," and "business-and-mixed"). Generally,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> are recorded for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> stop on a route. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> were
able to make use of the records for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,884</NUMEX> routes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.21</NUMEX> This analysis
is based on the data set of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,212</NUMEX> usable residential <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">routes22</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">476,953</NUMEX> stops. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 About 89 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> routes are
residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>. The rest are business or mixed (residential and
business).


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D. Postal Service Delivery Cost And Profitability</ENAMEX>
This analysis uses delivery data from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, but uses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> cost
levels for wages, fringe benefits, and other associated delivery
costs. Total volume grew <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13.5 percent</NUMEX>
17
A panel survey collects data repeatedly from the same
sample.
18
There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">157 thousand</NUMEX> city delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. There
were also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 thousand</NUMEX> rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>, most of which had costs
comparable to city delivery routes. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen, Ferguson</ENAMEX> &
Xenakis, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n. 9</ENAMEX>, supra.
19
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCS</ENAMEX> data were not available when the analysis for this
paper was conducted.
20
Business foot, business motorized, residential foot, residential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX> and loop, residential curb, mixed foot, mixed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and loop,
and mixed curb.
21
The data are organized by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> pay periods in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Portions
of the data from a few pay periods were not usable. Comparisons
with previously published summaries indicate that the missing data
did not bias our results.
22
To a much lesser extent this analysis makes use of data from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">717</NUMEX>
business routes.
23
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94%</NUMEX>) of these stops are residential, while
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> percent (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>) are either business, or mixed
business-and-residential stops. Not all stops on a residential
route are <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>. Some are business stops and some are mixed
(business and residential).
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1989 and 1996</TIMEX>, and the number of routes increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
percent. We make no attempt to adjust for these increases.
When calculating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery cost, we include the entire
(fixed and volume variable) in-office and out-of-office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">cost24</TIMEX> for
all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> routes, plus the cost of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overtime</TIMEX>, supervision, space, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>. Starting with a productive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25.25</NUMEX> for city
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>, we calculate a cost per residential delivery route of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$266</NUMEX> per delivery <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day.25</TIMEX> The cost we calculate can be considered to
be the avoided cost or the incremental cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery
function. Alternatively, it can be considered a lower bound on the
stand-alone cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.26</NUMEX>
We calculate the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> profit of residential delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> by totaling the revenue minus collection,
processing and transportation costs of the mail delivered on each
route and subtracting the delivery cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$266</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> displays a variety of mean route statistics for
residential routes separated into quartiles based on their profit.
less As can be seen, the mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> profit of each <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">quartile</ENAMEX> ranges
from positive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$248 to negative $110</NUMEX>. The average profit for all
residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$41</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46.5 percent</NUMEX> of the routes operating
at a loss. The route cost per piece ranges from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.6 cents</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cents</ENAMEX>, and averages <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.5 cents</NUMEX>. Route volume ranges from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,485</NUMEX>
pieces to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,131</NUMEX> pieces, and averages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,128</NUMEX> pieces. The number of
possible deliveries (which ranges from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">670 to 411</TIMEX>) is dependent on
route terrain. 27 All the statistics presented are monotonic
across28 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quartiles</ENAMEX> except for route type. This is because of the
close relationship between cost (per piece, delivery and stop),
volume
24
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In-office</ENAMEX>" refers to the in the office activity of a letter
carrier (primarily sequencing mail to be delivered),
"out-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>" refers to the activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> while on the
street.
25
This is based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> total cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33.20</NUMEX>
per hour. This, in turn, is based on a productive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> rate (pay,
overtime pay, and benefits for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> worked) increased to account
for other costs that can be associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. These other
costs include systemwide labor related costs (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s
compensation, civil service retirement unfunded liability),
indirect labor such as carrier supervision, vehicle costs, and
space related costs (rents, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>, utilities, custodial
maintenance). The standard work day for a city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> is eight
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.
26
It is a lower bound because the cost includes no marketing or
administrative costs which a stand-alone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> would normally
incur.
27
By "physical terrain" we mean the physical proximity of the
delivery points and whether they are most advantageously served by
a curb, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park & loop</ENAMEX>, or foot route.
28
A monotonic series is one whose every term is greater than (less
than) or equal to the previous term. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
(per piece, delivery and stop), and the number of deliveries
(stops) on a route. With respect to route type, we see that the
percentage of curb routes is greatest in the most profitable
quartile<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29</NUMEX> These routes are largely a suburban phenomenon, they
reach more stops in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> and hence, have more volume. The appendix
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table A1</ENAMEX>) presents demographic characteristics related to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quartiles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Table 1</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SELECTED AVERAGES FOR RESIDENTIAL ROUTES WHEN ROUTES ARE SORTED</ENAMEX>
BY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PROFIT PER ROUTE</ENAMEX>
Profit Cost (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per</ENAMEX> (possible) Volume Pieces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per</ENAMEX> (possible)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quartile</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piece Delivery Stop</ENAMEX> (pieces) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deliverya Stop</ENAMEX>


a
In the paper referenced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">n. 9</TIMEX>, supra, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> per possible
delivery were weighed by stop and produced a slightly higher pieces
per delivery. Here they are unweighted.
The revenue for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46.5 percent</NUMEX> of the routes (all of quartile <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
and most of quartile <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) is not enough to cover the costs of the
mail delivered on those routes. Thus, it might be argued that a
monopoly is necessary to ensure service to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. For
several reasons, it would seem the burden of proof for this
position should fall on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX>. The routes which are
unprofitable are dispersed across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in a great number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. A competitive postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> that refused to serve
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> on unprofitable
Curb routes deliver directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> to a curbside mail
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">receptacle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> and loop routes involve parking, covering an area
by foot, then parking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> in a new area.
routes would impose large transaction costs on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to
separate mail and to secure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> to deliver its remaining
mail. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> would be at a considerable disadvantage to those
providing universal service. Larger transaction networks (be they
mail, packages, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> or telephone) are more valuable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> than smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. It is for sound
business reasons that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Express</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Parcel Service</ENAMEX>
provide universal delivery service. A major business asset of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> and all other national posts is that they
provide service to every address in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> they serve. Thus,
there is a business incentive for any postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> (who is not
simply a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmer</ENAMEX>) to offer universal service within the
territories it serves.
Routes which are unprofitable when serviced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> per week
would become profitable when serviced less frequently. In a
competitive environment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> could easily retain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> service, but perhaps not a universal service standard<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.30</NUMEX>
Delivery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than six days</TIMEX> per week would certainly be preferable
to abandoning delivery altogether. Of course, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
were to simply abandon delivery to unprofitable routes, it would
not have to refuse, return or destroy mail destined to these
routes. Delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> with lower costs than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
would emerge to serve them and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> could hand off
its unprofitable mail to them. 31 Under any foreseeable
circumstances, universal delivery would not cease<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.32</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Volume Available For Cream Skimmers</ENAMEX>
It is unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> would base their selection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> to serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s delivery profits. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service delivery profitability depends on the revenue for all mail
delivered, and it is not likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> could capture
all categories of mail.
30
It is interesting to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Parcel Service</ENAMEX> recently
began delivery less frequently than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to certain residential
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>.
31
Costs would be lower by dint of lower wages and/or less frequent
delivery.
32
The concept of a universal service obligation may really mean
more frequent delivery than economically warranted for households
living on unprofitable routes. This, of course, is in addition to
providing retail services to rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Residential cream skimmers</ENAMEX> would serve bulk mailers with
sufficient volumes of mail for the areas they serve. We assume that
only mail that is presorted to the carrier route level would be
vulnerable to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX>. If a bulk <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mailer</ENAMEX> did not have
sufficient volume to sort to the carrier route level, the
transaction costs for both mailer and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimmer</ENAMEX> would be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prohibitive</ENAMEX>. Of course, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> might become intermediaries
between these bulk mailers and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> would
have to engage in processing and transportation. They would in
effect be a parallel postal system for bulk mailers. An analysis of
separate postal systems for bulk mailers is beyond the scope of
this paper.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> requires First-Class and advertising
mail to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least ten</NUMEX> pieces for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> to qualify for a
carrier route discount. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publications</ENAMEX> may qualify with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as few as six</NUMEX>
pieces for a carrier route. The amounts being presorted to the
carrier route level in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> are shown in the right hand column:

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> is unzoned and receives no discount for being
deposited near its destination. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">First-Class</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route
volume is prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> and may be local depending on the
billing operations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>. For purposes of this analysis we
assume that all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">First-Class</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route mail is available to
local cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publications Mail</ENAMEX>. While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 3.2 billion</NUMEX> pieces of the carrier
route volume is entered locally or entered close enough to its
destination to be available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>, we assume that all
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.5 billion</NUMEX> pieces are available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising Mail</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">85</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25.2 billion</NUMEX> pieces
of carrier route advertising mail are drop shipped or entered
locally. Notwithstanding, we assume here that all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route
advertising mail would be available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>.
To summarize, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37.7 billion</NUMEX> pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route volume are
potentially available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>.33 This represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.6</NUMEX>
percent of the total volume of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">182.7 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Geographic cream skimmers</ENAMEX> would concentrate on areas with the most
carrier route volume because their cost per piece would be lowest
and their potential profit would be the greatest.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> displays mean daily route statistics for routes when
divided into quartiles reflecting their volumes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route
mail. We see a wide divergence in carrier route volume among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quartiles</ENAMEX>. The range is from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,263</NUMEX> pieces to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX> pieces with an
average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">551</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> quartile routes have more than twice the
volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route mail as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> quartile. In fact, the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> quartile has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route volume
delivered on residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>. Thus, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> quartile of routes
are much more attractive targets for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> than the other
routes. We again see a monotonic behavior of the other variables
across quartiles<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Route</ENAMEX> profitability by quartile in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>
changes by a sizable amount as compared to route profitability in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. Less than half the routes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quartile 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, are also
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quartile 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. The appendix (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table A2</ENAMEX>) presents
demographic characteristics related to the quartiles in Table
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
33
Some of this mail is delivered by rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. For purpose of
this analysis, we assume that rural delivery is subject to the same
degree of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery. However, some carrier
route mail is delivered on business routes and some is delivered
via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> boxes and, thus, would not be available to cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX>. Consequently, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37.7 billion</NUMEX> represents an upper bound of
the volume available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>.
34
The only deviation from the monotonic behavior in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> occurs
for deliveries per route between quartiles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Table 2</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SELECTED AVERAGES FOR RESIDENTIAL ROUTES WHEN ROUTES ARE SORTED</ENAMEX>
BY VOLUME OF <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARRIER ROUTE MAIL PER ROUTE</ENAMEX>
Profit Cost (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per</ENAMEX> (possible) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quartile</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX>) Piece
Delivery Stop
Volume (pieces) All Carrier Pieces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per</ENAMEX> (possible) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail Route</ENAMEX>
Delivery Stop




<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Estimating</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Delivery Cost For Cream Skimmers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cream skimmers</ENAMEX> undercut prices charged by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> that has
heterogeneous costs but averaged prices. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cream skimmers</ENAMEX> profit by
selling low cost items at below the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> average price.
Delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> would attempt to serve those areas where
the cost to deliver carrier route pieces is the lowest (i.e., where
the volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carrier route pieces</ENAMEX> is the highest). The first
quartile of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> would make the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. It is
this case we examine.
In an important sense, this is an unrealistic case since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">quartile 1</ENAMEX> represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> routes which are scattered over more
than half the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">30,000 5-Digit ZIP Code</ENAMEX> areas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> It is
extremely unlikely that they constitute all the residential routes
in any <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5-Digit ZIP Code</ENAMEX> nor is it likely that they make up the
entire suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. It is unrealistic for cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX> to serve such a fragmented market. From both an
operational and marketing standpoint, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> would have to
serve markets with at best a large proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> in quartile
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Their markets would undoubtedly contain a large number of routes
in the other quartiles. Notwithstanding, for analytical purposes,
we assume the best possible case for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>; that they
would be able to serve only routes that fall within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quartile 1</TIMEX>.
A potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> must decide the level of service to
provide and this decision would affect the amount of volume that it
could actually capture. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, and
advertisements must be delivered within a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three day</TIMEX>
window. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> delivering only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day a week</TIMEX> would have to
forego much potential volume. On the other hand, delivery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> would certainly raise the cost per delivered piece and make
it less likely that a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimmer</ENAMEX> would be viable<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Mail</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweden</ENAMEX> chose to deliver <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in some
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in other areas).
In all probability, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmer</ENAMEX> could not prosper unless it
could deliver mail at a price less than the incumbent postal
administration. Its cost per delivered piece would be a function of
its cost of labor and productivity. It would be expected that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmer</ENAMEX> would have a significant labor cost advantage. Its
productivity would be influenced by the in-office and out-of-office
technology it employed. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> spent more
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of their time in-office preparing for delivery on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mailstreams</ENAMEX> must be merged and sorted into
delivery sequence<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.36</NUMEX> It is not clear what technology cream skimmers
would use. Moreover, we do not know whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmer</ENAMEX> would be more productive on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. This analysis will combine these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variables</ENAMEX> (labor cost, technology, in-office and out-of-office
productivity) into a single efficiency parameter.
35
In a sense, each piece of advertising mail competes with other
advertising mail for the recipient's attention. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> skimmer
could capture a large portion of the available carrier route
volume, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> might prefer more frequent delivery to
minimize this type of competition.
36
This function is rapidly being automated for letter size mail in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Delivery point barcoded mail is increasingly being
sequenced on sorting machines, saving significant in-office
delivery time. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1989 to 1996</TIMEX>, the percentage of in-office time
for city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> has declined from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent to 34 percent</NUMEX>. It is
expected that this trend will continue. Unless a potential cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skimmer</ENAMEX> had enough capital to employ sequencing automation, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> might have a significant advantage in sequencing and
merging letter-shaped mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class is almost all letter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shaped</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> are almost all flat shaped, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route
advertising is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> letter shaped.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Cream Skimmers Cost Per Piece</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> matrices, each reflecting a different
percentage of available volume assumed to be captured by cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX>. Each matrix presents cream skimmer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> or per piece
costs based on frequency of delivery and relative efficiency of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmer</ENAMEX>. We measure relative efficiency in terms of cream
skimmers cost relative to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s cost.
The shaded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in the top matrix, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13.1 cents</NUMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service cost per piece for delivering only carrier route presorted
mail in the least expensive quartile. This number is derived from
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.7 cent</NUMEX> cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> delivering all mail in the
least expensive quartile shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. If only the carrier
route mail is delivered, the average delivered volume decreases
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,051 to 1,263</NUMEX> in this quartile. The variable costs drop as
the volume drops, but the fixed costs are spread over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less</TIMEX> volume
which increases the fixed costs proportionately. The result is an
increase in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13.1 cents</NUMEX> shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. Going down that column, the costs
per piece are displayed assuming a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimmer</ENAMEX> had the same cost
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>, but delivers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fewer days</TIMEX> per week. The
costs decrease by the amount of fixed costs in delivery. The
variable cost remains the same because the volume does not change.
Most other national postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> would have a greater
percentage of fixed costs because they have fewer pieces per
possible delivery<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.37</NUMEX>
The columns display cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX>' costs as a function of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> efficiency, expressed as a percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s delivery cost per piece. The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">120 percent</NUMEX> column displays
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimmer</ENAMEX>'s per piece cost if its cost were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">120 percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>.38 The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> column displays the cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skimmer</ENAMEX>'s per piece cost if its cost were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Table 3</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CREAM SKIMMER</ENAMEX>'S <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">COST PER PIECE IN CENTS AS A FUNCTION OF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EFFICIENCY RELATIVE TO POSTAL SERVICE, DAYS OF DELIVERY AND PERCENT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OF CARRIER ROUTE MAIL</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> OF CARRIER ROUTE VOLUME CAPTURED

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> OF CARRIER ROUTE VOLUME CAPTURED

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> OF CARRIER ROUTE VOLUME CAPTURED

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> OF CARRIER ROUTE VOLUME CAPTURED

For all mail the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> cost (fixed and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">variable</ENAMEX>) is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.5 cents</NUMEX> per piece. (See Tables <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX>, cost per
piece all routes.) This is the cost for the delivery function. Each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> product has a variable cost for mail processing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX> and delivery. Each product also has an average
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incremental</ENAMEX> (avoidable) cost. In the case of advertising carrier
route mail, the average incremental cost is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 7 cents.39</NUMEX> If
threatened by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> could respond by
lowering its price towards average incremental costs. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service maintained uniform prices but had competition only in
selected areas, it would sacrifice revenue in those areas without
competition. These circumstances would probably call for selective
discounts (with average incremental costs as a floor) to large
volume mailers40 who would otherwise become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> of cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX>. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> would most likely have to have costs
no higher than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately 7 cents</NUMEX> per piece in order to compete
on a cost basis alone<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.41</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s productive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> wage of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $25</NUMEX> may
make it likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> could obtain some cost advantage
on that basis alone. We do not know how reducing the frequency of
delivery would affect demand for alternative delivery. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX>
frequency could satisfy a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day</TIMEX> window, but would miss many
delivery dates for time value <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. It should also be noted
that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> may not be willing to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
for a variety of reasons including the sense of security of dealing
with a government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.
If a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmer</ENAMEX> were to capture <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 25 percent</NUMEX> of the
available market, it would have difficulty succeeding. At that
level of market penetration, its costs would have to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> frequency in order to be below
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> incremental costs. With <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the average
volume at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> frequency, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimmer</ENAMEX>'s costs would have
to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> or less of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s in order to remain
below the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s average incremental costs.
39
The variable cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route advertising mail comes
predominantly from the delivery function (in-office and
out-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>). The delivery function is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50 percent</NUMEX> variable.
Thus, the variable cost of the advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route mail
product can be much lower than the average (fixed and variable)
cost of delivery. The average incremental cost of advertising
carrier route mail is only slightly higher than the variable cost
since we estimate it here to consist of variable costs plus single
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subclass</ENAMEX> stop costs for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
40
Except for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> with a very high elasticity of demand,
there is no reason for a monopoly to grant volume based discounts
since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> have no alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>. We understand this
was the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>, which had a virtual monopoly in surface
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parcel</ENAMEX> delivery in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, and did not give discounts to surface
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parcel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roadway Package Service</ENAMEX> began to target its
most lucrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> then began offering
discounts to certain large volume <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.
41
Some mailers currently use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> because of service
considerations.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H. Consequences Of Successful Cream</ENAMEX> Skimming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX> shows the required increase in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>
rates based on the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route volume that would be
captured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> targeting mail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quartile 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2.42</ENAMEX>
The maximum effect is an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 1.2 cents</NUMEX> in the
First-Class rate (with corresponding increases in the other
classes). This would be an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 4 percent</NUMEX>; a
significant but limited effect.
Lifting the letter mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> and allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> skimming
would likely have an important impact on rate setting for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s large volume carrier route <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, if our
assumptions are correct concerning the amount of volume available
for capture by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>. The maximum impact on overall postal
rates is, however, likely to be limited. The negative impact on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s finances would likely be offset to a great extent
by the effect of limited competition on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s
efficiency, service performance and product innovation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Table 4 IMPACT OF CREAM SKIMMING</ENAMEX> ON



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. Comparison Of Business And Residential Routes</ENAMEX>
We do not analyze <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> skimming on business routes because only
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> of mail volume delivered on them is carrier route as
compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX> on residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>. This makes them
unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimming</ENAMEX> based on our analysis. We
compare several statistics for city residential and business routes
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5 COSTS BY TYPE OF CITY DELIVERY ROUTE</ENAMEX>

It can be seen that business routes have slightly more pieces
per route with slightly higher cost per piece.43 The cost per
delivery point and stop on business routes is much higher, but the
profit per piece remains higher<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.44</NUMEX>
We are not aware of any study that has identified the reasons
why business routes have a higher cost per piece and much higher
cost per stop than residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>. Several factors may
contribute, including the high cost of serving each individual
business in office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. In contrast, residential apartment
houses generally have mail boxes in one central and convenient
location for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. Other factors include the larger proportion
of business mail requiring signatures and the greater difficulty of
getting around in congested business areas as opposed to
residential and suburban neighborhoods. Because business routes
have much higher cost per delivery point, they
43
Business routes get much more assistance from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">routers</ENAMEX> who
sequence the mail in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, thus saving in-office time for the
carrier. The cost per piece and per delivery point reflects these
extra costs.
44
Profit is higher on business routes than on residential routes
because of greater volumes of high profit mail, such as on Priority
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cream skimming</ENAMEX> delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> might be developed
for such mail in business areas, but are beyond the scope of this
paper.
are unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">geographic cream skimmers</ENAMEX> who could
be expected to have far fewer pieces over which to spread the cost
per delivery point<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.45</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Some Differences Between the U.S.</ENAMEX> and Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Countries</ENAMEX>
The classification <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> in industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have
varying degrees of efficiency (defined as adherence to cost)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.46</NUMEX>
Efficient classification discourages cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX> because it
leaves less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> to skim. The less efficient the classification
structure, the more the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> needs monopoly protection.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s classification structure contains several
score of cost based discounts and rate differentials, probably more
than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.47</NUMEX> This should tend to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
less vulnerable to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX>. Moreover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has more
pieces per capita than virtually any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Because the
delivery function has important economies of scale, ceteris
paribus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> should have lower per piece costs than virtually
every other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. This factor also makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> less
vulnerable to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX>. In addition, the proportion of fixed
cost in the delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is largely a function of volume per
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capita</ENAMEX> (per delivery). The larger the volume per capita, the larger
the proportion of variable costs and the smaller the proportion of
fixed costs. Since virtually every other postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has
less volume per capita than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, a larger proportion of their
delivery costs are fixed relative to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmer</ENAMEX> can
reduce its fixed cost relative to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> simply by reducing
the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of delivery. Thus, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimmer</ENAMEX> would obtain
less cost advantage by cutting delivery frequency in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> than
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with less per capita volume. This also tends to make
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> less vulnerable to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX> than other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.48
45
Of course, messenger services are common in central business
districts, but this is for reasons of service and not cost.
46
The most efficient classification structure would be based on
costs alone and would offer worksharing discounts wherever
practical. These discounts would equal the cost savings. No postal
administration meets this standard nor do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> recommend
that they do.
47
Advertising mail alone has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 60</NUMEX> different rate categories
with rate differentials based on shape and discounts for
presorting, barcoding and drop shipping.
48
A consequence of this is that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> which delivers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> per week, ceteris paribus, is a more difficult target for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> than one which delivers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> per week.
On the other hand, some factors appear to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service more vulnerable than other postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> to cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skimming</ENAMEX>. Few, if any, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have as large a proportion of
carrier route volume as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> This is the mail most
susceptible to diversion. In addition, few postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>
pay their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> as large a wage premium as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.49</NUMEX> A wage premium allows cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX> to obtain an
efficiency/cost advantage simply by paying the prevailing wage.
49 See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen, Chu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson & Xenakis</ENAMEX>, "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> Sectional
Comparison and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> of Productivity for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Administrations</ENAMEX>." Managing Change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> and Delivery
Industries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crew & Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.


APPENDIX
This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s analysis is based on volume and delivery statistics
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,212</NUMEX> residential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> routes. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> were extracted
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrier Cost Survey</ENAMEX> (CCS), conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. In addition to the volume and delivery statistics
for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,212</NUMEX> residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCS</ENAMEX> provides the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated 5-Digit ZIP Code</ENAMEX> served by each route. A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP Code</ENAMEX> may be
served by many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>. The data presented in this appendix are
based on the demographic data for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5-Digit ZIP Code</ENAMEX> for each
route in a quartile. Thus, the demographic data for the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5-Digit ZIP Code</ENAMEX> could be averaged into the totals for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
different quartiles. This would happen if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> routes from the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5-Digit ZIP Code</ENAMEX> were in separate quartiles.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Bureau of the Census</ENAMEX> has grouped the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census of Population and Housing</ENAMEX> data using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-Digit ZIP Codes</ENAMEX>. The
file (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3B</ENAMEX>) is available in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three</TIMEX> CDs of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1.4</NUMEX> gigabytes
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GBs</ENAMEX>) and contains socio-economic data for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,467</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-Digit ZIP Codes</ENAMEX>
served by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Rico ZIP Codes</ENAMEX> are
not included in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3B</ENAMEX> file.
By merging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3B</ENAMEX> file with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCS</ENAMEX> data, we have obtained
economic and demographic data for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZIP Codes</ENAMEX> in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,876</NUMEX>
residential routes reside. We could not obtain any socio-economic
information for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP Codes</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">336</NUMEX> residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most of</TIMEX>
them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>) because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZIP Codes</ENAMEX> were not included in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3B</ENAMEX> file.
Tables <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A1 through A3</TIMEX> provide statistics for age, household
income, and education attainment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5-Digit ZIP Code</ENAMEX> for the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,876</NUMEX> residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCS</ENAMEX>. Table <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A1</TIMEX> presents the statistics
by quartile when routes are sorted by profitability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tables A2</ENAMEX> and
A3 present the statistics by quartile and decile respectively when
routes are sorted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route volume. The statistics in Table
A1 show that, on average, routes in the more profitable quartiles
reside in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZIP Codes</ENAMEX> with higher income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and more educated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. Likewise, the statistics in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tables A2</ENAMEX> and A3 show that
routes with high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route volume reside in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZIP Codes</ENAMEX> with
higher levels of household income and education attainment.







