



Towards a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Postal Service</ENAMEX> Cost Function*
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Cohen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Pace</ENAMEX>
Poste Italiane
Antónia Rato
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTT - Correios de Portugal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Robinson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricardo Santos</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTT - Correios de Portugal</ENAMEX>
Gennaro Scarfiglieri
Poste Italiane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincenzo Visco Comandini</ENAMEX>
Poste Italiane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
Spyros Xenakis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
*The views expressed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> are those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and
do not necessarilyrepresent the opinions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTT - Correios de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal RateCommission</ENAMEX>.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTRODUCTION</ENAMEX>
Mailhandling activities in the posts of industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are
remarkably alike. Each of the major functions (delivery, mail
processing, transportation, and window <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>) is conducted using
similar methods and technologies. Therefore, it may be possible for
a fairly simple model to explain total and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost differences
between posts. Ideally, developing a cost model for the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX> plus
industrial posts would involve collecting data on many individual
cost elements from each and using regression analysis to estimate
the coefficients of a cost function. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s environment this is
impossible because virtually all posts in industrial countries
consider much of their operational cost data to be commercially
sensitive and will not share them.
In our previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), we developed a
model that related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs to volume per capita. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is
based on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> costs. More specifically, it is based on the accrued
cost of the major functions and their cost elasticities with
respect to volume. A plot of that cost function reveals the classic
hyperbolic shape with unit costs increasing more rapidly as volume
per capita declines because of the loss of economies of scale. See
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
In our previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, we made adjustments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> to allow
for comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX>. In particular, adjustments were
made for differences in labor cost, amount of worksharing, and mix
of mail by shape<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, we add an adjustment for counter
costs<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.2</NUMEX> The resulting model estimate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost
is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">74 cents</NUMEX> versus the actual value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">79 cents</NUMEX>. It must be pointed
out that the cost model is used to estimate costs over an extreme
range of volume. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> volume per capita in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">739</NUMEX> pieces
while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX> pieces per capita. Given this range, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> are encouraged by the relatively small deviation of the
estimate from actual.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
See the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appendix</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters</ENAMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters</ENAMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model Estimates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unit Cost</ENAMEX>
Benchmarked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Costs and Volumes</ENAMEX>
2.50
2.00
Cost per Piece (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$US</NUMEX>)
1.50
1.00
0.50
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.00 0 100 200 300 400 500 600 700 800</NUMEX>

Pieces per Capita
In this paper we examine the hypothesis that the cost model
provides reasonable estimates of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs of other posts of
industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.3 The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypothesis</ENAMEX> cannot, however, be
directly confirmed because we do not have sufficient cost data on
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to compare with the model results.
We provide indirect confirming evidence of the hypothesis, using
the fact that the model implies that mail processing and delivery
costs will comprise specific percentages of total costs at specific
per capita volume levels. We have obtained the actual percentages
of mail processing costs and delivery costs relative to total costs
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> posts with which we compare the predicted percentages.
Although the evidence is not conclusive, it confirms the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypothesis</ENAMEX>.
We first present our model for total costs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs. We
next present the test of our hypothesis by comparing the predicted
percentages for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> posts with the actual
percentages. We then produce a trend line through the data points
and compare it with the model results. Finally, we compare actual
unit revenues, and some derived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs, for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> posts
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>'s prediction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the book in which our previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>)] appears suggested that we examine the hypothesis that
the cost model accurately describes the costs of other posts.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COST MODEL</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is the same as that used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>)
except that we now present it as a generalized cost function. The
model assumes that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> primary determinants of cost for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>: volume and size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>. For each activity a
post performs, there are volume-driven attributable costs and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">networkdriven</ENAMEX> institutional costs.
To create a total cost function, we use FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service data to define the relationship between costs and cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>. Costs for each postal activity (mail processing, delivery,
etc) that can be attributed to mail volumes, are divided by total
volume to obtain an estimate of the marginal cost<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.4</NUMEX> The remaining
costs are institutional costs that are primarily driven by the size
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population</ENAMEX> is a reasonable proxy for the size of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and therefore institutional costs are divided by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to obtain the additional cost per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. This
produces annual cost functions for each of the major postal
activities and a total cost function.
Since all costs are variable in the long run, it is reasonable
that non-delivery institutional costs would decline over the large
volume range we explore with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. For purposes of this
analysis we assume that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of non-delivery institutional
costs would be volume variable<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>
No portion of delivery institutional costs is considered to be
volume variable, however, because route structure generally does
not change as volume drops. As long as coverage is relatively high,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> will have to cover their entire route. Thus, fixed
delivery costs would not be expected to drop until volume per
capita were so low that the resulting very low coverage allowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to skip parts of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
Attributable costs using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> cost treatment are greater than
volume variable costs. Consequently, the estimate is slightly
higher than the true marginal cost.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
The results are not very sensitive to this assumption as can be
seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>).
The cost function in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollars is:


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variable Institutional</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail Processing</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1032V</NUMEX> + 2.10P <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delivery</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0525V</NUMEX> + 42.24P
Transportation = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0200V</NUMEX> + 0.92P <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Window Service</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0092V</NUMEX> + 4.64P
All Other costs = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0241V</NUMEX> + 24.41P Total costs = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2089V</NUMEX> + 74.31P
where V = Volume and P = Population.
It can be seen that the total cost of providing postal service
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> for FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20.89 cents</NUMEX> per piece plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$74.31</NUMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. The total cost for other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> can be estimated by
substituting volume and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> into the above formula.
The total cost function can be used to estimate average unit
cost by dividing the terms by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX>:
Average Unit Cost = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2089</NUMEX> + (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">74.31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P / V</ENAMEX>). This can be restated
in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V / P</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> per capita (ppc), as:
Average Unit Cost = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2089</NUMEX> + (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">74.31 / ppc</ENAMEX>).
The percent of total cost for each function included in the
model and cost elasticity (with respect to volume) are shown in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Table 1</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX> assumes constant unit variable costs. Thus, when
volume is reduced total variable cost is reduced by the same
percentage. At lower per capita volumes, the ratio of fixed to
variable cost increases and the cost elasticities decrease (because
a greater proportion of total costs is fixed). Similarly, the model
assumes a constant coefficient for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
Table <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1: FY</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> USPS Percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Cost</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elasticity</ENAMEX> (with
respect to Volume) of the Major

a
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission Docket</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R2000</NUMEX>-1
b
Includes both in and out of office activities.
c
Does not include intra <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> transportation costs.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cost elasticities in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, when applied to the
accrued costs of each function, determine the coefficients in the
cost function, which in turn generate the unique shape of the unit
cost function (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Further, these coefficients determine the
percent of total cost that comes from mail processing and delivery
at a specific volume per capita.
The total cost for an individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can be expressed as a
function of pieces per capita by rewriting the above basic total
cost equation as:
Total Cost for country "i" = (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2089</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pi</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V/Pi</ENAMEX>) + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74.31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pi</ENAMEX>,
where Pi = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> for country "i",
0.2089Pi = slope
74.31Pi = intercept. The values of the slope (rate of increase
in total costs) and intercept (institutional costs) are directly
related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> A has twice as
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> B, then the slope and intercept of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX>'s
cost function will be twice as large as the slope and intercept of
B's cost function.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> displays the total cost curves as functions of pieces
per capita for each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the sample. The differences
in slopes and intercepts reflect population differences. If total
volume, instead of pieces per capita, were displayed on the
vertical axis, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-intercepts would remain unchanged but the
cost curves would be parallel. Although Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> shows a family of
total costs curves, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> displays a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost curve
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost curve depends on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> variable, pieces
per capita.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cost Functions for Sampled Posts</ENAMEX>
Not Adjusted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Structural Differences</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0 100 200 300 400 500 600</NUMEX>
Pieces per Capita


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. ADJUSTMENTS
To estimate the cost of a post using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, it is necessary
to take into account labor cost differences between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service and the given post. The test of our hypothesis, however,
does not involve predicting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs of other posts. It involves
predicting the percentage of total cost devoted to mail processing
and delivery. Thus, labor costs do not need to be adjusted.
The total percentage of mail processing costs would have to be
adjusted if worksharing, automation, or mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mix</ENAMEX> had significantly
different impacts on mail processing costs. We have adjusted mail
processing costs for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Posti Finland</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> include the costs of cancellation and mail preparation in
counter costs. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> classifies these
costs as part of mail processing, we adjust the percentages of mail
processing costs upward for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> to reflect a similar
treatment. This has no effect on total costs, and therefore only
affects the mail processing percentage.
The number of deliveries per week varies among the posts in the
sample (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX> deliver <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times per week,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Britain</ENAMEX> delivers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> in urban areas and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> areas). Consequently it is necessary to adjust the percentage
of delivery costs for these posts to the level it would be with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
deliveries per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> (as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>) When the percentage of
delivery cost is increased or decreased for a given post, the
percentage of mail processing cost is decreased or increased
accordingly<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX>


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONFIRMING</ENAMEX> THE HYPOTHESIS


4.1
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>


Canada <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Consignia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Mail</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Posti Finland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Poste</ENAMEX>
supplied the percentages of delivery and mail processing costs to
us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> supplied the data for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTT Correios de Portugal</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX> delivers unaddressed mail separately
from normal mail. Consequently, the volumes and percentages of
total cost for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX> do not include unaddressed mail.
Unaddressed mail is included in the calculations for other
posts.
The cost percentages reflect labor and non labor costs, except
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Post</ENAMEX> percentages are derived from
workforce full time equivalents contained in its annual report for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> and an internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Italiane</ENAMEX> study on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> delivery
operations developed in part from meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Post</ENAMEX> annual report provides the total
number of full time equivalents involved in postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> document provides the number involved in
delivery operations. While this is a proxy for labor and non labor
costs, it is considered realistic since in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, the use of
workforce full time equivalents provide estimates within a few
percentage points of those calculated with labor and non labor
costs.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> density (or more specifically the postal density
-- the average time it takes to travel between addresses) of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has an impact on street delivery costs. Ideally we could
adjust for this if data were available. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> al.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4.2 Empirical Findings</ENAMEX>
Empirical findings from the investigation are presented in
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> represents delivery cost percentage (of
total cost) as a function of pieces per capita as predicted by our
cost model. The bottom line represents the same for mail processing
costs.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Functional Percentage of Total Costs</ENAMEX>
Benchmarked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Costs and Volumes</ENAMEX>
Percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Costs</ENAMEX>
70
60
50
40
30
20
10
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0 0 100 200 300 400 500 600 700 800</NUMEX>

Pieces per Capita
With the exception of the lowest volume post (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX>)
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>'s predicted percentages are close to the actual
percentages for delivery. We think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX>, a very low
volume post, may have a somewhat lower percentage of delivery costs
than predicted owing to low coverage on very low volume routes
especially in rural areas. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> deliver to only a small
number of stops on a route they tend to cover the route in a way
more similar to a "traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>" than following a fixed route
past every stop. Thus, there may be less fixed costs on these
routes than indicated by the elasticities embedded in the cost
model based on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> costs, which reflect very high coverage levels.
If this conjecture is correct, then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s delivery percentages
could be adjusted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">upwards</TIMEX> (by an unknown amount) towards the
predicted value and their mail processing costs would then have to
be adjusted downwards. A downward adjustment would also improve
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s relation to the mail processing prediction but move
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX> further away. Some of the deviation for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX>
may be due to the fact that they have proportionally much larger
retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> involving collection and acceptance than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
and other posts. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>'s retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>
operations account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> of total costs, while in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> they account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately six percent</NUMEX>. Poste Italiane
also has a relatively large percentage of costs in collection and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>. Nevertheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> cannot explain
why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>'s percentage of mail processing cost is so low in
comparison to the other posts in the sample.
A significant virtue of these curves is that they are
independent of the price of labor. Thus, by using this evaluation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technique</ENAMEX>, we are able to avoid the need for obtaining productive
hourly costs translated into dollars using purchasing power
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parities</ENAMEX>.
It appears that other factors, for which adjustments are not
made, do not cause significant differences. This could be because
these factors do not vary significantly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, do not drive
costs significantly, or tend to cancel each other out.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4.3 Trend Analysis</ENAMEX>
The bold lines in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> display trend curves for the actual
processing and delivery cost percentages from the test <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.7
These curves were generated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excel</ENAMEX>. They have virtually the
same shape as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curves</ENAMEX> predicted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and further confirm
the fit between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and the data. The low delivery cost
percentage of the low volume per capita <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, pulls the
delivery trend line down away from the predicted line. The fact
that the actual mail processing percentages for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX>
are about equidistant below and above the predicted values causes
the mail processing trend line to match the model line at low
volumes despite relatively large errors. These disparities at low
volumes between the trend and model lines reinforce our belief that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is less useful in predicting costs for low per capita
volume posts than it is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> to high volume per capita posts.
It is to be expected that the accuracy of predictions will diminish
as the range over which the predictions are made increases.
These trend lines were selected because they best fit the data.
For delivery percentages, the trend line is y=<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">46.943e-0.0004x</ENAMEX> with
an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">R2</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.78</NUMEX>. For mail processing percentages the trend line is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">y</ENAMEX>=10.869Ln(x) - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38.407</NUMEX> with an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">R2</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.69</NUMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Functional Percentage</ENAMEX> of Total Costs with Regression
Curves
70
60
Percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Costs</ENAMEX>
50
40
30
20
10
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0 0 100 200 300 400 500 600 700 800</NUMEX>

Pieces per Capita
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESTIMATED UNIT COSTS</ENAMEX>
In order to compare unit costs, it is desirable to make the
adjustments we have discussed above plus an adjustment for
productive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> wage in purchasing power parities (PPP). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> for
these adjustments were not available, except for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> values used in making adjustments for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> data
are listed in the appendix. In the absence of actual cost data, we
compare model cost results to actual revenues.
For the posts in our sample we have used the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> to estimate
unit costs and adjusted only for deliveries per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>.) In <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, we compare these
estimates with average revenue per piece converted to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cents
using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OECD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPP</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Comparison of Model Estimated Coststo</ENAMEX> Actual Revenue
per Piece for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">U.S. cents</NUMEX>)
Model Cost Revenue Estimates per Piecea
Canada <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 41</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finland</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 39</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">38b</NUMEX> 40b <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 57</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX>
79c <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portugal</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62 54</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 50</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> 31c
a
From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> reports and Posts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> for
Portugal b Includes unaddressed mail
c
Actual cost per piece
The largest discrepancy appears to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. We know, however,
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Italiane</ENAMEX> productive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> wage is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three quarters</TIMEX> of
that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>. As stated in the introduction,
when we adjust for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Italian</TIMEX> labor costs, worksharing, mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mix</ENAMEX>, and
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters</ENAMEX>, we get a modeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">74 cents</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONCLUSIONS</ENAMEX>
The principal conclusion is that empirical evidence corroborates
the validity of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> because the predicted functional
percentages of costs are reasonably close to actual values. See
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. In particular, the general shape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost curve
(with respect to per capita volume) appears to be valid for the
posts of industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> sampled. See Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>,
however, is a more accurate predictor of the cost behavior of
medium to large per capita volume posts than for small per capita
volume posts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> also demonstrates that both volume and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> are important explanatory factors of postal costs.
Clearly, additional research is warranted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Regulators</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> in any industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are encouraged to use the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> in the appendix on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cost characteristics to make
adjustments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and determine if the model forecasts costs
with reasonable accuracy. Of course, we would not expect exact
correspondence even after adjustments are made owing to differences
in efficiency and service quality.
Appendix: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS Operational Statistics</ENAMEX>


•
Productive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> wage: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23.87644</NUMEX>


•
Mail mix by shape: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72 percent</NUMEX> letters and cards, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>
percent flats, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> parcels


•
Percentage of mail with some worksharing: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>


•
Percentage of letters barcoded by mailers: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>


•
Percentage of letters barcoded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>


•
Percentage of flats barcoded by mailers: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>


•
Percentage of mail not delivered (i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office Box</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mail</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21.4</NUMEX>


•
Average postal density (addresses per fixed street <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX>):
100.5


•
Counter Costs: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.6 percent</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REFERENCES</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stephane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Cohen, Matthew Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Roy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jöelle Toledano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waller</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spyros Xenakis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. "Delivery
Cost <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heterogeneity and Vulnerability</ENAMEX>." Paper presented at the 10th
Conference on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Economics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Potsdam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ferguson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spyros Xenakis</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Impact of Using Worksharing to Liberalize a Postal</ENAMEX>
Market." Paper presented at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wissenschaftliches Institut</ENAMEX> für
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kommunikationsdienste GmbH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6th Köenigswinter Seminar</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics, Liberalization of Postal Markets</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert, Carla Pace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Robinson</ENAMEX>, Gennaro
Scarfiglieri, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincenzo Visco Comandini</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waller</ENAMEX> and Spyros
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xenakis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comparison of the Burden of Universal Service in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Services</ENAMEX>:
Pricing, Productivity, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation and Strategy</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.A. Crew</ENAMEX>
and P.R. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC Docket No.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R2000-1 USPS LR-I-481</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TY Mail</ENAMEX>
Processing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> Costs by Shape with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piggyback Factors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Update</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LR-I-81 & 464 Provided</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Response</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POR No. 116</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Using FY 99</ENAMEX>
Base <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year and Alternative IOCS Methodology</ENAMEX>




