



A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comparison of the Burden of Universal Service</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
*


and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Cohen Rossana Scocchera</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX> Poste Italiane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Pace Vincenzo Visco Comandini</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poste Italiane Poste Italiane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Robinson John Waller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gennaro Scarfiglieri Spyros Xenakis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTRODUCTION</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Johnson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patriotism</ENAMEX> is the last refuge of a scoundrel
and many postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Service</ENAMEX>
Obligation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>) is the last refuge of a postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> wishing to
protect inefficiency, monopoly profits, or economic rents. Despite
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">inefficient</ENAMEX> service, opaque accounts, and large rents, many postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> maintain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX>, whatever its faults, is the
only means of ensuring universal, affordable postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX>, they argue,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> would be crushed by the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>. This paper
examines when this argument might be valid.
All posts probably have some cost associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>, but
it has been difficult to quantify. We agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panzar</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>)
that the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> is the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that would not
be provided in a competitive market. Under this definition, in
practice, there has been no discernable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> cost. Competition
exists in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> and the incumbent posts have
continued to provide universal service with no subsidy.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> as defined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> goes well
beyond ubiquitous service. It also includes a uniform price with
respect to location of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the recipient1</TIMEX> and a uniform frequency of
delivery. These conditions might have been appropriate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> when the post was the primary means of communication. Today
however, this definition seems unduly restrictive. It is incumbent
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of the restrictive definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> to explain why
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">postal</ENAMEX> service should be treated
*
The views expressed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> are those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and
do not necessarily represent the opinions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>.
In other words a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> cannot charge more for delivering similar
items to addresses in one section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> than another.
Under this definition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Parcel Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>) is not a true
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> because it imposes a surcharge for
residential delivery. This is ironic because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> delivers to every
address in the continental <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and delivers right to the door. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> which is a universal service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> under the
definition used here, delivers to mail boxes that are, in many
cases, remote from the actual address.
differently from other important products such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX>,
bank accounts and internet service<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> Notwithstanding, we use this
restrictive definition of universal service for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>.
The obligation to provide ubiquitous service is not in itself
onerous. It has been pointed out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-authors</ENAMEX> of this
paper that a post could rationalize its delivery costs by reducing
the frequency of service on unprofitable routes to the point where
they become profitable (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>). A post could also
rationalize its prices by reflecting the cost of service to
different areas. The restrictive definition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> does not
allow a post to rationalize either its cost or pricing structure,3
thus, creating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX>-skimming opportunities under liberalization.
The burden that the restrictive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> imposes on a post is the
increase in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs resulting from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX> under
liberalization caused by the requirements of uniform pricing and
levels of service. We use the term "burden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>" to
distinguish our concept from other papers that use the term "cost
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>."
We believe that insights into the burden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> can be
gained by comparing postal systems. Assuming that the keenest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insights</ENAMEX> can be gained by comparing systems with large differences,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> systems are good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has the highest volume per capita in the industrial world
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">739</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>), while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has one of the lowest (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX> pieces
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>
Previous work by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen et al.</ENAMEX> shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>) is not likely to require the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> to continue to satisfy
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999, 2000</TIMEX>) However, this result may not apply to
all posts and it is important to distinguish magnitudes of burden
for different posts. To this end, we develop a model to determine
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> burden for posts with different per capita volumes. In
particular, applying the model demonstrates that the burden of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>
is very great for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> and other posts with small per
capita volumes. On the other hand, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and other posts
with large and medium per capita volumes the burden is small.
We first compare some statistics for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> We then
examine the consequences of volume loss on postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> in order
to provide a measure of burden in terms of increases in average
unit costs as volume is lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
Many postal services are increasingly becoming primarily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> of advertising. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> households receive far more
advertising than letters, bills or other similar matter. According
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household Diary Study</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service 2000</ENAMEX>),
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> of the pieces received by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> were
advertising mail.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
An apparent exception is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Consignia</ENAMEX>. It rationalizes its delivery
cost by delivering twice a day in most urban areas and once a day
in rural areas.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has a very undeveloped direct mail market and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
monopoly does not include direct mail. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> includes all addressed direct mail consisting of
fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> pages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> handled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">314</NUMEX> pieces per
capita of direct mail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
equivalently, the increase in average rates for the volume
remaining<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX> we introduce the concept of delivery route profit
and quantify the relative profits from delivered mail and mail not
requiring delivery in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> We then compare the
distribution of profit margins for routes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and
the effect this has on vulnerability to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX>. Finally, we
discuss <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> measures of the cost of universal service, the entry
pricing measure and the net avoided cost measure in the context of
delivery profits. We compare them with our burden measure for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>.
Our principal findings are:
The burden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> is much greater for small per capita
volume posts than it is for large and medium per capita volume
posts.
The likelihood of a graveyard spiral resulting from volume loss
to cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX> is remote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> to large volume per capita
posts; whereas it is a real threat to small volume per capita
posts.
The measure of burden presented here combined with the
distribution of route profit margins for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> yields results contrary to the entry price and
net avoided cost measures for the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>.
The portion of mail not requiring delivery is a very important
contributor to the finances of a post.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMPARATIVE STATISTICS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> contains some statistics for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and for
their postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately one</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
per capita volume. Most of the delivery statistics in the table's
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> section are reasonably close to this <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> figure. The
number of delivery points in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, as a percentage of those in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, is a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
To provide a basis for comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>, we use a model of postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that follows
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1999</ENAMEX> costs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parametric</ENAMEX> analyses are conducted by varying volume under different
assumptions about the extent that institutional cost varies over
the long run. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is validated for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> by making
adjustments for major differences in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> posts, such as the
extent of worksharing.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
Prices of goods and services vary between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, and the prevailing market exchange rate does not
necessarily account for the relative differences in prices. We have
used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purchasing Power Parity</ENAMEX> (PPP) of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,677 liras</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
dollar to convert the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> statistics reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liras</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPP</ENAMEX> has been produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization of Economic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co-Operation and Development</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OECD</ENAMEX>) and shows the number of Italian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liras</ENAMEX> required in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> to buy goods and services equivalent to what
can be purchased with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one U.S. dollar</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the average market
exchange rate, reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>),
was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,817 liras</NUMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar.
disproportionately high <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX>. The disproportionate number
of small business addresses in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarfiglieri</ENAMEX> and Visco
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Comandini 2001</ENAMEX>) may help explain this.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> also has disproportionately more delivery points
per route. This results from a much lower coverage (percent of
addresses receiving mail on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given day</TIMEX>), a higher population
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">density</ENAMEX> and other unexplored route and topographical
considerations<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> We see in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> section that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service cost per piece is much lower than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> cost per
piece despite having a much higher labor cost per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>. This is
primarily a result of economies of scale, worksharing and the
extensive use of automation<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selected National</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Statistics</ENAMEX> for FY
1999a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy U.S.</ENAMEX> Percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Finally</ENAMEX>
Population <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57,679,895</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Area</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Square Miles</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">116,347</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Population</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square Mile 496 Number of Households</ENAMEX> 21,211,334
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272,691,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> we note that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,675,031 3 74 668</NUMEX> number of
retail <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103,620,000 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX> (per

100,000
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 16</NUMEX>
operated by
17
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 25</NUMEX>
much larger
14
than the number
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 21</NUMEX>
operated by the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">144</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
14
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">154</NUMEX>
Service.
24
illustrates
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37 173</NUMEX>
fact that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">206</NUMEX>

This the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the</ENAMEX> has
in
It
also illustrates that the concept of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> has many more
dimensions than ubiquitous delivery. However, the cross-subsidy
that results from ubiquitous delivery and uniform prices and
frequency of delivery is widely regarded as the most important
aspect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> mitigating against liberalization. This paper
will be restricted to dealing with this aspect.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
Motorcycles are the primary means of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> transport in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> are the primary means in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
It is also the result of the quantity of non-delivered mail (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">See</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 4</ENAMEX>).


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RELATIVE IMPACT OF VOLUME LOSS ON POSTAL SYSTEMS</ENAMEX>
The burden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> on a postal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> lies within its fixed
costs. Ceteris paribus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> (per piece) fixed costs are higher in
a low volume per capita system than in a high volume per capita
system. We examine the effect of volume on unit total costs.
The sensitivity of cost to volume for a postal system can be
investigated directly provided the ratio of fixed to variable costs
is known by function. Some postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> do not have this
information and some choose not to make it available to regulators
or the public. Consequently, we have built a model to estimate the
relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> average costs and per capita volume. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is described in the appendix and includes parameters for
the portion of variable costs by major postal functions. When the
average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost is graphed as a function of volume per capita one
obtains a curve with a parabolic shape. The exact shape of the
curve depends on the specific set of parameters used to benchmark
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, such as the proportion of fixed costs at a specific per
capita volume. Because the cost behavior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>
has been studied extensively and because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postal costs are the
most transparent in the industrialized world, we use <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S</ENAMEX> data from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> as provided in the most recent omnibus rate proceeding, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Docket</ENAMEX>
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R2000</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to benchmark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the model10</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
institutional/variable percentages for the major postal
functions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. Fixed/Variable Cost By Major Function a</ENAMEX> (FY
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>)

a
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX> Docket No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R2000</NUMEX>-1
b
Delivery includes in-office and out-of-office costs.
Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> may differ greatly from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> systems in labor cost, automation, route topography,
worksharing, mix of mail by shape, and the percentage of
non-delivered mail, etc., we cannot expect the cost estimates
furnished by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> to be extremely accurate estimates of
particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">non-U.S.</ENAMEX> systems. For our
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
We use pieces per capita rather than total volume to normalize
the volume.
10
This model has been developed on the assumption that the cost
behavior of postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> is essentially similar. The
functions of collection, delivery, transportation, processing and
window services are common to the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> of all
industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
purposes we do not need great accuracy, we only need reasonable
estimates in order to examine the sensitivity of total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost to
volume per capita.
The fixed portion of non-delivery costs would be expected to
change as we move from higher volume <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> to lower
volume ones. It would be expected that lower volume postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">administrations</ENAMEX> would try to keep them small to reduce the burden
on rate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">payers</ENAMEX>. Since these costs are variable in the long run and
we do not know how other postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> deal with them, we
parameterize them for purposes of modeling.
As a preliminary matter, using the fixed/variable ratios for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> costs from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> shows that as per
capita volume increases, the mail processing proportion of total
cost will increase and the delivery proportion will decrease. This
is because mail-processing costs are almost all variable while
delivery costs have a very large fixed component. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
volume per capita is the highest in the world, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service delivery costs proportion should be the smallest of any
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">postal</ENAMEX> service. On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> per capita volume
is among the lowest in the industrialized world, and so its
delivery costs proportion should be among the highest.

Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Functional Percentage of Total Costs</ENAMEX>
Benchmarked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Costs</ENAMEX> and Volumes with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Non</ENAMEX>-Delivery
Institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Costs Long-Run Variable</ENAMEX>
Percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Costs</ENAMEX>
70
60
50
40
30
20
10
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>

Pieces per Capita
Again using the ratios for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> costs in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>,
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> shows the variability of the major functions as per capita
volume changes. It can be seen that at low volumes, mail processing
and transportation costs have a high degree of fixity while at high
volumes they are almost all variable.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M odeled Variabilities</ENAMEX> by Function
B enchm arked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> .<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> . C o sts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">o lu m es w</ENAMEX> ith <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
on-D elivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C osts L ong-R un V ariab le</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0 1 00 200 3 00 400 500 600 700 800</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> ieces per C apita
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> shows the impact of per capita volume on average unit
costs. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curves</ENAMEX> represent different variabilities of
non-delivery fixed costs as shown in the legend. It appears that
unit costs are not very sensitive to changes in per capita volume
at the high end but are quite sensitive at the low end. For
example, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-percent reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> per capita for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would result in costs increasing about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one cent</NUMEX>. A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-percent reduction for a post at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> pieces per capita would
increase unit costs by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine cents</NUMEX>. The increase in unit cost
resulting from a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-percent decrease in per capita volume for a
range of volumes is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model Estimates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unit Cos</ENAMEX>
Benchmarked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Costs and Volumes</ENAMEX>

Pieces <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">per Capita Long-Run Variability of Non-Delivery</ENAMEX>
Institutional Costs

In the per capita volume range of most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the effect on unit
cost from a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-percent reduction in per capita volume is not
great. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 200</NUMEX> pieces per capita the effect of volume loss on
unit cost becomes much more pronounced<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unit Cost</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> Decrease in Volume Assuming <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Non-Delivery Institutional Costs are Long-Run Variable</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1999 U.S. Dollars</NUMEX>)
Pieces per Capita <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700 600 500 400 300 200 100</NUMEX>
Base unit cost <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.32 0.33 0.36 0.40 0.46 0.59 0.97</NUMEX> Unit cost with
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> volume loss <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.33 0.35 0.38 0.42 0.49 0.63 1.06</NUMEX>
When volume is lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>, net
revenue losses (revenue minus cost) must be made up from the
remaining volume to maintain breakeven status. The burden measure
quantifies the resulting increase in unit cost and revenue that
must be made up from each piece of mail that remains in the system.
An important question is whether the rate increases would lead to a
graveyard spiral. We think the burden measure provides an answer to
this question.
Insofar as the burden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> might introduce a death spiral
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crew and Kleindorfer 2000</ENAMEX>) owing to the loss of volume because of
liberalization, the probability seems slight until per capita
volumes are in the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 to 150-piece</NUMEX> range. Below that point the
possibility of a death spiral increases rapidly. Thus, we conclude
that the burden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> is much greater for low per capita
volume posts than for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> to high volume ones.
In order to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> more useful for comparing Poste
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italiane</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> we adjust model costs to
account for important known differences. Since worksharing
activities reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> costs by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 25 percent</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen et</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">al. 2001</ENAMEX>), we increase model costs to account for the lack of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worksharing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. The portion of the model costs that are labor
costs is adjusted downwards to reflect <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> labor cost
differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>. In
addition, model costs are adjusted to reflect the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Poste</ENAMEX> Italiane
proportion of low-cost letters (and cards), medium-cost flats, and
high-cost parcels. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appendix</ENAMEX> describes the adjustment factors.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX> shows estimates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs derived using
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.
It can be seen that the model comes fairly close to Poste
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italiane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs. Of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> could be further refined
to account for many more specific differences. We leave that
project for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX>. Nonetheless, we think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is
sufficiently accurate to allow us to draw a major conclusion: the
burden of universal service is highly dependent on volume per
capita, so policies suitable for liberalizing medium and large per
capita volume posts are likely not suitable for small per capita
volume posts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> have per capita volumes below
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model Estimates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> Costs Based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Costs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Variabilities Adjusted for Worksharing</ENAMEX>, Wage
Differences, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail Mix</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Run Variability Unit Costs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$</NUMEX> per piece) of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Non-Delv</ENAMEX>. Inst.
Costs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attributable Institutional Total</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0%</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.19 0.59 0.78 25 0.19 0.53 0.72 50 0.19 0.47 0.66</NUMEX>


Actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> Cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.79</NUMEX>



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. PROFITS FROM DELIVERED AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NON-DELIVERED MAIL</ENAMEX>
Because of the interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> and cross-subsidy within the
delivery system, it is important to define the concept of route
profit (and loss). We define the profitability of a delivery route
as the revenue generated by the mail delivered on the route minus
the attributable upstream costs of the mail delivered and the total
cost of the route (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). Some mail handled by a
postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> does not require delivery; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> pick up mail
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> boxes and large volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> pick up mail in
bulk from designated counters<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Non-</ENAMEX>delivered mail can also be
considered to have delivery profits in the same manner as delivered
mail<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX>
A postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> has variable and fixed upstream costs as well
as variable and fixed delivery costs. In a breakeven postal service
total delivery profits from all routes plus profits from
non-delivered mail must equal fixed upstream costs<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.14</NUMEX> Put another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, fixed upstream costs minus profits from non-delivered mail
must equal delivery profits.
In order to compare profits from delivered and non-delivered
mail in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> we increase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> revenue by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> so that it
equals cost and is thus at breakeven<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX> shows that
non-delivered mail accounts for a very disproportionate share of
delivery profits in both posts (and presumably in all posts). The
most obvious reason for this is that non-delivered mail incurs no
carrier delivery cost. In addition, although many delivery routes
are highly profitable, losses from unprofitable routes reduce the
net delivery profit from delivered mail.
12
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, this is frequently called "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> holdout"
mail.
13
Revenue minus attributable upstream costs that includes the
small amount of costs for non-carrier box or counter delivery
activities associated with non-delivered mail.
14
An analogous identity holds for a post at any given profit
(loss).
15
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> are from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> had profits of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400 million</NUMEX> and total revenue of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$62.8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distribution</ENAMEX> of Volume and Profits between
Delivered and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Non-</ENAMEX>delivered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX>
(Percent)
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy U.S.</ENAMEX> Volume Profits Volume Profits
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Delivered 8658 79 33 Non-</ENAMEX>delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1442</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 67</NUMEX>
Because total delivery profits from delivered and non-delivered
mail must equal fixed upstream costs, non-delivered mail plays an
important role in reducing the revenue needs of a breakeven post.
Ceteris paribus, the higher the proportion of non-delivered mail,
the lower the rates that a breakeven post must charge. Thus, the
higher the proportion of non-delivered mail, the less opportunity
there is for a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmer</ENAMEX> to undercut the incumbent<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16,17</NUMEX>
Moreover highly profitable non-delivered mail is much less
vulnerable to diversion<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.18</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DISTRIBUTION OF ROUTE PROFIT MARGINS AND VULNERABILITY TO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CREAM SKIMMING</ENAMEX>
Volumes, revenues and route profits differ widely on routes in
both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> The uniform pricing constraint of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> creates cream
skimming possibilities because an entrant can target only highly
profitable routes and charge a price below the uniform price.
Consequently, it is not cross-subsidy per se that allows cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skimming</ENAMEX>. All routes could be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">above</NUMEX> incremental cost and the
problem would still exist. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimming</ENAMEX> stems from the uniform
pricing and service constraints given that routes have disparate
profits, and not necessarily from the need to cross-subsidize
routes.
16
We would expect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>'s percentage of non-delivered mail
to be among the highest of industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> posts because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> payment system involves a large fraction of financial
transactions paid by check and mailed to large volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>.
This mail is generally picked up by them (or their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>) at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> (i.e., it is non-delivered mail).
17
In a small per capita volume post, the fixed cost of delivery
represents a larger share of total cost than in a large per capita
volume post. Ceteris paribus, per piece profit from non-delivered
mail is greater in a small per capita volume post than in a large
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
18
Many of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18 million boxholders</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> do not
want mail delivered to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>. We cannot quantify the
number, but presumably, this is an important reason why mail
recipients rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> box. These box <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> would not be
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Fifty-six percent</NUMEX> of
non-delivered mail is single piece. It is not likely that cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skimmers</ENAMEX> would be able to successfully put a collection system in
place to capture much of this mail. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX> of
non-delivered mail that remains, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class, much of
which is time sensitive. According to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> of cream
skimming, delivery frequency would be reduced. Time sensitive First
Class would be less likely to make use of a service with less
frequent delivery. Finally, non-single piece mail addressed to box
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> is being transported and delivered over large areas of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>. A delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimmer</ENAMEX> would have to have a national
presence to compete for this mail. This means much of the mail
could not be handled by local niche <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> or even regional cream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX>.
The more revenue that leaves the system because of cream
skimming, the more rates must be increased on the remaining mail to
maintain a breakeven status. Consequently, the greater the share of
system-wide revenue that is from high margin routes, the greater
impact that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX> could have on a postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.
In order to compare the possible effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> skimming on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>, we have arrayed their
routes by profit margin using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1999</ENAMEX> data. Again, we have adjusted
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> revenue to breakeven in order to facilitate
comparison.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> displays the profit margin19 of routes arrayed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">semi-deciles.</ENAMEX> The most profitable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> semi-decile has a margin
of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just over 30 percent</NUMEX> while the most profitable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> semi-decile
has a margin of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 50 percent</NUMEX>. However, a greater percentage of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> routes are profitable than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> routes.
We do not know the profit margin that would actually attract
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>. If it is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>, then <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> routes
would be vulnerable and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 7 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> routes would
be vulnerable.
Virtually all profitable routes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> are urban. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about half</NUMEX> of the routes served by city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> are
profitable while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three quarters</TIMEX> of the routes served by rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> are profitable<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20</NUMEX> It may well be that competition is much
more likely to develop in urban areas. If so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> would
be at greater risk from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service.
19
For purposes of this discussion, profit margin is defined as the
ratio of delivery profits to route costs (i.e. upstream variable
plus total delivery cost).
20
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> of the routes served by rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> are in high-density suburban areas.
60
50
40
30
20
Average Profit margin Percentage
10
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>


(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX>)


(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX>)


(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30</NUMEX>)


(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40</NUMEX>)


(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50</NUMEX>)


(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60</NUMEX>)



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 1011121314151617181920</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semi-decile</ENAMEX> (Routes by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Increments</ENAMEX>)
a
Revenue for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> is increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24%</NUMEX> to create
breakeven conditions.
The percent of total revenue by semi-decile is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>.
At every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">semidecile</ENAMEX> except the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> receives a
greater percentage of total revenue than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>.
This is due to the fact that a much larger percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
revenue comes from undelivered mail.
The distribution of profitable routes shown on Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s revenue (volume) per route
is much more skewed than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane's</ENAMEX>, as measured by the
relative size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> at the extremes. This would tend to make
the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> more attractive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> than Poste
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italiane</ENAMEX> (at most profit thresholds). This skewness results from
mail volume being highly correlated with income and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> income
distribution being much more skewed than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Italian</TIMEX> income
distribution. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berthelemy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Toledano</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith 1999</ENAMEX>)
In fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has the most skewed income distribution of any
industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as measured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>'s Gini Index.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Gini Index is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40.8</NUMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27.3.21</NUMEX> Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
should be fairly typical of the distribution of route profit
margins of industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> should be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outlier</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Development Indicators</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2.8</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The World Bank</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>. The unweighted average of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gini Indices</ENAMEX> for
industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30.6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> has the lowest index at
23.1.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delivered Mail</ENAMEX> Revenue As Percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Revenue</ENAMEX>
Routes by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semi-decile</ENAMEX> (Ranked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profit</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9</NUMEX>
10
Cumulative Percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Revenue</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Italy</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 10 16 18 21 24 26 30 31 36 35 41 39 46 43 50 46 54 49 58</NUMEX>
Routes by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semi-decile</ENAMEX> (Ranked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profit</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> Cumulative Percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Revenue</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Italy</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53 62 56 66 59 69 61 72 64 74 66 77 69 79 71 81 72 83 73 84</NUMEX>
Because volume and revenue are highly correlated, if volume is
lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX>, then revenue is also lost. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX> can be used to estimate likely profit and revenue losses to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> and Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> to estimate the cost impact of volume
losses. Depending on the threshold selected, the potential impact
on the respective posts can be compared.
We doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> could capture even a majority of
the volume on any route owing to the limited amount of contestable
volume in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and perhaps other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.22 Nevertheless, to
the extent that volume would be lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>, the impact
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> would be greater than on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service.
As mentioned above, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> data have been adjusted for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breakeven</ENAMEX>. Had we not done this, very few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> routes would be
profitable. A postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> that is below <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breakeven</ENAMEX> will be less
attractive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX> than otherwise. On the other hand, if
a postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> is above breakeven, its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> will be even more
profitable and hence, more attractive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cream skimmers</ENAMEX>.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. ENTRY PRICING
The entry pricing measure defines the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> as the sum
of lost profits from entry by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>. The form of entry that
we consider is delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream skimming</ENAMEX>. If an entrant were more
efficient than the incumbent, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> would not cause the lost
profit. Under the restrictive definition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>, however, it is
possible for the incumbent post to be more efficient than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entrant</ENAMEX> and still lose profits because the incumbent must charge a
uniform price. The entrant would most likely attack routes with
much higher than average profit margins. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> would not be
able to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>) found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 16 percent</NUMEX> of total
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> volume is contestable.
respond because of the restrictive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>. Ceteris paribus, the
more skewed the incumbent's route profit margin distribution, the
more vulnerable the post is to entry<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.23</NUMEX>
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> profit margin
distribution is much less skewed than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s
distribution. Thus, according to the entry price measure the cost
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> is higher in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>.24 This is contrary
to the conclusion that we have drawn in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 3</ENAMEX> (i.e., that the
burden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> is much higher for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> than for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>).
The possibility of an equal or less efficient entrant capturing
significant volume depends on the fraction of mail on profitable
routes that is actually contestable. Given the huge scale economies
of a universal service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> and the limited amount of
contestable mail, it is very difficult for an entrant, at least in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, to charge prices lower than an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen et</ENAMEX> al.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. NET AVOIDED COST
The net avoided cost measure (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> is the sum of the
losses from unprofitable routes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dobbs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Golay</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; Elsenblast
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stumpf 1995).</ENAMEX> As stated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, the profits from delivered and
non-delivered mail must equal the upstream fixed cost in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breakeven</ENAMEX> post. If the profits from the money making routes and
non-delivered mail exceed the upstream fixed cost, then there must
be an offset of money losing routes. This is simply an accounting
identity. The more skewed the distribution of delivery route profit
margins, the greater will be the losses from unprofitable routes.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> would be greater for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
Service than for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> (assuming adjustments for scale).
Again, this is contrary to our finding in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 3</ENAMEX> about the
relative burden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>.
Furthermore, we believe that the logic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> measure is
flawed. Suppose that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> decides to provide a subsidy to
its breakeven postal service to offset losses on unprofitable
routes because it wishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> and not rate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">payers</ENAMEX> to fund the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>. The postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> would then have a surplus. In order for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">postal</ENAMEX> service to return to breakeven, prices would be reduced. 25
Because of the price reduction unprofitable routes would become
even more unprofitable and some formerly profitable routes would
become unprofitable. Because the total losses from unprofitable
routes are greater than before, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would have to
increase its subsidy.
23
For purposes of the discussion of entry pricing and net avoided
cost, we ignore the impact of the percentage of non-delivered
mail.
24
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colvin</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>) estimated the entry pricing cost of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. That estimate assumed that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entrant</ENAMEX> would capture all volume on all profitable routes. It is a
worst case scenerio.
25
The same logic would hold for a postal service earning any given
profit (loss).
This process would continue until there is but one route not
subsidized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and that route would be the route that
initially was the most profitable one in the system. Thus, the net
avoided cost measure implies the absurdity that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must
fund <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire</TIMEX> delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> if it wants to fund the cost of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> service.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. CONCLUSION
We introduce and quantify the concept of the burden of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>,
which is the upward impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs that would result from
competitive entry. We find that the burden on low per capita postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> is much greater than on medium to high volume postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>. This is contrary to results obtained when using the net
avoided cost or entry pricing measures of the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USO</ENAMEX>. We
also find that the burden decreases as the percentage of
non-delivered mail increases. The distribution of route profits is
much more skewed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> than for Poste
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italiane</ENAMEX>. This would tend to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> more attractive to
potential cream <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skimmers</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, a greater percentage
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> revenue is generated by delivered mail, and this
would cause cream skimming to have a greater impact on its unit
costs.
APPENDIX
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model Definition</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is designed to define average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost as a function
of volume (Q), based on the USPS cost structure for FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AC = TC /</ENAMEX> (Q * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>)
where:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC +</ENAMEX> NDC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC =</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Vd / Q0</ENAMEX>) Q + Fd
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NDC</ENAMEX> = (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Vnd / Q0</ENAMEX>) Q + [ (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ev Fnd</ENAMEX>) / <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Q0</TIMEX> ] Q + (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 - Ev</ENAMEX>) Fnd
The functions can be combined and expressed as:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> = { [ V + (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ev Fnd</ENAMEX>) ] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/ Q0 } Q + Fd</ENAMEX> + (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 - Ev</ENAMEX>) Fnd
The terms are defined as:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AC</ENAMEX> = Average <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Unit Cost d = Subscript</ENAMEX> that indicates delivery
component of a cost or volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC = Total Delivery Cost Ev</ENAMEX> =
Long-run variability of non-delivery institutional (fixed)
costs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parametric</ENAMEX> values of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> used in analysis. F = USPS
Fixed Cost for FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999 nd</TIMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subscript</ENAMEX> that indicates non-delivery
component of a cost or volume NDC = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Non-Delivery Cost P</ENAMEX> =
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Population Q = <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quantity</ENAMEX> (Volume) per capita <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Q0</TIMEX> = USPS
Volume per capita for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1999 TC = Total Cost V = USPS Variable</ENAMEX>
Cost for FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
Adjustments for differences between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> and Poste
Italiane
costs exist between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX>. To make the comparison
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> (which is based on USPS cost data)
and the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> more meaningful, we
apply <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> factors to the results of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost
assuming <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of institutional (fixed) costs vary with volume in the
long run is calculated in the example.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
First, the attributable (variable) cost from the model
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V/Q0*P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.194</NUMEX>) is adjusted to reflect the different shape mix of
mail handled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX>. The proportions of letters (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88%</NUMEX>)
and nonletters (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> are applied to the USPS
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">variable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost of each (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13.46 and 26.60 cents</NUMEX>, respectively).
The weighted average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost that results (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15.04 cents</NUMEX>) is then
divided by the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> unit variable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16.88 cents</NUMEX>.
The resulting ratio (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.891</NUMEX>) is applied to the variable cost from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.

<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Example: 0.194 * 0.891</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.173</NUMEX>



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
Next, the resulting variable cost is adjusted to account
for the savings from worksharing reflected in the USPS costs, which
do not exist for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX>. The USPS variable costs in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> lower than they would have been without worksharing,
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>) so the variable cost from step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.173</NUMEX>) is
increased by that amount.

Example: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.173</NUMEX> * <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.242</NUMEX>


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Finally, both variable and institutional costs are
adjusted for labor cost differences. Since <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78.6%</NUMEX> of USPS costs are
labor costs, that portion of the variable cost from step two
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.242</NUMEX>) and institutional cost from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.662</NUMEX>) is adjusted
by the ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poste Italiane</ENAMEX> labor costs to those of USPS
(<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74.7%</NUMEX>).


Example: [ (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.786</NUMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.242</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.662</NUMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.747</NUMEX>) ] + [ (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.786</NUMEX>)
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.242</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.662</NUMEX>) ] = <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.724</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REFERENCES</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berthlmy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francoise L.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolle Toledano</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mail Goes Where the Money and Businesses Are</ENAMEX>." In Current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Reform</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael D.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Colvin</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. "Measuring the Cost
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Universal Service for Posts</ENAMEX>." In Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Reform, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William W. Ferguson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Waller</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spyros S. Xenakis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. "An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis of the Potential for Cream</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skimming</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Residential Delivery Market</ENAMEX>." In
Emerging Competition in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Services</ENAMEX>, edited by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: Kluwer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William W. Ferguson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Waller</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spyros S. Xenakis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Service</ENAMEX> without a Monopoly." In
Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Reform</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William W. Ferguson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Waller</ENAMEX> and Spyros
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Xenakis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Impact of Using Worksharing to Liberalize a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Market</ENAMEX>." Papers presented at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wissenschaftliches Institut</ENAMEX> fr
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kommunikationsdienste GmbH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6th Kenigswinter Seminar</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics, Liberalization of Postal Markets</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. "Liberalization
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Service Obligation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>." In Current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Reform</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
Dobbs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeanne Golay</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Service</ENAMEX>
Obligation and Reserved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sector</ENAMEX>." In Cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Service</ENAMEX>,
edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulrich Stumpf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfgang Elsenbast</ENAMEX>. Papers presented at
the 3rd <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knigswinter Seminar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIK Proceedings</ENAMEX>.
Elsenblast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfgang</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulrich Stumpf</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. "The Cost of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Service</ENAMEX> Obligations in a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Competitive Environment</ENAMEX>." Papers
presented at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">3rd Knigswinter Seminar</ENAMEX>. Wissenschaftliches
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institut fr Kommunikationsdienste</ENAMEX>.
Kolin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward J. Smith</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mail Goes Where the</ENAMEX>
Money Is: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Study of Rural Mail Delivery</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." In
Emerging Competition in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Services</ENAMEX>, edited by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: Kluwer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
Panzar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John C.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funding Universal Service</ENAMEX> Obligations:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Costs of Liberalization</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Future Directions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Reform, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Storer</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Estimating the Cost of the Universal Service Obligation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service." In <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Emerging Competition</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Services</ENAMEX>,
edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
Scarfiglieri, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gennaro</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vincenzo Visco Comandini</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Postal Profits Arise where People Are</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future Directions in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Reform</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household Diary Study</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fiscal Year 1999</TIMEX>." Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.




