



Delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cost Heterogeneity and Vulnerability to Entry*</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephane Bernard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Cohen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Robinson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX>
Joëlle Toledano
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
Spyros Xenakis
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTRODUCTION</ENAMEX>
Virtually every post in an industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> delivers
monopoly products everywhere at a uniform price in spite of large
differences in the cost of serving different geographic areas. This
raises the possibility of an entrant competing successfully even
though it has higher costs than the incumbent. A simple example
illustrates this. Suppose a post serves a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> and its cost to deliver a piece of mail in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cents</ENAMEX> and is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 cents</NUMEX> in the other. A breakeven post with a uniform
tariff would charge its average cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 cents</NUMEX> a piece for
delivery throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. If a less efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entrant</ENAMEX>'s cost
for serving the low cost area were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six cents</NUMEX> a piece, it could
charge <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than 10 cents</NUMEX> in that area and be profitable. Each
piece of mail that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entrant</ENAMEX> delivered would raise the average
cost of delivery in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Ceteris paribus, inefficient entry
means that the total resources required to deliver mail
increases.
*
The views expressed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> are those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and
do not necessarily represent the opinions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Rate Commission
If in the above example the cost had been <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine cents</NUMEX> in the low
cost area and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11 cents</NUMEX> in the high cost area, it would be much more
difficult for inefficient entry to occur. Delivery cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterogeneity</ENAMEX> is an essential condition for inefficient entry and
the degree of the heterogeneity would play an important role in
determining the vulnerability to inefficient entry<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>
The delivery function is the most important source of inherent
cost differences between the geographic areas served by a post and,
indeed between posts themselves. This paper explores the reasons
that underlie differences in delivery costs among geographic areas.
We do this by comparing delivery costs in two diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> We think that international comparisons can
lead to important insights.
We first present demographic and postal delivery characteristics
for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. This leads us to develop the concept of
postal density as a measure that reflects the impact of these
characteristics on delivery costs. We examine differences in postal
density for rural areas and for densely populated areas to identify
the effect of different delivery practices in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. A
comparison is then made of the heterogeneity in delivery costs for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> We proceed to explore the relative roles of
postal density and volume as delivery cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>. Finally, we
compare the engineering and econometric approaches used to estimate
unit delivery costs for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, respectively, over
reasonable ranges of the delivery cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>. The data used for
the analysis are described in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appendix</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SOME BASIC COMPARISONS</ENAMEX>
It would seem that the variation of delivery costs within the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> would be greater than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. Population density in the
former ranges from very high (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>) to very low (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, has densely populated
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> but no areas as sparsely settled as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>
Surprisingly, however, we will find that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has a greater
variation in delivery costs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">109</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square kilometer</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>.
A greater percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>,
while a larger percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> lives in suburbs.
The distance between delivery points in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is much smaller than
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and, consequently, the modes of delivery are very
different, as can be seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
The conditions for competitive entry depend on several other
factors as well [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen et al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cremer et al.</ENAMEX>, (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>)].
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> density (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square kilometer</NUMEX>) of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
least densely populated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the continental
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dakota 3.6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> 4.2. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> density of the two least
populated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creuse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lozère</ENAMEX>, is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>
per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square kilometer</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comparison of Mode of Delivery by Route</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aRounds</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than one</NUMEX> percent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bPark</ENAMEX> and loop refers to a route where the carrier parks his or
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> and serves a group of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> on foot, returns to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> and drives to another
location where the process is
repeated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cAutomobile</ENAMEX> includes small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>.
The geographic concentration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> permits
much more efficient delivery by foot or bicycle than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>3
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> serving rural areas use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> but in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> it is the primary means of delivery. The quality of
delivery service is also higher in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> where all delivery is to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> delivery is made to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and also to
curbside mailboxes (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and suburbs) and to rural roadside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailboxes</ENAMEX>. This allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> to place mail in the mailbox
directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. In addition, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> rural areas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> serve principal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> only and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> who do not live
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>'s line of travel must place their mailboxes on that
road. This frequently results in roadside boxes being clustered
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>'s line of travel intersects with roads not on the
line of travel. These boxes are less expensive to serve than if
they were spread out along the intersecting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> also makes extensive use of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> for
delivery<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX> They allow more efficient delivery because the carrier
makes only one stop to deliver to several addresses (commercial or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">residential</ENAMEX>). This requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to walk some distance from
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> to the kiosk to collect their mail. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX>
and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half million</NUMEX> addresses or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> percent of the total
addresses served have mail delivered to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POSTAL DENSITY</ENAMEX>
The variable cost of delivery depends on volume delivered, thus
the comparison of variable costs between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is
straightforward. It might seem that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> density could be
used to compare differences in the fixed cost of delivery. We have
seen, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> density is not the only explanation
for fixed cost differences. The fixed cost of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
The smaller volume per capita for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">320</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>) in
comparison to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">739</ENAMEX>) also contributes to efficient delivery
by foot or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
Kiosks are free standing structures containing locked mailboxes
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as few as three or four and as many as sixty or so</NUMEX>). They are
called "neighborhood delivery centralized box <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>."
delivery (called route time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> delivery cost analyses)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,5</NUMEX> is
accounted for by the need for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> to move from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">stop6</NUMEX> to
another whatever the mode of delivery. Therefore we use "postal
density" as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> of fixed costs.
Postal density is the number of delivery points that can be
visited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> of time, excluding loading time
and the variable portion of access time and the variable portion of
travel time to and from the route. It renders endogenous all of the
physical characteristics of the route including the mode of
delivery, the "grouping-ratio" (addresses per stop), and the
difficulty of accessing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.7 This measure also makes
comparison possible in spite of the differences in quality of
delivery service<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>
Delivery to a multiple address <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> or to a multiple address
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kiosk</ENAMEX> means that the fixed cost of traveling to that stop is spread
among the several addresses which receive mail there. The concept
of postal density conveniently expresses the cost consequences of
both multi-address <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and multi-address <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX>. We will see
below that the variations in postal density are different from
variations in population density. Postal density is a measure that
contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dimensions: exogenous cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> such as geographic
and demographic characteristics of the areas served, and endogenous
drivers reflecting the quality of delivery service. On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous</ENAMEX> dimension, postal density could in principle be "tuned"
by the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> by adjusting quality of service. Of course,
an increase in postal density would require a reduction in the
quality of service that may not be compatible with the way
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> service obligations are defined in a country<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>

3.1 Comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX> Densities
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> compares <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX> at various
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quantiles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> postal density is higher at every quantile,
but the ratio is strikingly high at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 95th and 90th</TIMEX> quantiles
where it exceeds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 to 1</NUMEX>. On average the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> postal density
exceeds the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> by a ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5 to 1</NUMEX>. This is somewhat less than
the ratio of population density between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> which
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.6</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.10</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC Docket</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R2000</NUMEX>-1.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
A stop can serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more addresses.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
It also gives a better view of the parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that are
actually populated. Totally deserted areas are not
reflected in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
We mean by "quality of delivery service" such things as door,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">curbside</ENAMEX> or roadside line of travel delivery. The
term as used here is not meant to include frequency of
delivery.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
The ability of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> to adjust quality of delivery service
can be affected by the applicable postal law in each
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> law requires delivery to the door.
This level of delivery service, treated as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> service obligation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, is primarily defined by
history and tradition. Thus, delivery quality (and
therefore postal density) can in theory be tuned by the operator
but in practice may be constrained by law.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> Part of the reason that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX> have such
low values with a narrow range may be due to stale data.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> determines the amount of current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> time based on
the percentages of time spent in route and load
activities calculated with data collected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. New data may
show an increase in variable load time to reflect
the increased use of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> and a decrease in route time. This
would produce higher postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Density Comparison with Routes Ranked</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Density



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural Areas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX> in rural areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> are very
different owing to the quality of service. We have found that the
postal density in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of addressees with the
lowest population density is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> while it is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> in the equivalent
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> This is remarkable in light of the much lower
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population densities</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Addresses</ENAMEX> in the most rural areas
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> are much closer together than in the equivalent areas of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> must, however, turn into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">driveway</ENAMEX> and proceed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwelling</ENAMEX>. Once there, he or she must
alight from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> and proceed to the mailbox, then return to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>, turn it around and proceed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> remains on the road, stops at a roadside mailbox and
places mail in it without leaving the vehicle<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> This contributes
to the affordability of postage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has made a
different cost/service tradeoff, which is reflected in each
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s concept of universal service.
Within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> it is surprising that the average postal density
of the bottom quartile of routes (ranked by cost) is lower than the
postal density for the rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> serving the least densely
settled <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the population (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX>). This is
because rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> have a higher postal density than
most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and loop city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> and business routes. This in turn
indicates the greater efficiency of delivering mail to roadside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailboxes</ENAMEX> compared to walking to the front door of a detached
dwelling or business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> and loop routes serve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and their
inner suburbs while curbline routes serve the outer suburbs. Thus,
the postal density of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>' walking between nearby stops is
lower than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>' driving between greatly separated
stops. The postal density of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">89 addresses per hour</NUMEX> for the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> corresponds to roadside <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mailboxes</ENAMEX> that are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meters</NUMEX> apart (on average). Many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">detached houses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are as
close as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 meters</NUMEX> apart. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the bottom decile of routes
ranked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> density averages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>. The average distance
between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stops is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around 400 meters</NUMEX>, and the delivery to the
door increases time between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stops.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">11 Moreover</ENAMEX>, on many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> served by rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>, mailboxes
must be placed on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> designated side of the
road. This relieves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> from the need to travel back
down a road to serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">curbside</NUMEX> boxes on the other side
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Densely Populated Areas</ENAMEX>
At the extreme, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> densities are as high as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population densities</ENAMEX>. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> shows that the inner
area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> has a higher population density than that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. But on average <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> densities are much lower as
indicated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> which shows that the urbanized area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
is much more densely populated than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population Density</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and
Parisa

aData Source: Demographia <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> bVille <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">de Paris</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and the
borough of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> for New York
This is reflected in the ratio of multi-address stops to single
address stops in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> displays this
relationship<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> It shows the ratio of delivery points to stops
ranked by cost. At the left side of the graph where volume is least
costly to deliver we find the most multiple address stops. As the
ratio of points to stops decreases, mail gets more expensive to
deliver. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX> has a much higher ratio of multiple address stops
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ratio: Delivery Points to Stops</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>
Semi-decile of Volume (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Routes Ranked by Increasing Delivery</ENAMEX>
Costs)
12 Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> contains data for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> only.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3.4 Comparison of Variation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Density</ENAMEX> and Volume
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> displays the range of postal density and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> volume
per address that encompass <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 90 percent</NUMEX> of the routes
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. It shows much greater variation in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> postal densities than for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and much smaller
variation in volume per address in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> The area
of overlap is quite small relative to the ranges for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
The greater variation in volume per address in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is probably
due to the fact that mail volume and income are highly correlated
and the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has a much larger variation in income
per household than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.13 The smaller variation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">densities</ENAMEX> is due to differences in the quality of delivery service
which dampen the impact of low population density on many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>.
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has a uniform quality of delivery, its postal
density differences are much greater.

Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Range</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Densities</ENAMEX> and Volumes for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3500</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> 2500
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0 100 200 300 400 500 600 700 800 900</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Density</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Possible Deliveries Per Hour</ENAMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. HETEROGENEITY AND <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">RELATIVE VULNERABILITY TO INEFFICIENT</ENAMEX>
ENTRY
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> displays the distribution of normalized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
delivery costs for each semi-decile of volume (or traffic) when
routes are ranked from least to most costly. To protect
commercially sensitive data and to facilitate comparison we display
normalized costs and not actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.14</NUMEX> All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs are
displayed relative to the mean of the distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs.
For purposes of this analysis we discard the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and last
semi-deciles for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> because the observations upon which
they are based contain data of questionable accuracy.
13 See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">14</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> costs refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> street time measured in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>
per delivered piece. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is an international currency and
facilitates cost comparisons.
Volume (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Pieces per Address</ENAMEX>)


Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comparison of Unit Delivery Costs of La Poste and</ENAMEX>
USPS
3.00
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indexed Unit Delivery Costs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mean</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.00</NUMEX>)
2.50
2.00
1.50
1.00
0.50
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.00 5% 10% 15% 20% 25% 30% 35% 40% 45% 50% 55% 60% 65% 70% 75%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80% 85% 90% 95% 100%</NUMEX>

Semi-decile of Volume (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Routes Ranked by Increasing Delivery</ENAMEX>
Costs)
We see that the range of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> distribution is greater than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> distribution. The former begins with a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.24</NUMEX>
(relative to the mean) and ends with a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.57</NUMEX> (relative to
the mean). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, begins with a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.33</NUMEX>
and ends with a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.93</NUMEX>. The standard deviation of the
normalized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> distribution is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> again as large as the
normalized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> distribution (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.67</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.44</NUMEX>). Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
distribution is more heterogeneous than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> distribution.
Vulnerability to inefficient entry can be addressed using
delivery cost heterogeneity. Some indicators of vulnerability are:
the percentage of the volume that has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost less than half
the mean, the size of the area between actual costs and the average
cost, and the average slope of the cost curve. These are based on
the conjecture that an entrant would seek to compete where the unit
delivery cost was very low while using the uniform tariff as an
umbrella price. These measures of vulnerability make sense, of
course, only with a uniform tariff constraint, and more generally
when geographical cost oriented tariffs are not applied.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> reveals that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX> of the volume has a
cost less than half the mean while in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20 percent</NUMEX> of
the volume is below this threshold. Ceteris paribus, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is more
vulnerable to inefficient entry. Another relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> would be
the geographical concentration of the low cost volume. We believe
that the low cost volume is scattered over perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> or
more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> metropolitan areas while in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> the volume is
concentrated in relatively few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. Thus, it would be far easier
for an entrant to market its alternative service in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> than in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the per capita volume
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> giving it less economies of scale. This means that the
consequence of volume erosion would be greater in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> than in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> There are, of course, other relevant factors affecting
entry such as wage premium, efficiency of operation and
classification efficiency<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX>
15 See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> compares <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> traffic and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX> when routes are ranked by cost. We see that in
both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> the volume for the least costly areas is
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> twice that of the most costly areas. Thus, the volume
range for both is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The range of postal density is
much greater for both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The maximum is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> times the
minimum for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX> times the minimum for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> The
greater variation in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> postal density leads to a greater
variation in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs relative to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> As discussed
below, the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> volume magnifies the impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost
from the variations in postal density.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>: Volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per Delivery Point</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Density</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10% 15% 20% 25% 30% 35% 40% 45% 50% 55% 60% 65% 70% 75% 80% 85%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90% 95%</NUMEX>
Semi-decile of Volume (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Routes Ranked by Increasing Delivery</ENAMEX>
Costs)
The different ranges in postal density and volume when routes
are organized by cost rather than organized by postal density or
volume (as displayed earlier in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) demonstrate the
interaction of postal density, volume, and delivery costs. In
particular the actual volume ranges shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> are much
greater than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to one ratios observed in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> displays an interesting phenomena in that for the most
costly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of the routes the postal density in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is
lower than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> This is due to the fact that in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> the most sparsely populated areas do not correspond to the
highest cost routes. This is partly explained by the line-of-travel
requirement, which greatly reduces the cost of delivery in areas
with low population density. Moreover, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> the routes with
the lowest postal density are not the routes with the lowest
traffic<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX> In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, on the contrary, routes with the lowest
postal density have the lowest volumes. This also explains why
there is greater heterogeneity in costs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> than in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
16 This is probably linked with a wealth effect, as volumes are
driven by the wealth of the recipient (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berthelemy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toledano</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>)).




<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. INTERACTION OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COST DRIVERS</ENAMEX>
In this section we examine the impact of changes in postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">density</ENAMEX> and volume per address on the average cost in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> average costs are derived from an engineering model
mentioned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appendix</ENAMEX> and described in detail in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> average costs are derived from an econometrically
estimated translog equation of street time<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> The equation relates
street time to volume per address, postal density, and the number
of addresses. The number of addresses is set as a "control"
variable in the equation, allowing us to develop average costs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4 presents La Poste</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> normalized <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery
costs for each combination of quartiles of low, medium and high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX> and volumes per address. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are
presented, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> values immediately below the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
values. Postal density in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is higher than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> in all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quartiles</ENAMEX> and ranges from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX> addresses/hour at the low quartile to
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">256 addresses/</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> at the highest quartile. This range of postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">densities</ENAMEX> is much greater than the corresponding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">140 addresses per hour</NUMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> volume per address is higher
in all quartiles, and its range is wider in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Poste</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> Index of Average Costs*
Low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Density</ENAMEX> (PD) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medium Postal Density High Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Density % Change La Poste</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Addresses/Hour</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">135 Addresses/Hour</ENAMEX>)
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">256 Addresses/Hour</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AC USPS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Addresses/Hour</ENAMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Addresses/Hour</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">140 Addresses/Hour</ENAMEX>) (due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PD</ENAMEX>)
Low Volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Poste</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">673 Pieces/Address/Year</ENAMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.81 1.09 0.62</NUMEX>

-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,090</NUMEX> Pieces/Address/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.76 1.28 0.92</NUMEX>
-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48%</NUMEX>
Medium Volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Poste</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">767 Pieces/Address/Year</ENAMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.64 1.00 0.58</NUMEX>
-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,448</NUMEX> Pieces/Address/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.35 1.00 0.73</NUMEX>
-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX>
High Volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Poste</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">946 Pieces/Address/Year</ENAMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.40 0.87 0.52</NUMEX>
-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,919</NUMEX> Pieces/Address/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.04 0.79 0.59</NUMEX>
-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43%</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste % Change</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AC</ENAMEX> (due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vol</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-23% -20% -16%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS %</ENAMEX>
Change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AC</ENAMEX> (due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vol</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-41% -38% -36%</NUMEX>
* Street <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Time only</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seconds per Piece</ENAMEX>) Note: Low = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> Quartile;
Medium = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> Quartile or Median; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">High</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quartile</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> The specification of the estimated translog equation is:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ST=β0+β1lnQ+β2</ENAMEX>(lnQ)<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2+β</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3lnD+β4</ENAMEX>(lnD)<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2+β</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5lnB+β6</ENAMEX>(lnB)<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2+β7</NUMEX>(lnQ)(lnD)+
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">β8</NUMEX>(lnQ)(lnB)<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">+β9</NUMEX>(lnD)(lnB)
Where: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ST = Street Time</ENAMEX>
Q = Volume (Pieces per Address)
D = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Density</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Addresses per Hour of Fixed Time</ENAMEX>)
B = Addresses
The translog equation was estimated using <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> data from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39,737</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> routes and a stratified sample of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,300</NUMEX> city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX> shows that in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> volume is a more important
cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> at low postal density than at high postal density. This
is because, ceteris paribus, at low postal density the fixed costs
are higher and the potential for scale economies is therefore
greater. Conversely, at high postal densities the fixed costs are
lower and thus the potential for scale economies is not as
great.
Similarly, postal density is a more important cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> in
both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> at low volume because at low volume the savings in
fixed costs realized from increasing postal density are spread to
fewer pieces. Conversely, postal density is a less important cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX> at high volume because the savings from an increase in
postal density are spread across a greater number of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1300</TIMEX>

pieces.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2200 44</TIMEX>
It should be noted that the impact of postal density on cost is
greater in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> than in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has a wider range of postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX> and
lower volumes. In contrast, the impact of volume is greater in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has lower postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX> and
a greater variation in volumes. Finally, postal density appears to
be a more important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> of unit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery costs than
volume over the actual ranges in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNIT COST BEHAVIOR</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Poste</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulation model</ENAMEX> and the cost function developed
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>, described above, provide alternative means of
estimating average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs over a range of volumes per delivery
point and postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX>. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> displays average costs
generated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX>
Unit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delivery Cosst</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sec/</ENAMEX>piece)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">simulation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and data for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> postal activities. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
displays the average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs generated with the cost function
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unit Delivery Costs</ENAMEX> as a Function of Volume and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Density Derived</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Poste Delivery Cost Simulation Model</ENAMEX>
90
60
30
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yearly</TIMEX> Volume per Address
Possible <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deliveries Per Hour</ENAMEX>)
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unit Delivery Costs</ENAMEX> as a Function of Volume and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Density Derived</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Translog Model</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS Data</ENAMEX>

The remarkably similar shapes of the two surfaces demonstrate a
convergence of simulation and regression approaches to estimating
the behavior of delivery costs with postal density and volume per
address as cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>. The difference in unit delivery costs
values reflect different input prices in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
The figures visually demonstrate the relationship between low
postal density and/or low volume and high average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs; and
conversely the relationship between high postal density and/or high
volume and low average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs. Also, the figures exhibit the
rapid change in unit delivery costs as either volume or density
increase. However, once either high volume or high density is
achieved, the opportunities for further reductions in average unit
costs by increases in either volume or density are minimal.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONCLUSIONS</ENAMEX>
The analysis of delivery costs for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
demonstrates that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery costs are more heterogeneous in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Ceteris</ENAMEX> paribus, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is more vulnerable
to inefficient entry than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
The heterogeneity of delivery costs is driven by differences in
volume, geographical characteristics and quality of delivery
service. The concept of postal density captures the nonvolume
factors in a single measure. Rationalizing street delivery cost by
decreasing the quality of delivery service can have a profound
impact on the postal density and consequently, on delivery
cost.
Due to this rationalization of delivery cost in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densities</ENAMEX> of the most sparsely populated areas are higher
than the densities of the most sparsely populated areas of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.
Postal density appears to be a more important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> of unit
street delivery costs than volume over the actual ranges in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S. Furthermore</ENAMEX>, high postal densities reduce the impact
of volume on unit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery costs, and high volume reduces
the impact of postal density.
APPENDIX:
Delivery Data
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
The delivery data for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX> are obtained for each delivery
area. A delivery area represents a postcode (or several postcodes
in some cases). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> is divided into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 6000</TIMEX> delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>. Each area averages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> routes (with of course a very high
deviation)<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs (expressed in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> and normalized
as explained) are estimated by an engineering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">model19</NUMEX> to allow for
simulations over variations of traffic. They are obtained the
following way: The information system allows the description of
each area with geographic characteristics (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stops</ENAMEX>, number of delivery points, surface, length of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>) and traffic. The delivery model constructed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Poste</ENAMEX> uses
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> of parameters, and allows the calculation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery with an error of less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> in each
area. At this stage, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unit cost is calculated for each area. It
gives a quite aggregate view of street costs compared to the
fineness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> costs. In reality, each area is quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heterogeneous</ENAMEX>: it generally consists of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and an
outlying area with different geographical characteristics. To have
a more precise view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs (and to have a better level of
comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> costs which are by route instead of by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographic</ENAMEX> area), the costs are then divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> per
area. We finally obtain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> unit costs in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> areas.20 The
subareas are then ranked on the criteria of increasing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs.
They are re-aggregated into increments of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of traffic:
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent of traffic delivered is reached with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, and the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent of traffic is obtained with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
delivery data are from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Carrier Cost System</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural National Mail Count System.21 City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> make up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>
percent of the routes and rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> make up the
remainder<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.22</NUMEX>


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Carrier System</ENAMEX> contains a stratified sample of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,300</NUMEX>
routes and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural National Mail Count System</ENAMEX> provides data
on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39,737</NUMEX> rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>. The data elements used in this study are:
the number of addresses served; the number of stops; (for city
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> only) volume per address, and address per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometer</NUMEX> (for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> only). City <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> time is derived from the USPS
Cost Segments and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Components Report</ENAMEX> for FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> and the average
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> delivery areas and more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> routes, and
many delivery areas, like in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lozère</ENAMEX> only have one route.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">19 See Roy 1999</ENAMEX> "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technico Economic Analysis</ENAMEX> of the Costs of
Outside Work in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Delivery</ENAMEX>". This <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is used in the cost
accounting system to determine costs by products.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> These sub-areas represent an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> routes per
area.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">21 See PRC Docket No.</ENAMEX> R2000-1.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 Approximately 30 percent</NUMEX> of rural routes serve non-rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> suburbs.
calculated and used for all city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> routes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural</ENAMEX> carrier
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> is included in the rural mail count system.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Variable</ENAMEX> and Fixed Costs
We divide out-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> delivery costs into their components
using the method developed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>.23 Load time
is included in the variable costs. For simplicity the variable
portion of access and travel to and from the beginning of the route
are ignored. The remaining time is fixed and includes the time
between stops (route time and the fixed portion of access) and the
fixed portion of travel time.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">23 See PRC Docket No.</ENAMEX> R2000-1.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REFERENCES</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berthélémy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Françoise L. and Joëlle Toledano</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mail Goes Where the Money and Business Are</ENAMEX>." In Current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Reform</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ferguson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waller</ENAMEX>, and Spyros
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xenakis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Service</ENAMEX> without a Monopoly." In Current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Reform</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert, Carla Pace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Robinson</ENAMEX>, Gennaro
Scarfiglieri, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincenzo Visco Comandini</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waller</ENAMEX> and Spyros
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xenakis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comparison of the Burden of Universal Service in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Services</ENAMEX>:
Pricing, Productivity, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation and Strategy</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.A. Crew</ENAMEX>
and P.R. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
Cremer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmuth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">André Grimaud</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Jacques Laffont</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
"The Cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Service</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Sector</ENAMEX>." In Current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Reform</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
Cremer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmuth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">André Grimaud</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Pierre Florens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Roy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joëlle Toledano</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. "Entry and
Competition in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Market</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundations</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Construction</ENAMEX>
of Entry Scenarios." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Regulatory Economics</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> (no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">107121</ENAMEX>.
Demographia <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">demographia</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/db-lonlanypar.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm.</ENAMEX>
Kolin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Davis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mail Goes Where the Money</ENAMEX>
Is: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Study of Rural Mail Delivery</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>." In Emerging
Competition in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Services</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>, Bernard. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> "Technico-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Analysis</ENAMEX> of the Costs of
Outside Work in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Delivery</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Emerging Competition</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delivery Services</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC Docket No.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R2000-1 USPS LR-I-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary Description</ENAMEX> of USPS
Development of Costs by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segments and Components</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Rate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prc</ENAMEX>.gov.




