



A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEASURE OF SCALE ECONOMIES FOR POSTAL SYSTEMS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ROBERT H. COHEN</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POSTAL RATE COMMISSION</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EDWARD H. CHU</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</ENAMEX>

PUBLISHED IN MANAGING CHANGE IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POSTAL DELIVERY INDUSTRIES</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MICHAEL A. CREW</ENAMEX> AND <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PAUL R. KLEINDORFER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLUWER ACADEMIC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUBLISHERS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
THE VIEWS EXPRESSED IN THIS PAPER ARE THOSE OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">AUTHORS</ENAMEX> AND
DO NOT NECESSARILY REPRESENT THE OPINIONS OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POSTAL RATE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PROFESSIONAL STAFF MEMBER</ENAMEX> OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POSTAL RATE COMMISSION FROM</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-1995</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PRELIMINARY VERSION OF</ENAMEX> THIS PAPER WAS PRESENTED AT
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WISSENSCHAFTLICHES INSTITUT FÜR KOMMUNIKATIONSDIENSTE</ENAMEX> (WIK) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMHH</ENAMEX>,
3RD <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KÖNIGSWINTER SEMINAR, COST OF UNIVERSAL SERVICE</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">NOVEMBER</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.



Introduction
The delivery function is comparatively new to modern postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. Originally the post was simply an inter-city letter
service. One could deposit a letter at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> in a city
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">transportation</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where the
recipient would call for it<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> It was not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-nineteenth</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery began on a regular basis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the century</TIMEX> rural delivery was started on a limited
basis, but it did not become ubiquitous until the early part of the
twentieth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>.
Delivery changed the post in many ways. No doubt it has been a
substantial cause of the tremendous growth in volume since its
inception. But delivery also changed the economics of the modern
post because it introduced a large amount of fixed costs.
While the letter mail monopoly preceded the introduction of
delivery service, the fixed costs associated with delivery underlie
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> modern justifications for the letter monopoly. First, it is
argued that a letter mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> is necessary to assure universal
service at a uniform price. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it is argued that delivery is a
natural monopoly and that legal protection is necessary to prevent
"cream skimming" and thereby to maximize the benefit of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> delivery system.2 The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> argument is a political one
which presumes significant urban-rural cross subsidizes in
delivery. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is an economic argument which presumes that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> as a monopolist is an efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> of
delivery. The analysis presented here is an attempt to address the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> argument.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James I., Jr.</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Introduction to the History of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Monopoly Law</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Monopoly, The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CATO Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
For purposes of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skimming</ENAMEX>" refers to
concentration on serving only those markets that exhibit
lower-than-average delivery costs, regardless of the characteristic
that causes those costs to be less than average. Such
characteristics are not confined to network density and could
include favorable geographic, demographic, or operational
characteristics. For example, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, curb delivery is less
costly than <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and loop delivery which is less costly than foot
delivery.
In an unsubsidized postal system as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> bears all costs of the system. The customer
therefore is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> where return to scale are maximized by
having a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> (a monopoly) provide delivery. On the other
hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> can be harmful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> when they protect
technically inefficient behavior, and allow economic rents to be
extracted<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> This paper sets up a framework to examine the following
question: Do the economies of scale in the delivery function exceed
the technical inefficiencies and economic rents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service? In short, does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> increase or decrease the price
of postal services to postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>?<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
This paper measures the returns to scale of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> delivery
function. It then compares this benefit with the cost that the
monopoly imposes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>.
Because delivery involves so much fixed cost, it would create a
tremendous barrier to entry even if the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> were
abolished. Thus, it may be that having once enjoyed a de jure
monopoly, national posts would enjoy a de facto monopoly even if
the legal one were abolished. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> provides a
quantification of the barrier to entry in the letter mail market in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> caused by high fixed costs in the delivery
function.
This paper next estimates the value of scale in delivery
exhibited by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> national postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> based on data from an
unpublished paper which was presented at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm</ENAMEX>
conference on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Delivery Services.6 7 Finally</ENAMEX>, it compares
the estimated value of scale with an estimate of the wage premium
in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
It is also claimed that monopolies harm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> with lower
quality of service and by being less innovative than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> which
must compete.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
It is important to distinguish postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> (i.e., paying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of mail. The latter may derive great
benefits from a monopoly in the form of services that would not be
provided in a competitive postal environment. These might be called
political rents. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX>, being forced to underwrite the
political rents and any inefficiencies and economic rents in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, may be better off in a competitive environment.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
This may well be the case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> which abolished its monopoly
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. A letter mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> began operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm</ENAMEX>
where it captured <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the market, but, nonetheless,
failed.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Exploratory Quantitative Comparison</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Administrations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Countries</ENAMEX>."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
The data for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> and is based on UPU
statistics which have been verified and revised as necessary based
on communications with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uniqueness of the Delivery Function</ENAMEX>
We distinguish what is known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> as the "in-office"
delivery function and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery function. The former is
an extension of mail processing; it is where the mail is sorted
into the delivery sequence. "Delivery function" as used in this
paper refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery.
Recent empirical research confirms the widely held belief that
economies of scale exist in the delivery of mail<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> Other functional
components of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> are presumed here not to exhibit
significant scale economies, although this has not been
demonstrated.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panzar</ENAMEX> has characterized street delivery as a bottleneck
function because a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> can deliver to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> at a
lower total cost than multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> delivering to the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. He suggests that processing and transportation of mail do
not seem to be characterized by scale economies, and that they
could be provided by competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. Under this scenario, he
suggests that rates be set to allow nondiscriminatory access to the
monopoly delivery service by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> competing in processing and
transportation<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> have
implicitly recognized the absence of significant scale economies in
mail processing and transportation functions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s rate structure. Postal rates in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> allow for a substantial degree of competition with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> in mailprocessing and transportation. For example,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> gives sorting and barcoding discounts to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40 percent</NUMEX> of First-Class letter volume. Mailers perform
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 60 percent</NUMEX> of this worksharing, while <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> perform
the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Natural Monopoly and Technological Agnosticism: The Case of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Colvin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
Panzar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Competition, Efficiency, and the Vertical</ENAMEX>
Structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Services</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Regulation and the Nature of Postal</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delivery Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.
rest<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10 11</NUMEX> In some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>, mailers transport much of their mail
to downstream locations to take advantage of zoned rates for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>.


Street Delivery Cost
While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> collects extensive data on the cost
behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>, it collects little data on the
cost behavior of rural carriers12 For purposes of this analysis, we
assume throughout that rural delivery cost behavior is similar to
that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX> In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, street delivery costs for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> and city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> combined comprises <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> of total
costs. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1 USPS Operational Costs</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major Function</ENAMEX>

Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nonoperating</ENAMEX> costs, such as payments made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
for retroactive charges are excluded.
10
These third-party sorters collect mail from mailers, sort and
apply barcodes, and deliver the mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> for a
portion of the discount. In addition, discounts encourage bulk
advertising mailers to sort their mail all the way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>'s
walk sequence, thereby avoiding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> "in-office"
function.
11
Economic rents in the form of a wage premium paid by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> partially explain why mailers and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> can
sort mail at a lower cost than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. When third
parties compete with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>, however, in highly
automated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> such as applying barcodes with optical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character readers</ENAMEX> and sorting barcoded mail, a wage premium would
seemingly not be a very significant factor.
12
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types of delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>;
city delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> and rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">thousand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 million</NUMEX> delivery points and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49 thousand</NUMEX> rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23 million</NUMEX> delivery points. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural</ENAMEX>
costs were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of total delivery costs.
13
For example, it is assumed that the ratio of rural carrier
in-office cost to total rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> cost is the same as the ratio
of city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> in-office cost to total city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> cost.
This paper adopts the analysis of street delivery costs
presented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> in several rate proceedings
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20 years</TIMEX>. That analysis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">disaggregates street</ENAMEX> delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> subcomponents: route time, access time, and load
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. "Route time" is the time it would take a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> to walk or
drive the route, passing, but not accessing, any delivery point.
"Access time" is the time it takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> to deviate from the
route in order to make a delivery. This may mean departing from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">basic</ENAMEX> line of travel and walking or driving to a delivery point and
returning to the basic line of travel, or it may mean slowing down
from normal driving speed, stopping to make a delivery to a
curbside mail receptacle, and then resuming normal speed. Finally,
"load time" is the time it takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> to place the mail in a
mail receptacle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">14 Table 2</ENAMEX> disaggregates <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> time in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Table 2</ENAMEX>

Note: For simplicity, coverage-related load time (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,232</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>) is included in access time, and street support is
"piggybacked" on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> functions.
Route time costs are essentially fixed, while access is partly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variable</ENAMEX>, and
load time is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> variable with volume. The analysis of
variability of access
time involves estimating the number of new accesses that would
be caused by an
increment of volume. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 93 percent</NUMEX> of
all possible stops
receive mail each delivery day. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">15 Consequently</ENAMEX>, the number of
new accesses
14
Load time is divided into elemental and coverage related load
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. Elemental load time varies with the number of pieces being
loaded. Coverage related load time is the fixed portion of load
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> at a stop; it varies with the number of stops. Thus, it is
partly variable and partly fixed.
15
A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or more</NUMEX> possible deliveries. For example,
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> unit apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a cluster of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mail boxes would be
one stop and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> possible deliveries.
caused by an increase in volume would be small. Regression
analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> street data indicates that at the current
volume, the variability of access cost is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 6 percent</NUMEX>. In other
words, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> increase in volume will yield a
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.6 percent</NUMEX> increase in the number of accesses.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> regularly collects a representative sample of
street delivery costs, volumes, and delivery point characteristics
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FY 1993</ENAMEX> data set
contains observations from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 300</NUMEX> routes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX> Observed every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks over a one year</TIMEX> period, data is collected from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 270,000</NUMEX>
stops. This data is used to model the behavior of access costs.
The coverage function shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> models the change in the
percentage of possible stops that are accessed on a route as a
result of changes in volume. 17 Marginal access cost can be
estimated from the coverage function. As volume per stop grows and
coverage approaches <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>, the volume variability of access
cost approaches <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. As the volume per stop declines, coverage
declines, and the volume variability of access costs rises.


Measure of Scale Economies
Our methodology for measuring scale economies essentially
compares the cost of providing delivery by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> with the
cost of providing delivery by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>.18 We measure the returns
to scale in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postal delivery function by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> determining
the total cost of delivery provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. Next, we
determine the total cost of delivery performed by the incumbent and
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that is assumed to be equally efficient. We assume
that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> share the market equally, each delivering a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the mail. Further, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> serves
16
See the testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in
Docket No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R94</NUMEX>-1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">USPS-T-5</ENAMEX>) at pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5-10</NUMEX>.
17
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> developed the coverage function and first
used it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Docket No. R76-1</ENAMEX> rate case. For this paper we have
altered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s model slightly. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s
model, all stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> and mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> are consolidated.
18
Of course, the cost of providing delivery by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> could
also be compared with the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. This would
simply inflate the measure of scale economies.

the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> each delivery day. Thus, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> would have
to incur the same route time costs that the incumbent currently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incurs</ENAMEX>. Since each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the volume, the number
of accesses by each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> will be less than the incumbent currently
experiences. The number of total accesses by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> will,
however, be greater than the total experienced by the incumbent
alone. This is because some stops receiving multiple pieces will
receive delivery from both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. We assume here that both firms
provide the same frequency of delivery (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX>
Since route time is essentially fixed<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,20</NUMEX> it would double with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> providing service, each with half the volume. Conversely,
because load time is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> variable with volume, it would not
change, since total volume is assumed not to change. Access cost
would fall somewhere in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>, since it is partly variable and
partly fixed. Access cost variability is estimated from the
coverage function shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Under the duopoly scenario
described, it would grow by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61 percent</NUMEX>. Given these responses to
volume, total street time cost would increase from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.1 billion</NUMEX>. The difference, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.1 billion</NUMEX>, represents an upper
bound on the benefits from scale economies of delivery<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.21</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monopoly Rents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inefficiencies</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> subject to collective
bargaining received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,001</NUMEX> in pay and allowances, and an
additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,713</NUMEX> in fringe benefits<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.22</NUMEX> To put these earnings into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>, the median <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> earnings
19
A niche incumbent might provide delivery less frequently or to a
subset of possible stops. These would be special cases of the more
general case analyzed here.
20
The slight variability the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has found in route time is
ignored here for convenience.
21
Ceteris paribus, less efficient postal services do not have
greater scale economies than more efficient ones. Theoretically
scale economies in delivery are not firm specific. They are a
product of the territory served and the current state of technology
which would be employed by an efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.1 billion</NUMEX>
figure is inflated by any inefficiency and/or wage premium which
characterize the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> and in that sense it is an upper bound.
22
The fringe benefit figure excludes unfunded civil service
retirement liability, certain annuitant benefits, workers
compensation, unemployment compensation, repriced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> leave,
bonuses and awards.
(without fringe benefits) was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24,076</NUMEX> for full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> workers
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael B. Wachter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> conclude that there is a wage and
fringe benefit premium for the postal bargaining labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29.5 percent</NUMEX> with respect to comparable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the private
sector<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.24</NUMEX> Such a wage premium would amount to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX> in
monopoly rents for the entire postal system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachter</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX>
system-wide wage premium exceeds the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.1 billion</NUMEX> delivery scale
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachter</ENAMEX>'s wage premium for the delivery
network alone, however, amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $2.3 billion</NUMEX> which is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.8</NUMEX>
billion less than the value of the scale benefit from delivery.
Unlike labor costs, technical inefficiency of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
has not been analyzed. There is, however, some indirect evidence of
inefficiencies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, total factor
productivity has increased at an average annual rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 0.4</NUMEX>
percent. This is in spite of the fact that little mechanization
existed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> and large amounts were
added in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. Beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX> and continuing to
the present, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $5 billion</NUMEX> has been invested to automated mail
processing, including the in-office carrier sequence function and
forwarding for undeliverable-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-addressed mail. Additional billions
have been invested in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, in part to house the automation.
In spite of this investment, productivity appears to have increased
only in response to hiring freezes, or reductions in the average
wage and fringe benefit package caused by special circumstances. 25
26
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">23 Statistical</ENAMEX> abstracts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 665</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>.
24
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comparability of U.S. Postal Service Wages</ENAMEX> and Benefits to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Sector</ENAMEX>: Evidence from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Compensation Premium</ENAMEX>,
New <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hire Increases, Quit Rates and Application Rates</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael L</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry T. Hirsch</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James W. Gillula</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1995</TIMEX>. Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachter</ENAMEX> has published a number of studies on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s
labor costs under contract to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachter</ENAMEX>
studies claim that they ignore the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
pays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> the same as it pays white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> argue
that it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> (not white male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>) who earn more than their private sector equivalents, and
this only means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> does not discriminate. 25
See "A study of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> Productivity and Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Measurement</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staff Study of the Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 9</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.
26
Other indications of inefficiency are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> claims that
work rules are unnecessarily restrictive and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73,075</NUMEX> grievances
were filed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and not resolved at the local
level. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> has failed to capture a
large market share in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas of direct competition with the
private sector which are relatively unaffected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express Statutes; Parcel Post and Express</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX>. This
may have been in part caused by either a wage premium or technical
inefficiencies or a combination of both. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> argues
that a
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> presents the consumer benefit from delivery scale
economies net of inefficiencies which are expressed as a percentage
of total postal costs. The top curve incorporates any wage premium
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> may have, the bottom curve nets out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachter</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29.5 percent</NUMEX> wage premium. The top curve shows that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0 percent</NUMEX> inefficiencies with its current wage premium,
the measure of scale economies equal <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.1 billion</NUMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 13 percent</NUMEX> inefficient, there would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> net
scale benefit. The bottom curve shows that at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0 percent</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inefficiencies</ENAMEX>, the net scale benefit is -<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 billion</NUMEX> if the value
of scale is adjusted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachter</ENAMEX>'s wage premium. Any inefficiency
would exacerbate the loss. If the wage premium is accurately
calculated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachter</ENAMEX>, it would be difficult to defend
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postal monopoly on purely economic grounds. Moreover,
understanding the net economic cost of the monopoly allows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to
see how much universal service costs postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, at least
under current institutional arrangements.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> presents the same information considering the street
function alone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wachter</ENAMEX>'s wage premium amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $2.3 billion</NUMEX>
for the delivery function alone. Thus, the net scale benefit is
initially positive, whether or not we adjust for the wage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">premium</ENAMEX>.
It is far more likely that a monopoly for delivery alone would
produce net benefits for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> than would a monopoly that
included processing and transportation as well as delivery. This
result lends support to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panzar</ENAMEX>'s suggestion of opening
processing and transportation to competition while maintaining a
monopoly in delivery.
lack of pricing flexibility has contributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s failure. Others argue that the quality of service,
product features, and underlying cost of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s
offerings make them uncompetitive.




Barriers to Entry
Because a large proportion of street costs are fixed<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,27</NUMEX> the unit
(per piece) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> cost initially declines rapidly as volume
increases and continues to decline at a decreasing rate. A firm
with a small share of total volume that competes with an incumbent
in delivery only, will find its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost high relative to the
incumbent, even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> pays no wage premium and or is
more efficient. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> can reduce its fixed costs by reducing
the level of service (i.e., deliver less frequently than the
incumbent). Many First-Class mailers do not require <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> delivery
and most advertising mailers do not require <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> delivery.
While it may be politically difficult, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> postal
administrations have the possibility of reducing delivery
frequency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> displays the cost savings if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> were to reduce delivery frequency. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> are substantial relative to the current <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX>
delivery costs. They are not so substantial when considered in the
context of the total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> expenditure in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3 Cost of Delivery Frequency</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX> illustrates how difficult it would be to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
delivery market<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.28</NUMEX>
The table displays the market share that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> would have
to capture in order
27
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 71 percent</NUMEX> of street cost are fixed.
28
Over and above the problems discussed here, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> mail box
law represents a huge barrier to entry. The law forbids any private
party from placing anything in a receptacle used to deliver mail to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> or business.
to have the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> costs as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>. For
example, if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days a week</TIMEX> and its combined
wage and efficiency advantage is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> would
have to capture <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of the total market in order to have the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> delivery cost as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. Even if this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competitor</ENAMEX> delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only one day</TIMEX> per week, it would have to
capture <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of the total market in order to have the same
unit delivery cost as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> on a national basis. This
is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 27 billion</NUMEX> pieces per year or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">519 million</NUMEX> pieces per week.
Assuming a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> would capture volume slowly and would have to
charge rates no higher than the incumbent, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> would
have to be ready to sustain large loses before it could break even.
Thus, the effects of economies of scale in delivery present
significant barriers to entry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Table 4 Break-Even Market Share for Competitors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Competitor Combined Wage</ENAMEX> and Efficiency Advantage



An <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Comparison of the Values of Scale</ENAMEX> in Delivery
with Wage Premiums
As mail volume increases in postal systems, variable costs
(processing and transportation) increase and fixed costs decrease
as a percentage of total costs. Therefore, street delivery costs,
which are largely fixed, decrease as a percentage of total costs as
volume increases. Route time cost, which is a fixed cost and the
largest component of street delivery costs, decreases with a rise
in volume. The fixed access cost as a percentage of total cost
would increase with volume until all stops are covered while the
variable access cost percentage decreases as volume increases.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> shows these relationships for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>
costs.
Conversely as volumes decrease, fixed costs become a higher
percentage of total costs. For example, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>
volume were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one third</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> level, then delivery costs as a
percentage of total costs would increase from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 21</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX> of total costs. In equally efficient but
smaller volume postal systems, street delivery costs should also be
a much greater percentage of total costs than the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX> displays the implied coverage, the percentage of total
cost represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery cost, and the percentage of
total cost represented by fixed delivery cost for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
based on their respective per capita volume in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. 29 For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 230</NUMEX> pieces per capita which yields a
coverage of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 64 percent</NUMEX>. Its per capita volume and
corresponding coverage imply that its fixed portion of delivery
equaled <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 19 percent</NUMEX> of its total costs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, by
comparison, had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 535</NUMEX> pieces per capita and had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91 percent</NUMEX>
coverage for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. Thus, the fixed portion of delivery in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
amounted to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 14 percent</NUMEX> of total cost. The implied coverages
range from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 100 percent</NUMEX>. The implied
proportions of fixed delivery cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tot</ENAMEX> total cost ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX>.
This assumes that the coverage function (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), developed
from an analysis of delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, is valid for the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> included in this analysis.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5 Fixed Delivery Costs</ENAMEX>

Note: Assumes fixed costs are incurred only in the delivery
function. All other functions are assumed to vary with volume.
For each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the international data set
described above, we calculate the value of scale in the delivery
function using the same approach we used for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> with a slight
modification. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, we calculate the value of scale by
comparing the cost of a hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duopoly</ENAMEX> with the cost of a
monopoly. This is calculated using volume per possible stops data
and the coverage function. For the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, we use a
slightly different approach because detailed street delivery cost
and point of delivery data are not available. We use volume per
capita as a proxy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> per possible stop and assume that the
street delivery cost to total cost relationship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is the
same for the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. See the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Appendix</ENAMEX> for a
more detailed discussion of the methodology.
Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1988</ENAMEX> data, we use the per capita volume for each
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to approximate pieces per possible stop. We assume a direct
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linear</ENAMEX> relationship between volume per capita and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> per
possible stop. Using the estimates of pieces per possible stop for
each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, we then calculate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> and the duopoly costs
based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> costs. We then take the ratio of the value of
scale to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> cost and multiply that ratio by the actual
total costs for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to estimate the value of scale for
each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
For example, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, the value of scale is about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.46 billion</NUMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, the total cost for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $36.5 billion</NUMEX>. When we adjust the total
cost for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s coverage level, the total cost would
be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $26.7 billion</NUMEX>. If we assume that all cost segments other
than street delivery vary with volume, the value of scale is about
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> of the total cost at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s volume and
coverage levels. We then apply the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> estimate to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s actual total cost for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.58 billion</NUMEX>) to
calculate the value of scale<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.30</NUMEX> The value of scale for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.1 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX> displays the estimates of
value of scale for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in our data set. The value of
scale ranges from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14 million</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 billion</NUMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
A measure of a wage premium can be calculated for each country
by comparing the postal <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> wage with the average manufacturing
wage in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.31 It should be noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> have a negative wage premium according to this measure.
The net value of scale is the difference between the value of scale
and the wage premium.
30
The total costs for national postal systems other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
are expressed in purchasing power parities.
31
The postal data for calculating the wage premium comes from the
above mentioned paper. The private sector data comes from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Comparisons of Hourly Compensation Costs</ENAMEX> for
Production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturing</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Labor Statistics</ENAMEX>, Report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">873, June 1994</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6 Comparison</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value</ENAMEX> of Scale in Delivery with the Wage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premium</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Postal Systems</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ millions</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1988</NUMEX>)

Note: Expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollars based on purchasing power
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parities</ENAMEX>.
If the wage premium measure is valid, then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have
a wage premium alone which exceeds the value of scale in the
delivery function; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
In these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, it appears that it would be difficult to
justify a postal delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> based on economic grounds.
Better understanding of inefficiencies in national postal systems
would allow further evaluation of the economic basis for the postal
monopoly in the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.32
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> do not have legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TECHNICAL APPENDIX</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Estimating the Coverage Function</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>
We use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1993</ENAMEX> data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Carrier</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">System</ENAMEX> (CCS) to model the behavior of access costs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCS</ENAMEX> data
base contains a representative sample of street delivery costs,
volumes, and delivery point characteristics for city delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCS FY 1993</ENAMEX> data set contains observations from about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> routes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> sampled each route every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a one year</TIMEX> period resulting in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 8,000</NUMEX> route-level
observations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Coverage Model</ENAMEX>
For this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, we use a nonlinear regression <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> that
establishes the relationship between volume and coverage. We define
"coverage" as the percentage of stops on a route that receive mail.
It has been well established that route coverages relate directly
to the fixed and variable nature of access cost. The coverage model
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specification</ENAMEX> is as follows:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COVi</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> - e -b*<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPSi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
where, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COVi</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASi / PSi ASi</ENAMEX> = Number of actual stops on route i
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSi</ENAMEX> = Number of possible stops on route i <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPSi</ENAMEX> = Number of pieces
per possible stop on route i
Since coverage cannot exceed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>, we have specified an
exponential function. The regression results from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> are
highly significant. The estimated coefficient, b, is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.6587</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">B. Measure of Scale Economies</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Scale Economies for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
We measure the returns to scale in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postal delivery
function by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> determining the total cost of delivery provided
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCm</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCm</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ECm</NUMEX> + fm * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACm</ENAMEX> + vm * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
where,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCm</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCm</ENAMEX> = route time cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECm</ENAMEX> = elemental load cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACm</ENAMEX> = access cost (also includes coverage-related load cost)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vm</ENAMEX> = variable portion of access cost = ((e -b*<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPS</ENAMEX> * (b * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPS</ENAMEX>) /
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> - e -b*<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPS</ENAMEX>))) fm = fixed portion of access cost = (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 - vm</ENAMEX>) m =
designates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> case
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1993</TIMEX>, street delivery cost totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $10.07</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">billion:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCm</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCm</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ECm</NUMEX> + fm * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACm</ENAMEX> + vm * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.95</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.91</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.8</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5.20</NUMEX>) + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5.20</NUMEX>)
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.07</NUMEX>
Next, we determine the total cost of delivery performed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that we assume to be equally
efficient. We calculate the cost for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in our
hypothetical duopoly by adjusting equation (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>):
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCfirmi</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCm</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECm</ENAMEX> + ffirmi * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACfirmi</ENAMEX> + vfirmi * ACfirmi
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
where, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCfirmi</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery cost for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">i ACfirmi</ENAMEX> =
access cost for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> i = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACm</ENAMEX> * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCOV NCOV</ENAMEX> = new coverage a duopoly
firm i = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> - (COVm - COVd)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COVm</ENAMEX> = coverage for a monopoly = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> - e -b*PPS
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COVi</ENAMEX> = coverage for a duopoly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> i = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> - e -b*<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PPS/2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vfirmi</ENAMEX> = variable portion of access cost = ((e -b<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">*PPS/2 *</TIMEX> (b *
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPS</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/2</ENAMEX>) / (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 - e -b*PPS/2</ENAMEX>))) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ffirmi</ENAMEX> = fixed portion of access cost =
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 - vfirmi</ENAMEX>)
The total delivery cost for the duopoly market is simply
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCduopoly</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCfirmi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1993</TIMEX>, total street delivery costs for the
hypothetical duopoly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> are as follows:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCfirmi</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCm</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECm</ENAMEX> + f * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACfirmi</ENAMEX> + v * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACfirmi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.95</NUMEX>
+ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.91</NUMEX>) + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.52</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.19</NUMEX>) + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.48</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.19</NUMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.098</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCduopoly</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCfirmi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) = <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 * 8.098</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.2</NUMEX>
Value of Scale= <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCduopoly - SCm</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.2</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.1</NUMEX>
The value of scale in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $6.1 billion</NUMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the total cost for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $48.2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. If we assume that all cost segments other than street
delivery (i.e., in-office delivery, mail processing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>, retail services, and other costs) vary with volume,
the value of scale amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 13 percent</NUMEX> of the total
cost.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Scale Economies for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> Systems1
For each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>) described
above, we use a slightly different approach because detailed street
delivery cost and point of delivery data are not available. We use
volume per capita as a proxy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> per possible stop and
assume that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> delivery cost to total cost relationship of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is the same for the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
First, we use volume per capita for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to approximate
pieces per possible stop. We assume a direct linear relationship
between volume per capita and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> per possible stop:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPSi</ENAMEX> = (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCi / VCu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s.</ENAMEX>) * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPSu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)
where, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPSi</ENAMEX> = Average pieces per possible stop for country i
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPSu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s.</ENAMEX> = Average pieces per possible stop for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">VCi</ENAMEX> =
Volume per capita for country i <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s.</ENAMEX> = Volume per capita for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
For the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, for example, we estimate an average of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX> pieces per possible stop (with a corresponding coverage of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 69 percent</NUMEX>):
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPSi</ENAMEX> = (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCi / VCu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s.</ENAMEX>) * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPSu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) = (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">264/536</NUMEX>) * <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.66</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.49</NUMEX> *
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.66</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX>
1In contrast to the previous section, all data in this section
are from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1988</TIMEX>.
Using the estimates of pieces per possible stop for each
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, we calculate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> cost and the duopoly cost using
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">equations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> costs. For example,
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, equations (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) would result in
the following results:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCm</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCm</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ECm</NUMEX> + fm * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACm</ENAMEX> + vm * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.95</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.94</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.48</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.08</NUMEX>) + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.52</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.08</NUMEX>)
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.98</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCfirmi</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCm</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECm</ENAMEX> + f * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACfirmi</ENAMEX> + v * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACfirmi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.95</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.94</NUMEX>) + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.27</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.78</NUMEX>) + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.73</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.78</NUMEX>)
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.22</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCduopoly</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCfirmi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
= <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 * 6.22</TIMEX>
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.44</NUMEX>
Value of Scale= SCduopoly - SCm
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.44</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.98</NUMEX>
= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.46</NUMEX>
The value of scale is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $4.46 billion</NUMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, the total cost for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $36.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. When we adjust the total cost for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s
coverage level, the total cost would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $26.7 billion</NUMEX>. If we
assume that all cost segments other than street delivery vary with
volume, the value of scale is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 17 percent</NUMEX> of the total cost at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s volume and coverage levels. We then apply the
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> estimate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s actual total cost for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.58 billion</NUMEX>) to calculate the value of scale. The value of
scale for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.1 billion</NUMEX>.




