



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward J. Gleiman</ENAMEX>

Speech before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Envelope Manufacturers Association</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williamsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 29, 2000</TIMEX>
Good morning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX>.
The law provides that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> may, from time to time,
request that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX> recommend "rates and fees [that] shall
provide sufficient revenues so that total estimated income â€¦to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> will equal as nearly as practicable total estimated
costs of [operating] the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>."
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 12th</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> submitted such a request
seeking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $3.7 million dollars</NUMEX> in revenue to be
generated by an overall average rate increase of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 6.4</NUMEX>
percent. After lengthy deliberations, during which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 days</TIMEX> of hearings to consider <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">178</NUMEX> pieces of testimony
presented by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">122</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> representing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has concluded that the---- Wait
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX>, I think I picked up the wrong presentation on my way out
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.

Let me try again.
Good morning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX> invited me to visit with you, I plumb forgot that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> would be in the final throes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R2000-1</ENAMEX> rate
case in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late October</TIMEX>. So, while it would certainly be a pleasure to
be here under normal circumstances, I want to extend a special
thanks to you for having me here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. If for no other reason, it
has provided an excuse to escape for a day the pressure--cooker
atmosphere associated with putting the finishing touches on a major
rate case decision.
Good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> willing and the creek don't rise, or perhaps I should
say if the computers don't crash, we hope to have that decision out
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, November 13th</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX> suggested that I talk about the future-- about postal
reform, its impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> and other changes the postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> may be facing. Before I whip out my somewhat cloudy
crystal ball, I thought you might be interested in a brief outline
of the process currently associated with postal rate making. And,
as I talk about the process, I will attempt to debunk a few myths
and set the record straight on what you may have heard at previous
get togethers. I will also talk about an issue that I believe has
greater potential to impact the future well-being of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service and the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> than the much discussed diversion
of transactional mail to electronic bill paying.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Prior to 1970</TIMEX>, postage rates were set by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Rates,
generally, did not cover the costs of providing service, so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> appropriated tax dollars to make up the difference. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Postal Reorganization Act of 1970</ENAMEX> changed all that. It replaced the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office Department</ENAMEX> with a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX> and
charged it with operating in a more business-like fashion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
would no longer set postal rates, but it wanted to ensure that the
public had an opportunity to be heard before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
changed rates or services. Therefore, it simultaneously established
a separate, independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX> to provide an open
process in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> could participate in the development of
postage rates.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myth Number One</ENAMEX>: Contrary to what you may have heard or read,
although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> was not among the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> recommendations of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kappel Commission</ENAMEX>---appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to study the future
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office Department</ENAMEX>---neither did it spring forth like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phoenix</ENAMEX> from the ashes in some secret conference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>. Permit me, if you will, to correct the record.
The key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> were there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire time</TIMEX>. I read from the
conference report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1970 Act</ENAMEX> at page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX>-
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bill containedâ€¦a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Board</ENAMEX> as an independent
agency not part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> amendment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">containedâ€¦an</ENAMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service. The conference substitute adopts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> provision (for
a freestanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>)â€¦changing the name to the (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> proposed)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commissionâ</ENAMEX>€¦

Perhaps there is a lesson or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> here for those who yearn for a
new Kappel-type presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> as some sort of panacea to
make
recommendations to mold the future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>.
Commissions study and recommend, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> proposes and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> disposes---as it sees fit!
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> intended that mailers should be able to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Rate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s proceedings to assure that some mailers were not
crosssubsidizing other mailers and to assure that postage rates
reflected the costs actually incurred to provide service. Further,
by requiring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> to justify rate and service changes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> hoped to provide a check on inefficiency.
Each of you probably has your own point of view on how well the
system works to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> lean and efficient. But I
hope you would agree that if mailers participate, and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service is subject to public scrutiny, the result is likely to be
better than if proposals go entirely unreviewed. A case in point
can be found in the last omnibus rate case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R97-1</ENAMEX> case.


â€¢
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer</ENAMEX> participation in developing the public evidentiary
record was responsible in part for enabling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to shave
some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750 million</NUMEX>---<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost one third</NUMEX>---off of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s request
for additional revenue. As a result, almost everyone received a
smaller rate increase than would have otherwise been the
case.


â€¢
Another example: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> mailers, stung by sharply
rising costs associated with the processing of their mail, insisted
that postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> join them in an effort aimed at finding
answers and ferreting





<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intervenor</ENAMEX> told us on the record<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">---</NUMEX>a rocket shot compared to
most rate-type proceedings. Moreover, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> does
attempt to shave some time off of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 months</TIMEX> provided in the
law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of mailers both large and small object.
Mailers want as much time as possible to examine the reams of data
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> provides in support of its proposals. With their
money at stake, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailers</ENAMEX> prefer that things be done right rather
than fast! By the way, the original <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> law contained no time
limit on rate cases. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-month</TIMEX> limit was added after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
early cases, overseen by an administrative law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, recruited
from another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, seemed to go on forever.
Some think that we ought to go back in time, ought to get rid of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> and replace it with not one but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> administrative
law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to be borrowed from some other government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. Bad
idea! But don't take my word for it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> wanted me to
remind those who prefer a return to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Admin Law Judges</ENAMEX> that "What's
past is prologue." And, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santayana</ENAMEX> asked me to add that "Those who
cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it."
I mentioned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> also has other responsibilities
which impact the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. These include: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) approving both
changes in existing services and the establishment of new
services---those are known as classification cases; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) adjudicating
complaints from anyone who believes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is not
providing rates or services as required by law; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) issuing advisory
opinions when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> proposes a substantially
nationwide change in the nature of its services; and, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) our mostly
recently assigned task, providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> reports
about the costs and revenues of international mail.
Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120 days</TIMEX> to consider appeals
from those who contend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> has proposed closing
their local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> without following the safeguard procedures
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> wrote into law.
This brings me to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Myth Number Three</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> cannot
close a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> without first obtaining the approval of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>, which supposedly takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>.
The facts are that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> gets involved in only appeals of
closings and then for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 120 days</TIMEX>. That's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX>. Not <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>! You can't get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> out of the equation even if you use
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> fuzzy math!
And how many closings have been appealed? According to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 296</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,614</NUMEX> closings were appealed over a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX>
period. I make that to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 11 percent</NUMEX>. And, what was the
disposition of those appeals, you ask? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> affirmed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> cases;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> cases dismissed; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 58</NUMEX> remanded on grounds that the USPS
had not complied with the procedural requirements of the law.
Number of times the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 120 days</TIMEX> to rule on
an appeal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zero</ENAMEX>! Number of cases in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> was told by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Many years ago</TIMEX>, when I was just starting my government
career, one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX> gave me some advice, in the way of a
quote purportedly from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Petronius Arbiter</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>


Actually, I'm not opposed to change---to postal reform. During
my time at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, we've made quite a few changes. We've
issued rules to encourage experimentation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> and
established procedures for expedited treatment of non-controversial
cases. We've established a website on which we post overnight every
document filed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, and we've created a search
engine that enables everyone to word search these documents.
Want to find out how many times and in what context the aspect
ratio of envelopes was mentioned in the current rate case? How
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about</NUMEX> in each and every case all the way back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>? Try our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">website</ENAMEX>!
Change is not the problem. The problem is---my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is---
that much of what has been on the table in the way of postal reform
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several years</TIMEX> is tantamount to an uncontrolled and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uncontrollable</ENAMEX> experiment. Maybe it is my training in the sciences
coming to the fore, or maybe it's my belief that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
is too important to our economy and too intertwined in our everyday
lives and livelihood to leave too much to chance.
Let me make clear at this point that I have a great deal of
admiration for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McHugh</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 17 years</TIMEX> I spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> I cannot remember more than
a handful of instances in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> invested more of him or
herself in an issue. And, although I took issue with a number of
provisions in his bill, I consider it unfortunate, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> has run out of time in his search for the "Holy Grail" of
postal reform. It is unclear who, if anyone, will take up the
challenge in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 107th</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
In the event that someone does take up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McHugh</ENAMEX> gauntlet and
seeks your support, I think it is important that you, that mailers
not just blindly endorse a bill simply because its title includes
the phrase "postal reform."

Which rates would be lawful in this scenario? The capped rates
that do not cover cost or the rates that exceed the cap but cover
costs? What's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Regulatory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> to do? More to the
point, what's a mailer really likely to experience in the way of
rate increases?
By the way, it's not altogether clear that this price cap regime
would achieve one of its other principle objectives, that is, to
put downward pressure on future cost increases. Why? Because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> has an "exigencies" escape clause and another provision that
prohibits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> from taking any action that might impact labor
negotiations. No, I'm not suggesting that the last provision I
mentioned be drop from any future bill. I do think, however, that
some consideration should be given to a statutory revenue cap as
one means of adding a bit of starch to the spine cost containment.
Without an effective cost containment program---and I have yet to
see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>---the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>, reformed or not, cannot be what
mailers want. It cannot be a low cost, efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> of
service.
These examples are just a couple of the problems in the reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> that many in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> wanted to put on a fast track
through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
Everyone talks about how it has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reorganization Act</ENAMEX> was enacted; that the postal landscape is very
different; that now is time to change the law. Again, I am not
opposed to legislative reform, but, if we are going to put our
money on legislative reform, we had better get it right, because
once that next major postal bill---a reform bill---is enacted, it
may be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 30 more years</TIMEX> before we get a shot at fixing things
again.
And, what would legislative reform mean for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX>? If
something akin to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.R.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> were enacted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> would be neither
strengthened norweakened. It would be different! It would be
relegated largely to after the fact audits as opposed to its
current pre-approved role. And, it would grow to perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times its current complement of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>.
Now, while we are figuring out what should be done in the way of
legislative change, we---the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>---should not just sit back and wait.
There is much to explore; much that can be done within the confines
of current law. We need to push the edges of the envelope---all
them!
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMA</ENAMEX> is already working on a number of forward-thinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>. As one of the world's slowest and worst typists---I guess
they call it keyboarding now---I especially like the idea of
envelopes carrying information I can scan into my computer to
connect with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX>'s website or with an information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.
Let me throw out a few of my ideas for change that are not
conditioned on congressional action:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">â€¢ NSAs</ENAMEX>, or negotiated service agreements, have been a hot topic
in the legislative equation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSAs</ENAMEX> are, for all intents and
purposes, not very different from narrowly drawn classification
proposals; a number of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has received and
approved over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> has any such
proposals on the drawing board, it ought to send them over. If
mailers have ideas, they ought to submit them. If someone thinks we
need to modify our regulations to encourage niche classification
cases, let us know. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSAs</ENAMEX> are doable under current law! Why wait for
legislation, if we can act now to drive costs out of the system and
lower rates for qualified mailers?
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">â€¢ -</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Just</TIMEX> before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">R97</NUMEX> case was filed, when many in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> were concerned about the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s request, I
suggested that a case calling for rates to be phased--in over time
might help avoid the rate shock that comes with large, double digit
increases. This was not an entirely new idea. It was a take--off on
a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS-PRC</ENAMEX> task force recommendation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX> for a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> rate cycle with a mid-cycle adjustment. These proposals
reflected the purported desire of mailers for smaller and,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implicitly</ENAMEX>, more frequent rate increases. We now seem to be in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> rate case cycle. Mailers are, however, understandably
concerned over the cost of litigating these more frequent cases.
But by phasing in rates, they may be able to have their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> and
eat it, too-- smaller periodic increases and fewer cases to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">litigate</ENAMEX>. It is time, I believe, to dust off the task force
recommendation and/or to give some serious thought to the phased
rate approach.
â€¢ -I mentioned our website a bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>. We've been told that
getting documents posted overnight and providing a search engine
has resulted in substantial savings to intervenors and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> can and should do more in this area. With a
little cooperation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, I think we can implement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electronic</ENAMEX> filing and service of documents.
I've already made several suggestions in the package services
area:
â€¢ When I spoke to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parcel Shippers Association</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> I suggested that, given the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s economies of scale
in delivery, alliances with other transportation or delivery firms
to carry their parcels the last mile
made sense---and would make dollars for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. This
is
happening already.
â€¢ I've also suggested that the Service explore making low weight
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parcel Post</ENAMEX> a wholesale, only, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> and pushing low weight
over-the-counter retail parcels into Priority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX>. The price
differential between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priority Mail</ENAMEX> and single piece parcels is very
small. For just a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> more, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> can send a
package Priority, and, if the individual purchases delivery
confirmation, it becomes actually less expensive to use the faster
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priority Mail</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>! Faster service at a lower price means
satisfied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>!
Speaking of delivery confirmation, it is currently available for
Priority and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parcel Post</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> has proposed extending this
service to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> mail. My thought here: Why stop with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>?
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly a quarter billion</NUMEX> pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>--Class mail for
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> purchase the more expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certified Mail</ENAMEX>
option. Delivery of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certified Mail</ENAMEX> piece is more costly to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> than handling a delivery confirmation piece.
Certified mail requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> to make a special trip to the
door. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> is already equipped with a scanner for
delivery confirmation purposes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> has an opportunity to
avoid the time---and time is money---that it takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> to
make that special trip to the door. Delivery confirmation provide
more information quicker at less cost to both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>!
As an old vaudevillian might say, "I've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> of
'em"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">---Well</ENAMEX>, maybe not that many, but it is, I think, time to move
on. I do want to assure you, though, that while I have been talking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, I have not lost sight of the forest.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last October</TIMEX> there was a congressional hearing at which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> presented unverified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
estimates of the impact of the diversion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>--Class
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mail---</ENAMEX>bills and payments---to new technologies. The lead on the
story was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> volume to decline with a loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 billion</NUMEX> in
revenue. At <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33 cents</NUMEX> a pop, I make that to be just short of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> pieces of mail. And, the price of a stamp, according to the
story, it would increase by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 cents</NUMEX>!
That is a pretty bleak picture! However, at the risk of being
labeled a troglodyte, may I suggest that if you scratch the surface
of that picture you might find that a few rays of sunshine still
remain for hard copy mail. While I have no doubt there will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diversion</ENAMEX>, my uneducated guess is that the glide path will be
longer and the incline not so steep. Many believe that there will
be gains to offset losses in transactional mail volume. For
instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Wientzen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMA</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>
that high tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX> are generating new volumes of hard copy
mail as what he called "pure play Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>" launch catalogues
and direct mail campaigns to drive traffic to their Web sites.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX> expressed similar views in a news article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past summer</TIMEX>.
Moreover, unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is incapable of shedding volume
variable costs or waits until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX> before adjusting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>--Class
rates, the price of a stamp does not have to go up by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 cents</NUMEX>.
Unless, it waits until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX> to shore up its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>, volume
declines
May not be so severe. What if I'm wrong? What if the worst case
scenario does come to pass? As I recall from the numbers in that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20th</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Journal-Constitution</ENAMEX> article, there goes much of
that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> of envelopes that currently carry bills and
payments. That is not a pleasant prospect, but it is a heck of a
lot better than the prospect of losing a big chunk of the remaining
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92 percent</NUMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> because an overreaching law restricts
the sharing of personal information and results in direct marketing
volumes going south.
Personal privacy, one's right to control the use of his or her
personal information, is a hot issue. It is a hard one to be
against. And, it is a dangerous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to ignore, either as an
individual or as a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Elements</ENAMEX> of the postal or mailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> or whatever you
might call it have been engaged in the privacy issue at both the
federal and state levels. More often than not, those involved have
been the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that would feel directly the impact of
restrictions on the collection and sharing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> data---the
list <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the direct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX>. Think about this: if the
direct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX> and list <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are forced to cut back because
of data restrictions, won't that impact the manufacture of goods
that are marketed? Might it result in printers printing fewer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">catalogues</ENAMEX>? Won't it impact the envelope manufactures? And, could
it not result in a decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> volumes
across--the--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>?
Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the greater mailer-postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> who have
not been paying attention to the privacy issue must do so. They
must join with others in a broad-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> that ignores
differences they may have on traditional postal issues. If there is
less information and less prospecting, there will be fewer sales.
Fewer sales means <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer</NUMEX> parcels to deliver, whether by white trucks
with an eagle or big, brown <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> needs, as a
whole, I believe, to be proactive in pursuing of a rational,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation-wide</ENAMEX> approach that addresses both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, the rights
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and the needs of the business community.
I cut my teeth on information policy and personal privacy issues
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 25 years ago</TIMEX>, as project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> at the then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
Health, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education and Welfare</ENAMEX> I worked directly on implementation
of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">records Privacy Act of 1974</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> access law. I support the cornerstone concept of these
laws, known as fair information practices. And, I submit that the
federal privacy law, governs the collection and use of personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and which provides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> a modicum of
flexibility, is a reasonable point of departure for future
discussions of either industry selfregulation or legislation.
I had best stop at this point, since I've taken more time and
spouted off more than I should have. But let me leave you with a
thought to keep in mind, in the event you are asked to evaluate my
presentation.
This fellow is flying a hot air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> and suddenly realizes he
is lost. He cuts back on the hot air, descends and yells to a man
he spots on the ground.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Excuse me</ENAMEX>, can you tell me where I am?"
"Sure," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> yells back, "you're in a hot air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> about
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 feet</NUMEX> above this field."
'The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonist</ENAMEX> yells back, "You must work in information
technology."
"I do," replies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, "but how did you know?"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>," shouts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonist</ENAMEX>, "everything you told me was
technically correct, but it's of no use to anyone."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the ground thinks for a moment and yells back, "You
must work in management."
"Why, yes, I do," replies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonist</ENAMEX> proudly, "but how did
you know?"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the ground, "you don't know where you
are or where you are going, but you expect me to be able to help.
You're in the same position you were in before we met, but now it's
my fault!"
Thank you for having me here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>.




