



Before the
Graphics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Association</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 2000</TIMEX>
Good morning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX>.
This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time I have participated in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graphics</ENAMEX>
My first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCA</ENAMEX> conference was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February of 1997</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th</TIMEX> to be
precise, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coral Gables</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Scharf</ENAMEX> lured me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
with promises of sunshine, warm temperatures and the chance to
follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Del Polito</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>. It was cloudy, the temperature
never got above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">45 degrees Fahrenheit</NUMEX> and, after listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
proselytize about postal reform, I tried to enlist!
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX> invited me to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14th</TIMEX> GCA
conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clearwater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. "How could I resist," he asked,
" a chance to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-start on my summer <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">tan?</ENAMEX>" It rained---the
entire time!
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX> called in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> to ask if I would participate in an
R2000-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> postmortem conference, I agreed on the condition that (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) I
speak before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX> and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) that I not be subjected to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s
erratic weather.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX>, I see that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>'s performance is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">---afternoon</TIMEX>. So,
I want to thank you on meeting my first condition.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your</TIMEX> meeting my other condition, what can I say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX> but
thank you. It certainly is a pleasure to be here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>---in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>!
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Now</TIMEX> before you get upset with me, I think you need to know the
real reason we are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>---in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. How many of you know
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Denton</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> who is on the
program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>---with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene---</ENAMEX>is rabid. Oops, I mean he is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">rabid baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>. So much so that he tries to see at least one
game at each major league <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamond</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. Well, as I heard the
story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denton</ENAMEX> was leaning into the plate in fantasy <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> camp
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX> when he took a high, inside, fast ball on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.
Ever since he has been more confused than usual. Apparently he
thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubbies</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chisox</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and home inter-league
series <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. So, he convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX> to hold the conference out
here so he could get a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fer" on that every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
deal.
By the way, for those of you who want the straight skinny on why
I'm leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denton</ENAMEX>'s fault, too! He told me
that there is a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> strikes and you're out" rule for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> on omnibus rates cases. And, judging from the
comments some of you have been making, it appears that I didn't
make it to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> base in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R2000-1</ENAMEX> game. I've got to tell you,
though, that most industry comments pale by comparison to some of
the suggestions I received from the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> on what I can do
with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">34 cent</NUMEX> stamp.
Seriously, though, I know some of you are not all that happy
with a number of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s recommendations. I will speak to
some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of which I have become aware. And, while I do
not mean to suggest that I view anyone's concerns as being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parochial</ENAMEX>, I think it might be useful to set the broader stage of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ratemaking</ENAMEX>---to lay out the general principles that guide
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s conclusions. I also plan to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>
discussing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> finances and mention a couple of other
matters of more than passing interest---at least to me, and I hope
to you.
The law that established the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Postal Service</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> provides
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> may, from time to time, request that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX> recommend "rates and fees [that] shall
provide sufficient revenue so that the total estimated income…to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> will equal as nearly as practicable the total
estimated costs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>."
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> isn't free to make just any old
recommendations so long as the numbers add up. It has to act in
accordance with the general policies set forth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Reorganization Act and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> specific ratemaking factors.

§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3622</TIMEX>. Rates and fees
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> and maintenance of a fair and equitable
schedule;


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
the value of the mail service actually provided each
class or type ofmail service to both the sender and the recipient,
including but not limited to the collection, mode of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>, and priority of delivery;


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
the requirement that each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of mail or type of mail
service bearthe direct and indirect postal costs attributable to
that class or type plus that portion of all other costs of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> reasonably assignable to such class or
type;


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
the effect of rate increases upon the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>,
business mailusers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> in the private sector of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> engaged in the delivery of mail matter other than
letters;


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)
the available alternative means of sending and receiving
letters andother mail matter at reasonable costs;


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)
the degree of preparation of mail for delivery into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> systemperformed by the mailer and its effect upon reducing
costs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>;


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)
simplicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> for the entire schedule and
simple, identifiablerelationships between the rates or fees charged
the various classes of mail for postal services;


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>)
the educational, cultural, scientific, and informational
value to therecipient of mail matter; and


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>) such other factors as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> deems appropriate.
Factor number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> deserves special mention as it is the
mandatory factor. It is at the heart of many a difference of
opinion between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> and mailers,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mailers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX>, and between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of mailers. It is the
factor that causes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to examine all operational costs,
from collection to delivery and the processing that takes place in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>. It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> on which rates are based. Each subclass
must generate sufficient revenue to cover its costs. This policy is
important for another reason. It, combined with factor number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>,
forms the basis for the many, important work-sharing discounts that
are on the books.
It seems to me that, at times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>
recommendations tend to take lightly the considerations embodied in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">39 USC</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3622</TIMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>). "How come," they ask, "did we wind up
with an increase that was larger than that proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>,
when almost everyone else got a break?" There are usually a number
of reasons that situations like this occur. For example, the
Commission believes that costs vary more directly with volume than
does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX>. As a consequence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> costing methodology
generally attributes a larger portion of total operating costs than
does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>.
But why not even things out by ignoring cost differentials
between, say, letters and flats; cost differential put on the table
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>? Why not just look the other way on these
cost differences, or level the playing field by passing on to some
mail <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">300 percent</NUMEX> of costs avoided by work-sharing? Why not give
discounts based on cost avoidances promised in a previous rate or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classification</ENAMEX> case but which savings were never captured by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>? Because it is one thing to encourage work-sharing,
but quite another to ignore the law, and give revenue away. And,
giving away revenue has an effect.
Keep in mind the requirement that a subclass has to generate
revenue to cover its costs. Now, what happens when we give
excessive discounts for some type of mail? Simple! We have to make
up the revenue from other mail, for example, by bumping up, if you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will</ENAMEX>, the benchmark from which those discounted rates are
measured.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> rather formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of mailers whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will
benefit mightily from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s recommendations, the
periodicals mailers, pointed out in a press statement that the
overall average increase for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">First-Class</ENAMEX> mail was much smaller than
the average increase for mail their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> send. Does it matter
that the cost of processing their mail went way up and the cost of
processing First-Class mail declined? Yes. By law, it must matter
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>!
What if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> chose to ignore this divergence in costs
and hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">First-Class</ENAMEX> mail with a larger increase? Whose interest
would be served by our doing so and for how long?


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R2000</NUMEX>-1
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Dollars</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX>)
Total Contribution to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Costs</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,453</NUMEX>
Package Other Service <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.15% 0.89% $1,820</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Percent Contribution</ENAMEX> to Percent Institutional Percent Volume
Revenue Cost

Total <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100.0% 100.0% 100.00%</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1/ Includes Priority Mail</ENAMEX>
I want you to take a moment to look at this pie chart. I think
it is important for everyone to understand the extent to which
First-Class mail is already carrying a disproportionate share of
the institutional cost or overhead burden of the postal system.
Now, forget about this rate case and put aside any notion that I am
suggesting others mailers should pay a larger share. Think instead
about the discussion---the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hand wringing---</ENAMEX> that has been taking
place since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of last year</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> unveiled an assessment prepared for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> concerning the extent to which
transaction mail---<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">First-Class</ENAMEX> mail---is likely to fall prey to
electronic bill presentment and payment. Should we load up on that
type of mail---give it heftier increases? Might not doing so just
accelerate the departure of this mail from the system? When that
mail leaves the system, who gets to eat that big slice of the
institutional cost pie that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class mail currently enjoys?
Now, remember <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes ago</TIMEX> when I talked about the
Commission and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> difference of opinion on the matter
of how costs vary with volume? In the USPS view of the world,
institutional costs are a larger share of total costs and fewer
costs can be expected to be shed, if and when, say, transaction
mail leaves the system. This means, potentially, an even bigger
slice of institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> for someone else---one of you, to
swallow. Not a pleasant prospect and not one easily avoided---not
even by any reform package or proposal that I've seen.
Well, I guess I have already crossed the line and gotten into
some specifics of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">R20001</NUMEX> case. And, I did not paint a horrific
picture of the future, just so you might think the present <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX>
recommendation ain't so bad, after all. However, before I lose the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forest---</ENAMEX>and a very important one it is---for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, I want to
step back a bit.
In my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost seven years</TIMEX> at the helm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX>, if I have
learned nothing else, I've learned that each case presents a new
challenge. In this case the challenge lay in evaluating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s request for additional funds over and above its expected
operating expenses.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last January</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> proposed an array of rate
increases designed to generate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $2.8 billion</NUMEX> in
revenue. What was unusual about this request was that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly $1.7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> of these dollars was for a contingency, a hedge against the
unknown---to cover unforeseen events. Another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quarter billion</NUMEX> plus
dollars of the total amount sought was earmarked to pay down
operating debt accrued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past years</TIMEX>.
The size of the contingency quickly became a cause celebre with
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to the rate case. They sponsored evidence challenging
the need for a cushion so substantially above and beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s own best estimate of future increases in the cost of
collecting, processing and delivering the mail.
And, as you probably know, in presenting estimates of its future
needs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> used financial and operational data from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX> as a benchmark. Unfortunately, by the time the
Service filed its request, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX> had already come and
gone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> requested and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> completed an
update of its original cost projections in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-July</TIMEX>.
To give you a flavor of the impact of this updating effort,
which allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to use more recent information than
was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s initial package, let's look at a few of the
changes:


•
Notwithstanding the comments of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governors</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> meeting about not being able to
recover increased fuel costs and the need for flexibility to permit
them to level a fuel surcharge, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> was able to factor into
the update the increased costs of fueling its delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fleet</ENAMEX>.


•
Despite the comments of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> concerning costs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NALC</ENAMEX> arbitration, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> was able to include
these additional labor costs in the update.


•
It also was able to take account of the dollars
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with actual cost-of-living adjustments, health insurance
and the like, which were higher than earlier projected
figures.


But the update was not one-sided, only adding new costs, some
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> also presented additional revenue
and costing-cutting initiatives, such as the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX>-a-year
"break through productivity plan" announced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmaster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past spring</TIMEX>. Unfortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> was
only willing to commit to saving slightly more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one half</NUMEX> the
highly publicized, promised amount.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> item that did not change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> update
was the contingency. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 billion</NUMEX> remained.
The many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> who had already argued that a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 billion</NUMEX>
contingency was unreasonable before the update, were absolutely
certain that amount was unjustified given the incorporation of new
cost data and shorter time frame for prognosticating.
The evidence presented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> on the contingency issue
was determinative. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and I, reduced the requested
amount by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700 million</NUMEX>, leaving a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> contingency. We
concluded that this amount more than met the reasonableness
standard of the law.
Now, you should know that I put these remarks together over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> board meeting that took place Monday
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday of this week</TIMEX>. So, I had no idea of what action the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governors</ENAMEX> might take. It would not surprise me, however, if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> returned the case because we cut the contingency, if for
no other reason than that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> views the contingency as its
private sandbox and doesn't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> playing there.
Nevertheless, I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governors</ENAMEX> should be quite happy with a
billion dollar contingency since, after all, at the board
meeting---at least some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governors</ENAMEX> apparently did not even
know there was a contingency provision. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> is said to
have remarked at the public meeting that he thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service needed some mechanism for recovering unforeseen
expenses!
You have already heard the doom and gloom projections about USPS
finances generally and about this Recommended Decision not
providing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> with sufficient revenue to breakeven
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the current fiscal year</TIMEX>. But think about this: if rate increases
are implemented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>---which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> has indicated is
likely---and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s best estimate from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this past July</TIMEX>
is on target, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> should be sitting on a sizable
cushion at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this fiscal year</TIMEX>. Put another way, based on
the evidence the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> put on the record during rebuttal
hearings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as this past August 30th</TIMEX>, in the absence of
the occurrence of unforeseen events costing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than</NUMEX>---the portion
of the full <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> contingency earned when new rates are
implemented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600 million</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> should do quite
well with what we recommend.
This is, I believe, a good point to do a comparison of the
evidentiary record the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> based its decision on and the
financial picture postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are now painting just three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNEXPLAINED CHANGE</ENAMEX> IN USPS FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FINANCIAL POSIT ION</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNEXPLAINED CHANGE</ENAMEX> IN USPS FY2001 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FINANCIAL POSITION</ENAMEX> ($
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net Income PRC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R2000-1 Rate Decision - 11/13/00</ENAMEX> 1,342
Impact of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delayed Rate Implementation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">658</ENAMEX>)
Adjusted FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> Net Income 684
Operating Plan - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/14/00</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">480</ENAMEX>) (Expected Net Loss)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unexplained Swing</ENAMEX> in Net Income: (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,164</NUMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/13/00</NUMEX> compared to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/14/00</NUMEX>)
I have a couple of tables I want to share with you. Each carries
the title "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unexplained Change in USPS FY 2001 Financial</ENAMEX>
Picture."
The first table is based on USPS assumptions regarding rates,
costs, volumes, contingency and recovery of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior years</TIMEX>'
losses.


•
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> filed its case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX>, we all were
told the net income for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FY2001</TIMEX>, after covering increased operating
costs, would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.9 billion</NUMEX>---<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 billion</NUMEX> for the contingency and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX> for recover of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior years</TIMEX> losses.


•
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> filed its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> update, which it could
have modified during rebuttal in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late August</TIMEX>, we were told the net
income for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FY2001</TIMEX> would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX>.


•
When you adjust those figures for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
implementation, you get a positive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$630 million</NUMEX> on the bottom
line.


•
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> operating plan presented to and approved by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-November</TIMEX> shows a deficit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $500 million</NUMEX>
even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> had rubber-stamped the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>
request.


•
When ones substitutes generally lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> rates and uses
all other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> assumptions, one still gets a positive, albeit much
smaller, bottom line---the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$132 million</NUMEX> figure.


•
Going from a plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$630 million</NUMEX> to a minus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$480 million</NUMEX> is
a swing of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 billion</NUMEX>.


The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> table shows the numbers using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> assumptions and
recommended rates.
So, regardless of whether one uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s updated
assumption or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s rates and assumptions, there has
been an unexplained swing of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 billion</NUMEX> in the projected bottom
line for FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a couple of months</TIMEX>!


•
Were the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July-August</TIMEX> updates that far off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>? We now
know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the FY2000</TIMEX> ink was not as red as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> thought
it would be---the loss is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$199 million</NUMEX> as opposed to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$325</NUMEX>
million they projected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>. But that's good!


•
Are the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> operating plan figures wrong?


•
Has that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> commitment for half the promised "break
though productivity" fallen through?


•
Has something else happened?


•
If so, what is the explanation?


I know that some of you are unhappy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s
recommendations as they relate to your mail. I don't mean to be
glib about your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, but if I were you, I might be more
concerned about the near-term rate implications of this <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1</NUMEX> bottom
line swing. For those of you who have only disdain for the current
ratemaking process---the length of time it takes and the cost of
litigation---please keep in mind that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX> process affords the
only opportunity you may have to truly scrutinize this swing before
you get the next <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 billion</NUMEX> plus kick in your billfold.
Now, about our recommended rates: Could we have made different
recommendations? Most certainly! Would they have been better
recommendations? Maybe!
But let's look at the score card on how the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> classes made
out:


•
By our count, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 87 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> mail will
have rates that are less than or equal to those proposed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>.


•
Almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Periodical</ENAMEX> mail rates will be lower than those
proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>.


•
The average increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parcel Post</ENAMEX>, save the not so
small matter of a non-machinable surcharge that impacts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3</NUMEX>
percent of total volume, is on target with the USPS
request.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priority Mail</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bound Printed Matter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Mail---</ENAMEX>gosh
I'm having a hard time keeping up with all these name
changes---took a bit of a hit, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> more, give or take, than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> requested, based primarily on cost updates.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonprofits</ENAMEX> benefited from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last minute</TIMEX> legislation and
will have smaller increases than would have otherwise been the
case.


However, we did not, as you know, lower the Standard pound rate
as much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> wanted and we did not raise the breakpoint.
To those who choose to be supercritical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> regarding
our recommendations in these areas, I hope you will consider that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ratemaking</ENAMEX> generally involves a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> sum situation where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> works
against a revenue target. Lowering pound rates or raising
breakpoints may benefit some mailers, but it will also have a
negative impact on others who find themselves dealing, for example,
with higher piece rates and the like.
I have a host of one-liners I've collected over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that I
thought about using at this point in response to some of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who think we missed a "no-brainer," but I won't do that.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> will suffice. It's the one that comes to mind when I think
about how smart I was before I actually had to deal first hand with
an omnibus rate case. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.L. Mencken</ENAMEX> line I've used before:
"For ever problem there is a solution that is simple, neat,
plausible and wrong!"
Let's see now, where am I?


•
Lay out guiding principles. Check!


•
Talk about rate recommendations. Check!


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> finances-the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 billion</NUMEX> swing. Check!


•
Saw barrel off <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> and fire at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>.
Check!


•
I'm forgetting something. Ah, those other matters of
passing interest.


I'll try not to take too long, but I get to do this because this
may be my last shot as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRC</ENAMEX>. And, you know what they
say---Today <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a peacock</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> a feather duster! So, here goes-
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> or legislative reform or whatever you want to call
it: I am NOT opposed to postal reform! I just believe, to quote his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 28, 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIDS</ENAMEX> article, that that great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baer</ENAMEX>, had it right when he said, "Before we develop solutions we
need to reach some consensus on the problem." We've all got our
campaign ribbons from the war of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HR22</TIMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to pick up
that very tattered battle flag, put on their brightest red coats,
form into straight lines and march <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenkin's Hill</ENAMEX>.
For those of you who may not know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenkin's Hill</ENAMEX> is the hill on
which sits the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX>. Price caps may sound more attractive
with every passing rate case. But, as I have tried to explain to
some of you, costs trumped caps in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HR22</TIMEX>; that is, you were still
likely to see increases akin to those you experience under current
law. I propose that, rather than charging up the same hill with the
same old, tired ammunition, let's all of us regroup---and
rethink.

Dilbert kind of sums it up for me when it comes to postal
reform.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
A better bet for legislation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 107th</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that may be as important to the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> as some
perceive postal reform to be, is in the privacy area dealing with
the collection and sharing of personal data. This is an area I know
a bit about from a previous incarnation as the point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on
information policy at the then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of HEW</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>.
Overly restrictive privacy legislation at the federal level or,
even worse, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> different restrictive state bills could spell
disaster for everyone up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> from graphics and copy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to printers to cataloguers to envelope manufactures to banks
and to shipping and logistics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. You've got a split
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">congress</ENAMEX> and an issue with bipartisan appeal. Convincing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> of the benefits of federal preemption and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> of
the benefits of limiting causes of action, both stumbling blocks in
the past, might be doable as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">107th</ENAMEX> searches for common ground. The
result could be a framework everyone can live with.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negotiated Service Agreements</ENAMEX>. Setting aside for the
moment the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons of notice versus pre-approval, for some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> now I have been preaching that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSOs</ENAMEX> are by and large nothing
more that narrowly drawn or niche classifications. We've already
approved several such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> proposals. I urge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> to move
forward with whatever proposals they have developed. If mailers, a
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of or even one of them, can perform some task that may
drive costs out of the system, let's get on with
it---now!


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
And last but not least, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Gleiman</ENAMEX> suggestion---I
try to include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> classification and/or cost savings
proposal in each speech. This one is buried in a


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concurring</ENAMEX> opinion to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R2000-1</ENAMEX> decision. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certified Mail</ENAMEX> is
costly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>. Along with Return
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Receipt</ENAMEX>, also not cheap, these oldfashioned offerings are frequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of criticism from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. Delivery Confirmation, on the
other hand, is a high tech, low cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> that works and works
well. By extending <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Delivery Confirmation to First-Class</ENAMEX> mail as a
replacement for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certified Mail</ENAMEX>, the potential exists to drive in
excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> per year in window <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> and letter carrier
costs from the system. I could be wrong about all this, and I don't
want to fall into my old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. L. Mencken</ENAMEX>'s simple solutions
trap, but that's a heap of money, and I think this one deserves
some prompt consideration by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at postal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HQ</ENAMEX>!
It's pretty clear that some of you are tired of hearing from me
and others, I gather from the snoring, are just plain tired. So, I
best wrap things up.
When I talked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Hoyt</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>, he said I was
obligated to wrap up with a story or joke. I told him I didn't have
any new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. He offered that hardly anyone ever listens to
what I say anyway, so you all would not even know that I was
recycling old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>. Let's see if he is right.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Nolan</ENAMEX> and I were talking about some of his
responsibilities. You know all those letters that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> write to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>. Well, seems <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Henderson</ENAMEX> used to handle the responses,
personally. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> has delegated that and now those letters all go to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>. Turns out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that just tore
at his heartstrings. A little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> wrote that since his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
death, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was having a hard time making ends meet. The
little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> asked nothing for himself, only that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> send his
mother <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>. Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMG</ENAMEX>, being the kind soul that he is, reach
in his pocket, pulled out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those nice, crisp, new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> dollar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> and mailed it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> again
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, and the letter wound up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John's</ENAMEX> in box. He shared a
copy and I would like to share it with you.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Santa</ENAMEX>, Thanks so much for all you did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Christmas</TIMEX>.
Things are still pretty rough for us, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> sure could use
another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>. And, if you don't mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>, when you send it to my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mom</ENAMEX>, please don't route it through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. The last time they
deducted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>.
Actually, that is an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edward Day</ENAMEX> joke, or so I've been
told, not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward J. Gleiman</ENAMEX> joke. I thought it fit both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and the postal rate case postmortem.





