



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTRODUCTION</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, considerable attention has focused on
increasing competition in the provision of postal services. The
reasoning is that competitive pressure brings about productive
efficiency, efficient price structures, product innovation, and the
elimination of economic rents. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>, however, are
often under constraints that limit their ability to respond to such
pressure.
Consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX>. It is constrained by
laws and regulations formulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than two</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>. This political process focused as much on social
considerations as on the kinds of market forces that shape
competitive outcomes. And once made, provisions have tended to
remain. These observations apply, though in somewhat altered form,
even since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Presented</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Economics</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Research</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulated Industries</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 710, 2000 2</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> is
Special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>, an independent
expressed herein are his own and do not necessarily represent those
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> or any of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Correspondence may be sent
to rmit@iname.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Postal Reorganization Act of 1970</ENAMEX>. Specifically, that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> turned
rate making over to an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>, but it
also specified a range of factors to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> must give
weight and it required that certain classification structures of
the past be honored<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>
This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> focuses on changes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX>
would make if it had the freedom to position itself to withstand
competition in all of its markets. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crew 1995</ENAMEX>) After such
adjustment, it might become a sustainable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX>. If this
occurred, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s configuration would be that of a successful
competitor and, at the same time, any benefits from having one
provider would be retained. These benefits include economies of
scale and joint production. No changes of any kind are advocated.
Note that the extent of any changes that would be made is a measure
of the extent of non-market choices that have been allowed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX> currently provided.
Creating a competitive environment would involve, at a minimum,
eliminating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Express</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Statutes4</ENAMEX> and the mailbox rule<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>
Absent these, some portions of the mail stream would attract
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> As discussed below, it required continuation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> preferred
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subclasses</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> These statutes are laws that comprise the letter mail
monopoly. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> The mailbox rule specifies that no one other than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> (and the addressee) may put mail into the box. This
rule is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United States Criminal Code</ENAMEX>. No other country
has such a rule. Note that eliminating the rule is not a simple
change and has a downside. In particular: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
itself owns and maintains many of the boxes-specifically those
known as "cluster" boxes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of boxes, particularly
those in apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> and those secured by locks, do not
want to open them to all parties. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The ability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inspection Service</ENAMEX>, or similar replacement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, to control mail
fraud would be
the attention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would suffer
financial losses. This could lead to a spiral of rate increases and
further volume losses.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would be better off if it lowered selected
rates and took back some of the lost volume. If it did this, some
of its new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> would be driven out of business, causing
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> losses and charges that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should not be
competing with private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>. Such a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX> is not
desirable. A much better approach would be to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service to make adjustments <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.
Accordingly, the setting of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is that all protection
will be removed and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is given wide latitude
to make its products and services as uncontestable as possible. And
if it were found to be a sustainable monopoly, one could ask
whether that situation would be better than the one that exists
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> reasons why it might. First,
competitive configurations give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior</ENAMEX>, cost-based signals to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> so that the value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> received is greater.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would have to face real competitive
threats at all times. In fact, some business at the margins would
probably be lost. Therefore, the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> would sense on
a regular basis that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> stand ready to take its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>,
and it would see some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> leaving. Such pressure might not
satisfy those who envision a market with a number of active
reduced if general access to the boxes were allowed. And, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> favor the rule because it reduces
the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, but having a number of active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> is not
always a viable option.
The next section discusses general guidelines for the paper. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> section identifies changes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would make
immediately. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> looks at how the range of postal products
might change. It points to general directions and is not precise.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> section discusses worksharing and contracting, while the
sixth deals with the general issue of cost recognition in rate
design. It focuses to a considerable extent on weaknesses in the
current state of knowledge. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> sections discuss
costs by destination and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. Then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two</TIMEX> discuss
inverse price caps and the benefits of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> government
provider. A conclusion follows.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GENERAL GUIDE LINES First</ENAMEX>, it is necessary to discuss the
framework within which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s adjustment process will
be considered.
As noted above, relaxing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Express Statutes</ENAMEX> is the
essential <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step. Hiding under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statutes</ENAMEX>, however, is a rule
mandating that all bills, statements of account, and personal or
handwritten correspondence, if mailed, must be mailed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBMFC</ENAMEX> rule). To a much greater degree than is commonly
recognized, this rule is critically important to the functioning of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> as it now exists. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBMFC</ENAMEX> rule requires a
substantial portion of the mail volume to be sent at high
First-Class rates, instead of at the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard-A</ENAMEX> rates, even
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senders</ENAMEX> may not value the high service levels or the
special features of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX> If the rule were eliminated, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would lose a large portion of its revenue,
immediately, with little or no reduction in cost, and rate
adjustments would have to be made.
As an economic matter, it is possible that much of the MBMFC
mail is high-demand mail, and thus that the rule segments the
market according to demand. In order to continue benefiting from
this split, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> might try to maintain it, even
without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statutes</ENAMEX>. But since rates based on content are seldom
the outcome of competitive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, such an effort would in all
likelihood fail. What is important to understand is that the MBMFC
rule is fundamental to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Class</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A as we know them,
and eliminating it would unleash forces that would lead to a major
restructuring, not to a minor adjustment.
In addition, it seems likely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would be
prohibited from selling <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">below</NUMEX> incremental cost, would be required
to preserve some form of universal service<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,7</NUMEX> and would be permitted
to adjust its service levels. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would be
allowed to grant volume discounts and to negotiate contract
rates.
Another question concerns the most effective way to install a
profit motive. In general, the outcome of effective competition
is
overcome by licensing access to the mail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> In addition to
its high service levels, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class offers free forwarding and is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sealed</ENAMEX> (legally protected) against inspection. Standard A is
deferrable, without these features, and has a lower rate.
expected to be a normal profit level, with the understanding
that unusually efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> might achieve supra-normal profits
for a time. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility would be to allow a portion of any
profit to be used for performance bonuses to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, but there
would be reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> if high and persistent profits
resulted. Also, there would be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> if monopoly power allowed
certain products to have excessive prices. In order to attenuate
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, it might be reasonable to place price caps on any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de</ENAMEX> facto monopoly mail categories, particularly any used by small
mailers with no alternatives<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>
Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this</TIMEX> set of rules, particularly if profits are allowed,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would behave much like a profit-maximizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.
Considerable attention would be paid to demand and to prices that
could be charged successfully. In addition, one would expect a
renewed interest in costs for narrow product categories, even for
specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.9
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Express Statutes</ENAMEX> were repealed, it is possible
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would also change the framework for labor
negotiations, especially the no-strike rule and the requirement for
binding arbitration when no agreement is reached through
collective
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> The restriction would be that it must provide some reasonable
level of service on seemingly reasonable terms to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> might well be required to administer any price caps,
incremental-cost floors, or other restrictions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> Note that the
effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> adjustments could be substantial and
widespread, not only on mailers who have invested heavily around
the present <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of products and rates, but also on such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. Some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> would strongly
resist any changes.
bargaining. It might also lift the pay caps on management
salaries. Even without such changes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> could
pursue regional wage differentials. For purposes of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>,
however, it is not necessary to specify a new labor environment.
What is important is that labor negotiations take place within the
framework of a situation where the loss of business to competitors
is an everyday reality. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> makes all feasible
changes and the markets are found not to be contestable, it will be
because the economies of scale and joint production, and the
advantages of being an incumbent<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,10</NUMEX> are larger than any
disadvantages associated with the levels of productivity or
wages.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. IMMEDIATE CHANGES
With the freedoms and goals described above, there are a number
of changes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would make immediately. First,
it would eliminate the "preferred" categories of mail, all of which
have rates that are below corresponding commercial rates. This
means there would be no separate in-county rates, no separate rates
for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> material, no separate rates for nonprofit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> (which exist both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Periodicals</ENAMEX> and in Standard A),
no separate rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> mail<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,11</NUMEX> and no separate rates for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>-of-
10 Other advantages the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> could retain relate to
such things as the payment of taxes, the need for a return on
investment, the right of eminent domain, and immunity from parking
tickets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would have to decide on such issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">11 Free</ENAMEX> for
the blind mail would continue to be available only if the
Government continued to provide a subsidy to support it. Also, the
Government might continue special arrangements relating to voter
registration. As long as there is an appropriation, these programs
do not put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> at a competitive disadvantage.
agriculture mail. Under the rate levels of the most recently
completed rate case, eliminating the preferred categories would
yield about onethird of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion dollars</NUMEX> in additional
revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, several special rate arrangements would be discontinued.
Specifically, reduced rates for books would be eliminated, and even
if there were a separate subclass for them, it would not have rates
that are invariant with distance<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Periodicals</ENAMEX> would not
receive reduced rates, and any rates that resulted would not depend
on the proportion of advertising content<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX> These changes would
increase revenue by another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine-tenths</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion dollars</NUMEX>. These
amounts14 are not large, but competition generally prevents
charging higher rates to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> in order to fund reduced
rates for others.
The above changes would allow substantial reductions in the
complexity of rates and in the complexity of the data systems,
which in turn would allow improvements in the costs and volumes for
the subclasses that remained.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> change that would be made immediately concerns the
provisions for parcel mail in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presently</ENAMEX>, as a matter of
policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senders</ENAMEX> of parcels to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> in the Alaska <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> (which
is not accessible by surface transportation) pay surface rates for
mail that is transported by air in low volumes. This would not be
done in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> The law currently specifies that the rates for books will not
vary with distance. This makes the book subclass very inefficient
at serving those for whom it was established. 13 Under the existing
rate arrangement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> can consider externalities in
setting rates. This would not occur in a competitive system.
competitive system. To places where surface transportation is
not available, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senders</ENAMEX> would be required to pay air rates, and
possibly air rates keyed to the characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> air
system. According to rate case figures, this would provide
additional revenues of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $70 million</NUMEX>, but one would expect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> adjustments that went beyond this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, there would be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> closings. It is not easy to
predict which post <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> would be closed. Using conservative
guidelines, an analysis done in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> concluded that about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> should be closed<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX> Services for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> using these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> would be provided in a less expensive way, using contract
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX> in some cases. Since a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> have been closed
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 20 years</TIMEX>, this estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> may not be current.
But if <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> per year were saved for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, another
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion dollars</NUMEX> would become available.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fifth</NUMEX>, there might be changes in the role the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
plays in policing the fraudulent use of the mails. In a competitive
environment, it might not be left with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> powers and the right
to select those activities in the crime area that would give it a
competitive advantage. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> alternative would be to turn this
function over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>.
Finally, there are some operational changes that would probably
be made. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would undoubtedly begin
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> These amounts were calculated conservatively and would vary
by rate case.
handling unaddressed mail on city routes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,16</NUMEX> even as it does
already on rural routes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17 2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> might stop (or
substantially alter) its detached address label program for
advertising mail. For mailers, the use of detached labels would be
a poor alternative to using unaddressed mail; for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service, the use of detached labels is not well aligned with
current and future automation plans, and it may aggravate the
alignment of rates and costs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would probably
make changes in the way postage is sold. Currently it adheres to a
policy that postage will be sold at face value, regardless of the
costs associated with its sale. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step might be discounts for
the use of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> and permit indicia, which cost much less than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stamps</ENAMEX>, but other changes would follow. (Haldi <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>)


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. BASIC PRODUCTS OFFERED
Except for the creation of worksharing discounts and Express
Mail, the basic product line of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> was inherited
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> at the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> reorganization in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1970.18</NUMEX> It is
not
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 At the end of FY</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27,952</NUMEX> post <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. Each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">postmaster</ENAMEX>. This count does not include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branches</ENAMEX>, or contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmaster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Unaddressed</ENAMEX> mail would go to all stops on a
carrier's route. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presently</ENAMEX>, addresses are required on such pieces.
This is essentially a make-work scheme: the mailers do the extra
work of putting the address on each piece and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
does the extra work of arranging these pieces in delivery order.
Note that the postal services in many other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> carry
unaddressed mail. 17 An alternative to unaddressed mail would be to
auction off the right to be a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> bundle on specific days in
specific post <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. A related change would be to set box rents
at what the traffic will bear. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Express Mail</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subclass</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECOM</ENAMEX> were created since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> changed the qualifications
for In-county rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. The following subclasses have been
eliminated: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECOM</ENAMEX>, transient, controlled circulation, special
delivery, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">single-piece third</NUMEX>. Limited circulation was
eliminated, but it was not a subclass.
known what products would evolve under competition. To stimulate
discussion, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perspectives</ENAMEX> are offered below.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.1</NUMEX>. Speed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> important characteristics of mail are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) it does not cost
more to process some batches of mail before others, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the
volume of mail fluctuates. To accommodate these fluctuations and
use resources evenly, it would seem reasonable to offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tiers
of service: rapid and deferred, with air transportation being used
for the rapid product. Other distinctions are possible, such as
bulk and nonbulk, but the speed distinction would seem to
dominate.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic subclasses for letters and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flats</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Class</ENAMEX> (originally rapid, non-bulk, and sealed against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard A</ENAMEX> (originally deferrable, bulk, and not
sealed against inspection). Over time these distinctions have
deteriorated. First, due in part to worksharing programs, there are
now bulk categories in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Class</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, a substantial portion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard A</ENAMEX> is entered into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> near its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">destination</ENAMEX>, in which case the opportunity to defer is limited.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, mailers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> are demanding on-time delivery of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard A</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is accommodating these
interests. One could argue that many mailers are getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">First-Class</ENAMEX> service at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard-A</ENAMEX> rates. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, many mailers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Class</ENAMEX> are not concerned about inspection. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fifth</NUMEX>, the rate
structures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Class</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A are dissimilar in rather
extreme ways, detracting attention from any focus on service.
Nonetheless, the rationality of service tiers remains. If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBMFC</ENAMEX> rule was removed and all mailers could choose between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Class</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard A</ENAMEX>, and if the fundamental distinction
between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> was service, one would expect a moderate rate
difference based on a real service difference. Also, one would
expect increased similarity in their rate structures. But the
assumption that change would center around these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subclass</ENAMEX> may
not be a good one. More pervasive changes would seem likely, but it
is not clear what they would be.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX>. Tolerance for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irregular</ENAMEX>
Throughout its history, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> has backed away from
constraints on the dimensions and characteristics of pieces that
can be mailed. The view has been that its mission is to serve and
that whatever is mailed will be delivered. In many cases, and often
for the same rate, a piece can be handwritten or typed, awkward or
standard in shape, flimsy or stiff<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX> This posture has resulted in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> being told to design equipment and mail handling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> that will handle a frightening range of mail
characteristics. This has presented design difficulties and has
resulted in costly equipment. It has also led to operating
difficulties and to high processing costs.
Evidence of tolerance follows: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It was not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> that a
non-standard surcharge was put on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>, and even now it
applies only to the first ounce. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Except for some recent
automation categories, there is no rate distinction in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class
among letters, flats, and parcels. Therefore, a letter weighing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> ounce
19 In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> processed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 billion</NUMEX>
handwritten addresses. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Postmaster General</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. The report says: "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> or our new technology read your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handwriting</ENAMEX>, no matter how 'creative' it might be." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 54</ENAMEX>.
pays the same rate as a flat or a parcel of the same weight. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
There is no rate distinction in Priority between flats and parcels,
even though there could be differences in the equipment used to
process them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Except for the barcode discount, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Periodicals</ENAMEX> rates
are not based on shape or machinability. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, for
example, are too heavy to be processed on flat sorting machines and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> would be expected to have costs different from those of
magazines. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Handwritten addresses and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zip Codes</ENAMEX>
are accepted without surcharge. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) During high-speed, mechanized
processing, some flats with open edges become aerodynamic. Yet,
despite a large cost difference, there is no rate distinction
between these flats and those that can be processed effectively. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nonautomated First-Class</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>-A mailers have the option of
requesting that their mail be processed manually, even though the
costs for such processing are substantially higher than mechanized
processing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20</NUMEX> It is doubtful that any of these tolerances would
exist in a competitive system.
Conceptually, one can visualize a streamlined, low-cost
processing system for well-defined letter-size pieces that are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">machinereadable</ENAMEX>. Similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> could exist for flats and for
parcels. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> might allow lower rates for qualifying mail,
while pieces that would not qualify might be rejected or required
to pay a surcharge based on costs. Prices that recognize costs send
signals to mailers concerning the work that needs to be done. They
prevent high-cost mailers from being cross subsidized by low-cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mailers</ENAMEX>, and they
20 See response to interrogatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OCA/USPS-84</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Docket</ENAMEX> No.
R2000-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 13
allow the efficiencies of a low-cost mailstream to be available
to all who can use them.
One can surmise that a competitive postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> would do a
better job of presenting technologically feasible, low-cost product
options to mailers and either rejecting non-conforming pieces or
levying surcharges. Certainly a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> would go after such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lowcost</ENAMEX> pieces <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, as has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roadway Package Service</ENAMEX> in the parcel
area.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX>. Demand
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the hallmarks of competitive pricing is that higher
prices are charged to higher-demand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. This practice
becomes even more pronounced outside of a breakeven requirement,
when additions to net revenue can be kept.
Under current conventions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> sets prices for
whole subclasses and cannot select specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surcharges</ENAMEX> or discounts. And for these subclasses, there are no
cases where a lower price will lead to an increase in net revenue.
However, if there are categories of mail that are attractive to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, these categories should be viewed as extremely elastic
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would be expected to move its rates toward a
lower markup over costs. In other words, competition would force a
response from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service.21 Similarly</ENAMEX>, higher rates would
be expected for less elastic categories.
21 An extreme, but possibly realistic, situation should not be
overlooked. Suppose a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> needed a critical mass
in order to begin operations. If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mailer</ENAMEX> were large enough to
provide that mass, or nearly provide it, that mailer, by
threatening to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>, might be able to negotiate
extremely low rates.
Dealing with this kind of situation is different from anything
being done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Basically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would be expected
to assess competition and mailers' willingness to pay, and then to
segment its markets as much as possible. Indeed, one would expect a
degree of creativity from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> in finding ways to
acknowledge demand.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.4</NUMEX>. Content
The subclasses of mail that exist <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are based in
considerable degree on content. In short, there is a subclass for
library materials, one for books, one for bound printed matter, and
several for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX>. Further, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals subclasses</ENAMEX> have
strict rules on enclosures, have regulations that depend on whether
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> is bound or unbound, and most have rates that
depend on whether the material inside is advertising or
editorial<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.22</NUMEX> Also, there are cases where merchandise is treated
different from non-merchandise and where, under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBMFC</ENAMEX> rule
discussed above, some kinds of content may use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> subclass and not
others.
In cases where the willingness to pay of the sender is related
to content, it might be possible to argue that content would
continue to be recognized in rates. However, it is quite uncommon
for competitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to differentiate based on content.
Instead, one would expect the emphasis on content to either
decrease significantly or disappear. If content did continue as a
rate-setting factor, it would probably take a different form from
what now exists.
22 In postal parlance, editorial is defined as material that is
not advertising. 15


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX>. Service Measurement
Under the assumption that the level of service is important,
knowledge about the level achieved is important. This has been a
difficult issue for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> an external
measurement system for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> has been developed and one
now exists for Priority, but actual service levels for most other
subclasses have been a great unknown. To fill this void, many
mailers measure the service their own mail receives. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service usually responds to these measurements by saying that they
are not statistically valid or that they are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>.
Nevertheless, it is well known that actual service levels are often
quite far from the published standards.
In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> poised to meet competition, considerably
more effort would be directed toward meeting published standards
and toward measuring the service achieved. Mailers would demand
such performance and such knowledge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Competitors</ENAMEX> would jump at the
chance to meet unmet mailer needs. A step beyond this issue is the
question of tracking and tracing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is behind its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> at this point; under competition, catch-up would be
expected to occur at a faster pace.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. WORKSHARING AND CONTRACTING
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to compete is to bring the strengths of the private
sector in-house. This can be done through worksharing discounts or
contracts and is especially effective when mailers can do the work
in a different way than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell 1999)</ENAMEX> The
amount of work that can be turned over in this way is quite
large.
16
Consider the following example. Suppose mailers can sort
addresses on a computer and then print them in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP Code</ENAMEX> order.
Suppose further that they can do this for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.5 cents</NUMEX> per piece and
that this saves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 cents</NUMEX> per piece. In the areas
where worksharing discounts are offered now, the tendency has been
to move toward a discount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 cents</NUMEX>. This lowers the net mailing
cost for the mailers involved and makes them less likely to go to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. However, if the mailers were not on the verge of
stopping the worksharing activity or of going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would maximize its financial position by giving a
discount closer to the figure of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.5 cents</NUMEX>. So, with freedom to
compete, there could be important changes in the way worksharing
discounts are set. Of course, prior to such changes, information
and analysis would be needed.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> has extensive worksharing discounts. There
are, however, some limitations. First, no discounts are based on
any cost savings associated with the avoidance of collection
activities. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, discounts for transportation have been limited
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard A</ENAMEX>, Priority <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 5 pounds</NUMEX>, and parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard B.</ENAMEX>
There are no dropship discounts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express Mail</ENAMEX>, none in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Class, limited ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Periodicals</ENAMEX>, and none in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Standard</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library Rate</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, even the dropship discounts in Standard
A are limited. For example, mail traveling <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 miles</NUMEX> to get to a
destination <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> gets the same dropship discount as similar
mail traveling <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 miles</NUMEX>. Similarly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> truckloads of mail weighing
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 ounces</NUMEX> per piece get the same dropship discount as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> truckload of
mail weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce</NUMEX> per piece. Clearly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> could
do more to transfer some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> to the private sector
through worksharing discounts.
Another way to shift work to the private sector is through
contracts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>. This also has been done. For example,
contractors who submit the lowest bids do nearly all of the
long-haul trucking. Similarly, air transportation is provided under
contract, and a sorting hub for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express Mail</ENAMEX> is operated under
contract. A number of contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> also exist for retail
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. There may, however, be limits to how much contracting can
be done effectively, partly because of the time and cost associated
with utilizing, placing, and monitoring contracts.
Consider the contract the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> now has with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emery</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX> to process and transport Priority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX>. The idea was for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">low bidder</ENAMEX> to operate a highly focused sorting and
transportation system designed to get Priority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> delivered on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. Suppose, however, with suitable reverence to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX>, one
looks at this plan according to its degree of roundaboutness. Here
is what happens: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> collects the pieces and
brings them to a central point. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> goes through
a sorting process to separate those pieces that go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emery</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emery</ENAMEX> picks up the pieces at the cutoff time and transports them to
its own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are unloaded and fed into sorting
machines. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) After sorting, the pieces are transported to an air
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> and then sent by air to a destination, possibly using
lower-capacity equipment than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> might use. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) The
pieces are loaded on a truck and transported to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> integrates the pieces back into its
own system and takes them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> out of which the carriers
operate. This sounds like a lot of steps. Taking a degree of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s license, the alternative is to leave them in the postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, sort them <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, transport them immediately, and deliver
them.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is still out on the effectiveness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emery</ENAMEX>
contract. There are indications, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emery</ENAMEX> is losing
money, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> is spending more than if it had done
the work itself, and that there has not been a significant
improvement in delivery performance. It appears that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">roundaboutness</ENAMEX> and the associated extra steps may be taking a toll.
Whether this is an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> to lower costs and improve
performance remains to be seen.
Note that the possibility of contracting out is not limited to
operations prior to delivery. If there are economies of scale in
delivery, and certainly if mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> do not want multiple
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> accessing their mail boxes, it would be possible to define
routes, along with their expected workload, and auction them off to
the lowest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>. This is already done on a few "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> routes" at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-half</NUMEX> the cost of rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>, and it is reportedly
being done by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Services</ENAMEX> in the parcel
area. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Reilly</ENAMEX>)


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COST RECOGNITION IN RATE DESIGN</ENAMEX>
Rates for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> are set following extensive
hearings before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>. Voluminous testimony is
provided, as are the results of numerous cost studies. In fact, the
volume of cost data amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of pages. Based on
the data and the testimony submitted, as well as on evidence
19
submitted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of intervenors, rates are set in a very
detailed way. It is not uncommon for extensive testimony to focus
on discount differences of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two tenths</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a cent</NUMEX> per
piece.
Despite all of this attention, there are weaknesses in what is
know about costs. For example: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little</ENAMEX> is known about the
relative costs of flats and parcels in Priority and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express Mail</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Not enough is known about the effects of weight on costs in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Class</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard A</ENAMEX>, despite extensive related <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">testimony23</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Knowledge is limited on the relation between weight and
non-transportation costs in nearly all subclasses. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Not enough is
known about how nontransportation costs vary with distance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)
Based on studies that have been questioned extensively, the rates
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard-A</ENAMEX> mail do not vary with weight up to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 3.3 ounces</NUMEX>.
This means, for example, that for a large mailing going <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>, the same postage would be charged for ¾<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-ounce</NUMEX> pieces
requiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor trailer</ENAMEX> as would be charged for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3-ounce</NUMEX>
pieces requiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor trailers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) The extent of lower
costs for higher-volume mailers is unknown.
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> faced competition in all areas, some of
these weaknesses might be associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> that could be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skimmed</ENAMEX>. A response by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would be expected.
Improved cost studies would result. This is not meant to suggest
that costs have not been studied extensively. A great deal of money
is being spent on cost studies, but when the budget for these
studies is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">23 Competitors</ENAMEX> understand clearly that <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15-ounce</NUMEX> pieces of
saturation mail can be carried privately for less than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>-A
rates, while <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-ounce</NUMEX> pieces cannot.
compared to a revenue that is near <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$67 billion</NUMEX>, the percentage
amount is probably minimal.
When it is suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> should spend more
on cost studies, questions arise about private sector expenditures
in this area. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> possibilities. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> spend more. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>, most other productive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> are easier
to study and understand, since few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> locations and
a large proportion of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> working outdoors. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX>,
operating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> in the private sector, based on their extensive
experience, are allowed to prepare mental estimates of what costs
probably are. However it would work out, it seems clear that
competition would improve the alignment of rates and costs.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. COSTS BY DESTINATION
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> a number of studies have analyzed the widely
held belief that rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> are more expensive than city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX>.
The findings confirm the expectation to some extent, but the split
is not clean. It turns out that the income of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> is
also important, with many low-income, low-volume city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">routes</ENAMEX> being
unprofitable. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen 1993)</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason for being concerned about
this issue is the possibility that, were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Express</ENAMEX>
Statutes to be relaxed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> would take the profitable
routes and leave the incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> with the unprofitable
routes.
In the same vein, mail for the highest-volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> is not
even delivered � the mailers pick it up. In fact, many of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> have unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ZIP Codes</ENAMEX> and their own sorting bin on the
sorting machines. The question then becomes: would a
competitive
21
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">postal</ENAMEX> service establish rate tiers based on the destination of
the mail? We know, for example, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roadway Package Service</ENAMEX>, at
least initially, did not solicit mail for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>
charges extra for addresses designated as residential. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>
selects certain <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zip Codes</ENAMEX> for an additional surcharge. At least for
bulk mailers, and in a computerized world, such rate differences
are easy to manage.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> could, for example, place a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> numeral in
front of each <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP Code</ENAMEX>, yielding a code like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I-20878-2619</ENAMEX>. The
numeral "I" could indicate a low-cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> who picks up mail
in bulk. The numeral "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">II</ENAMEX>" could indicate locations of average
income and stop density that are relatively economical to deliver.
The numeral "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>" could be for high-cost areas.
Rates based on numerals could result, even though there would be
transaction costs. Such a system, however, might not be the most
desirable, one downside being that the smallest single-piece
mailers could default to a rate that is high enough to cover all
destinations. Also, to the extent that mailers send broadly to all
destinations, a system of this kind would not change postage bills,
it would just increase some rates and decrease others.
Before leaving the question of higher-cost delivery areas, it
should be noted that a mitigating option might be to reduce the
number of deliveries per week. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen 1999)</ENAMEX> Although many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>
would view this as an extreme step it could reduce costs and allow
increased efficiencies. For example, mail could be sorted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
and delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next</TIMEX>, resulting in a less demanding schedule.
Also, the effect on the recipient might not be as large as commonly
assumed-in effect, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-half</NUMEX> of the mail would be delayed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
day.
A related service issue is whether there are unreasonable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX> runs that should be eliminated. That is, a review
could be done to see how many transportation runs are scheduled
solely to meet a deadline or a service standard, but which involve
very little mail. These runs could cost far more than the value of
the small improvement in service.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. COSTS BY CUSTOMER
Although the details are kept private, it is well known that
many private-sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> set rates via contracts with selected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Sometimes these are based on agreements that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> will prepare the mail in certain ways; at other times they
are based on a threat that the mailer will find another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>. As
an economic matter, it is clear that a postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> is better off
having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> at a near-cost price than not having the customer
at all.
Were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> to be allowed to set rates under
contracts, or to bid for business, it would need costs by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>.
At the present time, costs by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> are not available and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s costing systems are not set up to develop such costs. In
short, this is a whole new costing area that would need to be
undertaken<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.24</NUMEX>
If contract rates with selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> were allowed, several
questions would need to be addressed. First, would the terms of
each agreement be made public? The answer is probably yes. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
would all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> satisfying the requirements of the contract be
allowed to use the same rates? The answer here is probably yes as
well, even though private-sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> would say no on both points.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, how rigorous and defensible would customer-specific costs
have to be in order to qualify as an acceptable base for a
contract, and would the costing receive review by any outside
party? One is tempted to argue that there should be a defensible
study, but the problem is obvious- some private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> undoubtedly
base contracts on the judgment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> involved.
Furthermore, the result can be based on negotiating skills.
The prospect of allowing contract prices in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> postal
service, based on judgment and negotiating skills, raises another
question. Specifically, private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>. If
discounts are too large, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> pay, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>
who may lose their jobs. Whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> can
engage in these kinds of negotiations deserves serious study.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INVERSE PRICE CAPS</ENAMEX>
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> should have a greater degree of pricing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX> and be able to engage in negotiations with selected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mailers</ENAMEX>, one way to provide such freedom, even without further
changes, would be to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> to operate under
inverse price caps.
Within the existing rate-setting framework, the idea of an
inverse price cap is to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to recommend an
average price level (or index) that is viewed as a floor. Then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> could make wide-ranging adjustments of the rates in
the subclass, including contract rates for some of the subclass
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, as long as the average rate for the subclass does not go
below the inverse cap. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> believed that a low markup
for the subclasses was in order, then the low markup could be
recommended. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> review would be provided and all affected parties
would have an opportunity to be heard. This is an alternative to
some recent legislative suggestions that the markup on the
competitive subclasses as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> must be at least as large as the
markup on all other subclasses.
The inverse price cap is a relatively simple notion that would
require no more than a minor adjustment to the law, if one is
needed at all. It deserves further study. Within the framework of
this paper, it could play a role as well. Specifically, suppose
unconstrained competition were allowed but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
turned out to have sufficient market power in some product areas to
allow other products to be priced at or near the level of
incremental cost. If this was viewed as unfair competition, an
independent regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> could establish and monitor
certain inverse price caps. This would provide substantial freedom
to compete, but within a constrained framework.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAVING A GOVERNMENT PROVIDER</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the questions of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
could become a sustainable monopoly if all protection were removed.
There are both disadvantages and advantages to having a single
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> under these conditions. Among the disadvantages
are that the degree of innovation and product differentiation might
continue to be limited. On the advantages side, several
considerations are relevant. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> has established the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zones</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZIP Codes</ENAMEX> that are now used by all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. It also
manages a forwarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> and a change-of-address system,25 both
of which honor policies on privacy. In addition, it carries mail
that is sealed against inspection and acts as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchdog</ENAMEX> over
fraudulent use of the mails.
If desired, having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> would allow the maintenance of
the mailbox rule (with, as discussed above, a reduction in
competitive pressure), which in turn would be helpful in protecting
the mail. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> could leave originating mail in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boxes</ENAMEX> and know who would pick it up and that it would be handled
appropriately. Having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> would also reduce vehicle traffic
in neighborhoods and allow familiarity with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>. Such a
carrier can deal better with irregularities and can watch over the
delivery area.
25 If competition was allowed and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> arose, it might be
that a change-of-address system could be operated by a separate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entity</ENAMEX> and made available to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. This is reportedly
being done in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>.


<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. CONCLUSION
It is a common belief that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Express Statutes</ENAMEX> and the
mailbox rule serve as protection to allow universal service at
uniform rates. When viewed in terms of changes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
would likely make if it wished to make itself into a sustainable
monopoly, it becomes clear that these restrictions protect much
more than just universal service. They also protect the preferred
subclasses of mail, low rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Periodicals</ENAMEX>, classifications that
are not market based, rates that do not follow costs, and a range
of other practices discussed in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>. If these are not
inherently desirable, or if a decision were made to give them less
weight, changes could be made to eliminate them now, even without
relaxing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statutes</ENAMEX>. If some of them are desirable but not
others, limited changes could be made, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> possibility being
inverse price caps.
There are, however, benefits to having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> postal
service, in addition to the uniform rates and special rate
structures. Specifically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> establishes the zones
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZIP Codes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> privacy, forwards mail, and protects
against crime. Also, having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> postal system reduces traffic and
pollution. Further, if the mailbox rule were maintained, only one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will pick up an outgoing letter placed in the mailbox.
Further analysis is needed of the benefits of the current system
relative to the benefits of an alternative system, and of whether
some of the benefits of an alternative system can be obtained by
making adjustments to the current system.


References
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. and Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, "Pricing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Services</ENAMEX> Under <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Competitive Entry" in Commercialization of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Services</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National and International</ENAMEX>
Perspectives, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William W. Ferguson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Waller</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spyros S. Xenakis</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Does the USPS Need a Monopoly to Carry</ENAMEX>
Out its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Universal Service Obligation?</ENAMEX>" presented at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Seventh</ENAMEX>
Conference on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Economics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sintra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23-26</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William W. Ferguson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spyros S. Xenakis</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rural Delivery and the Universal Service Obligation: A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantitative Investigation</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">in Regulation and the Nature of Postal</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delivery Services</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R.</ENAMEX>
Kleindorfer, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic Publishers</ENAMEX>.
Haldi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John T. Schmidt</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Transaction Costs of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alternative Postage Payment</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evidencing Systems</ENAMEX>" in Emerging
Competition in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Services</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert W. 1999</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Worksharing</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX>,
Technical Efficiency, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pareto Optimality</ENAMEX>," in Emerging
Competition In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal and Delivery Services</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R. Kleindorfer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kluwer Academic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Reilly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>, "They've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 7, 2000</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 101</ENAMEX>.



