



<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRENDS IN FIRST-CLASS MAIL VOLUMES WITH EMPHASIS ON</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BILL/PAYMENT AND ADVERTISING</ENAMEX> MAIL1
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spyros S. Xenakis</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of Rates, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> was presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1998</TIMEX> and
was revised in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1999</TIMEX> to include the data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household</ENAMEX>
Diary Study conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIGHLIGHTS</ENAMEX> AT A GLANCE




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household and Business Mail</ENAMEX>


•
The share of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> is
increasing while the share sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> is
decreasing.


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX> system is increasingly becoming a medium for
business transactions rather than personal exchange.




<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payment Mail</ENAMEX>


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Household bill/</ENAMEX>payment mail has started losing volume;
but the number of pieces lost, so far, is too small to have any
material impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> volume.


•
Payments are declining faster than bills; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are
now making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than one</NUMEX> payment by mail for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bills
received in the mail.


•
The loss of household bill/payment mail is having more
impact on First-Class single-piece than presort mail.




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising Mail</ENAMEX>


•
First-Class household advertising mail is growing
fast.


•
First-Class advertising mail growth could offset some of
the loss in bill/payment mail.


•
Standard A mail is also growing fast.


•
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> delivered at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion more</NUMEX> pieces of advertising than non-advertising
mail.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIGHLIGHTS</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household and Business Mail</ENAMEX>


•
The volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> personal (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>) mail
continues to decline. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1990 and 1997</TIMEX>, it decreased at a rate
of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.7 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. Its share of total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> has
dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.1</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the factors
cited for the decline in personal mail volume is falling long
distance telephone rates which have made telephone communication
more affordable and fostered substitution of telephone calls for
personal mail.


•
Business (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>) mail is the only sector of
First-Class mailstream that has experienced healthy growth in the
90s. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1990 and 1997</TIMEX>, its volume grew at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.8</NUMEX>
percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX> times higher than total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>. Its
share increased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34.4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42.7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
The prevailing view is that the high growth of business mail
reflects the healthy growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy.


•
The share of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> (i.e.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-NHH mail) is increasing while the share sent
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> is decreasing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> originated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.


•
The above trends support the observation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is increasingly becoming a medium for business transactions
rather than personal exchange.




<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payment Mail</ENAMEX>


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Household bill/</ENAMEX>payment mail, as defined in this analysis,
includes both the household payment mail (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>
used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their bills) and the household bill mail
(i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to send bills to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>). The volume of business bill/payment mail (i.e., mail
used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to pay their bills and send bills to other
businesses) is unknown and is not covered in this
analysis.


•
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, household bill/payment mail totaled <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24.8 billion</NUMEX>
pieces or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24.9 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>. Of those, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7.5 billion</NUMEX>
pieces were payments and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17.3 billion</NUMEX> pieces were bills.



•
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Household bill/</ENAMEX>payment mail is now declining. Its annual
growth has dropped from

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX> and further to
negative <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>.


•
So far, however, the number of bill/payment pieces lost
is too small to have any material impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> volume.
Payment mail is declining fast while bill mail is still increasing,
though at a falling rate. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1990 and 1997</TIMEX>, the number of
payments made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> declined by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.5 billion</NUMEX> pieces but the
number of bills received increased by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.4 billion</NUMEX> pieces. As a
result, the total bill/payment mail decreased by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 1.1 billion</NUMEX>
pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>.


•
So far, it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are converting from
paying by mail to other methods of payment at a faster rate than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are converting their methods of sending bills.
Consequently, the ratio of payments made by mail to bills received
in the mail has dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43.1 percent</NUMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. On average, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than one</NUMEX> payment by
mail for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bills received in the mail.


•
Payment mail is all First-Class single-piece
non-presorted letters, while bill mail consists mostly of presorted
letters. So far, the former has been more vulnerable to diversion
than the latter. Thus, the diversion of bill-paying by mail to
other methods of bill-paying is having more impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
single-piece than presort mail.




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising Mail</ENAMEX>


•
Household advertising mail, as used in this analysis,
includes only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> stand-alone advertising mail that is sent
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. It does not include advertising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stuffers</ENAMEX> (i.e., advertising mail sent enclosed with other items
such as bills). Moreover, the volume of business advertising mail
(i.e., advertising mail sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>) is
unknown and, thus, it is not addressed in this analysis.



•
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">First-Class</ENAMEX> household advertising mail amounted
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.9 billion</NUMEX> pieces or

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.9 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>.


•
First-Class household advertising mail is growing fast.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1987 and 1997</TIMEX>, it grew at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.6 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
Its volume almost doubled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>. It grew from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5.2 billion</NUMEX>
pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.9 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. If this trend
continues, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> advertising mail growth may offset the loss
in bill/payment mail, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> to maintain its
current growth.


•
If we subtract the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.9 billion</NUMEX> pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
household advertising mail, reported for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
First-Class volume and add them to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A mail volume, we
obtain the following figures for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>: (a) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">91.3 billion</NUMEX> pieces of
nonadvertising mail; and (b) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">92.8 billion</NUMEX> pieces of advertising
mail. Thus, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> delivered at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion more</NUMEX> pieces of advertising than nonadvertising mail.
(Because of lack of data for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, we have assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
advertising mail volume stayed constant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1997</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>).


•
The high growth rates of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> advertising and
Standard A mail have contributed to shifting the balance in favor
of more advertising than nonadvertising mail in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailstream</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 and 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A mail
grew at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times higher than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>.


•
With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">First-Class</ENAMEX> household advertising and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A
mail growing at high rates, it is expected that the trend of more
advertising than non-advertising mail in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailstream</ENAMEX> will continue for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> to come. This may have
serious political implications for the legal protection of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> monopoly on letter mail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
may question such protection when they learn that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service is increasingly becoming an advertising medium.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANALYSIS</ENAMEX>



Introduction
The focus of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>. First, we identify
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> or flows of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> and evaluate their volume
growth. Then, we turn our attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">First-Class</ENAMEX> household mail
and evaluate the growth of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of its uses: bill-paying and
advertising. As far as I know, this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the growth
rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> and uses have been analyzed.
For the purpose of this analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bill/</ENAMEX>payment mail is broadly
defined as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their bills
as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to send bills to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, advertising mail is narrowly defined
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> stand-alone advertising mail, i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>
used exclusively for advertising. Because of their importance, we
will revisit these definitions later during the review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>/payment and advertising mail data.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household Diary Study</ENAMEX>
All data used in this analysis come from a market research study
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household Diary Study</ENAMEX> (HDS). Thus, before we turn to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, I would like to review some highlights related to this
study.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX> is financed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> and is conducted annually
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chilton Research Services</ENAMEX>, a market research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> located in
Radnor, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>. The study was first conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. The
last data report available to us is for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. Thus, we have
household diary data for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>, which we use for this
analysis<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>
HDS collects data on mail either sent or received by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.
The analysis of these data provides a detailed description of the
household portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> mailstream. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX> does not
collect any information on mail sent from non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to other
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. Thus, the non-household or business portion of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailstream</ENAMEX> is not analyzed by the study.
The data are collected on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a fiscal year</TIMEX> basis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX> is designed
so that data collected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given year</TIMEX> can be compared with data
collected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">preceding or subsequent years</TIMEX>. This allows us to make
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inter</ENAMEX>-temporal data comparisons and develop volume growth rates.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> have been using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX> data for
volume forecasting and ratemaking purposes during rate cases.
Additionally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> uses the data for planning and
marketing purposes.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Survey Research Center of the University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> conducted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> studies on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household Mailstream Study</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMS</ENAMEX>) which, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX>, analyzed the
household mail; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Non</ENAMEX>-household <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailstream Study</ENAMEX> (NMS), which
analyzed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> portion of the mailstream. These studies
were, however, conducted only once. Thus, we do not have data for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years between 1977 and 1987</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> comparisons.
HDS collects information on household mail by surveying a random
sample of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> per year. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household</ENAMEX> is surveyed for
a randomly selected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 14</TIMEX> and final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> high
volume <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of the postal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are surveyed
per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>; for the remainder of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are surveyed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>.
After an entry interview and training, selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
household are asked to keep a diary of every mail piece sent or
received by the household during the sample week. The entry
interview provides mainly information on household demographics,
like the size and income of the household, and the education and
employment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the household. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> also
collects information about the household's attitudes and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">responsiveness</ENAMEX> regarding mail<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>
The data used in this analysis are mostly collected by the
week-long diary of household mail. The diary mainly collects
information on: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and subclass of mail sent or received by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>, the sector or flow of this mail, the content or use of
it, and the industry source of household mail originating in
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.


Sectors or Flows of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> shows the breakdown of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> by sector or
flow for FYs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987, 1990, 1993 and 1997</TIMEX>. The first row of the table
identifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-HH
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household-to-Household</ENAMEX>) sector. This mail, also called personal
mail, is sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and includes mainly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> greeting cards like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards, other cards, letters,
and invitations like a wedding invitation. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> does not
include bill/payment or advertising mail.
A subject that is discussed during the entry interview is the
household's reaction to advertising mail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> are
asked, among other things, if they read advertising mail and if
they find it useful. Surprisingly, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> said that they read or look at advertising mail, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
percent said that they find it useful or interesting.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1/ Personal Mail</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">households</ENAMEX> (e.g. holiday greeting cards, other cards, letters, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">invitations</ENAMEX>). This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> does not include bill/payment or
advertising mail.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">2/ First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> (e.g.
payments made to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> and credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>; and orders
placed or payments made in response to advertising). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 81</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-NHH mail contains some type of payment and is
classified as bill/payment mail. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> does not contain any
advertising mail.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3/ First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> (e.g.
utility, credit card, insurance and medical bills as well as
advertisements from credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>, leisure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>). This sector is the only source of advertising
mail shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4/ Household Mail</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> either sent or received by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">5/ Business Mail</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to
other non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. This mail is not subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> row of the table is devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household-to-Non</ENAMEX>-household) sector. This mail is sent by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and includes mainly payments made to
utility and credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> as well as orders placed or
payments made in response to advertising. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 81 percent</NUMEX> of this
mail contains some type of payment and is classified as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>/payment mail. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> does not contain advertising
mail.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> row shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-HH
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Non</ENAMEX>-household-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household</ENAMEX>) sector. This mail is sent by
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>, credit card,
insurance and medical bills as well as advertisements from credit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>, leisure services and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> row, labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Subtotal"</ENAMEX> shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
household mail as the sum of mail in the above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX>. This
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> either sent or received by all households
and is subject to analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">row</TIMEX> is devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-NHH
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Non</ENAMEX>-household-to-Non-household) sector. This mail, also called
business mail, is sent by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to other non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX> does not survey this mail, and thus, we practically know
nothing about its uses. More importantly, we do not know how much
of business mail is used for bill-paying or advertising. Thus, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">First-Class bill/</ENAMEX>payment and advertising mail volumes presented in
this analysis do not include the business bill/payment and
advertising mail.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> row, labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unknown"</ENAMEX> shows some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>
that cannot be identified with any of the aforementioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
sectors. This mail is insignificant, except for FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, the first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> the study was conducted. Finally, the last row, labeled
"Total" is devoted to total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>.
Now let us turn to columns in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. Columns (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>),
and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>), labeled "Volume" show, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>, the total First-Class
Mail pieces broken-down by sector for FYs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987, 1990, 1993</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, respectively. For example, the first number in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Column</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>)
shows that in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Mail</ENAMEX> volume was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.4</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> pieces. Similarly, the last number in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Column</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>) shows that
the total First-Class volume was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99.7 billion</NUMEX> pieces in FY
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
Columns (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>), and (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX>), labeled "Share of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total</ENAMEX>" show
the volume share of each sector in total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> for the
aforementioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal years</TIMEX>. For example, the first number in
Column (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX>) shows that in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the volume of mail sent by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> represented <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.6 percent</NUMEX> of total
First-Class volume.
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columns</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>), and (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>), labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Growth</ENAMEX>"
show the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> volume growth rates of all sectors and total
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> for the time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods 1987-90, 1990-93 and 1993-97</TIMEX>,
respectively. For example, the first number in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Column</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>) shows
that, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1993 and 1997</TIMEX>, personal mail volume declined by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>
percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. Similarly, the last number in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Column</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>) shows
that for, the same time period, total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> volume
increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.0 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. It should be noted that the
numbers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columns</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>), and (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>) are average annual growth
rates. If someone wants to estimate the cumulative volume growth
for a period, she has to multiply the annual growth rates in
Columns (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>), and (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>) by the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the
period.
Now let us evaluate the historical volume data in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-97</TIMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only NHH-to-NHH</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>) mail has experienced
healthy volume growth. All other sectors and total household mail
have suffered either volume decline or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anemic</ENAMEX> growth rates.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX> (personal) mail is the smallest sector of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
Mail. Its annual growth rate fell from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.6 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX> to
negative <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX> and further to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">negative 2.0 percent</NUMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>. Its volume declined from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.2 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.4 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. Finally, its share of total
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.1 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.4 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the factors cited for the decline in personal mail
volume is falling long distance telephone rates which have made
telephone communication more affordable and fostered substitution
of telephone calls for personal mail.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-NHH sector, which consists mainly of payment mail, has
experienced a steeper volume decline than personal mail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX>.
Its average annual growth rate fell from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.9 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX> to
negative <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.6 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX> and further to negative
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.8 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>. Its volume declined from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12.8 billion</NUMEX>
pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.3 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, a drop in volume of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.6 billion</NUMEX> pieces. Finally, its share of total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>
dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. As we
will see in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>, the decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX> volume is mostly
attributed to the decline of this sector's household payment
mail.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX>, the volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-HH sector has increased, but
its annual growth rate has been falling. Its volume increased from
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">38.2 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40.8 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. Its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> growth rate, however, fell from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.9 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX> and further to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-HH mail is now the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest sector of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
Mail. Its share of total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> has declined from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42.8</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41.0 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-HH sector
includes both bill and advertising mail. As we will see later, the
volumes of both bill and advertising mail, included in this sector,
have increased in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX>. However, the annual growth rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bill</ENAMEX>
mail is declining, whereas the annual growth rate of advertising
mail is increasing fast.
Household mail is defined as the sum of mail in the above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
sectors and is shown as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Subtotal</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. Its annual growth
rate fell from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.6 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.7</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX> and further
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">negative 1.4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>. Its volume declined by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.9</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> pieces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 1997</TIMEX>; and its share of total
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65.3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56.6 percent</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1997.NHH</NUMEX>-to-NHH
(business mail) is the only sector of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> that has
experienced healthy growth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX>. Its annual growth rates were
as follows: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.2 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.1</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>. Its volume grew from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30.7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">42.6 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, an
increase in volume of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11.9 billion</NUMEX> pieces. Finally, its share of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">total First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> increased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34.4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42.7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. The prevailing view is that the high
growth of business mail reflects the healthy growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Docket No. R97-1</ENAMEX>, referring to period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977-95</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service volume witness <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolley</ENAMEX> first observed that "the general
trend has been a decrease in the share of First-Class letters sent
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and an increase in the share sent by
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>."<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> He then testified that the increase in
non-household originated mail "reflects the importance of mail as
an input in the production of goods and services in the economy,
with mail volume being associated importantly with growth in output
of goods and services in the economy and in demands for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> in production."



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill/Payment</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising Mail</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> has the same format as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> and shows the breakdown
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> by use. The first row labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Mail</ENAMEX>"
and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> row labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Mail</ENAMEX>" are identical to first
and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> rows in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, respectively. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> rows labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill/Payment</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising</ENAMEX>," and "Other HH
Mail" identify the uses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-HH mail reported in
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> rows of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>/payment mail includes both the household payment mail
(i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their bills) and
the household bill mail (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to send bills to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>). On the other hand,
advertising mail includes only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> stand-alone advertising
mail (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used exclusively for advertising) that
is sent by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. Advertising mail does not
include advertising stuffers, i.e., advertising mail sent enclosed
with other items such as bills. Neither does it include the mail
sent in response to advertising. A large portion of
response-to-advertising mail involves a payment and is included in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>/payment mail. If the response-to-advertising mail were also
added to advertising mail it would have resulted in double
counting.
The volume of letters sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> or household originated
mail can be obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> by adding the volumes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-HH
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-NHH mail. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> originated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 16 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">First-Class</ENAMEX> mail, down from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. The volume of
letters sent by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> or nonhousehold originated mail can
also be calculated from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> by adding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-NHH
volumes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> sent <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
Mail, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1/ Bill/</ENAMEX>payment mail includes both the household payment mail

(i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their bills) and
the household bill mail (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to send bills to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>). The volume of business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>/payment mail (i.e., mail used by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> and send bills to other non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>) is unknown and is not
included in bill/payment mail.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">2/ Advertising</ENAMEX> mail only includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> stand-alone
advertising mail that is sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. It does
not include advertising stuffers (i.e., advertising mail sent
enclosed with other items such as bills). Moreover, the volume of
business advertising mail (i.e., advertising mail sent by
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to other non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>) is not known and, thus, it
is not included in advertising mail. Finally, it does not include
the mail sent by both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> in response to
advertising.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3/ Other HH</ENAMEX> mail is the residual household <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> with
the following major uses: financial statements,
announcements/meetings, notices of order, request for and
confirmation of donations, tax forms, education acceptances, and
insurance policies.
It should be noted that the figures of bill/payment and
advertising mail presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> account only for the
First-Class household mail and, thus, represent the lower bound of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">First-Class bill/</ENAMEX>payment and advertising mail volumes. The volume
of business bill/payment mail (i.e., mail used by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to
pay their bills and send bills to other non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>) is unknown
and, thus, it is not included in bill/payment mail figures
presented in this table. Likewise, the volume of business
advertising mail (i.e., advertising mail sent by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>) is not known and, thus, it has not been added to
advertising mail.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, household bill/payment mail amounted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24.8 billion</NUMEX>
pieces or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24.9 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
household advertising mail amounted to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.9 billion</NUMEX> pieces or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.9</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>.
The growth of bill/payment mail has slowed down significantly in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX>. Its average annual growth rate dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX> and further to negative <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>. Its share dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29.1 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24.9 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. So far, however, the number of mail pieces
lost to alternative bill-paying methods is too small to have any
material impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> volume. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1990 and 1997</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>/payment volume declined by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1.1 billion</NUMEX> pieces. These
represent an average loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">160 million</NUMEX> pieces or less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
Advertising mail has experienced high growth rates in all
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX>, it enjoyed a very high growth rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15.3</NUMEX>
percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX>, its growth slowed down to a healthy
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.0 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>; and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>, it grew by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3 percent</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. Its volume almost doubled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX>. It grew from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.9 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the volume of total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">99.7 billion</NUMEX>
pieces and the volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A mail (which is mainly
advertising mail) was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">77.3 billion</NUMEX> pieces. If we subtract the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.9</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> advertising mail from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
volume and add them to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A mail volume, we obtain the
following figures: (a) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">89.8 billion</NUMEX> pieces of non-advertising mail;
and (b) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">87.1 billion</NUMEX> pieces of advertising mail. Thus, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> delivered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6 billion</NUMEX> fewer pieces of advertising
than non-advertising mail.
Now, if we perform the same exercise using the actual FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">First-Class</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard A</ENAMEX> volume figures of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">101.2 billion</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82.9</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> pieces respectively, and assuming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
advertising mail volume has not changed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1997 and 1998</TIMEX>, we
obtain the following figures for FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>: (a) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">91.3 billion</NUMEX> pieces
of nonadvertising mail; and (b) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">92.8 billion</NUMEX> pieces of advertising
mail. Thus, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> delivered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5 billion</NUMEX> more
pieces of advertising than non-advertising mail.
It should be pointed out that high growth rates of both
First-Class advertising and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A mail have contributed to
shifting the balance in favor of more advertising than
non-advertising mail in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> mailstream. In the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two Fiscal Years, 1997 and 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A mail grew at an average
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times higher than First-Class
Mail<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> advertising and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A mail growing at high
rates, it is expected that the trend of more advertising than
non-advertising mail in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> mailstream will continue
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> to come. This may have serious political implications
for the legal protection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> monopoly on letter
mail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may question such protection when
it becomes common knowledge that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> delivers more
"junk" than other letter mail.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill/Payment Mail</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>/payment mail can originate either in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> or
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> can be anyone of the following three
sectors: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>, which has
the same format as the previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tables, shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">total First-Class</ENAMEX> bill/payment mail reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>.
The first row shows the bill/payment mail that comes from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household-to-Non</ENAMEX>-household) sector. This is the payment
mail, i.e., mail used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their bills. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
payment mail was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.5 billion</NUMEX> pieces or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30.1 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bill/payment</ENAMEX>
mail. The total household bill/payment mail, which was first
presented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second row</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, is now reported in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> row of this table. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> its volume was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24.8 billion</NUMEX>
pieces.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">row</TIMEX> shows the bill/payment mail that comes from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Non</ENAMEX>-household-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household</ENAMEX>) sector. This is the bill
mail, i.e., mail used by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to send bills to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> mail was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17.3 billion</NUMEX> pieces or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69.9 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>/payment mail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> row is devoted to bill/payment mail that is part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Non</ENAMEX>-household-to-Non-household) sector. This is the
business bill/payment mail (i.e.,
In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A mail grew <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.8 percent</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.3</NUMEX>
percent respectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> grew <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5 percent</NUMEX> in both
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

10
mail used by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to send and pay bills to other
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>). No figures are reported on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this row</TIMEX> because the
volume of business bill/payment mail is not known to the
Commission6.
Household payment mail has been declining. Its annual growth
rate dropped from positive <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.9 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX> to negative <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX> and further to negative
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.9 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>. Its volume declined from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10.0 billion</NUMEX>
pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.5 billion</NUMEX> pieces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, a drop of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 billion</NUMEX>
pieces. This drop in payment mail volume accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69 percent</NUMEX> of
the decline in the volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-NHH sector, amounted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.6</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> pieces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 1997</TIMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
The growth rate of household bill mail is also declining but its
volume has increased in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX>. Its annual growth rate dropped
from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.9 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-90</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-93</TIMEX> and further
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX>; but its volume increased by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.4 billion</NUMEX>
pieces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 1997</TIMEX>. This increase in the volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bill</ENAMEX>
mail offsets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of the decline in the volume of payment
mail allowing bill/payment mail to decline by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 1.1 billion</NUMEX>
pieces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 1996</TIMEX>. As said before, the decline in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">household bill/</ENAMEX>payment volume, so far, amounts to a very small
portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> volume.
There is another observation that can be made based on household
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>/payment volume figures reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. Although both
payments and bills seem to have been affected by the diversion from
payment by mail to other methods of payment, the effect of
diversion is more pronounced on payment mail. As a result, the
ratio of the number of payments made by mail to the number of bills
received in the mail has dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43.1</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. Thus, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, on average, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> made less
than one payment by mail for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bills received in the
mail.
Finally, payment mail is all First-Class single-piece
non-presorted letters, while bill mail is mostly presorted letters.
So far, the former has been more vulnerable to diversion than the
later. Thus, the diversion of bill-paying by mail to other methods
of bill-paying is having more impact on single-piece than presort
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">First-Class Per</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household Volumes</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the factors affecting the demand for mail services is the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. Households send and receive mail and their
number is expected to affect the demand for mail services in a
positive way. An increase in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> is expected
to cause an increase in mail volume.
For building "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">H.R. 22" Model</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> has assumed
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> business bill/payment mail was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20.0 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 billion</NUMEX> pieces. If the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> figure
were also true for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, then <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46.8 percent</NUMEX> of business mail would
have qualified as bill/payment mail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> and total (i.e.,
household plus business) bill/payment mail would have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44.7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> pieces or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44.9 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service did not tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> where this <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> figure
comes from.
As we have seen, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tables 1, 2, and 3</ENAMEX> show the breakdown of total
demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> and uses for FYs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987, 1990</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. Now, if we assume that the volume of all sectors
and uses in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tables 1, 2, and 3</ENAMEX> have an elasticity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with
respect to the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> (i.e., every one percent
increase in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> has yielded exactly a one
percent increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all annual</TIMEX> mail volumes and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all years</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Tables 1, 2</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), we can, then, divide the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> volume figures
by the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> in the respective year to obtain annual
volume figures per household. This process eliminates the effect of
household growth on mail volume and allows an analysis of the
volume behavior at the household level. However, when we analyze
the per-household volume figures, we have to remember that, for the
purpose of developing those figures, we made the aforementioned
assumption about the relationship of mail volume and number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and this assumption may not hold true for some or all
sectors (or uses) and for some or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tables 1, 2</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Tables 4, 5</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> display First-Class per-household annual
volumes. They are identical to Tables <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1, 2 and 3</TIMEX> respectively,
except that the total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> volumes in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tables 1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX> have been
replaced with per-household annual volumes in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tables 4</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 and 6</NUMEX>. A
comparison of figures in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tables 4, 5, and 6</ENAMEX> with the corresponding
figures in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tables 1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX>, respectively, shows that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> of total by per-household volume figures leaves the
shares of sectors and uses in total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> volume
unchanged. However, because the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> has been
increasing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, the replacement of total by per-household
volume figures produces annual growth rates which are lower than
those shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tables 1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX>. That is, the positive annual
growth rates in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tables 1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shrink</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tables 4</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 and 6</NUMEX> and
the negative rates augment in absolute terms.
For example, if we compare the annual growth rates of mail
volume for period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX> shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Column</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tables 1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> we
can see that: (a) the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.0 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> decrease of total HH-to-HH
volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> has been augmented to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3 percent</NUMEX> annual
decrease of per-household volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>; (b) the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.8 percent</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> decrease of total HH-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX> volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">augmented</ENAMEX> to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> decrease of per-household volume
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>; (c) the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> increase of total NHH-to-HH
volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> has shrunk to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.2 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> decrease of
per-household volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.1 percent</NUMEX> annual
increase of total NHH-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX> volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> has shrunk to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.7</NUMEX>
percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> increase of per-household volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>.
Similarly, a comparison of annual growth rates for the same
period in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> with those in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX> reveals the following: (a)
the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.0 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> decrease of bill/payment volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>
has been augmented to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> decrease of perhousehold
volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>; and (b) the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> increase of total
advertising mail volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> has shrunk to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.8 percent</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> increase of per-household volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>.
Finally, a comparison of annual growth rates for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-97</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> with those in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX> shows the following: (a) the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.9</NUMEX>
percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> decrease of the total number of payments in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>
has been augmented to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.2 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> decrease of the number
of payments per household in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>; and (b) the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0 percent</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> increase of total number of bills in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX> has shrunk to a
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> decrease of the number of bills per household in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Table 6</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1/ Personal Mail</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">households</ENAMEX> (e.g. holiday greeting cards, other cards, letters, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">invitations</ENAMEX>). This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> does not include bill/payment or
advertising mail.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">2/ First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> (e.g.
payments made to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> and credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>; and orders
placed or payments made in response to advertising). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 81</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HH</ENAMEX>-to-NHH mail contains some type of payment and is
classified as bill/payment mail. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> does not contain any
advertising mail.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3/ First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> (e.g.
utility, credit card, insurance and medical bills as well as
advertisements from credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>, leisure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>). This sector is the only source of advertising
mail shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4/ Household Mail</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> either sent or received by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">5/ Business Mail</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> sent by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to
other non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. This mail is not subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX>.
14


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1/ Bill/</ENAMEX>payment mail includes both the household payment mail
(i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their bills) and
the household bill mail (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to send bills to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>). The volume of business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>/payment mail (i.e., mail used by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> and send bills to other non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>) is unknown and is not
included in bill/payment mail.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">2/ Advertising</ENAMEX> mail only includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> stand-alone
advertising mail that is sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. It does
not include advertising stuffers (i.e., advertising mail sent
enclosed with other items such as bills). Moreover, the volume of
business advertising mail (i.e., advertising mail sent by
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to other non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>) is not known and, thus, it
is not included in advertising mail. Finally, it does not include
the mail sent by both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> in response to
advertising.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3/ Other HH</ENAMEX> mail is the residual household <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> with
the following major uses: financial statements, announcements/
meetings, notices of order, request for and confirmation of
donations, tax forms, education acceptances, and insurance
policies.
15


<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1/ First-Class</ENAMEX> household payment mail (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>
used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their bills). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2/ First-Class</ENAMEX> household
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> mail (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> used by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to send
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3/ First-Class</ENAMEX> business bill/payment mail
(i.e., mail used by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> to pay their bills and send
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> to other
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>). The volume of business bill/payment mail is
unknown. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDS</ENAMEX> does not study the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHH</ENAMEX>-to-NHH sector of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailstream</ENAMEX>.
16




