



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Worksharing</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Efficiency</ENAMEX>, and Pareto
Optimality
Presented at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sixth Conference on Postal</ENAMEX> and Delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics The Center for Research</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulated Industries</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreux</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17-20, 1998</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert W. Mitchell</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is Special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>,
an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Agency</ENAMEX>, separate from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States Postal Service</ENAMEX>. The opinions expressed are those of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and do not represent opinions or positions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Rate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>.



Introduction
Competition is generally believed to lead to efficiency, be it
economic or technical. One method of introducing competition into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> systems, without affecting the universal service obligation,
is through what have been termed "worksharing" discounts. One
begins with the view that the postal system is a vertically
integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> involving the collection, sorting, transporting,
and final delivery of mail. Under the presumption that the postal
monopoly applies in its clearest form only to the final delivery
process, where scale economies are likely the greatest, the
worksharing notion is that a discount should be offered to mailers
or competitors1 who do portions of the postal work and then turn
the mail over to the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> for completion of delivery. As
a technical matter, it should be noted up front that there is no
requirement that the mailer or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> really perform any
particular piece of work, only that the mail be presented so that
the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">service2</ENAMEX> does not have to do that piece of work. In
terms of understanding the functioning and effects of the
worksharing process, this distinction will be shown to be a matter
of some importance.
Because simplicity and ease of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> are usually given
some weight in rate setting, the number of worksharing discounts is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX>. Such a limitation might not exist in the private sector,
where the categories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to be served can be prescribed
and contract rates can be tailored to specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> or
situations, but it is taken as a constraint on broad-based
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.3 Given this limitation, attention focuses
on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> obvious questions: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Should worksharing discounts be
offered? (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) What are the effects of these discounts on mailers and
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) How should the size of these discounts be
determined? This paper answers the first primarily in terms of the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. The framework within which these issues will be considered
is the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> postal system, about which the author
knows a little.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> The term <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> stands for private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that compete for
portions of postal work, possibly as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of
mailers or mailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> The term postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> is a
reference to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s dominant or government-run postal delivery
system. References to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX> will be
capitalized. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> refers almost interchangeably to rate(s)
and price(s). The former term is more common in postal rate circles
and the latter more common in economics.
Needless to say, these issues involve much more than just the
fringes of postal activity. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> mailstream is workshared and an even larger portion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A4</ENAMEX> is either workshared or has preparation requirements
that involve work the mailer must do. Accordingly, the number of
dollars involved in worksharing is in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> and the effects
on mailers and the economy are quite large. Also, considerable sums
are spent by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> analyzing the costs associated with
worksharing, and mailers/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> incur considerable expense
litigating their positions on worksharing before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate</ENAMEX>
Commission.
Although competition and efficiency are important, and may be
the bottom line, the movement toward worksharing has been guided by
other justifications as well. Recognizing that these other
justifications overlap and may not all qualify as basic starting
points, it is worthwhile to list them. First, there are those who
argue that worksharing is a kind of deaveraging, which brings
prices closer to costs, and that deaveraging is both economically
efficient and fair. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, there is the view that worksharing
discounts are needed to make the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> more competitive,
thus helping to stave off threats from competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> and
electronic substitutes. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, there are arguments that worksharing
discounts are needed to send signals to mailers that allow the
mailers to decide whether they or their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> can do the work for
less than the postal service<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX>, there are those who argue
that worksharing discounts are a natural outcome of traditional
"make or buy" decisions. That is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> commonly contract out
any function that can be done by another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> at a lower cost.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fifth</NUMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> take the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Efficient Component Pricing</ENAMEX> (ECP) rule
as one that should be applied wherever opportunity presents itself.
Within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECP</ENAMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> possibilities: set the discount equal to
the simple cost difference between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories; set the
discount equal to the average incremental savings in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Due to a name change which is difficult to explain and is
confusing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A mail is the same mail that was formerly
identified as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third</ENAMEX> Class. It consists primarily of advertising
mail that is not required to be sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Class</ENAMEX>. It also includes
some mail that might be viewed as community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> or shoppers
and some that could be viewed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Periodicals</ENAMEX>. As a formal matter,
Standard A mail in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is broken into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> subclasses,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regular Standard A</ENAMEX> and the other called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enhanced Carrier</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Route Standard A.</ENAMEX> This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> will have some implications for this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distinction</ENAMEX>, but will not focus specifically on it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> The
achievement of having the lowest cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> do the work is
sometimes referred to as an outcome of "lowest combined cost."
cost associated with the worksharing program; set the price of
the workshared product equal to its marginal cost plus the unit
opportunity cost of the worksharing program; or set the discount
equal to the savings at the margin<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finally</ENAMEX>, there is the notion
that it is fair to provide nondiscriminatory downstream access to
the delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>. This notion argues that the postal service
should charge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> the same amount to use the delivery
system that the postal service charges itself. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> has
not been able to figure out how much the postal service charges
itself for delivery, this notion, while sounding meritorious and
politically correct, will not be mentioned again.
These various approaches sometimes lead to different discount
levels and different associated sets of effects. Also, they
sometimes break down in application, when faced with a practical
situation that does not align well with the assumptions of the
approach. Short of that, the information required to apply them can
be subject to wide margins of error and can be costly to
develop.
This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> parts. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part discusses various
kinds of worksharing. The point is that mailers respond to
"worksharing" discounts in a variety of ways and for a range of
reasons, and that these responses need to be understood in order to
understand the effects of the discounts. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">empirical</ENAMEX> and discusses various welfare aspects of selecting
discount levels for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The
entire discussion is based on an econometric model which provides
no-shift elasticities<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,7</NUMEX> discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">elasticities</ENAMEX>, and, by implication,
own-price elasticities and cross-price elasticities for basic mail
and workshared mail. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is viewed as good for limited
changes in prices and discount levels. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> part of the paper
takes a broader view and considers welfare, efficiency, and
fairness issues, consistent with the model in part <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the
overall worksharing program for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>. Part <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> contains
concluding observations. The focus in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> parts is on real
numbers and on how the system is believed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> to
behave.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> When the workshare price is equal to the marginal cost plus
the unit opportunity cost, it is often observed that the postal
service is "indifferent" to whether the workshare program is
offered. When the discount is equal to the savings at the margin,
as much work as possible will be transferred to the lower cost
provider.


Part I: Aspects of Worksharing
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle 1970s</TIMEX>, the rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> and
third-class mail in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> were very simple. First-Class
Mail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10¢</NUMEX> per piece (plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 9¢</NUMEX> for each
additional ounce beyond the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>), regardless of the piece's shape
or processing characteristics, and regardless of the distance it
needed to be carried. Similarly, third-class mail paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">41¢</NUMEX> per
pound with a minimum charge of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.9¢</NUMEX> per piece. It could be
letter-sized, flat-sized, or parcel shaped; it could go <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 miles</NUMEX>
or across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>; it could be mixed in a sack with other pieces
or it could be in a bundle for a specific <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-digit <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP Code</ENAMEX>. In all
cases, the rate was the same.
Now, the situation is quite different. The rate for the
First-Class piece depends on whether it is presorted, on whether it
qualifies for an automation category, on whether it is a letter or
a flat within the automation category, on which of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> presort levels
it achieves within the automation category, and on whether it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonstandard</ENAMEX> in shape. Further, the rate for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">additional ounces</NUMEX> is
considerably less than the rate for the first ounce. The rates for
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> class (now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> A) are similar but even more complex. One
must know whether the piece is a letter or a nonletter, whether it
qualifies for an automation category, whether it qualifies for a
carrier route presorted category, where it is entered in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, what its presort level is, what its weight is, and whether
it qualifies as saturation or near saturation. In the latter case,
it must be prepared in what is called the line-of-travel, which is
basically the sequence in which the carrier delivers his or her
route, and there are other requirements as well.
These various price differences, all of which are based to some
degree at least on studies of actual cost differences, send a wide
range of signals to mailers. Some of these signals call for a
decision on whether to workshare and others do little more than
tell the mailer that some pieces cost more to process than others.
But whatever their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> or however they are viewed, the
effects on mailers and on the mailstream have been
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> As will be explained further below, a no-shift elasticity is
an own-price elasticity under the constraint either that mailers
may not shift to and from the workshared category or that the size
of the workshare
enormous. Mailers are now presorting their mail, barcoding their
mail, changing flat-size pieces into letter-size pieces,
consolidating their mail, and carrying their mail great distances
in order to enter it at specific locations. Presort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are
collecting the mail, working with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> on the quality of
their addresses and on the machinability of their addresses,
sorting the mail, and entering the mail effectively. Private
trucking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have begun operations to do nothing more than carry
mail across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
Viewed simply, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> specific discounts are now being offered.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is for presorting, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> for putting on barcodes and
assuring machinability, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> for drop shipping, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
for being letter-sized instead of flat-sized. Potentially more
interesting, however, is to view the discounts in terms of the
responses they receive from mailers and the factors associated with
those responses. For this purpose, a classification of worksharing
types is proposed, with no requirement that the types be mutually
exclusive. This will aid in understanding mailer responses and in
evaluating the benefits of offering the discounts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Type-1 Worksharing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Type-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">worksharing</ENAMEX> is the simplest kind and
is most closely aligned with the plain meaning of the term
"workshare." The discount is given when the mailer or competitor
does some of the postal work and does it in essentially the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> as the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> would do the work. For example, a
discount could be given for mail presorted into packages, each
package being for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one 5</NUMEX>-digit <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP Code</ENAMEX> area. In a type-1
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worksharing</ENAMEX> situation, the mailer or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> would sort the mail
in essentially the same way that the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> would sort the
mail. This means collecting the mail and sorting it either by hand
or on a sorting machine. Such a machine might have an optical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character reader</ENAMEX> and might put on a barcode.
The purpose here is not to provide reasons or to quantify why
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mailer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> might be able to do the work for less than
the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, despite the likelihood that the
mailer/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>'s scale of operations will be smaller. Several
possible reasons, however, are clear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mailer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> might
pay lower wages than the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, might succeed in managing
and/or scheduling more tightly the sorting operations, might
achieve higher productivity levels, and might be working with a
more
discount does not change.
uniform and more tightly controlled mailstream. The latter
factor exists because postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> need to be designed to handle
a wide range of mailpieces, generated by a wide range of mailers.
Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> tend to be higher in cost and may be more difficult
to control.
A drop-ship discount might also evoke type-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> worksharing
activity. A mailer sending a quantity of mail to zone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> might
achieve a lower rate if he carries the mail to the destination mail
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. If he can transport the mail for less than the discount,
he will choose to do so. His success in performing the work at a
lower cost might be due to an ability to arrange completely full
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> or to achieve lower-price contracts with trucking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. The
latter possibility might exist if the mailer assumed some risk by
placing fewer constraints on the trucking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>.
In pure type-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> worksharing, the analysis of the decision and the
benefits is simple. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mailer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> can do the work at a
lower cost, he will choose to do it. His welfare level will be
increased by the difference between the discount and his cost of
doing the work. The profit position of the postal administration
depends on how the discount level is set, an issue that we need not
specify here.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Type-2 Worksharing</ENAMEX>. In a type-2 situation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mailer</ENAMEX>/competitor
achieves the workshared result but does the work in a different way
from the way the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> would do it. The best example of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">type-2</ENAMEX> worksharing involves, again, presort discounts. Either
physically or electronically, the mailer may be able to arrange all
of his addresses in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP Code</ENAMEX> order. This being done, he can then
print together and bundle all of the addresses for one <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP Code</ENAMEX>.
After this, the addresses in another <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP Code</ENAMEX> would be printed.
When a worksharing situation of this kind is faced, there is the
potential for the mailer to do the work at considerably less cost
than could the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. Even if he is sorting the addresses
by hand, he has the option of doing the work in a completely
different way Also, if the same mailing list is used more than
once, or is used again with slight modification, he can sort once
and do many mailings. As a practical matter, mailers are believed
in many cases to be able to do this work for a fraction of the cost
the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> would face. As a guess, this fraction could
easily be in the neighborhood of onequarter to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-eighth</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> features of this kind of situation deserve note. First, the
mailer may be able to do in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step what the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> does
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or more</NUMEX> steps. Such would be the case if the postal service
requires <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sortations to get the mail to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-digit level while
the computer goes there directly. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, mailers of some volume
may be in position to take advantage of this discount without the
help of a presort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> or mailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.
From a welfare point of view, a type-2 discount situation is
extremely attractive because the potential gains are large. In
effect, the potential exists to achieve the sortation without doing
the work; but if the discount is not offered, none of the benefit
will be realized.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Type-3 Worksharing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Type-3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">worksharing</ENAMEX> is where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mailer</ENAMEX>'s
decision, whether or not he turns the mail over to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, is
influenced by factors other than the size of the discount and his
cost of doing the work. The primary example of this situation is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> where the mailer is concerned about the level of service
received and finds that taking advantage of the worksharing
discount leads to better service. The most common service
consideration would involve the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to delivery, but
mailers can also be interested in achieving delivery on a certain
date or even in reducing the risk that the piece is lost in the
mail.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> examples of this kind of situation are important. First, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailer</ENAMEX> could find that mail presorted and/or barcoded zips through
the system without delay while other mail, which needs more postal
attention, is either delayed or is unpredictable. In this
situation, the value to the mailer of the improved service would be
considered along with the cost of doing the work<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">.8 Second</TIMEX>, a mailer
considering drop shipping could know that mail entered at a
destination <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> is always delivered within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two days</TIMEX>
while that entered at a distant location takes much longer and is
less predictable. This mailer would clearly consider the value of
the improved service along with the cost of the drop shipping.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> Some mailers have found that turning the mail over to a
presort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, which requires time to do the additional work,
results in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 1-day</TIMEX> loss in service. In response, some presort firms
provide same-day entry and some drop <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> to nearby locations.
From a welfare point of view, the situation here also has
potential. For example, suppose the discount is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4¢</NUMEX> (per piece) and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mailer</ENAMEX>'s cost of doing the work is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.8¢</NUMEX>. It would seem on first
glance that the gain from having the mailer do the work is only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2¢</NUMEX>. But if the value of the improved service is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 cent</NUMEX> per piece,
then the gain from offering the discount is amplified to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2¢</NUMEX>. If
the discount is not offered, the mailer would clearly not do the
work or receive the improved service. Important also is that if the
improved service is not feasible, the mailer could decide to use an
alternative to the postal system. Conversely, the mailer could
increase his volume if the discount and the associated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> are
offered.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Type-4 Worksharing</ENAMEX>. A type-4 discount situation is where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailer</ENAMEX> reduces the work required by changing his behavior in
efficient ways that were either not predicted or that do not seem
particularly associated with the nature of the discount. Two
examples are offered: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> involves drop-ship discounts and
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> involves the letter/flat differential.
A drop-ship discount can be as simple as a price for nationwide
mail and a price for mail entered at the destination <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mailer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> could be sending mail to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. If mailed
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, he would pay the nationwide price but if entered in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, he would pay the lower destination price. If the
difference between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> prices is large enough, the mailer
could hire a trucking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, as discussed above. But there is also
the option of having the mail printed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>,
which would make destination entry quite natural. Without the
drop-ship discount, the mailer will not consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
printer, even if the printing cost is the same as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. With
the drop-ship discount, the mail might be printed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
and the burden of transportation would be avoided entirely.
As a second example, consider the letter/flat differential<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>
Under such a rate structure, letter-size pieces have a lower rate
than flat-size pieces. The discount might be justified on the basis
of nothing more than an interest in cost-based rates, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worksharing</ENAMEX> might not be an issue. Some mailers, however, will
convert flats into letters. Considering
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may not view a letter/flat rate differential as
focused on worksharing. I include it here because it is a discount
and it can lead to a reduction in postal work.
the cost of delivery and the benefits received by the mailer,
the letter-size piece might be a more efficient piece for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> as a whole, but the mailer will not make the change unless a
rate differential is offered.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Type-5 Worksharing</ENAMEX>. A type-5 situation is one that has
worksharing aspects but which is directed primarily at making the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postal</ENAMEX> system more competitive. The drop-ship discount is, again,
an obvious example. Suppose a mailer in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> has mail that is
to be delivered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>. If the postal service presents him
with a rate that does not vary with distance, he may, in effect, be
subsidizing other mail. For example, if the average piece of mail
travels <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000 miles</NUMEX> and that is the cost on which the rate is
based, mail going over <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000 miles</NUMEX> gets a relative bargain and mail
staying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of entry can be viewed as helping to finance
the long-distance mail.
Now suppose there is a private delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> that
is competing with the postal service<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> That private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> will base
its rates on the costs that it incurs, given that it both receives
and delivers the mail in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>-it will not charge a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000-mile</NUMEX>
rate. If the postal service charges only a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000-mile</NUMEX> rate, with no
distance differentials and no associated drop-ship discounts, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">postal</ENAMEX> service will be at a disadvantage and may not be competing
effectively. It could easily lose business, even if it is the
low-cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>.
If the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> offers distance-sensitive rates, it will
be more competitive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>. This is the case whether or not
any mailers decide on the basis of the price differentials to
engage in drop shipping. In short, the rate structure could be
established in order to be competitive or to base the prices on the
actual costs of the mail, and worksharing activity could occur as a
natural result.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section Conclusion</ENAMEX>. Many worksharing discounts evoke responses
based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> of the situations described above. For
example, presort discounts have aspects of type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, type <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3,</ENAMEX>
and maybe some of type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Similarly, drop-ship discounts have
multiple aspects. The reason for delineating these various types is
to emphasize that if the advocacy of offering the discounts is to
be analyzed, all of the dimensions need to be considered.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 The Private Express Statutes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> do not
prevent private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> from delivering parcels, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX>,
catalogs over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> pages, or saturation mail. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, however,
may not use the mail boxes.


Part <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">II: A Specific Model</ENAMEX>
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Docket No. R97-1</ENAMEX> rate case before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate</ENAMEX>
Commission, an econometric model became available for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>
Mail with the characteristic that basic mail and workshared mail
are treated separately. The actual model contains a number of
variables<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> For present purposes, however, interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> only
on the price variables and the discount variables. Holding all
other variables constant, and integrating their effects into the
constant term, the equation for basic mail becomes:
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.189</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.164</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vb</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28.572</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
And the equation for workshared mail becomes:
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.289</NUMEX> D0.227



<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ws</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51.034</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pws</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
Where V = volume in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of pieces, b = basic (referring to
the non-workshared category of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ws</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workshare</ENAMEX>, P
= price, and D = discount. The volume variables are the number of
pieces in the category and the price variables are fixed-weight
indexes of the range of prices paid by the mailpieces making up the
category. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fiscal Year 1996</TIMEX>, the volume of basic (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX>)
mail was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">54.1 billion</NUMEX> pieces and the volume of workshared
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> presorted) mail was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">39.1 billion</NUMEX>. The workshared mail
consists primarily of mail presorted to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-digit level, with a
small proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> route presorted mail. Some of this mail
is also barcoded. The basic mail consists of all other mail and
therefore includes flat-size pieces as well as letter-size pieces,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">heavy-weight pieces</ENAMEX> as well as light-weight pieces. Some basic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mail</ENAMEX> has hand-written addresses but
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">11 See the Direct Testimony</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas E. Thress</ENAMEX> on Behalf of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USPS-T-7</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Docket No. R97-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40-41</NUMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thress</ENAMEX>' complete model
includes the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> cards, the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard A</ENAMEX>,
the workshare discount, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> lags on these variables, permanent
income, transitory income, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> costs, certain dummy variables, and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> coefficients.
most is machine addressed. Basic mail also includes some parcels
under <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11 ounces</NUMEX> and some non-standard pieces.
The price index (weighted price) for basic mail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39.2¢</NUMEX> and for workshared mail was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27.6¢.12</NUMEX> The difference between
these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.6¢</NUMEX>. This difference, however, reflects much more
than just a weighted average of the discounts available to the
workshared mail. It also includes rate differences due to weight
and to whether the piece is non-standard in shape. The value of D
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0¢</NUMEX>. This is a weighted average of the various
discounts available for presorting and barcoding.
Compared to the basic category, the qualitative characteristics
of the workshare category are reasonably uniform. In brief, most
workshared <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are probably paying a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 27.6¢</NUMEX>.
Therefore, the similar pieces which are not workshared, and are not
getting the discount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.0¢</NUMEX>, are paying a price of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0¢</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27.6¢</NUMEX> =
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33.6¢</NUMEX>. We may think, therefore, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39.2¢</NUMEX> price for basic mail
as composed of a group of mailers paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33.6¢</NUMEX> and another group
paying, maybe, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45.0¢</NUMEX>. The pieces paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33.6¢</NUMEX> may be viewed as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to become workshared, if the discount is increased. If
the prices of all basic mail were increased, say, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33.6¢</NUMEX>,
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45.0¢</NUMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39.2¢</NUMEX> average would all increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>. At the
new price level, the ratio of the price of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> mail to
the average price of basic mail would remain the same. If this
ratio is designated as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>, then:
P


candidate
g = <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
and
D = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g P</ENAMEX> b-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pws</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> The variables in the equations are in dollars and in billions
of pieces. For ease of discussion, they will be referenced in the
text in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> per piece. Also, gains and losses in welfare,
technical efficiency, and profits will be referenced in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
dollars, although certain graphs may refer to them in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX>.
The value of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX> in the situation described above is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.857</NUMEX>.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s costing systems, the per-piece
cost of basic mail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26.1¢</NUMEX> and the per-piece cost of
workshared mail was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.6¢.13</NUMEX> The difference between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these two</TIMEX> costs
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15.5¢</NUMEX>. These costs are developed primarily to be marginal costs
and will be assumed to be marginal costs in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>. This
difference of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15.5¢</NUMEX> is due to a range of characteristics which
workshared mail exhibits. For example, basic mail has a higher
average weight, with pieces ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 to 11 ounces</NUMEX>, while most
workshared mail weighs in the neighborhood of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ounce</NUMEX>. Also, most
workshared <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are letter-size and many basic pieces are flats,
which cost more to process. There are other differences as well.
The addresses on workshared <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> are generally thought to be more
accurate and are almost always machine readable. Some basic pieces
have handwritten addresses, and some basic pieces are parcels.
In order to go much further, we need to know the cost of the
pieces that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for moving from the basic category to
the workshare category. Since, in substantial degree, the rate
setting process in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> sets discounts equal to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> cost differences, I am assuming for present purposes
that the current discount equals the current cost difference
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> mail and the workshared mail. Therefore, the
cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> mail becomes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.6¢</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.6¢</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0¢</NUMEX>). Also, I
will be assuming that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.0¢</NUMEX> cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> to take
the mail from basic to workshared condition is constant as limited
quantities of mail move back and forth between basic and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workshared</ENAMEX>. This is a simplification of reality, which probably
involves a curve with a slight upward slope. That is, as the
discount is increased in steps, the cost to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service of</ENAMEX>
sorting the mail that becomes workshared on step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> is probably
greater than the cost of sorting the mail that becomes workshared
on step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. This assumption will be relaxed in Part III below, where
larger discount changes are considered.
Note that since the discount is equal to the savings experienced
at the margin as additional pieces become workshared, the base
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>) position becomes the efficient component pricing (ECP)
position. In postal parlance, we would say that the discount equals
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the cost avoidance at the margin, or that the
passthrough of the avoidance is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>.
Now that we know the prices, the quantities, and the costs, the
total revenue is easily calculable as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31.9988 billion</NUMEX>, the total
marginal cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as $18.2647 billion</NUMEX>, and the contribution to fixed
costs (or to institutional costs) as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13.7341 billion</NUMEX>. The
contribution is defined as the difference between total revenue and
total marginal cost. If this initial position is assumed to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breakeven</ENAMEX> position, then any other breakeven position must have
this same contribution.
Note that the demand equations shown above are somewhat
different from those normally encountered. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Equation</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> term in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vb</ENAMEX> equation contains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pb</ENAMEX>, so when Pb changes,
the discount is affected. The exponent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pb</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Equation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>), then,
is not a traditional elasticity; rather, it is an elasticity for
changes in own-price when the discount remains unchanged, referred
to in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> as a no-shift elasticity. In order for the
discount to remain unchanged when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pb</ENAMEX> is changed, the price of the
workshare category must be changed in an amount exactly equal to
gDPb, as made clear by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>). Note also that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) have the characteristic that ¶Vb<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/¶D = -¶Vws/¶D</ENAMEX> for each
observation point, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1996.14</NUMEX>
As a check, I wanted to have a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> model available. The
models presented above can be converted for this purpose into more
traditional models, with ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elasticities</ENAMEX> and cross
elasticities, with the same characteristics at the current
position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Substituting Equation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
yields:
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.189</NUMEX> (
Pb - <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pws</ENAMEX>)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.164</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vb</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28.572</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.289</NUMEX> (
Pb - <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pws</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.227</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ws</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51.034</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pws</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> These are the costs as reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. During
rate cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate Commission</ENAMEX> has sometimes made
adjustments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> costing. It is doubtful that using
adjusted costs would change the nature of the results obtained. 14
This characteristic is a symmetry condition imposed in the
econometrics as the demand equations were developed.
For the own-price elasticities in a traditional model, we need
respectively:

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">¶</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V Pbeb =¶ Pb b Vb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)
VP

ws ws

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ws ¶</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P V</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>)
ws ws
For the cross elasticities (ce) in a traditional model, we
need:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">¶</ENAMEX> VP
b ws
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ceb = ¶Pws Vb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">¶ V Pb</ENAMEX>
ws
ce ws =¶ PV (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX>)
b ws
If the partial derivatives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">substituted into Equations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) - (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX>), we get:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eb</ENAMEX> =-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">189.0</NUMEX> +-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gPb</ENAMEX> =-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1074</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g P -P</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>)
b ws
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227</NUMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> P
ws

ws -= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">289</NUMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> --= <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3328</TIMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX>)
g-P

b ws

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164</NUMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>
ws
ceb -= = <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7544</TIMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13</NUMEX>)
g-P

b ws
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227</NUMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cews</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pb -P</ENAMEX> = <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2707</TIMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14</NUMEX>)
g

b ws
Putting these into a traditional model with a constant
appropriate to the current position yields:
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1074</NUMEX> Pws0.7554

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vb</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50.6501</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pb</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX>)
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3328</NUMEX> Pb1.2707



<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ws</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23.1120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pws</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>)
To those who are conditioned to thinking of the demand for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class Mail</ENAMEX> as being rather inelastic, the elasticity, for
example, of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-1.1074</NUMEX> may seem high. The reason, however, is clear.
If the price of basic mail is incresed and the price of workshared
mail is held constant, the discount will increase automatically and
volume will decline for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) because the price is
higher, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> will reduce usage and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) because the
discount is higher, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> will decide to workshare and
will leave basic.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Equation</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX>), an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pws</ENAMEX> amounts to a decrease in
the discount, causing workshared mail to stop worksharing and shift
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vb</ENAMEX>. There is clearly a symmetry between changing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pws</ENAMEX> in the Vb
equation and changing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pb</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vws</ENAMEX> equation. Note, however, that
the cross-elasticities stop short of obeying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slutsky-Schultz</ENAMEX>
condition. This is because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>), which shows that a
change in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pb</ENAMEX> and a change in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pws</ENAMEX> do not have the same effect on the
discount.
We now have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> models that are equivalent at the current
position. Equations
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) are derived from the testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thress</ENAMEX> and
will be referred to as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thress</ENAMEX> equations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equations</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX>) and (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) are the more traditional constant
elasticity equations and will be referred to as the eXe (pronounced
e-cross<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-e</ENAMEX>) model or the eXe equations. Although built to have the
same characteristics at the current operating point, they
characterize sightly different behavior as we move away from the
current point.
These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> represent whatever it is that mailers think about
when they decide how much to mail and whether to presort. The
mailers know their costs, their options, their preferences, and
their other interests, such as service. Note that as the discount
increases, more and more mailers workshare. This provides an upward
sloping supply of workshared mail. In the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thress</ENAMEX> equation,
the discount going from its current level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0¢</NUMEX> up to a level of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0¢</NUMEX>, with no change in the basic price, causes the basic volume to
go from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">54.1 billion</NUMEX> down to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">52.7495 billion</NUMEX>. Thus, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1-cent</NUMEX>
increase in the discount causes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 2.5%</NUMEX> of the basic volume to
shift to presort. If anything, at least to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, this seems
on the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX>.
These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> have been constructed to represent the system in
the neighborhood of the current operating point. They should make
good predictions for small or moderate changes about the current
point. Without going too far, the directions of change, the general
magnitudes of changes, and the patterns representing the rates of
change should be meaningful. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> general kinds of changes will be
considered in this part of the paper. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> involves holding
the price of the basic category constant and changing the discount.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> involves keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> at breakeven while
the discount is changed. In both cases, attention will focus on
welfare levels and technical efficiency. Part III of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> will
consider changes outside the neighborhood of the current operating
point.
When cross elasticities are weak or non-existent, welfare
changes can be calculated from areas under simple demand curves.
When cross elasticities are strong, however, the demand curves
shift. Since the models being used here are characterized by strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX> elasticities, it was necessary to develop a method of dealing
with the shifting curves and with mailers that shift toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worksharing</ENAMEX> when the discounts increase. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> explored
several methods of estimating the effects involved. Several
decisions had to be made about how various adjustments would be
handled. In most cases, the results are relatively robust to the
decisions made.
The approach taken is based on the assumption that mailer
decisions on whether to engage in additional worksharing are based
entirely on the absolute level of the discount. Also, the
assumption is made that all new worksharing volume comes from basic
volume. In support of the latter assumption, it seems reasonable to
believe that potential mailers not now sending mail are not likely
well situated to find worksharing attractive at somewhat higher
discount levels than those at the base position. Another assumption
made is that the volume equations are better able to predict market
responses when one variable is changed from the base position than
when both variables are changed.
Within the framework of these assumptions, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> steps are
taken. First, the level of the discount is held constant, so that
no mailers will change their decision on whether to workshare, and
estimates are made for the basic market. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the level of the
discount is held constant and similar estimates are made for the
workshare market. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the discount is allowed to change and
estimates are made for the volume that shifts to or from being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workshared</ENAMEX>. Note that it is the volume that shifts that can be
processed by a higher or a lower cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>. Therefore, changes
in technical efficiency are based on the shifting volume. Not
necessarily in this order, these steps are described in the next
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sections.
Behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profits and Welfare</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount Changes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic</ENAMEX>
Price Held Constant.
If the prices of the basic category were regulated and precluded
from going above a certain level, as might occur under a price cap
arrangement, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> were given the freedom to
adjust the discount and therefore the workshare price, a natural
question would concern the extent to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s net
income (hereinafter often called profits) could be changed by
changing the discount, and how this change would compare with the
welfare effects on mailers. Also, a question can be asked about
technical efficiency gains and losses as work is shifted to and
from the mailers<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX> These questions can be answered with both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and the eXe model. The discount is changed directly in
the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, and by changing the price of workshared mail in
the latter. Because it is easier to think about, the discussion
will proceed as though the discount were being increased, so that
there is more worksharing. All of the equations, of course, apply
for both discount increases and decreases. Also, the discussion
will focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, with the understanding that similar
calculations can be made with the eXe model. To simplify the
discussion, we will talk about any worksharing as though the mailer
were doing it, even though the mailer might turn the work over to
another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that might be viewed as competing with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> for portions of the work) or to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor/agent</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step is to select a range of discounts from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1¢ to 11¢</NUMEX>.
This is a large neighborhood around the current level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>, but
weight need not be given to distant results. With this done, the
workshare prices (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pws</ENAMEX>) can be calculated immediately as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g Pb -D</ENAMEX>,
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pb</ENAMEX> remains at the current level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39.2¢</NUMEX>. Next, using
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>), the volume that leaves the basic category can be
calculated as the initial volume (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">54.1 billion</NUMEX>) less the volume
calculated at the current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pb</ENAMEX> and the new discount. Graphically, the
leaving shift volume appears as follows:

*
Vb Vb
15 In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, technical efficiency refers to the absolute
cost of getting a certain quantity of work done. Getting the work
done at a lower cost, regardless of who does the work, is more
efficient. Technical efficiency does not related to consumer
utility or to consumer welfare.
Values at the base (current) position are indicated by an *. The
leaving shift volume
*
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">equals Vb - Vb</ENAMEX>. A question needs to be answered about whether
the above curve is really a demand curve, since customary demand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">curves</ENAMEX> hold the prices of substitutes constant and this one holds
the discount constant. Fundamentally, a demand curve shows how a
market responds, given its preferences, to changes in price, when
other factors affecting quantity do not change. I view this demand
curve as showing how the market responds, given its preferences,
when other factors affecting volume do not change, including that
no mailer in the market may consider shifting from basic to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workshared</ENAMEX>. The curve, therefore, is customarily rich in
information about the utility the mailers in the market gain (or
lose) when the price changes. The constraint relating to shifting
will be relaxed in a separate step.
Using workshare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Equation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), a new workshared volume can be
calculated using the original workshare price and the new
discount<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graphically</ENAMEX>, the estimation appears as follows:


Vws* Vws
16 In the new position in this exercise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pws</ENAMEX> will be lower and D
will be higher. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pws</ENAMEX> is being held constant at this point in order
to focus on the shifting volume.
The difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vws</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vws</ENAMEX>* is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> estimate of the
arriving workshare shift volume, i.e., the volume that decided to
workshare under the higher discount, left the basic category, and
arrived at the workshare category. This estimate of the arriving
workshare shift volume turns out to be larger than the leaving
workshare shift volume. Such, of course, would be expected since
the shifting mailers are getting a lower price.
The equation for the basic category has prices in it, with the
understanding that the mailers look at the prices and decide how
much mail to send. As with all demand functions, the mailers are
presumed to understand that they must pay any paper, printing, and
preparation costs associated with their increased use of the mail.
The equation for the workshare category also has prices in it, and
may be presumed to model the decisions made by workshare mailers.
In addition to the costs incurred by basic mailers, however, these
mailers incur what are often referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> costs. That is,
they must incur costs to accomplish the worksharing, however they
do it. The mailers who shift from the basic category to the
workshare category face an unbalanced situation with respect to
user cost. Specifically, they go from a price requiring no user
cost to a price with a user cost. Therefore, the gain they
experience by shifting is not equal to the price difference;
rather, it is equal to the price difference less the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> cost they
experience. Throughout this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, I assume that the average user
cost for shifting mail is equal to the original discount (under
which they chose not to workshare) plus ½ of the increase in the
discount.
Comparing this estimate of the arriving shift volume to the
leaving shift volume, and assuming the shifting volume went from
the basic price (which does not change in this exercise) to a
"price" equal to the sum of the new workshare price and the user
cost, I found that the implied elasticity of the growth of the
shifting volume was generally in the neighborhood of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-2.5</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-4.0</NUMEX>.
Deciding this was unacceptably large (in absolute value), I chose
instead to increase the leaving shift volume with an elasticity of
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.189</NUMEX>, which is the elasticity <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thress</ENAMEX> found for the basic category
when the discount does not change. One could say that we are
growing the shift volume as it moves from its old (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">higher</NUMEX>) price
position to its new (lower) price position. For each discount
level, this provides an alternative estimate of the arriving shift
volumes, based on the leaving shift volume and a reasonable
attendant growth. The situation in which the shifting mailers find
themselves can be graphed as follows:
*
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pb Pws</ENAMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> cost
Pws

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VL VA</ENAMEX>
Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VL</ENAMEX> equals the leaving shift volume and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> equals the
arriving shift volume. Note that the cross-hatched trapezoid area
is the welfare gain of the shifting mailers<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> Note also that there
was no welfare effect on any other basic mailers, because they all
remained
*
at the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pb</ENAMEX> , and then the shift volume was allowed to
leave.
The new volume for the workshare category is taken to be the sum
of (a) the calculated workshared volume at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pws</ENAMEX> and the
original discount, and (b) the arriving shift volume. Graphically,
the situation is as follows:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> The areas of all trapezoid-like figures in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> are
estimated by assuming that the right-hand sides are straight
lines.

*
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vws VI</ENAMEX> Vws
Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX> (intermediate) is the volume of workshared mail that
exists at the new workshare price and the original discount, before
the shift volume arrives. The difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vws and VI</ENAMEX> is the
arriving shift volume, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, discussed above. Note that the
crosshatched trapezoid area is the welfare gain to the workshare
market, given the price decrease they experience, before the shift
volume arrives.
On the question of how much the leaving shift volume might grow,
there is another effect that needs to be mentioned, although it is
not dealt with further in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>. As worksharing discounts are
given and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> begin to compete for business and profits, it
is often believed that they might succeed in attracting more
overall volume into the system. This is sometimes called a "beat
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bushes</ENAMEX>" effect. Such would, of course, affect both postal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">service</ENAMEX> finances and mailer welfare. The basis for believing that
volume growth of this kind might occur is not only that there might
be more sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and possibly some product differentiation, but
also that these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> might be able to promote in ways that
the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> itself cannot. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, for
example, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> are convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> that delivery
service is good, while the same message coming from a postal
account <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> might not be as believable. Also, there are
sometimes restrictions for policy or appearance reasons on the ways
in which government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> such as postal services can
advertise and promote.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more adjustment is needed. The shifting volume that leaves
the basic category is in the lower price range of all the mail in
that category. Therefore, when the shifting volume leaves, the
price index for the basic category increases. Knowing that the
price being paid by the shifting volume just before it shifted was
equal to g times the basic price, a revised price index for the
basic category can be calculated. This revised price index must be
used to calculate the revenue from the basic category after the
shift volume leaves.
For each discount, the revenue and the cost at the new position
can be calculated. The difference between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is the gain in
profit for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. The welfare gain of the mailers is
the sum of the welfare gain of the shifting volume and the gain of
the workshare market before the shift volume arrives. Both of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> are cross-hatched above. The technical gain (or loss if
negative) for the new position can be calculated as the leaving
shift volume times the difference between the postal cost of doing
the work and the mailers' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> cost of doing the work. Given our
assumption that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s cost for doing the work is <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6¢,</ENAMEX>
and knowing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> cost is above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX> for all discount
increases, we can expect the gain to be negative for all discount
increases. If the discount decreases from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>, mail which mailers
have been sorting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than 6¢</TIMEX> will shift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service, and the technical gain will again be negative. These signs
on the technical gain would be expected for movements from an ECP
position.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> graphs on the next page show the profit results. The top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">graph</ENAMEX> is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and the bottom one is for the eXe
model. Several observations may be made. Given a decrease in the
discount, with the basic price held constant, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
profit increases in both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and appears in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> to
reach a peak at a discount of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2¢</NUMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2¢</TIMEX> is rather distant
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>, however, this result may not be reliable. At a discount of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4¢</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> model shows a profit increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$563 million</NUMEX> and
the eXe model shows <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$581 million</NUMEX>. In these same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases,
respectively, the technical loss from having the higher-cost person
do the work is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37 million and $29 million</NUMEX>. The technical losses,
experienced in some sense by all mailers, are clearly small


Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX> Copy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress Model</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">eXe Model</ENAMEX>


relative to the increase in profit. Note also that the slopes of
both graphs decrease in absolute value as the discount
decreases.
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ceteris-paribus</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-a-time) changes were then
investigated. First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s cost of processing
workshared mail was changed from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.6¢</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.6¢.18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX>, the
own-price elasticities in the worksharing equations were made equal
to the corresponding elasticities in the basic equations. This
removed the finding that the noshift elasticity of the workshared
mail is greater than that of basic mail. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the discount
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elasticity</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> model was doubled. When any of these
changes are made, the corresponding elasticities for the eXe model
must be found using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equations</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>) through (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, the discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">elasticity</ENAMEX> was set equal
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, with corresponding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zeros</NUMEX> in the eXe model. The findings
are summarized in the following table.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Description</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4¢</NUMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>) Profit Gain (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thress</ENAMEX> & eXe)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX>. Gain (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thress</ENAMEX> & eXe)




<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Table 1</ENAMEX>
At the current position, which involves a fixed basic price and
a worksharing discount of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>, the following observations may be
made, using figures from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thress</ENAMEX> equations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Assuming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> cost of doing the workshare work
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>, a reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2¢</NUMEX> in the worksharing discount will cause a
profit increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $563 million</NUMEX>. Due to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> The implication of this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2¢</TIMEX> reduction in the cost of
processing workshared mail is that the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> can sort the
mail for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4¢</TIMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>.
work being done by a less efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>, there would be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> technical loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $37 million</NUMEX>, which is relatively
small.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
Under the same conditions, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> cost of
doing the workshare work is actually 4¢ instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>, the profit
gain from reducing the worksharing discount by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2¢</NUMEX> would be notably
greater at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$637 million</NUMEX>, and there would be a technical gain of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
For discount decreases, the profits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
increase much more rapidly ifthe discount elasticities (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> cross elasticities) are low rather than high.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
The profit incentive for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> to decrease
the discount is less when the no-shift own-price elasticity of the
workshare category is greater than that of the basic
category.


The next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> graphs, constituting Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
profits and mailer welfare gains, as well as the sum of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> models provide results that are similar in magnitude. The
curvatures are also similar, with small differences at points quite
distant from the current discount of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>. The losses in mailer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX>, which are of course opposite in sign from the profits, are
substantially larger in magnitude than the profits. At a discount
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4¢</NUMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> gain in
profit is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$562 million</NUMEX> and the loss in mailer welfare is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$945</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> made up of triangles show the net loss or gain
of the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> curves.

Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX> Copy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0 0.02 0.04 0.06 0.08 0.1 Discount</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Dollars</NUMEX>, Current=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.06</NUMEX>
Profit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Squares</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer Welfare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Diamonds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> in
Triangles
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">eXe Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0 0.02 0.04 0.06 0.08 0.1 0.12</NUMEX>
Discount in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Dollars</NUMEX>, Current=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.06</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Squares</ENAMEX>, Mailer
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Welfare in Diamonds, Net Gain in Triangles</ENAMEX>


FIGURE <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
Behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Welfare Levels with Discount Changes</ENAMEX>, Under
Breakeven
The next step is to relax the constraint that the basic price is
fixed and to allow discount changes with the requirement that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> remain at breakeven. Due to insoluble algebra, a
simultaneous solution is not possible. Short of that, the
preference would be to select D, express <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pb</ENAMEX> in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pws</ENAMEX> ,
and then express <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pws</ENAMEX> in terms of the desired net revenue (taken to
be the same as the net revenue at the base position- hence
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breakeven</ENAMEX>). This, however, is circular and, although convergence
was sometimes obtained after a number of iterations, the procedure
was found, for the most part, to be unworkable and sometimes
unstable.
In the alternative, the procedure adopted was to select D,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express Pb</ENAMEX> in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pws</ENAMEX>, and to use the backsolver routine
provided in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lotus 1-2-3</ENAMEX> to hunt for the value of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pws</ENAMEX> that yields
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breakeven</ENAMEX>. Within this approach, a number of steps were needed, as
will be explained.
Given the new discount selected, the leaving shift volume can be
calculated in the same way as in the above example on profits. The
next step is to recognize that since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pb</ENAMEX> will be changing in this
case, to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breakeven</ENAMEX>, there will be a change in welfare in the
basic market. The following graph shows the basic market, before
the shift volume is allowed to leave.

*
Vb Vb
This is a demand curve, conditional on the constraint that the
discount remains the same, under which condition no mailers will
shift to workshared. The crosshatched trapezoid is the welfare loss
to these mailers as a market, given that they cannot shift.
The welfare effects on the mailers who shift are calculated in
the same way as in the above section on profits. The shift volume
is allowed to grow according to an ownprice elasticity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-0.189</NUMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> costs are estimated in the same way. Also, the welfare
effects in the workshare market are calculated in the same way as
before.
For discount increases (and conversely for discount decreases),
the net welfare is the sum of: (a) the reduction in welfare of the
basic market, before the shift volume leaves, (b) the increase in
welfare of the shifting volume, and (c) the increase in welfare of
the workshare market, before the shift volume arrives. The
technical cost effects, due to the work being done by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that
may do it at a higher cost, are also calculated in the same way as
before. That is, the leaving shift volume, before it grows, is
multiplied by the difference in the cost of doing the work.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> shows the basic results for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> models. The lines
composed of boxes show the welfare level of all mailers combined
and the lines composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX> show the technical losses (if
negative) of shifting the work to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> shows the
supply curve of workshare services. In traditional form, it has the
discount on the vertical axis.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, considerable attention is given to setting
the worksharing discounts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> approaches are often discussed. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the subclass approach and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is the rate category
approach. In the subclass approach, the basic and the workshare
category are each given a percentage markup over cost, in order to
obtain their average rate. As a simple example, suppose the cost of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worksharing</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10¢</NUMEX> and the cost of basic mail is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16¢</NUMEX>. If each is
given a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> markup, the average rate levels will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15¢ and 24¢</NUMEX>,
respectively. In this case, the rate difference is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9¢</NUMEX>, which is
equal to the cost difference of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX> inflated by the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> markup.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welf are in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">eXe Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welf are in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FIGURE 3 Change in Discount, Breakeven Maintained</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 354045</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quantity Supplied in Billions</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">eXe Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 354045</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quantity Supplied in Billions</ENAMEX>
FIGURE <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
In the rate category approach, the difference in the rates for
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories is based on the cost difference. Assuming <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>
passthrough of the cost difference, which is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX> in this example,
the rate difference would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>. Handled in this way, the rates
might turn out to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17¢ and 23¢</NUMEX>. As discussions concerning rate
setting occur, considerable attention is given to selecting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passthrough</ENAMEX>. The (adjustable) assumption of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s cost for doing the workshare work is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX> and that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> of this 6¢ is passed through into rates. If the passthrough
were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 100%</NUMEX>, a result for which some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> argue, the discount
would be larger and we would say that we are moving from rate
category treatment toward subclass treatment. If the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> subclasses
were given different proportionate markups, rather than the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markups</ENAMEX> in the example just completed, the comparisons would not be
so simple.
In Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, it is clear that as the discount level is
increased, implying a passthrough of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 100%</NUMEX>, the general welfare
level increases, but at a declining rate. The curves of both models
appear to reach a maximum at a discount of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 8¢</NUMEX>. At the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8¢</NUMEX>
level, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> model shows a welfare gain of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32 million</NUMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eXe</ENAMEX> model of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27 million</NUMEX>. At the same time, they show technical
losses, respectively, of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million and $29 million</NUMEX>.
It is interesting to look at the makeup of these welfare gains.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, at the discount level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8¢</NUMEX> and the net gain
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32 million</NUMEX>, the basic market incurs a welfare loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$480</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.89¢</NUMEX> per piece), the workshare market realizes a gain of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$487 million</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.23¢</NUMEX> per piece), and the mailers who shift gain <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.0¢</NUMEX> per piece). The volume of mail shifting is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.493</NUMEX>
billion leaving basic and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.507</NUMEX> arriving at the workshare category.
This is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 4.6%</NUMEX> of the basic volume. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8¢</ENAMEX> discount level,
the overall volume in the system, basic plus workshared, increases
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.69%</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Bernstein</ENAMEX>, testifying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Docket No. R971</ENAMEX>, prepared estimates of welfare gains under more
efficient worksharing discounts<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.19</NUMEX> His analysis left some questions
unanswered but pointed to efficient discounts well above the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8¢</NUMEX>
level and to gains on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hundred million dollars</NUMEX>.
Compared to his
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Directt Testimony</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Bernstein</ENAMEX> on Behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States Postal Service</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USPS-T-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Docket No. R97-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Rate</ENAMEX>
Commission, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 93</ENAMEX>.
estimates, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8¢</NUMEX> level seems small, as does the gain of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. In fact, the gain of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32 million</NUMEX> is small by almost any
standard. Furthermore, achieving it places a burden on basic
mailers of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$480 million</NUMEX>, which is notably large by almost any
standard. In terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pareto</ENAMEX> optimality, it appears that a change
from the current position imposes large losses on some mailers,
large gains on others, and relatively small net gains.
The supply curves of workshare services, shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, are
less informative. Assuming they are valid around the current
discount level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX>, they clearly show a good deal of sensitivity
to the discount. At low discounts, however, they still show more
volume than might be expected; and at high discount levels, they
show supply levels which are not as large as might be expected.
A matter of considerable discussion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
concerns whether the (noshift) own-price elasticity of workshared
volume is greater than that of basic volume, as these two
categories are now constituted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress</ENAMEX> model suggests that if
the discount remains unchanged, and thus that shifting is not
allowed, the elasticity of basic volume is negative <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.189</NUMEX> and of
workshared volume is negative <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.289</NUMEX>. Prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thress</ENAMEX>' work,
information of this kind was not available. A natural question
becomes: how sensitive are the results to differences in the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elasticities</ENAMEX>? Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> shows the basic curves for a situation where
both no-shift elasticities are the same at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-0.189</NUMEX>. It is clear that
the efficient discount moves closer to the cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6¢</NUMEX> and
that the welfare gains become much smaller. Specifically, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, the peak occurs at a discount of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7¢</NUMEX> and the welfare
gain is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $6 million</NUMEX>. The conclusion, then, is influenced
strongly by whether the workshare category is more elastic.
The discussion surrounding rate category versus subclass status
often focuses on the strength of the cross elasticities. In order
to shed some light on this question, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> special runs on cross
elasticities were done. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> shows the curves for a situation
where the discount and cross elasticities are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> for
when the discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">elasticities</ENAMEX> are doubled, and Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> for when
the discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">elasticities</ENAMEX> are doubled and the two no-shift
elasticities are equal to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-0.189</NUMEX>. Note that some of the scales on
the vertical axes are different on these plots.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welf are in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">eXe Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welf are in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FIGURE 5 No-Shift Easticities of Basic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workshare</ENAMEX> equal at
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.189</NUMEX>
The pattern shown by these graphs is clear. When the cross
elasticities are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, substantial welfare gains are available from
discounts larger than 6¢ and the optimal discount appears to be
well above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8¢</NUMEX>. As the cross elasticities become larger, the
efficient discount levels move closer to the ECP level and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> welfare gains available become quite small<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20</NUMEX> And, when
the no-shift elasticities of the basic and workshared product are
the same, the gains become even smaller and the peak becomes very
pronounced.
These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are good only for small to moderate movements from
the current position. For larger movements, a somewhat different
approach is taken, beginning in the next section.
20 Recall that under the assumptions made in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, setting
the discount at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 cents</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECP</ENAMEX> position, where <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 cents</NUMEX> is the
cost savings at the margin.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welf are in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">eXe Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welf are in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FIGURE 6 Discount</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cross Elasticities</ENAMEX> are Zero
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welf are in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">eXe Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welf are in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FIGURE 7 Discount Elasticity</ENAMEX> is Doubled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thress Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welf are in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">eXe Model</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 4 6 81012</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cents/Piece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Level</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>
Welfare in boxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Eff</ENAMEX>. in diamonds


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FIGURE 8 Discount Elasticities are Doubled and No-Shift</ENAMEX>
Easticities are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal</ENAMEX>
39



Part III: Some Broader Questions
The advocacy of a worksharing program may be viewed in broader
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> from a base equilibrium position of no worksharing
program being offered. Then the question becomes: what would happen
if the basic price were held constant and a worksharing program
were begun? The previous section asked only about making changes to
an existing program, and a well developed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at that.
If no worksharing discounts were being offered, it is possible
that some mailers would still workshare. They could feel that the
cost of the worksharing is small and that they receive an
improvement in service. This could happen in presorting. Another
possibility is that they are worksharing without doing anything
extra, such as in achieving drop shipment because they are already
located at the destination.
Consider a program of discounts for presortation. Initially, as
a conservative starting point, suppose the postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> is at
breakeven with no discounts and no presort volume. Since many
mailers have computerized mailing systems in place and have
sufficient volume, they can do presorting work at a very low cost.
Without hard evidence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> believes that a presort discount
of ¾ of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a cent</NUMEX> might induce <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as many as 20 billion presorted</NUMEX> pieces.
This is shown in the supply curve in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.

