



<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">TABLE 1</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">EFFECT OF REPLACING TERMINAL DUES WITH DOMESTIC POSTAGE ON THE</ENAMEX>
FINANCES <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OF INDUSTRIALIZED AND DEVELOPING COUNTRIES AND THE POSTAL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERVICE</ENAMEX> (Amounts in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX>)

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FY 2000 Adjusted to Reflect Terminal Dues System</ENAMEX> Based on
Domestic Postage
4Payments from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPAs</ENAMEX> for the Delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> Outbound
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mail 4/ 8/ 5</ENAMEX> FPA Payments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delivery of Foreign</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Origin Inbound Mail</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5/ 9/ 6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service Net Terminal Dues</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L.4 - L.5</ENAMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$153,922</NUMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,979</NUMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$172,900</NUMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> Estimated Change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service Net Terminal Dues</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">- L.3</ENAMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$109,249</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,159</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59,090</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Postal</ENAMEX>
Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1/ FY 2000</ENAMEX> terminal dues essentially reflect the
current terminal dues system, except for
the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 %</NUMEX> surcharge on payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> that go into a common
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> to be used
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> for improvements to quality of service. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2/ WT 13</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">4</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3/ WT 11</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Col. 1, L. 1 / 1000</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4/ WT 13</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5/</NUMEX> WT
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11, Col. 1, L. 2 / 1000</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6/ WT 13</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">4</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7/ WT 11</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">2</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 1 / 1000</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8/ WT 13</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9/ WT 11</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Col</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2, L. 2 /</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPAs</ENAMEX> were to pay each other
terminal dues applying full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class mail rates to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC</ENAMEX> and AO
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mail</ENAMEX> exchanged, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> would both pay and receive
substantially larger sums. It should be noted, however, that the
Commission has not analyzed the impact of price elasticity on the
volumes of inbound and outbound mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> shows that
under a domestic postage-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>
would have paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$172.9 million</NUMEX> more in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> than it collected,
an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59.1 million</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">See line7,</ENAMEX> column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> further
shows that the total payments to industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> would
increase from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million to $ million</NUMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">118 percent</NUMEX> increase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">In</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">column 1</ENAMEX>, compare line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC</ENAMEX> payments to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> would increase from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million to $ million</NUMEX>.
(In column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, compare line 2 and line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). The balance of outbound
and inbound accounts would change from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-$44.7 million to -$153.9</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, implying an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$109.2 million</NUMEX> in international
mail expenses (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">See</ENAMEX> column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, lines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3, 6</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>).
and combined would account for percent of the increase in the IC
terminal dues net balance. would account for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million</NUMEX> and would
account for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million</NUMEX>. This is due partly to the relatively high
domestic rates for these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> domestic
rates and partly to the disparity in the mail volumes exchanged
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. and are among the three
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> outbound mail, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> being . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
outbound mail to and exceeds the inbound mail from each of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a -to-one</NUMEX> ratio. Thus, the imbalance in the
volume of mail exchanged magnifies the effect of the relatively
higher rates in these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. actually sent more mail to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> than it received.
Basing terminal dues on domestic postage would have the opposite
effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of mail with developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Table 1</ENAMEX>
shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> would increase
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million to $ million</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In</ENAMEX> column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, compare line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to line
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), while <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> payments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> would increase
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million to $ million</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In</ENAMEX> column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, compare line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to line
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). Thus, the expenses associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of
international mail to and from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> would decrease by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $50.2</NUMEX>
million under a domestic postage-based terminal dues system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">See</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">column 2,</ENAMEX> line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>).
Overall, considering both the negative effect on expenses
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICs</ENAMEX> and the positive
effect on expenses associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of mail to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX>, the
implication of this analysis is that a switch from the terminal
dues system in effect in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> to a domestic postage-based system
would have a negative effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $59.1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Column 3</ENAMEX>, line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). This amount represents <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.4 percent</NUMEX> of
the revenues raised from international postage rates applicable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AO</ENAMEX> mail dispatched to foreign postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>
(excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>). This result is valid to the extent that the
assumptions concerning the weight profile of the mail, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applicability of First-Class</ENAMEX> rates to such mail, are valid.
In addition it should be noted that the terminal dues changed on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2001</TIMEX>. The terminal dues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>
paid to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICs</ENAMEX> and collected from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICs</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FY 2000</ENAMEX> essentially equal
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal dues</ENAMEX> in effect on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2001</TIMEX>. However, the
terminal dues between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICs</ENAMEX> will increase gradually over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a three-year</TIMEX>
period, implying different results for subsequent periods. Another
change beginning on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2001</TIMEX> is a new <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX> surcharge
on payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monies</ENAMEX> generated by the surcharge
flow into a common pool to be parceled out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPU</ENAMEX> for
quality of service improvements. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> chose the actual FY
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> results as a convenient benchmark for measuring the effect of
a domestic postage-based terminal dues system. For this reason, FY
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> actual results were not restated to reflect the effect of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surcharge</ENAMEX>. However, the effect is relatively easy to calculate.
The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX> surcharge would have added <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million</NUMEX> to the FY
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> terminal dues cost (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5%</NUMEX> x <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million</NUMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, line <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">column 2</ENAMEX> and column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. This would also increase line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3</TIMEX>, columns 2
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million</NUMEX>. Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> net
terminal dues shown at line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3</TIMEX>, column 3 would increase by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million</NUMEX>
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ to $</NUMEX> . Since the surcharge would not apply in the "domestic
postage" scenario, none of the figures in lines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 to 7</TIMEX> would
change. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7</TIMEX>, column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> shows the difference between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s actual net terminal dues in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-$113.8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>) and if the terminal dues in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> had been based on
domestic postage (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-$172.9 million</NUMEX>). The difference is -<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59.1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. Since the
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX> surcharge on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> payments would have decreased the FY
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> net terminal dues to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-$</NUMEX> , this also would reduce the net
balance under a domestic postage-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-$59.1 million</NUMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-$172.9 minus -$113.8</NUMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-$ million</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-$172.9 minus - $</NUMEX> ).
Effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cost Coverage and Institutional Cost Contribution</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> below displays the revenue, attributable cost, contribution
to institutional cost, and cost coverage for (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) actual FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> adjusted to reflect a domestic postage-based payment
system for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of mail among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. It should be noted
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> includes the revenues and attributable costs for the
volume of mail exchanged between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
even though this study did not consider a change in terminal dues
rates with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> is the largest market for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
International mail.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">TABLE 2</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">EFFECT OF REPLACING TERMINAL DUES WITH DOMESTIC POSTAGE ON</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL MAIL'S CONTRIBUTION TO INSTITUTIONAL COST AND COST</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">COVERAGE</ENAMEX> (Amounts in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2000 1/ Incremental Outbound Inbound Cost</ENAMEX> Total
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)=(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)+(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)+(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Revenue 2 Attributable Cost 3 Contibution</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional</ENAMEX>
Cost 4Cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coverage</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,486 $291 -$1,777 $1,030 $322 $50 $1,402 $456</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31</NUMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$375</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">144.3% 90.4% -126.7%</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FY 2000 Assuming Domestic Postage Replaces Current Terminal Dues</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2/ Incremental Outbound Inbound Cost</ENAMEX> Total
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>)=(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)+(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)+(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Revenue <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,486</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4/ 6 Attributable</ENAMEX> Cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/ $322 $50</NUMEX> 7
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contibution</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Cost</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$316</NUMEX> 8Cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coverage</ENAMEX>
-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">119.8%</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1/ Postal rate Commission</ENAMEX> Report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Volumes</ENAMEX>, Costs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revenues</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.42,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table IV-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lines</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, as applicable.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2/ For Columns 5</ENAMEX> though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, the only amounts that change in lines
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 & 2</ENAMEX>, compared to columns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>, are outbound
attributable cost and inbound revenue. Contribution and cost
coverage change to reflect those differences.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3/ Col. 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Col. 5, L.1 / 1000</ENAMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WT 13, Col. 5, L.4</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/ 1000 4/ Col. 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> 3/ 1,000,000
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> shows that in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, outbound mail had a
contribution to institutional costs of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$456 million</NUMEX>. The
corresponding amount for inbound mail was a negative <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31 million</NUMEX>.
It should be noted that this raises an important policy issue.
Inbound mail could be viewed as a subclass of mail. By law,
subclasses of domestic mail must produce revenues equal to or
exceeding attributable costs.
International mail as a whole produced a contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$375</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. Lines <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8</TIMEX> show the effect of changing the method
of payment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC/AO</ENAMEX> mail between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and all
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPAs</ENAMEX>. Changing the terminal dues system affects the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s inbound revenues and its outbound attributable
costs. Thus comparing line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>, column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5</TIMEX>, column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, shows
that inbound revenues increased from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$291 million to $ million</NUMEX>,
while comparing line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6</TIMEX>, column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> shows that
attributable costs increased from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,030 million to $ million</NUMEX>. The
net effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s international mail finances
is to reduce the contribution to institutional costs from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$375</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$316 million</NUMEX>, a reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59 million</NUMEX>. This amount
reflects the net increase in the terminal dues net balance that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> would experience under a domestic postage-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, as expected (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">See</ENAMEX> table <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, Column 3, Line 7</ENAMEX>). It should be
noted that had the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX> surcharge on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> terminal dues been
in effect in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, the contribution under the current terminal
dues system would have been <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million</NUMEX> lower and the reduction in
contribution from shifting to a domestic postage-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> would
be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ million</NUMEX> compared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59 million</NUMEX> above.
The cost coverage for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> outbound mail, without considering
the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX> surcharge, would be reduced from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">144.3 percent</NUMEX> to
percent and the cost coverage for inbound mail would increase from
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90.4 percent to percent</NUMEX>. Combining outbound and inbound mail, and
including incremental costs would result in an overall cost
coverage of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">119.8 percent</NUMEX> compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> cost coverage of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">126.7 percent</NUMEX>.
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> wanted to recover the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59 million</NUMEX> in
lost contribution, it could increase the rates on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">outbound LC</ENAMEX>/AO
mail, excluding outbound rates to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX>.
Alternatively, if it wanted to maintain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> overall cost
coverage of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">126.7 percent</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> could increase
those same rates by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 13.9 percent</NUMEX>. There are, of course,
other contribution or cost coverage goals that could be
selected.
Reliability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis.</ENAMEX> There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> critical inputs to
this analysis: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the distribution of outbound mail by weight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interval</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the distribution of inbound mail by weight interval,
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> domestic postage rates, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) FPA
domestic postage rates.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distribution of Outbound Mail</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weight Interval</ENAMEX>. Like the
rates of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>, the domestic postage rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPAs</ENAMEX> vary by
weight interval. Thus, the analysis requires a distribution of
outbound mail by weight interval. As part of its annual submission
of data and workpapers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> to support the
Commission's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Mail</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal</ENAMEX>
Service provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> billing determinant data for outbound
mail. This data include volumes by the weight intervals associated
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s rates for outbound international
mail. Because the data are not maintained by individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
except for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, it was not possible to develop a
weight interval distribution for outbound mail unique to each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">destination FPA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, therefore, assumed that the weight
interval distribution for all outbound mail sent to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPAs</ENAMEX>,
excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, was a reasonable proxy for the weight interval
distribution for mail sent to each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPA</ENAMEX>. This distribution is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to the actual number of pieces sent to each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in FY
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Thus, distortion could enter the analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> outbound
mail if there are differences between the proxy distribution and
the actual distribution. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> believes it unlikely that
this would have a meaningful impact on the calculation of terminal
dues based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPA</ENAMEX> domestic rates.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distribution of Inbound Mailby Weight Interval</ENAMEX>. The analysis
also requires a distribution of piece volumes by weight interval
for inbound mail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, by a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmaster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>, requested this distribution from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> responded that the information does not exist.
However the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> did provide as much detail as is
collected a volume distribution by transportation mode and shape
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
In the absence of data showing the weight distribution of
inbound mail, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> employed, as a proxy distribution,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> postal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> in the course of
preparing a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal dues system</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> system, called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REIMS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>, relates terminal dues to domestic postage.
This distribution represents the aggregate distribution for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REIMS</ENAMEX> II <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REIMS</ENAMEX> II <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are all industrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, so the distribution is likely a reasonable approximation
for mail received by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> from industrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
Developing a distribution for inbound mail from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> is more
problematic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> was not able to obtain any data on
developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Generally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC</ENAMEX> mail is lighter than AO mail.
Further, studies by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Postal Union</ENAMEX> indicate that the
average weight for each shape (envelope, flat, packet) of mail sent
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICs</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 to 30 percent</NUMEX> less than the average weight of
mail from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICs</ENAMEX>. Hence, it appears likely that the proportion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AO</ENAMEX> mail is less for inbound mail than for outbound. In the
absence of specific data, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> assumed that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REIMS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> data would be a reasonable proxy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> also. This
assumption seems likely to result in an overstatement of the
domestic postage that would be collected on inbound mail. The
magnitude of the overstatement cannot be estimated with
confidence.
As noted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">REIMS II</ENAMEX> data was separated by shape: letters,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flats</ENAMEX>, and small packets. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s
available inbound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC/AO</ENAMEX> volume data is reported separately for
surface and air, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> applied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REIMS</ENAMEX> II
distributions. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air LC/AO</ENAMEX> mail, the distribution for all shapes
was used because inbound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air LC/AO</ENAMEX> contains all shapes. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surface</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC/AO</ENAMEX> mail, the distribution for flats and small packets combined
was used for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. First, the volume of inbound surface
letters is negligible. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the average weight per piece was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.9</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ounces in FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. This implies that the surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mailstream</ENAMEX> is
composed of flats and small packets. These distribution keys appear
to reasonably reflect the distribution of inbound of mail, subject
to the caveats above.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">REIMS II</ENAMEX> data did not identify the volume of cards. Because
there are inbound cards, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> assumed that the
relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> outbound cards and the total volume of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outbound Air LC/AO</ENAMEX> mail applies to inbound mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air LC/AO</ENAMEX>. The
reasonableness of the assumption is unknown.
The Selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> PostalService Domestic Rates. Based on
field observations and some discussions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>
field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> determined that no inbound mail
would be likely to meet the eligibility requirements for domestic
bulk business rates. Thus any inbound mail piece would pay the
First-Class rate, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priority Mail</ENAMEX> rate for items weighing more
than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13 ounces</NUMEX>. Although inbound books and records might be
eligible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Mail</ENAMEX> rates, the amount of this mail is
minimal. For these reasons, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has applied the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>'s domestic rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class and Priority Mail</ENAMEX>
to the inbound mail distribution described above. Of course, if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> made available domestic bulk business rates to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPAs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPAs</ENAMEX> might prepare inbound mail so that it would meet the
eligibility requirements. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s analysis does not take
into account this possibility. However, because the discounts for
bulk mail are cost based, any lost revenues should be offset by
corresponding reduced costs.
The Selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPA</ENAMEX> Domestic Rates. To obtain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPA</ENAMEX> domestic
rates, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> used the available FPA web sites. The
Commission identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> with rates for industrial countries
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> with rates for developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service First-Class/</ENAMEX>Priority Rates were applied to inbound
mail, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> tried to identify the corresponding rates for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPAs</ENAMEX>. Identifying these rates was problematic because many
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> do not have First-Class rates for heavy mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outbound LC/AO</ENAMEX> mail weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 22 pounds</NUMEX>. To fill the gap in
missing FPA rates, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> calculated an extra ounce rate
between the two highest weight intervals for which there were
rates. (The difference between the rates divided by the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grams</ENAMEX> in the weight interval). The proportion of volume covered by
this extrapolation procedure ranges from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
percent. Although this approach seems reasonable, there is a
potential for substantial overstatement or understatement because
the amount of estimated domestic postage-based terminal dues
calculated under this procedure represents <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> of total IC
payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FPAs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX> of total <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> payments. The potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distortion</ENAMEX> is unquantifiable at this time.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> also assumed that the average revenue per piece
for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> whose rates were available applied
to the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICs</ENAMEX> whose rates were not available. Similarly,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> assumed that the average revenue per piece for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with available rates applied to the remaining
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">203 DCs</TIMEX> without available rates. The latter assumption is probably
weak, but there is currently no way to improve upon it.
Potential <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Improvements</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Study</ENAMEX>. In this study, the
Commission has sought to provide its best estimates within the time
provided. The analysis so far suggests the following possibilities
for further study:
Industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. First, it would be to desirable to
develop a separate estimate of the international mail revenues
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with outbound IC mail. This would allow an estimate of
the effect on international postage rates of shifting to domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">postage</ENAMEX>-based terminal dues in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of mail between
industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The use of domestic postage-based
terminal dues appears most feasible among industrialized
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it would be informative to divide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC</ENAMEX> mail exchange
into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AO</ENAMEX> components. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC</ENAMEX> mail is the most profitable mail and
the mail to which First-Class domestic postage rates are most
likely to be applicable in the future. It seems likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
and foreign mailers would prepare AO mail so that it would qualify
for lower domestic rates applicable to printed matter and/or lower
priority delivery. Hence, a separate estimate of the financial
effects of shifting from terminal dues to domestic postage rates
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC</ENAMEX> mail is likely to identify the most significant, persistent,
and predicable effects of a shift to domestic postagebased terminal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dues</ENAMEX>. To divide IC mail into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AO</ENAMEX> components, we need further
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> or to make additional assumptions.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, our estimate of the revenue from inbound IC mail could be
improved by a specific study of the weight distribution of inbound
mail received from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC FPAs</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of mail. Our use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REIMS</ENAMEX> II
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> as a proxy for this distribution appears plausible, but no
more.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, we need to obtain the domestic postage rates for New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zealand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the only significant outbound IC mail flows
omitted from this analysis.
Developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The first improvement needed in regard to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> mail is a specific study providing the weight distribution of
inbound mail received from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC FPAs</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of mail. This would
allow a plausible estimate of the revenue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX> would
receive by applying domestic postage rates to such mail. Our use of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REIMS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> data as a proxy for this distribution was necessary, but
not realistic.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, further work would likely allow us to develop, for a
higher percentage of outbound <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> mail, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) estimates of the
domestic postage costs that would be incurred if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>
paid domestic postage instead of terminal dues and, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the
outbound mail revenues associated with such mail flows. In this
effort, we would anticipate focusing on the most significant postal
destinations among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> rather than trying to analyze each and
every destinating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is attaching a disk with the electronic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spreadsheets</ENAMEX> and a hard copy explanation of the procedures used.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> considers the terminal dues amounts
contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> commercially sensitive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> also considers the data in the electronic spreadsheets
commercially sensitive because they contain country-specific data.
If you have any questions, please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Cohen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202-789-6850</ENAMEX>)
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Robinson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202-789-6854</ENAMEX>).
With best wishes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Omas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice Chairman</ENAMEX>



