



Changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household</ENAMEX>-Level Demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Delivery</ENAMEX>
Services from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986 to 1994</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank A. Wolak Department of Economics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University</ENAMEX>
Motivation-Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> there has been an dramatic
increase in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Available modes of interpersonal communication and
the range in quality of these modes of communication in terms
speed, reliability, and flexibility <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Reductions in the price of
these modes of communication-long-distance telephone service, FAX
machines, on-line information services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CompuServe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Online</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> price for incremental messages)
Many of these modes of communication are very attractive
alternatives to traditional postal delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> supplied by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Postal Service</ENAMEX> (USPS).
Particularly true for household sector-E-mail, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic</ENAMEX> bill
paying, FAX, long-distance call

Total pieces delivered and mail revenues have continued to
increase

Percentages by volume in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">First-Class</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Mail</ENAMEX> A
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Formerly Third Class</ENAMEX>)--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Periodicals</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>, All others--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Mail</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A-Primarily</ENAMEX> advertising circulars and mail-order
catalogues-comprises an increasing share of pieces delivered
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37.5%</NUMEX> of pieces delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX> of pieces delivered in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1993 to 1994</TIMEX>, single-piece <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First-Class</ENAMEX> volume fell by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>
percent, but a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.8 percent</NUMEX> increase in pre-sorted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class
volume resulted in a net <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.4 percent</NUMEX> increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">First-Class</ENAMEX>
volume. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1994 to 1995</TIMEX>, single-piece fell by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0 percent</NUMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1995-1996</TIMEX> it fell by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX>.
This event appears to signal a leveling-off or decline in
household-level use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> postal delivery services


Purpose of Talk
Reconcile growth in aggregate pieces delivered and mail revenues
with increasing relative price of postal delivery services and
growing number of substitutes at household level
Are household sector trends consistent with aggregate
trends?
Quantify decline in aggregate household sector postage
consumption.
Determine the relative extent to which the decline in household
sector
consumption over time can be attributed to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Increasing penetration of alternative modes of
communication
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Increasing relative price of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> postal delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>


Specific Questions Addressed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) What has happened to the average household-level consumption
and aggregate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Population</ENAMEX>) household consumption of postal
delivery services over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) What are own-price, cross-price and expenditure elasticities
of the household-level demand for postal delivery services and how
have they changed over time?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) What is the impact of home computing technology on postal
demand?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) What household characteristics predict differences in
household-level postal demand?


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aggregate Household Consumption of Postal Delivery</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Labor Statistics</ENAMEX> (BLS) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Expenditure Survey</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CES</ENAMEX>). A national probability sample of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. Sampling frame
generated from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-percent detail file.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> surveys administered to different samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarterly</TIMEX> Interview Survey and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diary Survey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diary Survey</ENAMEX>-Each selected household is requested to keep two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-week</TIMEX> diaries of all expenditures over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">consecutive weeks</TIMEX>. Source
for householdlevel postage expenditures and other non-durable goods
expenditures.
Interview Survey-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household</ENAMEX> is interviewed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every three months</TIMEX>
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 15month</TIMEX> period. Questions about durables holdings--<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>,
housing, and personal computers.
Both surveys collect information on household
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">characteristics-hours</TIMEX> of work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, occupation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, age and race of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, marital status,
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, dwelling type, income, and census region of
residence.
For each household in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diary Survey</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986 to 1994</TIMEX>, BLS
computes a sampling weight giving the representativeness of that
household in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> it is
sampled
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) How many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> represented by a household with
these
demographic characteristics
Using these weights and BLS-recommended procedure, can compute
estimate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> aggregate expenditures on postal delivery
services or aggregate expenditures any other category of goods

*Preliminary figures. Nominal declines aggregate household
postage expenditures. In constant
dollars, decline would be steeper due to real postage price
increases Decline from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$74.26</NUMEX> per household in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$54.35</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
Almost double nominal increase in aggregate household telephones
services expenditures from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986 to 1994</TIMEX>.
Increase from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$421.67</NUMEX> per household in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$690.65</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
Shift away from consumption of postal delivery services to
telephone services for household sector
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1987 to 1994</TIMEX> share of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS</ENAMEX> mail revenues from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> household
fell From a little less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> to a little more than 10
percent
Significant shift way from consumption of postal delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for household sector relative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> economy at large
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> research question: What are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of these shifts
in the consumption of postal delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>?


Digression on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Model of Household Behavior</ENAMEX>
Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household</ENAMEX> is assumed to have a demand function for each
good which depends on the prices of all goods, the household's
budgeted total expenditure and observable and unobservable
characteristics of the household
Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> ,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> ,...,p be the prices for goods household purchases, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
be the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
household's budgeted total expenditure and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A ,A ,...</ENAMEX>,A are the
attributes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
(observable and unobservable characteristics) of the
household.
Define the household's demand function for the ith (i=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,...,K</NUMEX>)
good x * = <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> ,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> ,...,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> ,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A ,A ,...</ENAMEX>,A )
i i12K 12 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
the amount each good, x , the household consumes. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
goods and
i
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> characteristics.
One household characteristic we focus on is an indicator
variable of whether or not the household owns a personal computer.
This is our measure of the potential for electronic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">substitution</ENAMEX>.
This will allow us to determine extent to which decline is
household-level
demand is due to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Increasing relative price of postage
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Increasing penetration of personal computing technology

Using econometric modeling techniques applied to our sample of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>, we are able recover an estimate of the demand
function
x * = <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> ,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> ,...,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> ,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A ,A ,...</ENAMEX>,A )
i i12K 12 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
for each household in the sample.
Demand functions differ across household depending on observable
and unobservable characteristics of the household
Using our econometric model, we can compute an estimate of any
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> household's demand for postal delivery services given its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> and
A ,A ,...,A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>


Quantifying Demand Responses at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Level</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Price Elasticity</ENAMEX> of Demand = One <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> increase in the price
of the ith good, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> , brings about what percentage change in the
household's demand for
i
good j, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dj</ENAMEX>
If i = j, then it is the own-price elasticity of demand,
otherwise magnitude is called the cross-price elasticity of
demand.
Elasticity concept can be extended to any other variable in
household's
demand function Expenditure elasticity of Demand = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> percent
increase in the household's total expenditure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>, brings about what
percentage change in household-level demand for good j, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dj</ENAMEX>
For each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> household can compute an estimate of its own-price
and crossprice elasticities of demand and the expenditure
elasticity of demand.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of observable attributes that is assumed to shift the
household's demand
for postage is whether or not is owns a personal computer. Model
yields an estimate of the percentage change in a household's demand
for postage as a result of owning a computer


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aggregate Demand Function</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Household Sector</ENAMEX>
Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLS</ENAMEX> weights, can compute an estimate of the aggregate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
population demand function for postage from the household sector as
the weighted sum of sample household level-demand functions Can
compute own-price and cross-price elasticities of aggregate
household demand for postage using this aggregate demand
function.
Estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aggregate U.S. Household Postage Demand</ENAMEX> Elasticity
Estimates These magnitudes give the percent change in the demand
from the household sector as result of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percent change in any
price, household's total expenditure or fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> households
owning a personal computer.

Substantial increase in absolute value of own-price elasticity
of aggregate household demand from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986 to 1994</TIMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-0.76</NUMEX> to
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.27</NUMEX>.
Decline in total expenditure (income) elasticity of demand from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.36</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.25</NUMEX> over same period.
Increasing degree of substitutability between postal delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and telephone services over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decade</TIMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-0.12</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> (complements) to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.11</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substitutes</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
Increased penetration of personal computing technology at
household-level
initially predicts increased demand for postal delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, predicts reduction in demand for postal delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>,
holding all other factors constant.


Estimated Aggregate Revenue Losses Based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> Elasticity
Estimates
In general, an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X%</NUMEX> own-price increase in a product with an
own-price elasticity of , increases revenues by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> + ,)<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX>.
If , is less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in absolute value revenues increase. If it
is greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> revenues fall. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">, = -1.27</ENAMEX>.
Note that before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, , is less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in absolute value, so
that aggregate household revenues increase with price
increases.
Consider <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 1995</TIMEX> price increase for a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one ounce</NUMEX>
First-Class letter from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0.29 to 0.32</NUMEX>, a little more than a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
increase.
From estimated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> household postage expenditures in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> are
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX>, which implies a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.7 percent</NUMEX> reduction in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> aggregate expenditures or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$135 million</NUMEX>
reduction in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> revenues from household sales, holding all else
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">constant</ENAMEX>.
Impact of on household-level demand a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> increase in
penetration of computer ownership for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> owning a personal computer is
0.25.
A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> increase in this number is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.17</NUMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.25</NUMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.29</NUMEX>, a
plausible increase in the penetration of computer ownership by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single year</TIMEX>.
From estimate in above table <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> aggregate elasticity of demand
with respect to computer ownership is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-0.16</NUMEX>. Therefore, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX>
increase in purchase probability brings about a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.16</NUMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17</NUMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.7</NUMEX>
percent reduction in aggregate demand.
Assuming no postal price change, this implies a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.7 percent</NUMEX>
reduction in revenues from sales to household, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$135 million</NUMEX>
reduction in revenues, same as a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> price increase.


Caveats
There is uncertainty associated with all of the numbers
presented in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> due to sampling error and estimation error
in econometric estimation procedure used to recover household-level
demand functions
Less confidence in exact magnitudes reported, more confidence in
trends
they illustrate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Decline in revenue share from household
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sector 2</ENAMEX>) Increasing, in absolute value, own-price elasticity <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
Increasing substitutability away from postage consumption with
computer use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Increasing substitutability between postage and
telephone consumption.
Economic and econometric theory underlying analysis available in
technical paper by same title that can be downloaded from
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www-leland.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stanford</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">edu/~wolak</ENAMEX>


Future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLS</ENAMEX> data recently made available. It is source of
preliminary numbers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1996</ENAMEX> data promised by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of summer</TIMEX>.
Have the above trends continued for household-level demand in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> of electronic substitution-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USPS Postal Diary Survey</ENAMEX>
provides detailed information telecommunications capital equipment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holdings</ENAMEX>, on-line service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and electronic bill paying.



