
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sturgeon King</ENAMEX>

            The 1960s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ban on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> cigars so devastated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> didn't
hesitate, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade later</TIMEX>, to punish the flag-burning ayatollahs with a similar
ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> caviar. By now, an entire generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cigar smokers
has paid the price of freedom by buying overpriced ersatz <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Havanas</ENAMEX> made in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican Republic</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honduras</ENAMEX> from imitation <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. Since the collapse
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and the descent into anarchy of much of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
sturgeon fishery, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the free world have also become the primary
market for inedible caviar processed from sturgeon caught by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Kazakh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poachers</ENAMEX> and clumsily salted in clandestine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> by shady post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capitalists</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
who want a decent smoke can smuggle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohibas</ENAMEX>, but caviar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> can survive
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> embargo legally by calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browne Trading Co.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">944-7848</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Mitchell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browne Trading</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, imports
impeccable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> caviar selected from the few former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processors</ENAMEX> that
still observe the old rules originally imposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czars</ENAMEX>, faithfully honored
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bolsheviks</ENAMEX>, but ignored since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free marketers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, who has built his business on the delicacy of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">palate</ENAMEX> (he was profiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> as the prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s high-end <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>), speaks with the understated authority of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> craftsman. He claims he can taste the difference between caviar from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sturgeon and another. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason to give him the benefit of the doubt is
that on his mother's side he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browne</ENAMEX>, descended from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that began
trading caviar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly four centuries ago</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> sturgeon caught at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mouth</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennebec River</ENAMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>. Another reason is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gleaming caviar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> imports from the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> is pure magic.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spoonful</ENAMEX> after spoonful plays across the palate like an ocean breeze. If money
were not an issue, an average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> in good health could dispose of a pound
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>'s golden osetra in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> reason is that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caviar</ENAMEX> is favored by many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chefs</ENAMEX> who occupy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s culinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stratosphere</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Boulud</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel's</ENAMEX> calls it "the pearl of our business."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Ripert</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Bernardin</ENAMEX> has been serving it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gray</ENAMEX>
Kunz of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lespinasse</ENAMEX> calls it a benchmark. I have known wine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tasters</ENAMEX> who say they
can distinguish in a sip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burgundy</ENAMEX> the intensity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> sunshine that
warmed a particular slope of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">C√¥te d'Or</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>. And there are
cabinetmakers I have heard of who can diagnose the health of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> (when it
was alive) by the feel of its grain in a length of seasoned lumber. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX> is the only craftsman I know who can credibly claim such intimacy with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sturgeon</ENAMEX>.

            
The brochure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cynde</ENAMEX>,
have designed for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browne Trading Co.</ENAMEX> features a photograph taken in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>'s maternal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> standing over a young <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sturgeon</ENAMEX> weighing
perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> pounds. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> grown, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> weigh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to three</NUMEX> times as much and
are now a protected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, but they were once so abundant in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> waters
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Burr</ENAMEX> claimed he could cross the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
on their backs. In those innocent years of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> didn't
eat much caviar. What they didn't carelessly discard they packed in salt and
shipped to the tables of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s great nobles. By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> appetites
outgrew their democratic origins, local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sturgeon</ENAMEX> had become scarce. Now the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s best caviar comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian Sea</ENAMEX>--most of it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
side, which means it can't be sold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            The time
to harvest sturgeon is at the appropriate moment during their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> journey
upstream to spawn. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX> selects his caviar from the long-established
processing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> at the mouth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volga</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astrakhan</ENAMEX> and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atyra√</ENAMEX>º
(formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guriev</ENAMEX>), where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ural</ENAMEX> empties into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kazakhstan</ENAMEX>. These
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> still strictly control the catch along the spawning grounds, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poachers</ENAMEX> now take sturgeon with impunity from the depths of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian</ENAMEX> before
their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. It is caviar from these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> that is clumsily processed
and enters the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> market for sale, often at bargain prices, to unwary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. Wary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>, however, can spot such caviar instantly. The aroma is
likely to be fishy or stale. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> will seem shapeless and gummy or oily and
filmed with a whitish glaze. The flavor will be strong or dull or salty. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> may be of various colors and sizes or have turned to jelly.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Mitchell</ENAMEX> were placed in a lineup of suspected caviar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, he would be the least likely choice. When we met for lunch the other
day at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> looked much younger than his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42 years</TIMEX>, and though he was well turned out in suit and tie, I felt he would be
much happier on the deck of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pequod</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty-five years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>
had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> job running the launch at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camden Yacht Club</ENAMEX> when a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">yachtsman</ENAMEX> offered him a job selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> he had just opened in a
restored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">th century mill</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> stocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montrachets</ENAMEX> and
Haut-Brions for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> aristocracy, and soon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> was selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>, foie 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gras</ENAMEX> , and so on. One day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Louis Palladin</ENAMEX>,
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, would soon elevate him to
culinary stardom, walked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and asked for caviar. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>
confessed he didn't stock it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladin</ENAMEX> offered to introduce him to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">importer</ENAMEX>. That winter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> began selling his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Caspian</ENAMEX> caviar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chefs</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. The following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> another of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, who owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-growth <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">vineyards</ENAMEX>, invited him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bordeaux</ENAMEX>, and it was there that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX> decided on the career in fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that would eventually lead him to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">re-establish Browne</ENAMEX> Trading, the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that, for generations, had
been selling caviar, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> from the mouth of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennebec</ENAMEX>.

            You don't
have to own a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> to order <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>'s caviar. If you've just won the
lottery or taken your Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> public, you can probably afford to treat
yourself to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 ounces</NUMEX> of his beluga at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115</NUMEX>. The same quantity of osetra, which
comes from a much smaller species of sturgeon whose <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a third</NUMEX> the
size of beluga but whose flavor many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> prefer, costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ounces</NUMEX> of
sevruga from the smallest of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Caspian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> can be had for a mere
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38</NUMEX>. Since silver spoons sometimes lend a metallic taste to caviar, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>
sells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spoons</ENAMEX> made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-of-pearl for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as little as $25</NUMEX> a pair (or you can
save your money and use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX>).

            
Whatever you do, never serve caviar with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chopped egg</ENAMEX> or onion or capers, and use lemon sparingly if at all. These are
relics of a time when fresh caviar of the best quality was hard to find in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. The best way to enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>'s caviar is just as it comes from
the tin. If you have some left over, it will keep in the refrigerator for a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week or so</TIMEX>, as long as you stir it from time to time so that the surface
doesn't dry out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caviar</ENAMEX> in tins that have never been opened can be kept for
longer periods at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">26 degrees Fahrenheit</NUMEX>. At that temperature, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> will keep
the caviar from freezing. Home freezers, which are much colder, are not
recommended.

            Though it is always best to
eat caviar by itself, you might try a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spoonful</ENAMEX> atop some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>'s belon
oysters, the intensely flavored <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> variety that has been transplanted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> waters and now grows wild there. Or, to enliven an otherwise slow
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, you might remove the upper <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of an eggshell, deposit the raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>
in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice glass</ENAMEX>, and scramble it under the steam nozzle of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">espresso</ENAMEX> machine. Then return the cooked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> to the lower portion of the
eggshell, mix with a spoonful of osetra, and have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second and third egg</TIMEX> on
hand with which to repeat the process until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">satiated</TIMEX>. If you accompany each egg
with a shot of triple distilled, ice cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX>, your afternoon will soon
acquire a dreamlike consistency.

         
      
   
