
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>

            Soon, my garden will betray
me. It will seem as if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, things are going along just fine--fresh, new
leaves and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>--and the next, I haven't finished with this, I forgot
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that, I neglected this, I left that out in the rain, that should have
been moved, that is overgrown, that is dead, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> are taking over .
Taking to bed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Mitchell</ENAMEX> is the surest palliative I know. He
understands that I may feel like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and a wretch by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, until his
death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> wrote a gardening column called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Earthman</ENAMEX>"
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . During his lifetime, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> were
collected in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Essential Earthman</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Man's Garden</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX>, posthumous, collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>'s work titled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell on Gardening</ENAMEX> has just been published.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the few garden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> to admit that misery is a major operating
principle in the life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX>, which is one "of unexpected failures and
sorrows, somewhat redeemed by unexpected and utterly accidental triumphs."
Devastating winds, early frosts, late frosts, killing storms, bad luck, bad
timing, and general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human stupidity</ENAMEX> are the norm. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, I learned
many things from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>, such as the lesson of dividing up a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> to make
it seem bigger; the importance of small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in a garden; and how to
nurture tender <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>. But mostly I learned to get over
myself.

            It is surely unfair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>, who is probably the smartest,
funniest, most literate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> garden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, but I read and reread him
mostly for self-help, as if he were a sort of garden shrink. I read not as much
for how to do this or that in the garden as for how to be a better gardening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. He provides a sense of comfort, much like the feeling you get from a
cookbook when you have no intention of making any of the dishes. He had scores
of devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with little or no interest in gardening.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> had
the remarkable ability to delight in a single flower in bloom, however many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> and catastrophes surrounded it. Because when he wrote "my garden is a
mess," he meant it. The overgrown façade of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was legendary in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, as were the garden's <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>, and the black plastic pond tubs he
never bothered to sink into the ground. The photo on the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX>'s 
               Garden shows him in front of his green, murky pond. A big
piece of tape seems to hold up some <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX>, dead stems of which obscure his
feet.

            
If philosophies of gardening were on a
continuum, on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side you'd find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>, the cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimist</ENAMEX>, and on the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>, the stern gardening Übermensch . He would have hated her,
and she would be appalled by him. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s charmed garden world, there are
no <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> and no storms. Plans are made, schedules followed, and order kept.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s picture-perfect house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">porn</ENAMEX> engages your fantasy life while you peruse,
then makes you feel bad afterward.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> never wagged his
finger at you saying now is the time to do such or other. How could he? He was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of us, forever late--ordering his <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bulbs</ENAMEX>, planting them, moving them, or
bringing in his tender <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, and lugging them out again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>.
(He was never sure how someone who hated houseplants as much as he did could
end up with a living room so full of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> that it was impossible
to walk or sit anywhere without being poked.) He recognized that the best-laid
plans often fail and that the surest way to make a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> thrive was to plant it
where it didn't belong. Sometimes even his beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">irises</ENAMEX> refused to bloom. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">garden</ENAMEX> was plagued with bindweed. He didn't let it get him down.

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
the garden seemed the ideal place to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> the charms and vagaries of the
natural world. He was coyly gleeful about how lucky we are to toil in this
chaos: to see the early snowdrops pushing up from the snow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX> or
some flower graciously volunteering where you never would have been clever
enough to plant it; or just to watch a couple of dragonflies having sex on a
hot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer day</TIMEX>. (He rigged up a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landing strip</ENAMEX> for the dragonflies at the edge
of his pond after seeing one drown.)

            In print and in life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> was as amusing as he was easily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amused</ENAMEX>. He would entertain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> (where I worked) with his
stories--his rough, sonorous voice; his slow drawl; his erudition and love
affair with the language; his cigarette ash building up until it rolled,
unnoticed by him, down the front of his shirt. He always acted as if he were
getting away with something or sneaking around like a mischievous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> where
he didn't actually belong.

            It's not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> was soft
on things. On the contrary, he could be quite cantankerous. He reproached the
much beloved garden at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dumbarton Oaks</ENAMEX> for its limited plant palate, especially
what he referred to as the "forsythia mess"--a hillside covered in the yellow,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early spring</TIMEX> flowering shrub that others consider a bold sweep of color. He had
little patience for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> to be foolproof and in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">continuous bloom</ENAMEX>. A foolproof flower, such as the stiff, relentless black-eyed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>, can never break your heart. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> that could "make a lady
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">squeal</ENAMEX>." He loved his bearded <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">irises</ENAMEX>, old <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">peonies</ENAMEX>. He thought they
bloomed for just the right length of time, smartly disappearing before you can
tire of them. If you bemoaned that a particular rose only flowered once a year
and for such a short period, he would advise you to take a vacation from work
in order to stay at home and watch it bloom. He did.

            In an essay, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.B. White</ENAMEX>
describes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX>, who, very sick in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of the last year</TIMEX> of
her life, goes out into the garden, as she has done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year before</TIMEX>, to plant
the spring bulbs she knew she would never live to see rise. I had always
thought she did this for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> would come up for him
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that spring</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX> did this because, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX>,
she simply loved the feel of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bulbs</ENAMEX> in her hand, the textures and colors of
their little tunics. He would know. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> died from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, from his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> window, on the planting of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bed</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irises</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of his death, he left his bed and insisted on going out
to help his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor plant daffodils</ENAMEX>. He was concerned because it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bulbs</ENAMEX> should've been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month before</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
