
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I don't know how much you
remember of your college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, but I would like some advice pertaining to the
dreaded topic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>, just in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two weeks</TIMEX>, has
developed a habit of going out and coming in late. I'm a light sleeper, and
I've been suffering from her nocturnal excursions. We had decided (before these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two weeks</TIMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>--until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, when I found a
note from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> saying maybe we should not proceed as planned due to our
different sleeping habits. Since then she has either not been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> or
has come and gone so quickly as to leave no time for discussion of this matter.
I might add that our housing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are due in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX>, and it's disturbing
to me how irresponsibly she is handling the situation--which stemmed from her
suggestion in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.
            

            
               Please
help. Thanks so much.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tired</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear Ti</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie remembers this of her
college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>: There were curfews making it impossible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to keep
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">vampire hours</TIMEX>. (A few stealth roommates evaded the rules, but even this was
rare.)

            Given the irresponsibility
you describe, not to mention the sleep disturbance, prudence (the virtue, not
yours truly) demands that you either rustle up another roomie--preferably a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who is planning to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>--or take your chances being
assigned a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>. It couldn't be much worse. Well, actually it could, in
which case you are within your rights to pester the proper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> for a
change.

            And good
luck with finals. Prudie remembers them well.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, restfully

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I retired after making a
pot of money in my business and looked forward to the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley</ENAMEX> ...
traveling to places I never had time for, fancy eats out, and so forth. But
something happened on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> are the ones
doing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley</ENAMEX>. They give me a paltry allowance while they live high on the hog
with cruises, flying trips, etc., leaving me home to feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and empty
the litter pans.
            

            
               I'm
unhappy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>. What can I do?
            

            
               --Grampsy
            

            Dear
Gramp,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has the slightest
suspicion either that you are joshing her or are tucked away at some prep
school. The situation you describe does not have the ring of truth. Rather than
lost dreams of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley</ENAMEX>," the dilemma you describe reminds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripley</ENAMEX>."

            It is
hard to imagine a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> emeritus at the mercy of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who park
him at home while they travel the globe. Giving you the benefit of the doubt,
however, and assuming that this problem is genuine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests, unless you
signed everything over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, that you stop being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX> and take
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of your money, your time, and their frequent flyer miles.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, skeptically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Please
help me. I've been dating this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> and we get along fine most of
the time, but I often find myself comparing him to my ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, with whom I
broke up after we dated on and off for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. I ended the relationship
because of his alcohol problem. I find myself having to fight off the urge to
call him--and sometimes I give in and call. Then I feel guilty. Does my calling
him mean I unconsciously want to get back with my ex?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feeling Guilty</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wis.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Feeling,

            Prudie
sympathizes, having herself, once or twice, become attached to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-impaired. There is some kind of magnet that draws <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to troubled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Do try to fight the urge to reconnect with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Beam</ENAMEX>. Perhaps by recalling
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-induced difficulties you can keep your hand from reaching for the
phone.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, magnetically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               In nature, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> kill
for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a couple</NUMEX> of reasons: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and defense. Is it not insane for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
murder? If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> did not eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, he or she did not need to kill
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.
            

            
               Second
issue: What do you think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want to take the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" out of
common words? Thank you for your time. I just needed to get these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> issues
off my chest.
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,--Pheonyx
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sin</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes you are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condoning</ENAMEX> murder if one eats the deceased. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX> comes immediately to
mind and, of course, he was insane.

            As for
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want to neuter speech by removing the word
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" from words, she thinks they are hersterical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
traditionally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Please
don't get me wrong, I love kissing, but there is such a thing as the
appropriate kiss for the appropriate occasion. My problem is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pseudopassionate hello kiss</ENAMEX> with heavy tongue action. Am I the only one put off
by this? Have mores changed when I wasn't looking? And the big question: How do
I handle this without making an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> for life?
            

            
               --Not That
Irresistible
            

            Dear
Not,

            Interestingly, this happened
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>--but only once. The shock was so great she found herself downing too
much white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> (this was at lunch) as an antiseptic, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> did not know
the gentleman nearly well enough to be familiar with his health history.

            You are
entirely right to find this revolting, unwelcome intimacy outré. Mores have not
changed--you have just managed to connect with some clods. It would be
perfectly correct to pull back and make a show of surprise and displeasure. As
for making an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who would do this worth having as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
antiseptically

         
      
   
