
   
   
      
         
            

            
               ASK
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRUDENCE</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, drawing on her rich experience of life, will answer questions
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. She will respond to questions about manners, personal
relations, politics, economics, and other subjects. Questions should be sent to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
They should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your
letter to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I just
had lunch at a local Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafe</ENAMEX>. I brought my own laptop and wireless modem,
the better to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> in its full framed glory. I was (slowly)
downloading full images while everyone else was using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynx</ENAMEX>. I did order a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese sandwich</ENAMEX>, and nobody gave me any dirty looks, but even so, I felt a
little guilty about not spending any money for my online experience. Is it rude
to bring your own digital device to an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafe</ENAMEX>? What about bringing food
but paying for a terminal?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Somewhere</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
            

            
               P.S. To be specific,
I'm at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speakeasy</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>, and I just finished my tasty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich</ENAMEX>.
            

            Dear
Somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> had never heard of
an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafe</ENAMEX> until she received your letter. Apparently such things do not
exist east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rockies</ENAMEX> or north of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years of age</TIMEX>. I have, however,
consulted the Web site to which you refer, and now have a clue as to the
subject of your query.

            As I understand it, the cafe
provides computers and modems for the use of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> for a fee and also
sells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. Your question is whether it is improper for you to bring your own
laptop and wireless modem, thus bypassing the fee, and to buy only a cheese
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the cafe
has established the rules for the use of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. Since they have let
you in and have not kicked you out, it appears that you have not violated any
of those rules. You are not being rude. But if there are many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you,
and especially if you are occupying space that might be occupied by a paying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>, the management will change the rules. They will establish a cover
charge or require a minimum food purchase for the use of a table. The situation
will be like that in a cabaret, where you cannot sit down at a table and watch
the show without paying something.

            In the
meantime, until the rules are changed, it would be wise of you to leave a tip
or spend more on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. Otherwise you will not get a good table or will have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crumbs</ENAMEX> brushed into your laptop, even though, strictly speaking, you are
abiding by the rules.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, easterly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               This question is about the
etiquette of having a love affair with a macroeconomist. He's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> older
than me and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>. I have an iron-clad rule about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and
sex (i.e., don't do it), but now that I've changed jobs he's made his personal
interest in me pretty clear; and I like him a lot. In view of this quite
relevant fact--and the global scarcity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who, like him, are tall, funny,
and smarter than me--the age thing doesn't bother me. BUT. The problem is: I
don't know if he's still married to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and
I don't know how to ask. I know this sounds dumb. But our earlier professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friendliness</ENAMEX> did not extend to swapping details of our private lives, although
he does mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Is this some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> code for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               So, can
you suggest a polite way to raise this, preferably using some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> currency-crisis metaphor to get the point across? (He's up to his neck in
all that stuff out there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>.)
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hesitating</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Hesitating in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> is pleased that you
are not put off by the fact that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is a macroeconomist and 15 years
older than you. There can be lots of life left in an old macroeconomist.

            Now, how to find out if he is
married:

            You might say to him, "I
understand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> is committed to standing by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> to the end, no
matter what happens. Do you think such a commitment is wise? How about such
commitments between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, even between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>?"

            You might try: "I suppose you
are hoping that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will do something about the marriage penalty in the
income tax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Would it make much difference to you?"

            How about: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OECD</ENAMEX> tax-free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">store</ENAMEX> is having a sale on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chanel No. 5</ENAMEX>. Should I buy some for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>?"

            Of course,
you could just ask him.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
delightedly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Is it
proper etiquette to e-mail thank-you notes? It seems OK to send invitations by
e-mail (for dinners or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>), and I announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my</TIMEX> engagement this way to many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (easier than calling them all on the phone). But whenever I e-mail a
thank-you note (for dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> or gifts), I always end up sending a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX>-mail note as well--out of guilt. I doubt that I will send thank-you notes
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding</TIMEX> gifts this way, but I am curious to know what others think,
especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Post</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela L.</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX>,

            I don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Post</ENAMEX>
thinks. She doesn't have an e-mail address. I believe thank-you notes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> you know and care about should be individually handwritten and sent by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snail</ENAMEX> mail. That is a way to show the depth of your gratitude and affection.
Even on occasions where use of a printed acknowledgment is appropriate, as in
acknowledging the receipt of letters of condolence upon bereavement, the
printed card should be signed by hand with a personal word added.

            If you
want to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> a letter thanking him for the fine state of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, you can send that by e-mail. (For more information, see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Web site.)

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
traditionally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I sincerely hope you will
not find cause to "go back to [your] needlepoint" anytime soon [see the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, "Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence"</ENAMEX>]. I realize that this feeling is quite selfish, as
it ignores any potential need for needlepoint items you might have, but all I
can offer is the assurance that it is an honest sentiment: Having been born a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> too late, this admirer of yours is pleased to see that not everyone has
adopted the social graces of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beavis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Butt-Head</ENAMEX> or, for that matter, of the
average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               May
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needlepoint</ENAMEX> suffer from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of utter neglect!
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix Kasza</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear Mr.
Kasza,

            Thanks,
I'll let the needlepoint rest for a while longer.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, gratefully

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Maybe
you can help. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> has loved the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 20 years</TIMEX>. While he
has been and done so many things to end the relationship forever, she is so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loving</ENAMEX> and forgiving. Now, the big one has happened. He took her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> ... and
has not been seen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> now. He moved here from another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and his
surroundings are new, but we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> have tried to bring him into the fold.
Now he's gone. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s heart is broken and I can't help. I think he was
using her all the time. What can I do? I'm VERY worried about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mentation</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               --Help
            

            Dear
Help,

            You ask what you can do. You
can play only a secondary role. Only she can salvage her life. If she is
determined to do that, you can help her; otherwise, you can't.

            She has to recognize that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is gone--as gone as if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> had hit him. Even if he returns, he is
gone from her and can no longer be a part of her life. She also has to
recognize that she has behaved very unwisely. As you say, she was "too" in
love--she had invested too much of herself in an asset that has turned out to
be a bad risk and eventually a major loss.

            Now she has to find new
interests. Not knowing her, I cannot tell what they might be--reading, music,
appreciation of nature, volunteer activity, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, or whatever is closest to
her. She has to want these as a new life, not as stopgaps while she waits for
him to return. These new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> will be more valuable to her if she can
share them with someone. That is where you may come in. It would be better
still if she could share those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> with someone she loves. That cannot be
ordered up. But love is more likely to come if she is an interested and
interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.

            I
strongly recommend that she read a little book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor E. Frankl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search for Meaning</ENAMEX> . It shows what the will to appreciate and restore life
can do in the most adverse of circumstances.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
optimistically

         
      
   
