
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Tipping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX> is easy
enough--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> for adequate service, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> if they give me the
post-dinner coffee free. But what of those other services that require
tipping?
            

            
               A day in the life
presents this newly minted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattanite</ENAMEX> with any number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX> to
grease--hands extending from disparately different uniforms and expecting some
coinage commensurate with the services their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> provide. They're cabbies,
coffee shop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX>, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in old<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">-timey</ENAMEX> police hats
turning the revolving doors for me.
            

            
               Recently my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>
began forcing me to forego my usual visit to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12-</NUMEX>a-cut barber in favor of
her "hair artiste" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raoul</ENAMEX>, who wants not only the customary <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> for the
half inch he shears with such aesthetic sensibility from my scalp but also a
tip. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bartenders</ENAMEX> have their own ideas about what it's worth to me to have
them put a lime sliver and a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> in my martini.
            

            
               The question, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX>, as
you may have guessed, is: How much dough should I be shelling out? If I make
the bartender mad, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX> tonics start tasting less like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX> and more like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tonic</ENAMEX>. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raoul</ENAMEX> doesn't get his just deserts, I'm stuck with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">bowl-</ENAMEX>cut. Lately I've been purposely overtipping, just to be safe. At least, I
think I'm overtipping. Is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks extra enough for an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> block cab ride?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy, we're reminded frequently <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, is becoming
increasingly service-oriented. And we know what that means. More tips.
            

            
               Please
help.
            

            
               --Tip o' the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hat</ENAMEX>, the
sober <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> with the bad hair
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Tip,</ENAMEX>

            Your
letter was so charming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> almost forgot it was about a problem. It was
also a reminder that whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hands Out Brigade</ENAMEX> used to be an issue mostly
when traveling, it is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fixture</ENAMEX> of everyday life. Prudie, for starters,
thinks a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> tip too extravagant for an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> block ride--unless, of course, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX> provided wonderful therapeutic advice. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> Prudie has observed
tipping <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> tack on a couple of bucks, no matter what the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX>. As
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you deal with regularly (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doormen</ENAMEX>, since you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattanite</ENAMEX>),
grease their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX> once every several encounters, or else you'll go crazy and
broke. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artiste</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raoul</ENAMEX>, remain generous--as with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bartender</ENAMEX>--because some consequences of withholding tips are more noticeable
than others. In other words, pick your spots, while at the same time
remembering that many service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rely on tips to get by.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, balancingly

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               In your advice column you
recently offered this particular bit of "advice": "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> finds the appellation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Ms</ENAMEX>.' ridiculous and crosses it out whenever possible, believing that single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are 'Miss' and married ones are 'Mrs.' (The nice thing about divorce is
that then you get to choose between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forms of address.)"
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MY GOD</ENAMEX>!
What sort of ancient sexist claptrap is this? I, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>,
and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmothers</ENAMEX> haven't been fighting for equality for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 150</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> just to have this dubious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> sweep our work under the rug. I do
support a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who likes to take her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s name and who likes hearing a
solid "Mrs." in front of her name. But in return I expect her support in
keeping the stoic, inscrutable "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX>" in front of mine.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aries Keck</ENAMEX>, charter
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">subscriber</ENAMEX>
            

            
               P.S. to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>: Do
yourselves a favor--lose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>. She's both insulting and inane.
            

            Dear Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aries Keck</ENAMEX>, charter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is
pained by your opinion, as well as by your wish to have her sacked. As for a
"dubious" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, that may not be the word you intended. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does think,
however, that "insulting" and "inane" were what you meant to say. Please know
that I meant no assault on you, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>, and your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, pacifically

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               I am a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knights</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Kamellia</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX>. I am planning
a wedding for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, and I would like to invite some of
my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to the wedding. What should we wear?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Comeau</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Toledo</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Cyn,

            Well, certainly not
sheets.

            Had your name and entire
address not been included, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would certainly have thought your letter a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prank</ENAMEX>. Since no rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would wish to have her name attached to
admitted membership in such a shameful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, however, I will answer the
question you pose in the spirit in which it is asked.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
should wear whatever attire is appropriate for the time of the wedding. Whether
or not it is black tie is indicated on the invitation.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
disapprovingly

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> ... well,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">floundered</ENAMEX>. Fortunately, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> leapt in to educate her. The error that
elicited more letters than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> cares to reveal--though all were polite--had
to do with a quotation from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thoreau</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will let "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fussbudget From Parma</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heights</ENAMEX>," a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Swartz</ENAMEX>, speak for all who wrote to set Prudie
straight.
            

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>
edition, in your answer to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>," you discuss the meaning of the relationship
between "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>" and circumstantial evidence. You explain the
relationship by saying that if you find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, it is evidence
that it was put there deliberately. Either I am dense and missing some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subtlety</ENAMEX>, or you don't understand the origin of the quip.
            

            
               Some
unscrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX>) back then made a practice of diluting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> they sold with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, thus being able to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> at the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.
"Finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>," thus, refers to the inference that this is good
circumstantial evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, since the water
presumably came from a stream, not that someone deliberately put a fish in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               --Fussbudget From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parma Heights</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
