
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I'm writing to ask you a
question about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s extraordinarily mean-spirited joke about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX> at a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               First, I wonder if you
agree with many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the press that the joke is, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's words, "too vicious to print." In my experience, vicious things
reflect more harshly on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who says them. To that end, I tend to think
that not printing the joke has unfairly spared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> from a well-deserved kick
in the shins from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, I am intrigued by the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> may bump into
each other any number of times before her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. How, in your
opinion, should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea</ENAMEX> conduct herself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s presence? I'm certain
that the apology from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has likely left her with no option
but to treat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> with respect and courtesy. But is there a good way to
make a boorish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> squirm without being boorish yourself?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puckishly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
Wrath
            

            Dear
Puck,

            How nice to hear from you
again. Your queries are interesting ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is in agreement that
withholding direct quotes by public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> often protects the evil-sayer from
others as well as from themselves. The mirror image consideration, however, is
that it is unappetizing to give the offending remark wider
circulation--especially when it is insulting to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of tender <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
Reality, though, must come into play, and in cases such as this there will
always be a way for the outré remark to become known. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curious</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who want
to see the "joke" in all its tawdriness can consult <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s thoughtful
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> in a recent 
                  Slate
               .) Also,
the censoring process increases curiosity--as when one refuses to answer a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s question.

            A sidelight that has been
generally overlooked is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> took a double slam in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s joke. In any case, thoughtful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will surely wonder about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX> and heart of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who could publicly denigrate the looks of a young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has famously conducted herself like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> knows in her
heart that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is toast as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is concerned, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX> being
old enough to remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> and the opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>.

            As for
your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought: How should Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> behave toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> while
being both correct and shaming? My old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> taught me the answer
to that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one years ago</TIMEX>. Kill 'em with kindness, and they don't know where to
look.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, turning the
other cheek

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.,</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> are spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> with us. We love them all. Trouble is,
little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexandra</ENAMEX> does not know from discipline, and I nearly twitch when I see
her talk back to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>. I have bitten my tongue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX>, but I finally said
something to the brat. My brother-in-law then chastised me for being
harsh.
            

            
               I
realize that criticizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> is criticizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> (or at least the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parenting</ENAMEX>), but somebody should say something to somebody. I muttered my
apologies to keep the peace, but I felt sullied having done so. What do you
think?
            

            
               --Lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Lost,

            Prudie sympathizes with your
situation. And you are indeed correct that admonishing someone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is
also a comment on the parenting, but inappropriate outbursts by any youngster
inspire most sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to try to interject a little decorum. Then, too,
the outré behavior you describe was taking place at your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, allowing you to
feel (rightly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">l'état</ENAMEX>, c'est moo . ("I'm bossy around
here.")

            The odds
are not great, but sometimes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>'s rebuke can serve to wake up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>--in which case you've done a good turn all around. You might even
continue the discussion with the tyrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tyke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, pointing out that
discipline bespeaks love and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> will have hell's own time if she
continues speaking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in such a manner. If your one stab at being the
kiddie kaiser causes your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to invite you to mind your own
business at least you will know that you tried.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, civilly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               When a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>, or loved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> stumbles, it seems inelegant to ask, "Are you
all right?" How would you suggest I more properly offer sympathy? My best
attempt: "Is your dignity intact<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Lederman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann Arbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie
suggests you go back to "Are you all right?" There is something peculiar about
asking, "Is your dignity intact<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" unless, perhaps, "dignity" is code for
derrière in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, solicitously

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Your
response to the query about the Zone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diet</ENAMEX> was rich in common sense and went halfway
toward torpedoing the trendy, useless diet industry. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> is to
increase the calories one burns. There's a time-honored way to do this: It's
called taking a walk. How does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feel about exercise as the road to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trimmer</ENAMEX>, slimmer you?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>,
Nev.
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>,

            Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees that
working out is the better part of weight loss; she just plum forgot to mention
it. And walking is wonderful exercise. It requires no special equipment
or membership fees, and you can't strain anything.

            Modified
eating with no physical exertion would be like putting lipstick on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">donkey</ENAMEX>--perfectly pointless.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, gratefully

         
      
   
