
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Please hold the morality
lecture and give me an unbiased opinion and your best advice. For the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> I have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> of a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. We work together. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> really does not understand him, and he swears that if it weren't for his
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> he would bail out in a heartbeat. Without actually promising,
he's made me feel that, in time, we will formally and legally be
together.
            

            

               Strangely enough, his marital status is not my problem. What is disturbing
is that I'm quite certain he is seeing someone in addition to me. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> have infinite possibilities if you know what you're doing.)
Sooner or later I have to deal with this new wrinkle.
            

            
               Thanking you in
advance, I am--Confused in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Con,

            The wrinkle you refer to is
not so new. There is, in fact, a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western song about this:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lady, Your Husband Is Cheating on Us</ENAMEX>."

            Your
specific instructions to skip the morality lecture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inclines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> to cut right
to the chase. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for whom a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> are insufficient is
a louse and a tomcat. This romance will ultimately bring grief, because you
will come to feel jealous and betrayed. So why don't you pole vault out of the
relationship sooner rather than later, and save yourself some time?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, assuredly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have
a teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>, who loves to chew <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>. To make matters worse, she wore
braces for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and just got them off. She was unable to chew <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> while the
braces were on, so now she is going "cow wild," so to speak. I find the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>
habit objectionable. Could you please speak to this issue, with regard to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> ramifications of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> chewing in public?
            

            
               Thank
you,--Dagupster
            

            Dear
Dag,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees there is
something tacky about being seen chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>. Your use of the term "cow wild,"
instead of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog</ENAMEX>," is apt. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>, however, the habit does not rank up
there with green spiked hair and nose rings, so at least you have one blessing
to count.

            Your
mention of the words "in public" suggests a compromise that will keep you from
seeming like a completely snobbish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ogre</ENAMEX>. Hand down the edict that the newly
braces-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> may chew <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> only when she is alone. Try to
communicate that the jaw's constant movement up and down is not attractive and
sends the wrong message. If she feels in need of something to occupy her mouth,
suggest breath <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mints</ENAMEX>. Sugarless, of course, since you do not need more expenses
for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>'s teeth.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, decorously

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have recently been
diagnosed as bipolar. I've been fairly nutty for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, and it's a relief to
get some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> and therapy that helps.
            

            
               My question's this: How
and when does one share this little tidbit? I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> in the media
industry, and I'm single. So now that I'm clearing up those pesky little mood
swings, prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> abound!
            

            
               I
don't want anybody to feel led on, and I'm not ashamed, but I don't want to run
around advertising this to everyone I meet. I prefer to lay back a bit,
socially. Suggestions?
            

            
               Thanks,--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NW Weather</ENAMEX>
Vane
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear N</ENAMEX>,

            How very nice that you have
been stabilized and feel as though you are living a new life.

            As for sharing your health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, you do not owe this information to casual acquaintances. It would, in
fact, be peculiar to breeze it about as an opening gambit--not unlike saying,
"Hello, I have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>."

            The time
to confide this kind of health history--any health history--is when a
relationship feels as though it is deepening. Do know, however, that your
situation is not unusual--hence the name of a best seller: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would even give you odds that of those you pursue, a fair
number will be chemically balanced themselves.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, tranquilly

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>
Prudie,
               
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie T.</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
recently inquired about proper footwear in public. You observed, "The idea
of entering a place of food service without shoes (or a shirt) seems vaguely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>."
            

            
               I have visited many places
of food service across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45 years</TIMEX>, and since I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Appalachia</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, I have continued the practice. Oddly enough, I have never observed
anyone entering an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX> eatery barefoot.
            

            
               Since
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX> epithet would seem authoritative (I cannot imagine Prudie
substituting a different ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in her admonition), would you please
document the claim? Prudie, your behavior here is incorrect, impolite, and
unjust.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Booth</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butterfield,Morgantown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.Va.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contrite</ENAMEX> and apologizes profusely for the slur. As penance, she promises to
retire the hillbilly stereotype from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> forward.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
repentantly

         
      
   
