
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> is greatly
pleased at the confidence so many of you have shown in her by asking her
advice. Sadly she must, however, return to her needlework now.
            

            
               In leaving, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> would
like to offer this last piece of advice:
            

            
               Except
in a very few instances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> is neither better informed nor wiser than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who write to her. She is able to offer helpful advice only because the
problems described are not hers; she is not emotionally involved in them and
can consider them objectively. So her advice has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, when you are
greatly troubled with a problem you should write it down in the form of a
letter--which you may, if you wish, address to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>. The act of translating
the problem into written words, rather than brooding over it endlessly and
incoherently, will itself be helpful. It will enable you to see the problem in
its true dimensions. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, you should not mail the letter but should read it
over to yourself and imagine what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> would say. You will find--not
always, but often--that you know the answer. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> read the letters she
received, she often felt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> knew the answer but only wanted some
confirmation. Try it seriously for yourself.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, fondly
bidding you farewell
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               How should I respond to a
(relatively) good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who ridicules my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX>? Or to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are misinformed about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian Party</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               I don't bring it up, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> does. I try to change the subject, as I am tired of defending my
political views to him and to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't understand
Libertarian philosophies, nor do they seem to want to. And, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do want
to talk about it, they erroneously link <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyndon LaRouche</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX>
Party (he's a registered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, for God's sake!) or just reject out of hand
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian Party</ENAMEX>'s principles.
            

            
               Any
suggestions?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan the Man</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dan</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man</ENAMEX>,

            This is a common problem.
You have no obligation to participate in a discussion that you find fruitless
and irritating. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> cannot be a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> if he persists on this
subject despite your obviously unhappy reaction. Also, you have no obligation
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian Party</ENAMEX> to fight on every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street corner</ENAMEX> in its defense.

            You
should tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> candidly that you do not want to discuss this subject.
If he persists, or takes offense, you should find a more congenial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.
There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian Party</ENAMEX> but who are
open-minded about it and willing to listen, even though you may not be able to
convert them. If you are receptive to the ideas of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about politics
and policy, you will find some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> receptive to yours.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
open-mindedly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Is a gratuity appropriate
when dining at a restaurant buffet? On the one hand, since the server is not
taking and filling meal orders, a tip seems unnecessary. Yet on the other hand,
the server is not less likely to be underpaid merely because the restaurant
offers a buffet, and so a tip may still be expected. And if the restaurant
offers menus in addition to its buffet, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> are occupying a table
that might otherwise be filled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> who order from the menu, who would
presumably tip normally.
            

            
               If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">server</ENAMEX> brings <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>, should one tip based on the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>? What if
the server brings only water?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gratuitously</ENAMEX>
Challenged
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gratuitously Challenged</ENAMEX>,

            The pay a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waiter</ENAMEX> gets is adjusted by the market to the probability of getting tips. If a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waiter</ENAMEX> works in conditions where tips are unlikely, he will get a higher wage
than if he works where tips are customary, other things being equal. If you go
through a buffet line and there is no personal service offered to you except
handing dishes over a counter, you are not expected to tip. If you go through a
buffet line and the waiter seats you; gives you a drink, even if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>; and one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waiter</ENAMEX> is assigned to you, you should give a tip. But the tip need not be as
large as it would be if you got full table service.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, tipsily

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Are
you my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (my real
name)
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,

            Since I
don't know your ego, I don't know whether I am your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX>. Anyway, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX> has more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Prudences</ENAMEX> than it has prudence.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, gladly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               You
probably will think this is from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nut</ENAMEX>, but it is a serious
question. Why does a responsible political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> have a goal of reducing taxes
on the rich? It seems only logical that those with high incomes should pay more
than those with lower incomes! A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> that most rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should have
is how to equitably distribute the great wealth of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxation of</ENAMEX>
the wealthy and assistance to the less fortunate is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> simple way. Also money
is needed for many, many good purposes! What is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>'s rebuttal
to this?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Parkinson</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> cannot speak for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> (who can?), but she can give you some thoughts on the
matter.

            There are probably some
exceptions, but in general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich people</ENAMEX> do pay more taxes than poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Generally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> agree that rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should pay more taxes than poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The issue that divides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> is how much more the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> should pay.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX> has twice as much income
as B, should A pay twice as much tax, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as much, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times as
much? That is partly a question of fairness, to which simply saying that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> should pay more provides no answer. It is also a question of economic
efficiency. Beyond some point, taxation of the rich probably reduces incentives
to save, invest, innovate, and work, to a degree that is harmful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
are not rich. But just where that point is no one seems to know.

            Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> generally
answer these questions in the direction of lower taxes on the rich more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> generally do? That is one of the main reasons they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            Your
question also raises the issue of attitudes toward taxation in general. Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s victory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have come to believe that offering a
tax cut for everyone is the sure road to electoral success. That idea now seems
to be shared by many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, although it did not seem to work in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
taxonomically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               A few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> I dated a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, but he moved and it was hard to keep together, so we
broke up. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About four months later</TIMEX>, he died in a fire. Problem is, his younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> also liked me. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days ago</TIMEX> I saw him for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> died, and he still likes me. I kind of like him now, too; he's grown up
a lot since the last time I saw him. I just don't know if it would be rude to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s memory to date him. I'd appreciate any input.
            

            
               --Needs Help in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missouri</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear Needs
Help,

            You have
no problem. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four months</TIMEX> would be long enough to mourn this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> even if you had
been married to him, which you weren't. Preserving and honoring the memory of a
deceased loved one does not require you to give up ordinary activities. There
is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the human heart for remembering the dead and living with the living.
If you were deeply attached to the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, or now think you were, you
will not forget him. Your present attraction to the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> may be a
sign of your appreciation of the characteristics of the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, many of
which the younger <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> may share.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
consolingly

         
      
   
