
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am
simply sick at heart about the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> payload that literally went up in
smoke. What's with our space program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, anyway? Are they inept, can these
things not be helped, or have we no business trying this stuff in the first
place?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocket Doubter</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>,

            Like you,
Prudie was appalled at the literal burning up of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>. Just think what
that money could have accomplished for programs "down here." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does not
know the right answer to your question, but she can't help but be reminded of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Violet Bonham-Carter</ENAMEX>'s remark: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Outer</ENAMEX> space is no place for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of
breeding."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, groundedly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               A close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is a
plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> who did some minor (OK, semi-major) facial work on me in the
past. The results were fine, but now I want to go to a far more famous--far
more expensive--plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> for major work: a facelift.
            

            
               I know
my plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon friend</ENAMEX> is going to notice the changes when we get together
and will likely feel hurt that I chose a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>. How can I have my new face
and my old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> at the same time?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uplift</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>,

            There are many options. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
You could say to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon friend</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivana Trump</ENAMEX> said: I'm very well
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rested</ENAMEX>, and I changed my makeup. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) You could tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that you won Dr.
Famous in a raffle. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) You could say you were in an auto accident, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> took you straight to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr. Famous</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) You could be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">truthful</ENAMEX> and say your own version of "I was overcome by curiosity about this
much talked about doc, and now I know his work is as good as yours."

            And this
is to give you fortitude: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor friend</ENAMEX> tells her that good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> understand these things and do not take affront.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, soothingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I can't believe I'm
writing to an online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> for advice, but things are rotten with my marriage.
My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who has the more important job, is almost disdainful of me in front of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and anything but friendly in private. She is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the
withering remark and is hypercritical of nearly everything I do or say.
            

            
               To be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX>, I want to pass on to you a complaint that I do find valid, so you can
better judge the situation. She objects to a habit that is really part of my
personality. For whatever reason, I am what you might call a back-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>,
even when we're not in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. My instinct is to give her directions, which way
to turn, how to get places, etc. Her directional sense is average, not
terrible. I fear where this is heading. Have you any ideas?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanging</ENAMEX> on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Hang,

            From your outline of things,
it sounds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> as though you are living in ballbuster hell, and she is
married to a shepherd. Gut instinct tells me there are underlying problems
festering that make her mean. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>, for example, could use directions more
often than not, and coming from a loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> they would cause no
irritation.) Your herding her around suggests that you are compensating, in the
sense that you have found a way to assert control.

            You both
need to get to the bottom of the serious troubles undermining your marriage.
Whether or not you two can do it alone or with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> is your call. But do
something and go forward--either together or separately.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, certainly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            

               Granted, I am not young, but I am not a fuddy-duddy either. Are you reacting
to all the blue nail polish, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> piercings, spiky <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>, and nose rings?
Sometimes the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salespeople</ENAMEX> are so strange looking it is distracting. Am I
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nuts</ENAMEX> and just out of it?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thanks</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fussy</ENAMEX> or
Normal
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fuss,</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>--not young but not a fuddy-duddy, either--couldn't agree with you more.
Often feeling like a lobotomized dowager, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> blanches when she sees some of
the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, frequently wondering how it is possible that they think they
look appealing. There is hope, though. When they grow a little older and get
serious about becoming employed, the green hair and atavistic piercings
disappear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, we seem to be stuck with the odd-colored nail polish--purple,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blue</ENAMEX>, and green being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s unfavorites.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, wistfully

         
      
   
