
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Industry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best-Seller Lists</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, it seems as if
half the books in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> have the word "best seller" or some variant on the
cover or the flap copy, as in "the best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of ..." But what does
that mean? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About</TIMEX> as much as the phrase "original recipe" does on a jar of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spaghetti sauce</ENAMEX>. Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> nor the publishing industry regulates
the use of the term, and besides, there are many different kinds of best-seller
lists published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. There are the major national
Today , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> ) and the major regional lists (the
Times , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> ). There are
lists that compare sales at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain stores</ENAMEX> with sales at independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.
There are romance lists, business lists, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> lists, religious
lists, health lists, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lists.

            What is a
best-seller list? It is a ranking of the relative sales of particular kinds of
books at certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> within a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-week</TIMEX> period. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best-seller</ENAMEX> lists
tell us not which books sell the most, in absolute terms, but which fiction,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nonfiction</ENAMEX>, or advice books sell the fastest at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> list makers
think deserve attention. A how-to book that sells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> copies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX>
will shoot to the top of the best-seller lists, whether or not those are the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> copies it ever sells. A novel that sells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies a week for 10 years
will never appear on the lists, because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> it will be beaten by
faster-selling books.

            Why do best-seller lists matter so much? Because they are
the most convincing form of publicity around, which gives them the quality of
self-fulfilling prophecies. If a book is a best seller, bookstore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> will
be more likely to put it in the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to buy it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX> will also be eager to publish more books like it, since best-seller
lists also stand in for industrywide sales data. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most</ENAMEX> book publishing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are privately held and keep this information secret; even when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are publicly traded, it is nearly impossible to find out the unit
sales of individual books.)

            This helps
account for the uniformity in the books that top all these lists--books by
brand-name or celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, inspirational and self-help books. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> will do anything to try to break this vicious cycle. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> ran a story about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> who purchased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> copies
of their own book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Discipline of Market Leaders</ENAMEX> , and got their
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000 to 40,000</NUMEX> more, in a successful plot to get
onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> list. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read about the legal tricks book
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> employ to try to place their books on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> list.)

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, what best-seller lists are most
likely to reflect is the amount of money spent to publicize the books that wind
up on them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superstores</ENAMEX> now allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> to pay to place a book up front or
in the window or to display advertising. That, plus an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> tour or
appearance on national TV shows, can propel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> fast enough to
get a book on the list. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word-of-mouth</ENAMEX> or good reviews don't generate the
dramatic concentrated sales required.

            Some
lists gather sales figures from more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> than others do. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times boasts the most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> reporting--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX>, plus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesalers</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice Literary Supplement</ENAMEX> list, which tells you what the serious
bohemians are reading, asks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 25</NUMEX> high-end independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City Lights</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Prose</ENAMEX>;
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Bookstore</ENAMEX>. Some list <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> rely on statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extrapolation</ENAMEX> to provide an estimation of what is selling at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> that do
not report; some don't. Some lists, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's,
only <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> sales in big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain stores</ENAMEX>. Others, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's,
include online booksellers. Some follow only independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.

            This may seem haphazard compared with the way the music
industry's main best-seller list--published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billboard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>--is
compiled: It tracks every single album sold at every single music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoundScan Inc.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that began tracking CD and tape
sales with a barcode system, has in fact tried to get booksellers to employ a
comparable system called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BookScan</ENAMEX> but with little success. The problem is
partly that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BookScan</ENAMEX> is too expensive for many booksellers. But the real issue
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BookScan</ENAMEX> misses the point: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want a single
compilation of what's really selling best throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>; they want a
variety of lists that break down sales figures in ways beneficial to them.

            Here are
some of the most closely watched lists in the publishing industry:

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX>
               
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
list is the industry standard. It's the most prestigious, appearing as it does
in the premier book review in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. And it's the widest-reaching, based
on data from the largest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times best sellers at a discount, thereby generating even more sales for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> best sellers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX> regularly write bonuses into
contracts to factor in the possibility that a book will makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
list. This clause is typically phrased "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,000</NUMEX> for positions <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-5</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">positions 6-10</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> for positions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-15</TIMEX>."

            The
Times divides its best sellers into hardcover and paperback lists and
then divides each of these into fiction, nonfiction, and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> category
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Advice, How-To, and Miscellaneous</ENAMEX>." This last category has led some to
accuse the straight nonfiction list of being a "useful fiction," designed to
give publicity to books that would otherwise fail.

            One significant but little-known fact about the
Times best-seller list is that it does not follow every single book
published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> sends a list to bookstores
indicating which books they are "tracking" as potential future best sellers and
asks for sales information on those books (and any others the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> want
to report on). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says this tracking list is drawn up from
information from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> say they routinely call up the
Times to tip them off to books selling with increasing momentum so that
they can be added to the tracking list.

            The
Times Web site publishes another list: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chains vs. Independents</ENAMEX>," which
compares how books in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> categories are selling in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different
types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. This list was a concession to independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>, many of
which were outraged when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> created hot links between every
single book on its Internet best-seller list and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>'s online
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bookstore</ENAMEX>, which then gave a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> discount to all the listed books. Some
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> were so angry about this that they boycotted the list
and, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in 1998</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern California</ENAMEX> refused to
report their sales to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> list. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> claimed
that the number boycotting never reached a "critical mass" that would have
threatened the integrity of its list.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX>
               
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
Chronicle best-seller list tracks sales at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX>,
gathering data from a larger percentage of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> than the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> list does. This doesn't mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> list doesn't
contain traditional, mainstream commercial titles--it does--but it includes
books too esoteric for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> and books that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are willing to pay full
price for. Occasionally, books thought of as backlist titles or classics will
pop up on this list, and many less flashy books that are quality reads start
out on the independent-heavy lists such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> 's.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> list is most valued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> for what is considered its
predictive value. Recent national best sellers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow Falling</ENAMEX> on
Cedars , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cold Mountain , and Divine Secrets of the Ya-Ya</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sisterhood</ENAMEX> appeared on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> list long before they made it
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.S. Byatt's Possession</ENAMEX> was on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> list for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> before it appeared on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
list.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today
               
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's list is
the most inclusive one around. It lists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> books (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> on its Web site) and
mixes all categories: fiction, nonfiction, hardcover, trade, and mass market
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paperbacks</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> gather data in a straightforward fashion: They record
actual sales (no statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX>) at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> and include online
booksellers, which many other lists don't. This results in an unusual list that
pits the paperbacks of successful literary novels such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arundhati Roy</ENAMEX>'s
The God of Small Things against hardcover celebrity health books such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilu Henner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Health Makeover</ENAMEX> and inspirational titles such as
Chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soup for the Pet Lover's Soul</ENAMEX> . The list even includes the
occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s title. Literary books rarely appear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 20</TIMEX>
positions.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's list shows how different types of books that are separated on other
lists rank against one another. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Chernow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titan</ENAMEX> , a
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller Sr.</ENAMEX>, held the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> position on the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> nonfiction list <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week of Aug. 17</TIMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
list, it was not even in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>. The often ignored murky bottom of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> list also makes interesting reading. It is peppered with
literary books such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Catcher in the Rye and To Kill a</ENAMEX>
Mockingbird , which are probably selling well because of their inclusion on
every high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> syllabus. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The week</TIMEX> after the movie version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lolita</ENAMEX> aired on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>, the book jumped from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">204</NUMEX> to make a
surprise appearance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX>. Continuing publicity from its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> pushed it
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX>
               
            

            These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> lists are
designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the book industry: booksellers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>, literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, and domestic and international publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PW</ENAMEX> 's
lists are divided into subcategories relevant only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the publishing
world. Fiction and nonfiction are kept separate for hardcover books but mixed
for trade paperback and mass market. Also listed separately are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religious</ENAMEX>, computer, and audio books. These lists are compiled at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> chains
and independents and are enhanced by statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Rawlinson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> , sees the proliferation of lists as
a way to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> information on the different types of books they
specialize in. But she also admits the plethora of lists gives more books
"best-seller opportunities."

         
      
   
