
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               The
words sex, impotence, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> are certainly very public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, therefore I
feel comfortable writing this. I am a male in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">60s</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX> I had a
radical prostate operation that left me impotent. During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> used
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to satisfy her sexual needs. I recently obtained some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, and it
works for me. Self-satisfaction was required to prove this, as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has
chosen not to participate. I now face the following problem: My sexual desires
have been restored, but to act on them will require my involvement with women
other than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who does not see things this way. I think I should do as
she did. Do you have an opinion on this?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is fanning herself.
Let's see if she has understood this: When you were impotent your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, as it were. Now that you are operative she is not a willing partner
but has decreed that you may not see other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            Prudie
certainly does have an opinion. It is that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is a four-door,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gold-plated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harridan</ENAMEX> who most likely is using you as either a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bed and breakfast</ENAMEX>
or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. Her stepping out then forbidding you to do so, even though
she is an unwilling sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, makes her sound like a perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for
the single life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you take your newly operative self to a
divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and after that find a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who genuinely cares about
you.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, potently

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Please help me. I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and face a serious problem. I am addicted to thinking about sex.
Every time I do something--watch television, play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX>, swim, take a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bath</ENAMEX>--all I can think about is sex. I am even distracted from studying. I open
the book, read a little, then whoosh, all these thoughts about having sex start
pouring in from everywhere.
            

            
               To make matters worse, I
have never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>. Actually, I don't even want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, because I am not
very open and friendly toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. Thus, I have never even touched a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>,
much less kissed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. I am not gay. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, I am <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, which
means that I belong to a culture in which the only way to have sex is to get
married, which I don't think I will be doing until I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>. So I will remain a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">virgin</ENAMEX> until then.
            

            
               Now you
have the whole story. Please advise me how I could overcome this addiction--and
please don't advise me to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> or get married early, because that
is out of the question. Please don't print my name because I want
            

            
               --Extreme
Privacy
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Extreme,</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will not advise you to
get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, but rather, a therapist. You can accomplish this either
through your university health service or getting recommendations from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
Since you 1) have never gone out with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) basically think you don't
like them, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does not know how you are going to turn your feelings around
at the magic and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preordained</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 28</TIMEX>. As for your obsessive and unbidden
thoughts about sex, they make it clear you need a professional's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.

            You are
fixated on an activity that you feel is verboten but which, in fact, is
normal. But do not feel that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> are coming off. You are, after all,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 18</TIMEX>, and beginning to tackle the problem will surely ease the situation. As
a stopgap measure, you might try to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> so they will
not seem like such alien and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">forbidden creatures</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, certainly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            

               Whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> thinks it is legal or not, do you think
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is being rude by installing the browser without asking? Or just the
opposite: Are they being polite by offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> another option without
having to be told? Like giving a person <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and letting him
decide whether or not to put it in.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
Courtesy
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie,
for no particular reason, is quite fond of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and, perforce, their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">browser</ENAMEX>. And she very much likes your analogy. From now on, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will think
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> browser as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> in one's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>. Following this
continuum, how could you think someone rude who is trying to enhance your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">computer</ENAMEX>'s "flavor"?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, tastefully

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I must admit I was
surprised by your response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who helped a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and co-worker draft
a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-worker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. The letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> had urged the playing
of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX> card," suggesting that the reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> were
complaining so frequently about his behavior was because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> was black.
The letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> asked you whether you thought playing the race card was
appropriate. Expecting you to reply "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>," I was most surprised to read your
advice to the contrary.
            

            
               In my
opinion, raising race as the motivation behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>' complaints, in
the absence of evidence to support the charge, is quite reckless. Even if we
accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s protestations that he does nothing to offend, we still have
no basis for charging that they are acting out of racist hatred. It could be
that they have ultrasensitive hearing or that they are obnoxious or nosy.
Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> are simply bored busybodies with nothing better to do
than complain about every little thing that annoys them. Charging that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> are racist, let alone--gasp!--urging the letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to get the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil Liberties Union</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX> involved, is very
serious business. Based on the information the letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> provided, there is
no reason to conclude that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> are racist.
            

            
               --Hopefully
optimistic,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen J. Konig</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.K.</ENAMEX>,
            

            Prudie
does not agree with you that there is no basis to conclude that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
are racist, having found a number of indicia to the contrary. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry David Thoreau</ENAMEX> observed, "Some circumstantial evidence is very strong, as
when you find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, confidently

         
      
   
