
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Slate readers</ENAMEX>
have expressed regret that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> has abandoned her advice column in favor of
her needlework. Sensitive to the continuing need for guidance among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> has prevailed upon her niece and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">namesake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, to assume the responsibility. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> (as
she is known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) will begin to respond to some of the unanswered
e-mails that have piled up in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>'s queue as well as to new inquiries that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may submit. Like her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will be drawing upon her rich
experience of life in responding to questions about manners, personal
relations, politics, and other subjects. Unlike her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, she does not do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macroeconomics</ENAMEX>--though, in the family tradition, she does do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">needlepoint</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               As
before, you should send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries
should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be
signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            

               Recently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> received a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> in the face from what I assume were
self-proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. How did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> handle it, and what would have been the
best response?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wondering From</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Won</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie, of course, does not
accompany Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> on trips, so she is unable to tell you his reaction. All
one could see in the news photos was a picture of him mopping up.

            There is
really no gracious way to receive a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pie</ENAMEX> in the face ... unless it might be to
say, "This is not quite as good as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> used to make."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, tastefully

            
               
                  Oh,
Prudie,
               
            

            
               You quite clearly state
your unwillingness to advise on issues of macroeconomics, but one assumes you
are aware of all this "tragedy of the commons" talk that's going around about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>. (It's mostly loose talk about the incentives that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> have to
use the resources of the Web, regardless of the consequences to others in terms
of slower response <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and eventually even strangulation of the Web
altogether.)
            

            
               If we
assume (since you don't do macro) that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prognosticators</ENAMEX> of doom are
correct, what's a body to do? If my actions won't, in the big scheme of things,
make a teeny, tiny spot of difference, and the Web as we know it is doomed
eventually whatever I do, is it moral of me to download those huge
film-and-sound files that I might someday like to see, eventually discarding
them without even opening them just to get back the local disk space? More
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">importantly</ENAMEX>, is it good manners? As the teeming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> flock to the Web, is
it devil take the hindmost in the scramble for resources? Or is bandwidth abuse
a real moral question? Should we be boycotting multimedia sites that make even
my fractional T3 connection choke? We need your help and advice on this issue,
before it's too late.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Confused</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Chicago</TIMEX>
            

            Dear
Con,

            Prudie
realizes that you are raising an issue of burning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> to many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Webbies</ENAMEX>, but
she thinks it would take an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> to do it justice. Fortunately, she has
prevailed upon her <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Prudence</ENAMEX>--just this one time--to set aside her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">needlework</ENAMEX> and help out her niece. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auntie Prudence</ENAMEX> offers the following
advice:

            Since you raise the
question, you obviously feel uneasy about your frivolous use of the Web. You
would feel better, and the world would be infinitesimally better, if you
restrained yourself. But in the end the solution will have to come from
technology, policy, and economics. That is, a way will be found to charge for
the use of the Web. Someone will have a great incentive to sell speedy access,
as free access becomes slower, and find a way to do it.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> has
developed an Internet monitoring program that tracks a user's actions on the
Net. The program is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scout</ENAMEX>. Surely there will be others. If the private
sector does not devise ways to sell, and so limit, use of the Net, the
government will surely find a way to tax it.

            I hope
this helps.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, accessibly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Inform us, please, why
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> seem now to be embedded in some sort of system or process? Not a
single wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> or wise doll in business or the media fails to note that he,
she, or the subject under discussion is part of a "process."
            

            
               Raising capital is part
of a process. Just talking on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Show</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imus</ENAMEX> thing is
part of a process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawyering</ENAMEX> is processing. Every process seems to be part of a
"system." Don't give us the guff that everyone is part of the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>,
please. Has processing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> led to a class system of the
process <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> and the processed?
            

            
               Thank
you.
            

            
               --Wexxford 1
            

            Dear
Wexx,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Alas,</ENAMEX>
"processing" is the word du jour , and the jour is proving to have
a fairly long shelf life. Prudie totally agrees with you in your response to
this example of tech-speak. I suspect you and I both remember the time when the
only things "processed" were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and applications for licenses and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passports</ENAMEX>. The only thing you can do to counteract this unwelcome addition to
the language is never to use the P word yourself.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
sympathetically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> and I recently returned from a holiday. I left the vacation photos
on my desk, and when I was gone, she went through them and removed the ones she
didn't like. She won't give them back, and I'm annoyed. They're my pictures,
after all. What do you think?
            

            
               --Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Out,

            Prudie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blushes</ENAMEX> to say it, but she would do the same. It may be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> thing. Some of
us are not always photogenic, and who needs to have rotten pictures recorded
for posterity?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
narcissistically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> divorced when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> because of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> and
clinical depression. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years later</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and I were really close, and my
life was getting back on track. He then found another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and asked my
permission to marry her. Not knowing what I was getting into, I had no reason
to say no. Since then we've moved to another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and I have grown
apart. I miss my old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so much that I dream about it. I just feel so alone,
and I'm afraid of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>. And it now feels like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was once my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>
is now only a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Misplaced</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wis.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mis,</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is
sorry for your losses--first your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, and then, in a different sense, your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. You might try to discuss your loneliness with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, for he may be
unaware of what is transpiring. You might also ask to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>. Your age
makes Prudie hope you can go away to college so that the natural progression of
growing up--and away--will help move you into your own life. Good luck to
you.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, hopefully

         
      
   
