
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I hope you don't find
this too personal or indelicate a subject for public consumption, but I am in a
dilemma about a relationship.
            

            
               I am
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorced</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-30s</TIMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. A while ago I started to see an older man
(he is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>) who is very taken with me and genuinely likes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. He is starting
to think long-term, but my reservation is that he is iffy in the boudoir
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. Do you think this is a legitimate consideration, or am I being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sappy</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               --In a dither in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
In,

            Unfortunately, you do not
define what you mean by "iffy." Do you mean he is putting off going to bed, so
you wonder if he has declared his major? Or do you mean you've already been to
bed and are thinking you could put up with this if he were a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>?

            No matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s advice
would probably be the same for either situation: You must determine the
importance of sex in your life. You are still young, so you can afford some
more looking time. On the other hand, you may already have run through a number
of klinkers and determined that it's a jungle out there.

            You can't
go wrong giving it more time to see how things develop. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does not wish to
sound like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ouija</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> or the thing in the cookie, but time reveals much.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, patiently

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Misters, misters
everywhere. 'Tis the spring entertaining season again, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fumble
with their once or twice a year attempt at Victorian propriety. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> common
confusion surrounds the use of "mister" when addressing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               At my Victorian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grandmama</ENAMEX>'s knee I was taught that one uses the abbreviation "messrs" (plural
of mister) only when addressing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with the same surname residing at the
same address--an admittedly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> situation.
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> I
find it often used for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surnames</ENAMEX> who do sometimes reside
at the same address: "Messrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesson</ENAMEX>." I can't think of a similar
complication in modern feminine address. Did I miss a change in the
weather?
            

            
               --Plurally
Perplexed
            

            Dear
Plur,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granny</ENAMEX> would be pleased by
your attention to this arcane detail. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Messrs</ENAMEX> is now the accepted plural of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mister</ENAMEX>, even for the unrelated and separately domiciled. The origin, of course,
is from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, messieurs , with the distaff appellation being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mesdames</ENAMEX> .

            Prudie
liked your example of Messrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesson</ENAMEX>, though she cannot remember if
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> have to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. In any case, she rejoices that
your problem is of such a nonstressful nature.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
linguistically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               How
often should one thank a waiter for service rendered during the course of a
meal? Several of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> think it is appropriate to specifically thank the
waiter for each task he or she performs. I am of the opinion that one should
always be polite to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX>, but it is best to allow them to fulfill simple
operations like filling a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water glass</ENAMEX> or removing plates with a minimum of
interruption. Repeatedly saying thank you forces the waiter to engage in
conversation, when they just want to finish a small task in a hurry. Who's
right?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nonplussed</ENAMEX> in
Puyallup
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Non,</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> instinctively thanks
wait-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for each effort expended--unless she is telling a story, in which
case she pretends not to have noticed. It is perfectly correct to parcel out
the thank yous at a reduced rate, as long as one is pleasant-seeming and not
totally indifferent to the server.

            
Naturally, there is less need to acknowledge service when one is enjoying
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">haste cuisine</ENAMEX>.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, thankfully

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            

               Regarding a letter from your column about a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> being
afraid her "pedigree" isn't good enough for his mother, I have some suggestions
for retorts, should the occasion arise.
            

            

               Pretentious boob: "Do you come from an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>?"
            

            
               Answer: "Oh, yes, we go
all the way back to the apes."
            

            

               Pretentious boob: "What is your pedigree?"
            

            
               Answer: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dogs</ENAMEX> (long
pause and withering look) ... have pedigrees."
            

            
               Thanks
for a fun column. And by the way, thanks for your wise answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> a
while back. You knew something I took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to learn.
            

            
               --badbert
            

            Dear
bad,

            Your kind
words are gratefully received, as is your standing in for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> with suggested
responses to the snob.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
appreciatively

         
      
   
