
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Do you
know anything about the Zone diet? I seem to recall there was some controversy
surrounding it, but I can't remember what. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is seeing a nutritionist
who has him following the basic premise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Zone</ENAMEX>. I am curious as well as
confused. Any info, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX>, would be gratefully appreciated.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
And,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is not a fan of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diets</ENAMEX>. She prefers low-fat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> and smaller portions. The trouble with diets
is that they are demanding, boring, and most often do not offer lasting
results. The trick is to retrain oneself in terms of how one eats and to reach
a new set point in one's weight.

            For a fast start, Prudie
does approve of diets, however trendy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spas</ENAMEX> where the right <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> are
chosen for you. This is just to permit shedding a few initial <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pounds</NUMEX> to provide
motivation and hope, along with the feeling that one is able to achieve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>.

            Prudie
knows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who swear by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Zone</ENAMEX>, and others who swear at it. The real
problem with any prescribed diet is lack of balance, and the fact that feeling
deprived leads to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate cake</ENAMEX>. Perhaps a reliable approach is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the
late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacqueline Onassis</ENAMEX> is said to have used. She ate whatever she felt
like--and left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of it on the plate.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, trimly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I have an irritation, not
a problem, but I thought perhaps you could offer me a palliative.
            

            
               What is
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> telling you they are going to "the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>," sometimes
"the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> in the world," in such and such a field? I know there are many
fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> around, but this seems to me to be a form of bragging. How do
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> decide that their doctor is the best? These pronouncements on
subjective issues annoy me no end. I have yet to hear someone say they are
going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who is kind of mediocre.
            

            
               --Thank you,<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbara</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Bar,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>,
though she has made her peace with this manifestation of human nature. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
just need to feel that their care is top of the line.

            Whenever
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hears such a declaration, she basically zones out, and the remark has
the same weight as "I just had the best cheese <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX>."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, medicinally

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I read your response to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who wondered how he should introduce his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s beau. I have
found a good term for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to use: "gentleman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>." It's very handy in the
early stages of dating, because it's wonderfully vague--not to mention that it
provides an opportunity to poke fun at oneself and modern dating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rituals</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               If
things move in a more serious direction, the gentleman can be upgraded to "my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fella</ENAMEX>" in casual conversation, or for introductions, "my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James"</ENAMEX> (or whatever
the appropriate name is). This allows others to join in the fun by referring to
the gentleman as "So-and-so's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>." Of course, while this form of address
does away with the confusion created by the term "my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>," I think you'd
agree that one should put off using the possessive endearment until it is truly
called for, or it will come across as treacly baby talk.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wryly</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
Wrath
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wry,</ENAMEX>

            "Gentleman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>" is not
only wonderfully vague, but very <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Williams</ENAMEX>. Of course, you knew
that.

            Prudie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heartily</ENAMEX> approves of your suggestions for the relationship upgrade
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nomenclature</ENAMEX>. She is sure you have been helpful to countless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>
struggling with proper designation for the beloved and is grateful for the
assist.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, nominally

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acronym</ENAMEX>? Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> call it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NARAL</ENAMEX>" instead of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NARRAL</ENAMEX>"?
            

            
               Would
it be OK to follow this trend and refer to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">NOW</TIMEX> as NO or OW? Could the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX> be
just AA? Are government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> allowed to drop letters? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> would sound
so much more hip as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deejay</ENAMEX>." And even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> would project more power
and mystery if it went by "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>" rather than the prissy, feminine "MS."
            

            
               --<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dear X</ENAMEX>,

            It sounds
as though you have time on your hands. You might want to consider volunteering
at a homeless shelter.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, busily

         
      
   
