
   
   
      
         
            Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conspiracies and King</ENAMEX>

            A bad liver killed James
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Ray</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, but not everyone believes it. No sooner had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Jr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> died than rumors began spreading that his death was part of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> plot. Not surprising: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> had promoted the theory
that the civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s murder was part of a larger conspiracy.

            He wasn't
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to say so. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Right</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s death, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-camp, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph</ENAMEX>
Abernathy, hinted at some vast unfathomed plot. White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremacists</ENAMEX> claimed
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militants</ENAMEX> were responsible. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> was arrested, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Assassination</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquiry Committee</ENAMEX> claimed he was one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in
a famous photograph (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, at least, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> assassination <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX>) of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dealey Plaza</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> was murdered.

            Despite multiple debunkings, these fantasies endure. Most
recently, a crackpot named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Pepper</ENAMEX> has convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s entire family
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>, .

            Why do we
love conspiracy theories so much? Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> refuse to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guilt</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Harvey Oswald</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s assassination) because they can't accept
that one insignificant lowlife could topple a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and alter history. More
generally, conspiracism (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Pipes</ENAMEX> calls it)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flourishes</ENAMEX> during turbulent times--revolutions in particular--when
long-established orders seem imperiled by uncontrollable events, endangered
powers imagine secret plots to undermine them, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispossessed</ENAMEX> worry about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persecution</ENAMEX>. With their grand designs in which everything has its place,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspiracists</ENAMEX> seek to impose a reassuring order on the randomness of history.
As the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Hofstadter</ENAMEX> noted in his famous essay "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paranoid Style in American Politics</ENAMEX>," "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]hey regard a 'vast' or 'gigantic'
conspiracy as the motive force in historical events. History is a
conspiracy."

            
The histories conspiracists concoct are
convoluted--counterhistories full of strange codes and logic through which
factual history can be glimpsed as in a fun-house mirror. Conspiracy theorists
adopt the trappings of scholarship, touting irrelevant titles and credentials.
They burrow into the arcana of their topics and inundate potential acolytes
with a barrage of pedantic details. Rather than build a case from evidence,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conspiracists</ENAMEX> deny the available evidence, maintaining that appearances
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deceive</ENAMEX>. Rather than admit to inconvenient facts, they dismiss them as lies,
making their own theories irrefutable. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conspiracism</ENAMEX> .)

            Modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conspiracism</ENAMEX> is almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand years old</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pipes</ENAMEX>, in a book called
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conspiracy: How the Paranoid Style Flourishes and Where It Comes From</ENAMEX> ,
pinpoints the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusades</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 th century</TIMEX>--the wars waged by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> who controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>--as its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> mass
outbreak. To legitimize their attacks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> demonized their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>--not hard to do, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> had a competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> and religion of
vast size and power. But <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, too, had to be converted or killed. How
to justify the eradication of a weak and numerically insignificant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX> convinced themselves the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabal</ENAMEX> with insidious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powers</ENAMEX>, out to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christendom</ENAMEX>.

            Besides this anti-Semitism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pipes</ENAMEX> identifies a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>,
related strain in Western conspiracist thought: fear of secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>. This
variety focused on small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (other than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>) whose rituals seemed
mysterious and whose beliefs seemed threatening to Christianity.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masons</ENAMEX>--professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stonecutters</ENAMEX>--were the earliest targets. Since medieval
times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masons</ENAMEX> had devised confidential phrases and handshakes to recognize
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsmen</ENAMEX> and protect their trade secrets from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>. During the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enlightenment</ENAMEX>, their guilds became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> for discussing the new liberal ideas
of deism and toleration (and also came to include nonstonecutters as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>).
Religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> feared that, within their lodges, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masons</ENAMEX>, too, were
plotting Christianity's doom.

            Pipes
contends these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> strains of conspiracism co-existed and intermingled over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, giving rise to various fantasies of global schemes. Typically, these
fantasies have centered on such staples as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bavarian Illuminati</ENAMEX> (a Masonlike
order founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschilds</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> banking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX>) and, later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council on Foreign Relations</ENAMEX> (a bunch
of foreign-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wonks</ENAMEX> who meet on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East 68 th Street</ENAMEX>).

            
Though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> in origin, conspiracism has
thrived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. But where aristocratic <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> feared closed-door
cabals of powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s suspicions focused on its own
government. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Revolution</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> now agree, was itself an
outgrowth of conspiracism: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colonists</ENAMEX> rebelled because they imagined a
systematic plot by the monarchy to deprive them of their liberties. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> were actually just blundering their way through the
tricky business of running a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">trans-Atlantic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, but suspicious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
viewed each restriction of their rights--the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Stamp Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tea Act</ENAMEX>, and so
on--as part of a scheme to reduce them to slavery. And so the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX>.

            
Democratization fostered more conspiracy-mongering. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1820s and '30s</TIMEX>, most
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were allowing all white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to vote (before that, they had to own land),
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX> was leading his famous "war" on the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>.
In this climate popular hostility was trained against powerful private
interests and gave new life to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Masonry</ENAMEX> as a political movement. (Masonic
lodges were often made up of leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX>
Party was formally born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1826</TIMEX>, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> who had quit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> was murdered, and it became a robust <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1832</TIMEX>
elections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masonry</ENAMEX> came to be seen, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hofstadter</ENAMEX> put it, as "a standing
conspiracy against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>."

            So it has gone, with conspiracism playing a role in crisis
after crisis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> arose because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northerners</ENAMEX> feared that a small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slave Power</ENAMEX>" had seized control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> were
convinced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> was determined to destroy their way of life. In the depths
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> had infiltrated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
and were about to subvert our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>. (Some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are still writing
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
conspiracism stems mainly from the instability of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1960s</TIMEX> and early
'70s--a period of both uncontrolled violence (assassinations, urban riots,
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> turned bloody) and anti-government ideology (the left
challenged laws regulating speech, sex, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use; the right fought busing,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and the welfare state).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> breakdown plus anti-statism bred
widespread conspiracism, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> case shows. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> a week
before his assassination for a march in support of striking sanitation workers
there. During the march, a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invaders</ENAMEX> began looting, the
cops attacked them (and the peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX>), and a full-scale riot left
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> hurt. Surely that blood bath--and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> like it in those
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--couldn't have been far from the mind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bradford Huie</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s confessor, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huie</ENAMEX> claimed in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> Look
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> article that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King's well-placed killers</ENAMEX> "wanted to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s murder
to trigger violent conflict between white and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>."

            Of
course, there was a good reason to think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had it in for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX>--the
government did have it in for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX> loathed
the civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, thought he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>, and waged a relentless
campaign of surveillance and sabotage against him. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Author Taylor Branch</ENAMEX>
recounts a shocking episode in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> tried to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> commit suicide,
as noted in this review of his book.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX> never contemplated murder, but you
didn't have to be crazy to think powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> had it in for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX>.

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> became increasingly
involved in clandestine, invasive, and illegal acts against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>--bugging,
wiretapping, surveillance, opening mail, infiltrating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>--the
government claimed it was just protecting the public from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX>, but people
soon stopped buying the explanation. By the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s men
were tapping the phones of prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Kraft</ENAMEX>, stashing envelopes full of hush money underneath pay
phones, even--believe it or not--breaking into and bugging the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of
the opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX> brought executive
recklessness back under control. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s resignation and increased
vigilance by the press, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, covert government activities
were, if not eradicated, at least no longer the rule. Hatred of the government
gave way to a jaded contempt. Outrage settled into anomie. It was no longer
news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> might resort to such activities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> that
were planted in the hothouse of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '60s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '70s</TIMEX> germinated, and in
the cynical, offhand conspiracism of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, we reap their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
