
   
   
      
         
            

            
               ASK
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRUDENCE</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, drawing on her rich experience of life, will
answer questions submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. She will respond to questions about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manners</ENAMEX>, personal relations, politics, economics, and other subjects. Questions
should be sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. They should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length.
Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably including
your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               In the past, when
escorting a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobile</ENAMEX> after, say, coming out of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX>, I would unlock the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX>-side door for her first before walking
around to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s side. On modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> with power locks, however,
unlocking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s-side door automatically unlocks all other doors. This
innovation makes <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> unlocking her door a superfluous and illogical
gesture.
            

            
               Where
do you come down on this question of chivalry vs. logic? Is it insulting to
unlock her door first when we both know it's unnecessary?
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
Lovelocked
            

            
               Dear
Lovelocked,
            

            There is no conflict here
between chivalry and logic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chivalry</ENAMEX> requires not only that you unlock the door
but also that you open the door for her, hold her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> to help her enter, see
that the edge of her skirt has been removed from the door frame, and then close
the door. Helping her enter can also be the occasion for sweetly kissing her on
the cheek. Modern gadgets will not do all that, and real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> don't want them
to. Something has to be left for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to do.

            Anyway,
the idea of a conflict between chivalry and logic is mistaken. Chivalrous
gestures, even though not utilitarian at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> level, have a utilitarian logic at
another level. Chivalrous gestures are a means of communication, and that is
useful. When you hold the door for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, even though she is quite capable
of doing it for herself, you are communicating the fact that you care about her
and want to be her helper. Unless you are a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>, it may be the best way
you have of communicating those sentiments to her. Which gestures communicate
what changes over time, as does other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>. In my time, at least, holding
the door communicated respect or affection or some other favorable
emotion--depending on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> involved. What holding the door for
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> communicates is different from what holding it for your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> does.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Ever
since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>'s book came out detailing the raw side of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kennedy</ENAMEX> and
the dark side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX>, I've been wondering what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s context
that warrants an eternal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arlington National Cemetery</ENAMEX>. While there are
few precedents anywhere in the world for eternal flames to honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>,
there are even fewer precedents for turning them off once ignited. I don't
suppose many would argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> has greater stature than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, so isn't it a little silly to honor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> in so unique a fashion? What,
if anything, can be done that doesn't come across as overtly partisan or
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               --Troubled in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Arlington</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Dear
Troubled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>,
            

            To snuff out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arlington National Cemetery</ENAMEX> would be more trouble than it is worth. What is
important is the flame of admiration and affection for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> that burns in the
hearts of many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. When that flame burns out, as I think it soon will,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX> will not matter. No one will go to it except to roast
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marshmallows</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> flock to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial</ENAMEX> because they revere <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who rose from humble origins to
become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, free the slaves, and
write some of the most profound and moving words in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language. If
the same marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in the same place were dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William McKinley</ENAMEX>,
no one would go there.

            In a prime
location opposite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is a statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX> on a horse.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pass it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, but no one stops to look at it. It will
be the same with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX>, in time.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 days</TIMEX> away when a fair number of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> had already
placed lights around their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and fully decorated their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. I like to
think of myself as somewhat festive, but why has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> turned into a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full-month</TIMEX> affair? What can we do to keep this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> from becoming the
national bore?
            

            
               --Scrooge
            

            
               Dear
Scrooge,
            

            Reread
your life story in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Christmas Carol</ENAMEX> . If you have no problem more
serious than boredom with an excess of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, you are fortunate indeed.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, tolerantly

         
      
   
