
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               A black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-worker</ENAMEX> asked
me for advice about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, who call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to complain about his
playing a radio too loudly. He owns a radio; he just never plays it, he says.
Once he dropped a weight while exercising, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> called the police
to complain about the excessive noise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> were nonplussed and said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> were overly fussy, but the complaints and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> visits
continue.
            

            
               My bewildered associate
drafted a longish letter of apology for giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors offense</ENAMEX>. I offered
to write a more appropriate letter for him. He accepted my offer and will
deliver the letter at the earliest convenient moment. But first, I'd like your
opinion of my note. I had him declare in the note that he was really perplexed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> why he was being singled out for complaint. Was it not possible that the
(white) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> didn't like him for things he has no control over (being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX>)? If that should be the case, perhaps counseling by a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> might
be appropriate, and he would be willing to participate.
            

            
               This is everything I
know. I wouldn't have stuck my neck out on this, but my co-worker is really a
nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. I couldn't bear to see him apologizing for things that never
happened. He's always cheerful, never swears, dresses neatly, works quietly. I
don't know what your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is like, but the rest of us cannot be described
that way.
            

            
               I am
not a social agitator, but I am in favor of justice. Did I do the right thing
suggesting he play the race card?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helpfully Hopeful</ENAMEX> or
Hopefully Helpful
            

            Dear
Help,

            It is good of you to help
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and co-worker. It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s guess, however, that bigots will not
voluntarily go into counseling with a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.

            The introduction of what you
call the race card is appropriate, seeing that the deck is obviously stacked
because of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s color. It is always a last resort to play hardball,
but in this case a call to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberties Union</ENAMEX> might be helpful.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, by the way, is populated by cheerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are neatly dressed and
do indeed work quietly. As for never swearing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, combatively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I, too, am sick of all the
controversial opinions and hype regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, but I must challenge your comments
(and those of all the others out there) voicing concern that it is "becoming a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">recreational drug</ENAMEX>," "creating ersatz libido," etc.
            

            
               I am a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48-year-old</TIMEX> male
who, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several years</TIMEX>, had a very mediocre sex life. I was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in
the joke: "Call him oatmeal. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three minutes</TIMEX> and he's done." I was also in denial
until <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> suggested I try <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>. I've been on it
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I are both much happier. She has since confided
that sex was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of our relationship she was not happy with.
            

            
               Prudie,
the unfortunate misconception that everyone is hyperventilating about is that
this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> does something other than help those that need it. It's not an
aphrodisiac, it's not going to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wannabes</ENAMEX> into young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">studs</ENAMEX>. The only people
it's going to do anything for are those with erectile dysfunction. Besides,
those looking for a recreational sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> aren't going to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and
claim they can't get it up; their egos wouldn't let them. If they do obtain it
on the black market they are going to find that it doesn't do anything for them
they can't already do without it. It only helps those who need it. To quote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>, "It's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>."
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sign me, No Ersatz</ENAMEX>
Libido, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just No Longer Frustrated</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear No,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> wrote in the column to
which you refer, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> of good will cannot begrudge those in genuine need."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of good will, and you, apparently, were in genuine need.
(While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is sincerely happy for you and the missis, your breakfast cereal
reference suggests another difficulty altogether, but we'll leave that alone
for now.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, you are mistaken about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> not trying to use
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> to achieve a little extra oomph. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> herself knows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have
got their hands on it, and a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> reports that all
kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> without impotence problems are requesting prescriptions. (You
misgauge the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who are not thinking with their egos.)

            And wasn't
that an unfortunate remark by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>? It seemed like bragging, once
removed, don't you think?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, steadfastly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Since it is stated that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> "responds to questions about manners, personal relations, politics, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>," here's one about politics--sort of.
            

            
               I read
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> has gone on record saying that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> is not only "a sin, but just another problem like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>, sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addiction</ENAMEX>, and kleptomania." He added--I guess to prove his goodness bona
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fides</ENAMEX>--that he's never cheated on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. What do you think of all
this?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wondering</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Won</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>
belongs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ignorance and Bigotry Wing of the Betty Ford Clinic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
is, of course, entitled to apply his own interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> to his
personal life. But when it comes to dictating to others, it always amazes me
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and preachers--substitute their own
interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> for medical and psychiatric findings.

            Whenever
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hears rigid, unsound, and ungenerous dictums, for some reason she
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">automatically</ENAMEX> thinks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Swaggart</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
righteously

         
      
   
