
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">History Is on Clinton's Side in the Impeachment Fight</ENAMEX>

            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of televised
palaver, the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> commentariat has given up: In
determining grounds for impeachment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> just isn't much help.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article II, Section 4</ENAMEX> allows for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s removal if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> convicts
is high? "Clearly, high crimes was referring to serious, serious crimes like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treason</ENAMEX> and bribery, which are examples," said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> legal pundit on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> . In other words, no one really knows.

            This
leaves history as our only guide. Unfortunately for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> (if fortunately
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has undertaken impeachment proceedings against only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>, acquitted) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>,
resigned). That doesn't yield much in the way of precedent. Then again, the
rarity of impeachment proceedings may itself be a sort of precedent. If so,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should relax--because, given what we know so far, he's on
pretty firm ground.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and only presidential impeachment trial,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson's</ENAMEX>, has generally been viewed as a partisan vendetta by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radicals</ENAMEX>, who favored the abolition of slavery and
supported black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suffrage</ENAMEX>, despised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> for his timid plans for readmitting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> who
thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> inferior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, wanted to give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> wide latitude
in shaping their own laws and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, regardless of the consequences for
the freed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>. He vetoed key pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> legislation, including
an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1866</TIMEX> bill that would have granted basic civil rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, and he
opposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">14 th Amendment</ENAMEX>. Political warfare ensued.

            Although
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> once drew the scorn of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>--they were seen as
intemperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX>--since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, they've mostly been cast as the good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> fight. Changing attitudes toward race in the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> have helped overhaul the old interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> as a
bad idea gone wrong. Except, that is, on the impeachment episode. Here, even
the acknowledged wisdom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> plans hasn't changed
the consensus that they acted from partisan motives.

            
The impeachment fight began when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, in their tug of war with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, passed some dubious laws that
shifted power from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1867 Tenure</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act,</ENAMEX> prohibited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> from firing their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>; another
required that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> deliver all his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> orders via <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulysses S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> removed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin M. Stanton</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Radicals</ENAMEX> struck. They passed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> articles of impeachment, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
relating to these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> laws. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other articles accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> of ignoring or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disgracing Congress</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX>'s removal, the most substantive charge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
offered a somewhat contradictory defense. On the one hand, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> said,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, had appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX>, and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenure of Office</ENAMEX> Act
didn't apply; on the other hand, they claimed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> had deliberately
flouted the law to test it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. Still, the case against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> was weak: It was hard to construe the act of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> firing his own
subordinate as a "high crime." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> of his term anyway,
and when he passed word that he'd stop obstructing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> plans, his survival seemed assured. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radicals</ENAMEX>
voted to convict, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> voted to
acquit. Impeachment fell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote short of the required <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, though other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would have supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> if necessary.

            In resting their case on an alleged violation of the law
and not on policy differences, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> conceded that impeachment had to
amount to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a parliamentary</TIMEX>-style vote of no confidence. Before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, this had been an open question; after him, it wasn't. Further, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Radicals</ENAMEX>' defeat suggested that successful impeachment charges against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would have to allege substantial crimes on his part. Allegations of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> wrongdoing that essentially served to cover for political differences
wouldn't be likely to topple a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--even if they were technically
accurate.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
survival, combined with the passage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years</TIMEX>, made impeachment, by the time
of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, seem like an altogether unlikely scenario--the equivalent, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Stanley Kutler</ENAMEX> has written, of a nuclear <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> strike. In retrospect,
of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> has come to mean the vast tapestry of that began to
unravel with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1972</TIMEX> break-in of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. But as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late as the spring of 1973</TIMEX> the scope of these
misdeeds--including critical details about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s involvement--remained
unclear. So improbable did impeachment seem that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s Attorney
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Kleindienst</ENAMEX> defied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to try it, confident it would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relent</ENAMEX>.

            
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s troubles worsened, however, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> grew bold. After the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1973</TIMEX> disclosure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had taped his Oval
Office conversations, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Drinan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> introduced the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> impeachment resolution in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night</ENAMEX>
Massacre--in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had to fire his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> and deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
general in order to get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Special Prosecutor Archibald Cox</ENAMEX>--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more
impeachment bills, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> introduced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of
new disclosures, including the release of transcripts of damning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
conversations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> began impeachment deliberations in
earnest on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 9, 1974</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fence-</ENAMEX>sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>--were ready to endorse some form of
impeachment articles.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> held its final deliberations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from July 24</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 30</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX>,
it voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27-11</NUMEX> to pass the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> article of impeachment, which focused on
"obstruction of justice": paying hush money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> burglars, using
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to block the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> investigation, lying to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, and otherwise covering up crimes. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, it passed a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, equally devastating, article by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28-10</NUMEX> vote. This "abuse of power"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> charged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> with having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> audit his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, spying on private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, setting up the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plumbers</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> that broke
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and anti-war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon Papers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Ellsberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and otherwise using federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> for personal and political advantage. Finally, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 30</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> passed a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, slightly weaker, article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21-17</TIMEX>, which charged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with having willfully disobeyed subpoenas. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other articles--urging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s impeachment for concealing the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> and for tax
evasion--went down to defeat; moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> wanted to play only their
strongest cards. That didn't matter much, though; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, knowing he was licked,
resigned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days later</TIMEX>.

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s survival deterred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> from
considering impeachment in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s ouster has had the opposite
effect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emboldening</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX> remains for many an unhealed
wound, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> delight in needling him with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>
comparisons--whether to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. Impeachment, once taboo, now
seems like a legitimate weapon, a way to settle the score. The principle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutually Assured Destruction</ENAMEX>, after all, dictated that once nukes are launched,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retaliation</ENAMEX> becomes much easier.

            Still, if
the relative freshness of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> works against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the enormity of it
works in his favor. In effect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s misdeeds () so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s--even the
most severe charges of suborning perjury--that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> could wind up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bollixed</ENAMEX>. They are left either arguing, preposterously, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s crimes
are just as bad as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s or claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s crimes far exceeded the
threshold for impeachable offenses and shouldn't be the standard for judging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s. In this situation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s impeachment looms as the operative
precedent: a case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who despised and battled their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--perhaps with
good reason--but whose zeal in pursuing flimsy impeachment charges turned the
judgment of history against them.

            
               If you
missed the links in the article, you can click for a summary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
transgressions, and for the full text of the articles of impeachment against
him.
            

         
      
   
