
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Bringing
Home the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacon</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Six Degrees</ENAMEX>
            

            Sadly, this is the last week
for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Six Degrees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Bacon</ENAMEX>." We've toured the Web near and far, explored
its nether regions, and even learned a little on the way. But all good things
must come to an end. As a parting challenge, we dare you to link from this page
to the respective home pages of every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">monarch</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">927</TIMEX>, in consecutive
order.

            Happy
surfing!

            
               Solution
to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Puzzle No. 8</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Frikik to Free Kick</ENAMEX>"
            

            Last week
we challenged you to link from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off-Color Turkish Page</ENAMEX> (which features a mildly ribald definition
of the term "frikik") to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FIFA</ENAMEX>'s official definition of a soccer free kick in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> steps or
less. Congratulations go to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s winners: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carol Clapp, Gillian Lord</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>
Degrees' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tasmanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Ruthfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Travers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Willis</ENAMEX>. They all did it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> links. Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>'
solution:

            From the starting page, click the Home icon at the bottom left-hand corner
of the page or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> at the top left. This will take you ...

            here,
where you should click <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Links</ENAMEX> to Other Sites of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest</ENAMEX> (the last of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">links</ENAMEX>), and from

            there, choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tun√</ENAMEX>ß in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> link (at the bottom,
under "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends ..."</ENAMEX>). This will take you ...

            here. Then,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">click Galatasary</ENAMEX> (under "HOBBY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROOM Sports</ENAMEX> that I am interested"). This
will take you ...

            here, where you should
click Current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Season</TIMEX> , to go ...

            here. Click More
Links (on the right-hand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> under "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Miscellaneous"</ENAMEX>), and from

            there, choose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> (under "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Agency</ENAMEX>"). This will take you ...

            here, where you should click the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FIFA Online</ENAMEX> link, which
you'll find on the left (under "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">THE BASICS"</ENAMEX>).

            From <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FIFA Online</ENAMEX>, click
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publications</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Directories</ENAMEX> (on the bar below the opening graphic), and
from ...

            there, click <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Laws of the Game and Decisions of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Football Associations Board</ENAMEX> . That will take you

            here, where you should choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Law 13 Free-Kick link</ENAMEX>
from the menu on the left, and you're there.

            
Goooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooal!!!!

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
