
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I have
no problem of a personal nature at the moment. What I do have is a societal
irritation. Not only the young but also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who are professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> have taken to ending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">declarative</TIMEX> sentences as though they were
questions. Have you heard this irritating "modernization"? How did experienced
radio and TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of both genders turn into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Girls</ENAMEX>, and do you know
where this annoying development came from?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earache</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ear,</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is
relieved that you are not in distress of a personal nature and hopes it is some
comfort to you that she herself regards this way of speaking as revolting? It
is called "up talk," and if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> knew its instigator she would slowly twist
his question mark until it hurt. This raising of the voice at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of a</TIMEX>
declarative sentence is the unfortunate result of trying to fluff up something
that needs no fluffing: correct speech.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
declaratively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Are you
hearing anything about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>? Do you have any thoughts on
the subject?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Portland</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Len</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is hearing a great
deal about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>--but mercifully not from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s thoughts, she
is sick of the subject, and to distract herself from the pharmacological drama
going on she is entertained by imagining the drug being given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folkman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.

            Do not misunderstand. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
of good will cannot begrudge those in genuine need, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> is on its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to becoming a recreational <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, thereby creating ersatz libido, and
thereby creating God only knows what problems.

            Prudie
also thinks the name unfortunate, sounding, as it does, like the well-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertilizer</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, dismissively

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I need
to know how to ask if someone is pregnant without giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> if they're
not. A casual (married) acquaintance of mine appears to be showing but not in a
manner in which one can be certain. I suppose I could wait her out, but I want
to start gossiping as soon as possible.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,Naturally
Curious in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Nat,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> once made the mistake
of asking the question you have in mind. My unfortunate query elicited this
response: "I have a problem with my weight, and you have just ruined my
day."

            The only
possibilities other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> are obesity or a tumor--neither of which needs
remarking on. And your use of the words "casual acquaintance" makes Prudie
certain that you should ask no questions and put the gossip on hold.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, privately

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I can hardly believe I am
having this problem in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age. I am in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 20s</TIMEX> and in a serious
relationship. We are discussing marriage, but he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>: his mother's,
shall we say, "views." It seems my maybe-future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> is all caught up
in ancestors, social pedigree, and similarly irrelevant issues. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> is
afraid she will not welcome me with open arms out of fear her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> will wind up
out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Register</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               What is
to be done?
            

            
               --No <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DAR</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear No,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> tolerance for
this kind of thinking and, as a matter of fact, has always considered the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Register the American Kennel Club</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.

            Your
immediate determination is whether your beau shares his mother's views. If he
is afraid of her disapproval, he will surely be substandard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> material.
If he is not wholeheartedly in your corner on this one, say adios and look for
someone who will not regard you as the little match <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
democratically

         
      
   
