
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               It's been said that the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> words <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> fear most are: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, we need to talk." Well, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who refuses to talk. Instead of leaving normal notes, such as "Please take
out the garbage" or "Don't forget to pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>," she leaves
me long (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> page) handwritten letters about concern for each other's
feelings, sharing chores, etc. When I ask her if it wouldn't be easier to sit
down and talk things out, she says, "Why? I've already put it in
writing."
            

            
               I feel
as though I've married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cyrano de Bergerac</ENAMEX>. How can I get her simply to start
talking?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-Strain</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear I,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will pass up the
chance to point out what would be seen by some as your good fortune. A more
common question might surely be "How can I get her to stop talking?"

            But to
address the problem at hand: Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, for whatever reason, is committed to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">epistolary</ENAMEX> marriage. Perhaps she's a frustrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, unable to get
published? Perhaps she feels you tune her out? If you've really made an effort
to hash this out, your options are to: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) grab pen and paper yourself; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) seek
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>' counseling; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) reconsider the importance to you of the written vs.
the spoken word.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, vocally

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Is it
proper for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> to wear black at a wedding?
            

            
               --Pedlar
            

            Dear
Ped,

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX> might say it is an
appropriate color, considering the occasion. Fashion, however, has made black
dresses for bridesmaids all the vogue. It could be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just got sick of
seeing those dresses the color of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepto-Bismol</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> is
also slenderizing, so perhaps the heavier bridesmaids lobby made itself
heard.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, colorfully

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Despite my frequent
requests, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> continually pull up in front of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at all
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and blast their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> horns rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, get out, and ring the bell of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> they've come to pick up. This happens as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late as midnight</TIMEX>.
            

            
               When I politely ask the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> to stop this, they use profanity, ignore me, or threaten violence. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> say they'll speak to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> about this behavior, but if they
have done so it hasn't worked. Getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to respond has been useless
and seems petty anyway.
            

            
               Many
times these horns have awakened me from sleep. I have used up my patience. What
can I do?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horny</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horn</ENAMEX>,

            Have you tried earplugs?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is not being facetious. Having done a turn in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> herself, she
knows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in blue are not going to come for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> blowing horns, since
they ignored her calls regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> blowing leaves.

            And since
you are getting nowhere with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, mental health
would seem to dictate that you handle the situation with the best
self-protection available. Think like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-stepper: Accept that which you
cannot change and have the wisdom to know what those things are. Or think like
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> master: There is no solution. Seek it lovingly.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
philosophically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> and is now
carrying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> she has been with for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX>. They don't
live together, they rarely go out on dates, and when they see each other it
normally means one spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> at the other's place. There are times
when they don't hear from each other for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>. There is nothing here
that resembles commitment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> still has not decided what his role is
going to be, if any.
            

            
               In
short, he's being a real jerk and it makes me damned angry to see my friend
suffering and stressing out because of this caveman, given her delicate
condition. What should I do?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concerned Friend</ENAMEX> in
NYC
            

            Dear
Con,

            Mind your own business. No
offense. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> believes that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in domestic affairs such as you
describe are like, well, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX>. If it will calm you any, it sounds as if
this pair is practicing emotional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&M</ENAMEX>.

            Prudie
thinks there's a slim chance that you are your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, if you get my drift.
If this is the case, you should 1) tell Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Future</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> what is expected and, if
it is not forthcoming, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) wipe the slate clean and begin to make the best life
you can as a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
pamperingly

         
      
   
