
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am recently married,
and like most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> girls, I have looked forward to being addressed as
"Mrs." for some time. Imagine my surprise when I found that my mail, instead of
being addressed to "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Smith</ENAMEX>," is now being addressed to "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>." Since I always thought that form of address was reserved for divorced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, I'm a bit put out to have my new marriage so abruptly terminated, at
least as it relates to correspondence.
            

            
               I'm
assuming this is some misguided attempt to preserve my individuality, but if
that were my goal I would have kept my maiden name. Am I completely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misinformed</ENAMEX>? If not, how can I correct the problem?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proudly</ENAMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> (nee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hightower</ENAMEX>)
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Proud,</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> couldn't agree with
you more--and she is on the other side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> line. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> also
finds the appellation "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX>" ridiculous and crosses it out whenever possible,
believing that single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss</ENAMEX>" and married ones are "Mrs.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">"</ENAMEX> (The nice
thing about divorce is that then you get to choose between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forms of
address.)

            As for correcting the
problem, when a response is called for, cross out the offending form of your
name and write in what you would prefer. Some mailings, often from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>,
offer the choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss</ENAMEX>, Mrs., or Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">And</ENAMEX> of course your printed envelopes can
say "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Smith</ENAMEX>."

            As for
mailings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Clearing House</ENAMEX> that frequently send
material to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and toddlers, there is no recourse.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
salutatorally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have a little problem
with my current Significant Other. We are both nearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, are educated, have
good jobs, are reasonably attractive and intelligent. Each day together (it's
been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 8 months</TIMEX> now) has been wonderful and a many-splendored
thing.
            

            
               The
problem? I find my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>'s politics reprehensible--in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">barbaric</ENAMEX>. I haven't strenuously objected to my love's praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> and (I'm serious here) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Gordon Liddy</ENAMEX> because of the terrific time
we're having and the incredible sex we share. But I'm at the breaking point. It
is hard to foresee a future with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whose philosophy is akin to that of a
cryptofascist clown. How do I break the news and let both of us keep our
dignity, even if (s)he is a troglodyte?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evolved</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fe</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ev</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> can tell you are
conflicted ... but not very. Just tell the cryptofascist clown troglodyte, I
mean, your Significant Other, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">au revoir</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees that your deep
disagreement about character evaluation is bound, in the long run, to sink your
love <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>. Sex may come and sex may go, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> is liable to be around
forever.

            Simply
state your regret and wish him/her much happiness in the future. And perhaps
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Democratic Club</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> might be worth a visit.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, politically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               A while back you had a
letter about the bald black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> being confused with another black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. He was
more than annoyed and thought it was the old "all black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> look alike."
Well, I have a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>, who is bald and wears a full beard and horn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rim</ENAMEX> glasses. He tells me he is forever being mistaken for other bald, bearded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who wear glasses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> even once mistook such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a photograph for
himself!
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX>,
and we had a very interesting conversation about this topic. He tells me that
our brains store only a few visual traits about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with whom we are
casually acquainted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> is "the bald, bearded, spectacle wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>
is "the redheaded, long nosed, thin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>," etc. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> changed her hairstyle
from curly to straight and reported that while attending her annual
professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> convention, she was shocked at the number of people
who didn't recognize her. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who lose a lot of weight tell similar
stories.
            

            
               This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tendency</ENAMEX> explains the oft-noted phenomenon that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> think all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>, etc., look alike. The problem is that they don't know enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
those racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, so their brains will use race as the most distinctive
characteristic about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. They know so many white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they
classify them by other traits--such as shape of the face, hair color, body
shape. Once they make the acquaintance of enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>, their brains
will discontinue using race as an identifying visual characteristic.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Lee</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>,

            It was
good of you (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>) to share an enlightened explanation for a widespread
situation. It no doubt will smooth the ruffled feathers of many a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's
been mistaken for someone else--even a generic someone else. To support your
point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is told that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Everett Koop</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX> say they are
each taken for the other.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, gratefully

            
               It is trout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie's</ENAMEX>. Here are a couple of responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s having quoted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thoreau</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               In a
recent column you quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thoreau</ENAMEX>: "Some circumstantial evidence is very strong,
as when you find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>." I've heard this particular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before
but was too embarrassed to admit that I didn't get it. Exactly what is this
"circumstantial evidence" supposed to indicate?
            

            
               --Hoping for an
Explanation
            

            Dear
Hope,

            Basically,
it is an encouragement to pay attention to circumstantial evidence. In this
case, the evidence is strong that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> didn't get there by
accident--someone put it there--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> not being a natural habitat for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>.
Though, perhaps, a deed is unobserved, its execution can sometimes be safely
inferred from the facts.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, empirically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            

               Regarding "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>" quote, bravo and bravissimo ! Well
done, indeed. I'll beat my different drum in your honor <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>!
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim B.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>,

            How kind
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thoreauly</ENAMEX> charming of you.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
appreciatively

         
      
   
