
   
   
      
         
            Return to Sender

            
               "Plot
Holes" is an occasional series assessing the narrative logic of movies.
            

            Congratulations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> of the motion-picture industry--except for you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX>--for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX>-movie season of shimmering coherence. If we allow <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tomorrow Never</ENAMEX>
Dies the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> logic waiver, only The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postman</ENAMEX> , of
all the major releases, had true lunacy at its heart.

            Though
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner</ENAMEX>'s hymn to post-apocalyptic mail delivery was not nearly as bad a movie
as everybody said, it did display a riotous disdain for common sense. It wasn't
just the little things that didn't add up--wouldn't an itinerant Shakespearean
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>? If you killed a mule for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, wouldn't you end up
with something more solid than a viscous gray paste?--it was the entire
premise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postman</ENAMEX> is about a drifter in the bleak and fractured
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2013</TIMEX> who finds a bag of undelivered mail and, by posing as a letter
carrier, rouses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> to rise up against the evil Gen. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>.
Unfortunately, the movie rests upon the supposition that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have such a
reservoir of affection for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> would break into
a spontaneous rendition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America the Beautiful</ENAMEX>" when a letter carrier
departs on his rounds, or that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> facing a firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> would yell out--in
the unlikeliest line of dialogue of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ride</ENAMEX>, postman, ride!"

            
Compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Postman</ENAMEX> , the other big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> movies-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">As Good As It Gets , Amistad , Good Will</ENAMEX>
Hunting , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic , et al.</ENAMEX>--were logic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incarnate</ENAMEX>. Sure, wobbles appeared here and there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth</ENAMEX>
Shue as a romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX> mark yet another of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s attempts to refute the observable laws of the universe, a bit of
wishful thinking on par with cold fusion. The fundamental implausibility of
As <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good As It Gets</ENAMEX> , in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicholson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> magically
evolves from a toxic slime ball to an adorably vulnerable neurotic, can be
forgiven as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> fantasy, but there are details scattered throughout the
movie that just do not compute. Why, to cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> example, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholson</ENAMEX>'s
character entrusted with the care of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> after he has
amply demonstrated his hatred of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> by tossing it down a laundry chute?
Are there no kennels in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>?

            Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> , one of the most meticulous films ever made, is
not immune to the occasional glitch. In one crucial scene, the vagabond artist
played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> retires with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Winslet</ENAMEX>) to her sitting
room, where he makes a nude sketch of her sitting on a divan as the languorous
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> tick by. Meanwhile, her suspicious fiance has apparently been furiously
searching for her for much of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>. "There are only so many places she can
be!" he rants in frustration to his evil manservant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, did you ever
think about checking her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> ?

            
One could go on with these petty complaints,
but what's the point? In terms of insane-in-the-membrane movie action, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> was downtime. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX> , a film that was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consciously</ENAMEX> conceived as a howler, ran smack-dab recently into its own
real-life plot hole. Only after the full-fledged arrival of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> did things
start to pick up, when the release of Firestorm heralded a return to the
usual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> standards of cognitive dissonance. There was much
cluck-clucking among movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> about the dual appearance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firestorm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Rain</ENAMEX> , since both were about murderous crimes
occurring in the course of natural disasters and both featured kick-ass
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroines</ENAMEX> eager to risk their lives for imperiled stained-glass windows or the
abandoned hatchlings of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Rain</ENAMEX> , though a pretty
bad movie, at least had the integrity of its own screwy internal logic.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firestorm</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, was truly deranged. I realize this movie
did not linger long at the box office or spark all-night conversations in
coffeehouses, but trust me--it's worthy of study.

            My
favorite part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firestorm</ENAMEX> was an extended sequence in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howie Long</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howie Long</ENAMEX>? ), playing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Forest Service</ENAMEX> smoke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX>, parachutes
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> into the path of a forest fire to rescue a group of killers
masquerading as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX>. He and a captive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ornithologist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suzy Amis</ENAMEX>) escape
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> that they appropriate from a remote wilderness
trading post. In the pursuit that follows, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> rummages around in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motorcycle</ENAMEX>'s saddlebag, produces a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> saw, starts it with one hand, and
tosses it over his shoulder into the windshield of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>.
Then--while still gunning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> down a logging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>--he produces a
parachute from out of nowhere and straps it on just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> sails out over
the deepest gorge in the world. After a leisurely free fall, the smoke jumper
and the ornithologist land safely, though minor damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s kneecap
serves as an occasion for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX>'s most unforgettable line thus far: "I
need an orthopedist--and you're a birdwatcher."

            
Finally, on a much classier <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, there is
Fallen . This bleak supernatural detective story has a script by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>, the talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reversal of Fortune</ENAMEX> , and has been
stylishly directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Hoblit</ENAMEX>, but both of them are working against long
odds here. Fallen is essentially a variant of the vampire genre, and
there has never been a vampire movie that made any sense at all. In this case,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel Washington</ENAMEX> plays a homicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hobbes</ENAMEX> who pays a visit
to a killer just before his execution. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer mischievously</ENAMEX> tells Hobbes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">riddle</ENAMEX> ("Why is there a space between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spakowski?</ENAMEX>"), mutters something
in a language that turns out to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aramaic</ENAMEX>, and then starts singing
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time Is on My Side</ENAMEX>" as he heads for the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobbes</ENAMEX> follows up on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons-Spakowski</ENAMEX> riddle and--due in part to a much more responsive and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX> than exists in reality--discovers that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> had been possessed by the spirit of a dark angel named
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azazel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azazel</ENAMEX> (who we're told is "sadistic, left-handed, and likes to sing")
has the ability to flit from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> to another simply through touch.
What happens if the body he's occupying dies? That's covered in the cobwebbed
demonic manual Hobbes conveniently finds in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX> of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> is toast, the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azazel</ENAMEX> will die unless it can find a new body
within a radius of "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> cubits."

            
               Fallen moves along at
a creepy and compelling pace as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobbes</ENAMEX> learns the identity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azazel</ENAMEX>, pursues
him from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to the next, and tries to outwit him so that he can lethally
strand his spirit. But--wait a minute--why is all this happening? Why, if you
were an evil sprite like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azazel</ENAMEX>, would you leave clues for the cagey <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobbes</ENAMEX> to
follow in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? Wouldn't you just as soon go undetected, as you have
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of time</TIMEX>? I can't remember a movie with more style and less
motivation. Fallen works feverishly to keep you distracted from its
hollow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> but, like a lot of movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, it starts to self-destruct
well before you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> cubits away from the theater.

         
      
   
