
   
   
      
         
            

            
               ASK
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRUDENCE</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, drawing on her rich experience of life, will answer questions
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. She will respond to questions about manners, personal
relations, politics, economics, and other subjects. Questions should be sent to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
They should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your
letter to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Is
there a cure for unrequited love? Also, could you fully explain the law of
diminishing returns? And, while you're at it, please share your opinion of the
plays of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too Much Time on Her</ENAMEX>
HandsSeattle
            

            Dear Too
Much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>,

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> cure for unrequited love
is requited love. There are other cures also, such as devotion to the study of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX> language. If you are reflecting a personal problem, remember that
unrequited love is not fatal. As someone said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> have died from time to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX> have eaten them, but not for love." This applies to women
also.

            The law of diminishing
returns says that if the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> input applied to a production process is
increased, the yield will not increase proportionately. For example, if your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">boyfriend</ENAMEX> sends you a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>, he will get more return than if he
sent you a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1-pound</NUMEX> box, but not twice as much return.

            When I
was young I felt it necessary to pretend that I understood and liked the plays
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX>. I no longer do.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
diminishingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               You
have wisdom. Please tell me: Do you see an end to human suffering? If not, why?
If so, how will it unfold?
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,--Jil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina</ENAMEX>,

            That much wisdom, or that
kind of wisdom, I don't claim to have. My judgment, for which I make no serious
claims, is that there will not be an end to human suffering. You can look at it
in an evolutionist kind of way and say that suffering is the stimulus to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adaptation</ENAMEX> and there is no reason to foresee an end to adaptation, or if the
adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> is complete, they will have ceased to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. You can
look at it in a religious way and say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> were destined to suffer for
some sin, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Adam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>'s. But these religions typically hold out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> of an end to suffering, either for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> or for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>,
although they then cease to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.

            Maybe
suffering is a definition of "human." But adaptation and hope are also
definitions of human. Suffering need not overwhelm. To go to the mundane, I
quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ethel Merman in Annie Get Your Gun</ENAMEX> .

            Taking stock
of what I have and what I haven't,

            What do I
find?

            A healthy balance on the
credit side.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, brightly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Why are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who
are so opposed to poverty programs in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so in favor of bailouts for
crippled economies all over the globe? Especially at a time when welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> are being forced off the rolls and told that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will no
longer subsidize those who refuse to help themselves. And at a time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> are being further disenfranchised because
their elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are accused of being poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public servants</ENAMEX> and bad
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Now I read that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis was brought on by corruption, nepotism, bad loans, poor
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living above their means on borrowed dollars.
Am I missing something here? If not, why are all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>, who've turned a cold shoulder to our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX>
government, falling all over each other to rush cash to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seoul</ENAMEX> and roll over
their loans? After all, the "lazy," "poor," and "inept" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are
having to pay for their sins.
            

            
               Is
this a global repeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & L</ENAMEX> fiasco? Does everybody pay except the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who built those glorious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of cards, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> whose reckless
loans allowed them to do it?
            

            
               --JoeFort <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Md.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>,

            You ask hard questions, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> is not sure that even she can answer them to your satisfaction.
However, she will try.

            Despite the recent changes
in the welfare system, federal, state, and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> will still be
spending large amounts of money to assist poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--not only through welfare
but also through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, food stamps, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Security Income</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>. The reason given for the recent changes in the
welfare program for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> was that the program as it was, promoted
self-destructive behavior--dropping out of school, dropping out of the work
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>, and having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> present. New conditions were imposed
on the receipt of welfare in the belief that these conditions would lead to
behavior that was better for many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would have received
benefits under the former system.

            We don't know yet how valid
that belief is, but there is sufficient evidence to support the view that it is
valid for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Probably the best guess is that under the new system
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will be better off and some worse off, and no one knows the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">relative</ENAMEX> numbers. We shall see. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> hopes and believes that if the number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> significantly worse off turns out to be large, adjustments will be
made in the program.

            Now, as for assistance to
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>: You should recognize that despite all the attention
"foreign aid" receives, expenditures for it in the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">postwar period</TIMEX> have
been tiny relative to the size of the federal budget. Only a small part of the
aid now being extended to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> will come out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> budget, and that aid
is being provided in the form of a loan and in the expectation that it will be
repaid. Like the changes in the welfare program, the aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> is being
provided on the basis of certain beliefs that may or may not turn out to be
correct. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> the belief is that there is danger of a panic, a
flight from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> currency in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> economy would be forced
down to a level far below its true potential. The thought is that if the panic
is averted by the provision of temporary help, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> economy will recover
to a level at which it is able to repay its debts.

            This, also, may turn out to
be a mistake. There are well-informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think that the world economy
would be better off if no aid was provided and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX> and the
international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who lent money there were forced to make their own
adjustment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> doesn't know which of these views is correct, but she
understands the thinking of those who conclude that the risks of not giving
help are greater than the risks of giving help.

            There are
some inescapable losses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> situation, and the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> who
invested there will share in those losses. But the hope is that the aid will
avoid losses that are caused only by irrational panic.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
tentatively

         
      
   
