
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
residents sans country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at their
restored <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> I wanted to thank them, but
when my fingers went instinctively to the e-mail "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Send</ENAMEX>" button, I wondered if
e-mail was socially correct for such purposes.
            

            
               What
are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s thoughts on the evolution of e-mail and the social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graces</ENAMEX>--assuming there is any connection?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polite</ENAMEX> but
Puzzled
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po</ENAMEX>,

            Prudie supposes if you're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Astor</ENAMEX>, e-mail might not cut it, but the handwritten <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and butter
note is starting to seem like the whalebone corset, given the modern
possibilities. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX> mail is not always reliable, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graces</ENAMEX> have substituted the fax, ensuring both timeliness and actual
arrival. Since e-mail is even quicker and just as dependable as faxing, by all
means feel at ease being electronically grateful. It is, after all, the thought
that counts. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is assuming your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> are wired.)

            A good
test for you to figure out your comfort level about this matter is to imagine
how you would respond to receiving a thank-you note on the Net.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, currently

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am fortunate enough to
have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>-in-law: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who gave birth to my wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and one who
is married to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. I get along famously with both of them, and they get
along famously with each other ... I thought.
            

            
               Recently, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepmother</ENAMEX>-in-law has taken to saying some unkind words about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>.
On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> occasions these were said just to me, and on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> occasion they were said
in front of others. Both times I quickly changed the subject but felt as though
I had been punched in the stomach.
            

            
               I feel
the need to express my intolerance of this type of behavior, but it is
imperative that it be done in the nicest way possible. How do you suggest I
approach the topic? I want to be understood perfectly but also don't want to
cause problems with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepmother</ENAMEX>-in-law.
            

            
               --Please sign meTrying
To Be Graceful
            

            Dear
Try,

            You are admirable in trying
to head off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> Nos. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX> from morphing into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> of the
family. Why don't you try something like this: "I know you and (insert name)
have a very nice friendship, and I can't figure out where your new ,
unfriendly remarks are coming from. Perhaps I am misunderstanding you. It has
always meant so much to (insert <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s name) that the social
relationship was cordial. It would be a shame to change the balance and make
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>) unhappy."

            With this
approach you will not be attacking her, you will be offering her a benign
directional signal, and she will get the message. If she does not take the
hint, then you and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will dope out a way to up the ante.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, disarmingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               May I offer a comment on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impatiently Waiting</ENAMEX>'s situation (her Steady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
says he's "not ready" for marriage)? If so, it's this: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ultimatums</ENAMEX> and head
games are a terrible way to start a marriage. What you need instead is a
heart-to-heart, not about the marriage potential in your relationship but about
where each of you is going individually and what each wishes to achieve. This
kind of conversation will give you more information about your place in his
heart.
            

            
               At the
same time, you need to ascertain why you want to marry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>. Are you looking
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">security</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>? Or maybe you just think it's time to get married? Then
assess whether the reasons are specific to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX> and worthy of your own lifelong
commitment. If your desire is to spend forever with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>, tell him
so--bluntly--with no allusion to marriage. If he seems even a tad lukewarm to
the idea, run for the hills. But if he passionately agrees, start in on forever
and shut up about a wedding. More than likely it will pop up before you know
it.
            

            
               --Been There
            

            Dear
Been,

            What wise
words for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in romantic turmoil! It was good of you to take the time
to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>. I suspect you would agree that it is easier to ride a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> in
the direction in which it is going.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
philosophically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am writing on my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s e-mail password. When he left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> (he was treated for
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> and a sleep disorder) he got an e-mail address for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he met
there. It was a secret affair for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> until I found out. Then he said
they were "just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>." He said he could talk to her on subjects he can't
talk to me about--intellectual things--claiming that I can't give him what he
desires on a cerebral level. Was I jealous? Hell yes, and hurt!
            

            
               I should tell you that a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> he had an impotence problem and couldn't manage on a physical
level, so I got into cybersex. I considered it enhanced masturbation and think
it saved our marriage. And we had counseling.
            

            
               So ...
I agreed to let him have his "intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>." Now he wants to meet her
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, "just to have a chat." I expressed to him that having an e-mail
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> is fine with me, but going out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> without me is a major
problem. I checked his mailbox and found he had deleted many messages to her.
He is also being secretive and in denial that this situation is unfair. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> are anonymous, and so am <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX> She is not anonymous--and an ex-therapist,
yet. I don't have a degree, but I know it is wrong when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> goes outside his
marriage to fill a need, whether it be intellectual or sexual. I am feeling
helpless. And now he claims I am ugly when I'm jealous. Can I get off this
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roller coaster</ENAMEX> from hell?
            

            
               --Hurt in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Hurt,

            At least he didn't say you
were cute when you were angry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is going to lay it on the line. Your
relationship sounds like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s breakfast. It is full of all kinds of things
that are not very appetizing.

            Since you
say you've had counseling, we can skip that option. Cyberflings, yours and his,
are just symptoms of a marriage that is not working. The writing is on the
screen: The elements that make a decent marriage are no longer there. Prudie
understands that you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are between a rock and a hard drive but recommends
that you sign off with as little rancor as you can manage.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
electronically

         
      
   
