
   
   
      
         
            

            
               ASK
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRUDENCE</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, drawing on her rich experience of life, will answer questions
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. She will respond to questions about manners, personal
relations, politics, economics, and other subjects. Questions should be sent to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
They should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your
letter to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               The
papers are filled with stories about the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX>. The stories
list other family occurrences that show the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> as a hard-luck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. It
is, for example, listed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> tragedy that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to die in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> driven by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> is walking by and a busload of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> die
in a crash, it would make the list of tragedies longer. Is this an example of
good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellsworth M.</ENAMEX>
ButlerBoonton, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>,

            I agree
that the word "tragedy" is used without discrimination in reference to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> family. The death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and the
assassinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX> were tragedies. As far as I can see, most of
the subsequent "problems" were the result of their own recklessness or worse.
Since they are so prominent and have been blessed with so much wealth and
public adulation, they have a responsibility to be role models of sensible
behavior. It is unfortunate that they do not see it that way.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, sadly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have
met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whom I am attracted to. She is attracted to me and we would like to
see more of each other. The problem is we are both married. The attraction is
more than plutonic, it is also physical. What would you recommend?
            

            
               --Troubled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vegas</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Troubled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>,

            Your letter is indeed
ambiguous. You say that the attraction between this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and you is "more than
plutonic, it is also physical." In my old dictionary, "plutonic" means "of
Pluto, infernal." I will assume that you mean "platonic." But then I don't know
whether you mean that the attraction is physical or that the consummated
relationship is physical and sexual.

            I will assume that you would
like to have sexual relations but have not done so. My advice is not to do it
unless you are prepared to leave--i.e., divorce--your present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason
is that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will probably learn of it, and when she does there will be
the devil to pay. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> reason is that even if she doesn't find out, you
will know, and you will probably go around with a burden of guilt that will
sour your life and your relations with both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. But there is a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, most
important, reason. The relationship you are longing for is wrong. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX> that everyone knows is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thou</ENAMEX> shalt not commit adultery."
It may be often violated, but hardly anyone in our culture denies that it is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commandment</ENAMEX>. If our behavior is to be governed only by cost-benefit
calculations, and not by moral standards, we are in pretty bad shape.

            Whether
you should leave your present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> I cannot tell without knowing much more than
you have revealed. I urge you to be very cautious about it. It is easy to be
attracted to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, whose faults you do not know, who does not know your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faults</ENAMEX>, and who has never asked you to take out the garbage or mow the lawn.
But you have to think of what the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> will be like after she has become
the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Also, you haven't said whether you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> have any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Their interests deserve a lot of weight.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, Mosaically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have a long-distance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>. I've only seen him <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and I'm beginning to
dislike him. However, he constantly phones me and sent me a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
present. Should I send him a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas present</TIMEX> or would this encourage him even
more?
            

            
               I want
to break up with him.
            

            
               --Desperately
            

            Dear
Desperately,

            There
must be something more here than meets the eye. On the facts presented, you
have no problem. Don't send him a gift. Send his gift back.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, simply

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I
received a small <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> gift from a workmate. I thanked her when she handed
me the gift. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> thinks that a thank-you note is appropriate, but I think
that the verbal thank you satisfies my obligation. What do you think?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,Bunsworth
            

            Dear
Bunsworth,

            You made
an "oral" expression of gratitude, which was, of course, also "verbal." That is
enough unless the gift was extraordinary. If the gift was an item of houseware,
like a microwave, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> should write a thank-you note.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
sufficiently

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have
read a few of your comments, and you do indeed sound like a thoroughly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">courteous</ENAMEX> and sensible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. I just have an idea I should like to broadcast
via you: In public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> finds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s section, the adult
reading section, and the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>'s section (read: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>). Isn't this a
kind and gentle way of referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the teen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>? I thought it
would gently help those young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to begin to accept the idea that they are
growing up and should soon become grown-ups, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. That's all.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Louine</ENAMEX> King
            

            
               P.S. I
hate the idea that the word "adult" so often refers to pornographic things.
There goes another perfectly good word, unless we can recapture it with
dignity! Thanks for your (electronic) ear.
            

            Dear
Louine,

            I thank you for your
comment. Indeed, it is important that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> should recognize that they are
becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, and that they are not in some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> where they have full
capabilities and no responsibilities. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tradition, as I understand
it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 13</TIMEX> and go through rites intended to
impress that upon them. The signs you observe in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> are a small step
toward making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> aware of their status.

            The use
of the word "adult" to rate some movies and, I suppose, other forms of
entertainment, is, I agree, often inappropriate. I think we should have two
categories--"adult" and "immature."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, agedly

         
      
   
