
   
   
      
         
            Narcissus-ism

            You can't avoid daffodils in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, and you wouldn't want to. With their long ruffled trumpets and bright
petals splayed like the rays of the sun, these unabashed bloomers give of
themselves freely and ask little in return. Even the hardest among us feel like
better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for taking pleasure in their charms.

            My
current favorite is shyer than most. It's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Narcissus Hawera</ENAMEX> , and
it bloomed for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>. It's small, rarely
exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 inches</NUMEX>. It's a translucent, pale yellow, with a head that dips
slightly, beckoning you to lift it with a finger to get a better look. It has a
short, straight snub nose with the tiniest unevenness along the rim. Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perianth</ENAMEX> is reflexed, meaning that the petals sweep back from the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cup</NUMEX> and twist
a little, so that the flower looks as if it's being blown by a gentle wind. A
curve at the top of the stem causes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawera</ENAMEX> to flutter, giving it a
disarming nervousness.

            Despite seeming so vulnerable, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawera</ENAMEX> is sturdy and
not at all fussy. It's an excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performer</ENAMEX>, often yielding several bell-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> on a single stem and blooming for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. Content almost anywhere, it
multiplies freely. It has a sweet, delicate fragrance, unlike the heady odor
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narcissuses</ENAMEX> give off.

            I first
saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawera</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX> in a garden outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, where it had been
planted along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of a stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in long drifts interspersed with
sweeps of fern. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Jekyll</ENAMEX>
was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to suggest pairing ferns with daffodils, pointing out that just
as the daffodil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">foliage</ENAMEX> begins to brown and die back, the fern hits its stride
and covers the mess. This particular fern was fine and lacy and looked fetching
next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawera</ENAMEX> . I scratched its name into my notebook and actually
remembered to order some in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, I saw it
coming up in a pleasing manner from between the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> of a garden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX>.

            
I set aside some of my own bulbs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>,
potting them to bring indoors to bloom in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>. Although slow to appear,
taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly two months</TIMEX> to flower after being brought inside, Hawera
was glorious when it finally arrived. It ruined for me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> varieties of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">daffodils I</ENAMEX> already had flowering. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Narcissus Topolino</ENAMEX> , I had tried
because it was said to be an easy forcer, and it was--eagerly blooming in a
vulgar fashion with a trumpet too long for its small face. The other,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Narcissus Diskcissal</ENAMEX> , was said to be fragrant, and it was--too fragrant.
Plus, it was a splotchy yellow with white leaching through it. Once the elegant
Hawera ventured forth, the others were exiled to the compost pile.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawera</ENAMEX> is a late bloomer in the garden as well, and while other
varieties of narcissus have been opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> garden, there is
still no sign of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawera</ENAMEX> . Daffodils are categorized as early-, middle-,
or late-blooming, and if you choose a few from each, you can hope for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, and you may actually get them. When it gets <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>, as it
invariably does, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> worry for their daffodils. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daffodils</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cold-weather creatures</ENAMEX>, and for the most part, the chillier it is, the longer
they'll stick around. The thing to worry about now is what bulbs to order for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a quick review of daffodils.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gardeners</ENAMEX> who really have it together place their orders
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX>, sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between June and August</TIMEX>, while the rest of us scramble in the
fall. By then, who can even remember what the garden looked like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>?
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, I'm determined to make my selection while I'm still looking at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">spring</ENAMEX>'s display, deciding what I need, and how many, and where it will all go.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for some planting tips.)

            
Unfortunately, the fall catalogs don't arrive until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-May</TIMEX> at the earliest.
The thing to do is to take notes now on what you want and snap pictures of your
garden to remind yourself where to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>. If you don't trust
yourself even to do this, you can order now, using <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>'s catalog. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nurseries</ENAMEX> will send you their latest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> if you don't have it. Regardless of
when you place your order, the nursery will ship the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bulbs</ENAMEX> at the proper time
for planting in your area, so if you do it now, you can forget about it until
later.

            
Many of the best catalogs--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daffodil Mart</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Engelen</ENAMEX>--don't have pictures but compensate with useful line drawings and
excellent descriptions. Either find yourself a reference book such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guide to Bulbs</ENAMEX> , or use one of the catalogs with color photos
for reference, so you can take advantage of the picture-less catalogs' high
quality, good selection, and cheaper prices. (The nicer the pictures, the
higher the prices.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Scheepers</ENAMEX> catalog manages to have good photos and
good prices because it is the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Engelen</ENAMEX>. Get both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">catalogs</ENAMEX>, because they work well together, and you can order from either or
both depending on the quantities you plan to purchase. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Engelen</ENAMEX> can offer
lower prices because it deals in larger quantities.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daffodil Mart</ENAMEX>
will be offering similar discounts for really large orders--say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> of
something--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> daffodils in a woodland setting or scattered about a lawn
aren't really that many. You can also get a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to order together.
Both of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will have lower prices on many items <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because
the dollar is strong against the guilder, and most bulbs are grown in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>.

            It would
be hard for a beginning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> to go wrong with daffodils. They are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foolproof</ENAMEX>, long-lived, inexpensive, and repellent to animal pests. They have no
downside and are a quiet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for good in the world.

            
               If you
didn't click through to the internal links, click for a daffodil review and for
some planting tips.
            

         
      
   
