
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Degrees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Bacon</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puzzle No. 4</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedrich von Hayek</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salma Hayek</ENAMEX>"
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanna</ENAMEX> play? Click for the
rules.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s puzzle was
submitted by 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader Greg Ransom</ENAMEX>, a devotee of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Prize-winning Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedrich von Hayek</ENAMEX>. Ransom challenges you to
get from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Hayek</ENAMEX> to this page celebrating movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siren</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salma Hayek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Desperado , Fools Rush In</ENAMEX> , and
the forthcoming Dogma .

            We did it in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> links. If
you can tie or beat that, e-mail your solution (with instructions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URLs</ENAMEX>) to
FrancisBacon@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. (All submissions will become the
property of 
                  Slate
                and will be published at 
                  Slate
               's
discretion. 
                  Slate
                may publish your name on its site in connection
with your submission.)

            Results will be announced
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 5 p.m. PT</TIMEX>, along with a new puzzle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> are
also invited to submit their own puzzles (along with a solution path).

            Happy surfing!

            
               Solution
to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Puzzle No. 3</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yo Mama to Yo-Yo Ma</ENAMEX>"
            

            Last week
we asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to get from this
page of "yo mama" jokes to this page on cellist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yo-Yo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> links or less. Solutions came
from as far afield as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Shirriff</ENAMEX>, managed the task in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just seven</TIMEX> links. Here's how he did it:

            From Yo
Mama, click music . This takes you to ...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX>
Page. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click Sony Music WWW Server</ENAMEX> to go ...

            here. Then,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">click Cool Links</ENAMEX> . You will find yourself ...

            at this site,
where you should click unfURLed .

            From here, click <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> in the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists</ENAMEX> Index," ...

            and in the browsable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> index, click <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yo-Yo</ENAMEX> , which will lead you ...

            here. Finally, click <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yo-Yo Ma Biography</ENAMEX> .

            You're done in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> links.

            
Congratulations to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shirriff</ENAMEX> for running <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> quicker than everybody
else.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
