
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picasso Rules</ENAMEX>

            At some
point during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Richardson</ENAMEX>'s superb biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> you begin to feel
grateful to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>, not for the pleasure it affords the consumer, but for the
outlet it offers the psychopath. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX> once explained that "in art one must
kill one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>," and his life as told by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> plays out as a series of
these little metaphorical murders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX> whose work <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> is unable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dismiss</ENAMEX> (not many: he once described the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine</ENAMEX> ceiling as "a vast sketch by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daumier</ENAMEX>") he cannibalizes. He sketches one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gauguin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tahitian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and
signs the portrait "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Picasso</ENAMEX>." He copies the signatures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinlen</ENAMEX> and
Forain over and again like some angry shaman. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> describing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>
racing back and forth between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Louvre</ENAMEX> says he
"paces around and around like a hound in search of game."

            In the
current exhibit of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s early work on display in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> (which is pegged to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s first volume), the walls wreak
havoc with art history: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso consuming Symbolism; Picasso</ENAMEX> eating
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Impressionism; Picasso devouring Fauvism</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the myths of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
is that he could never have been anything other than what he was. But if you
take <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and transport it to late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, it is easier to imagine it doing almost anything except painting
pictures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> with the predatory instincts that led <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> to become an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> in late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> become takeover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> or
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> or filmmakers in our culture.

            The life and the work are bound together by this single
character trait: not so much the instinct to create as the compulsion to erase.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> is unable to abide even his own tradition. As soon as he
settles into a new style of painting (or a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, or a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>), he is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contriving</ENAMEX> to destroy it (or her). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s account does not so much excuse
the bad behavior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> as use it to explain the career: The art was
great at least in part because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> was flawed.

            This makes
all the more puzzling a strain in the critical response not only to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
but also to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>: a tendency to dismiss his art because of his life. So far
as I can tell, the trend was set in motion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade or so ago</TIMEX> when Arianna
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stassinopoulos Huffington</ENAMEX> published her sexual history of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>. You can see
it gathering steam in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Surviving Picasso , the 1996 Merchant</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX> film
that views <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso pathetically</ENAMEX>, through the unsympathetic eyes of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Françoise Gilot</ENAMEX>. But it reached a new level of respectability <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Gopnik</ENAMEX>, reviewed the second
volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s life of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gopnik</ENAMEX> turns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>: If <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s art is
bad, he argues, it is so at least in part because <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> was a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. This
is not exactly a new line of art criticism, but it's rare to find it taking
root at such altitudes. (The piece recently won a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Magazine Award</ENAMEX>.)
And, given the violently mixed reaction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> exhibition
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX> writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , "I think, from the
show, that if he had died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX>, before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Demoiselles</ENAMEX> d'Avignon, he would
be remembered as a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> tier Symbolist."), you can't help but wonder if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gopnik</ENAMEX> has finally figured out the way to dull the enthusiasm <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> feel
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>--by playing to their self-righteousness. After a long passage
detailing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s crimes against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gopnik</ENAMEX> rolls up his sleeves:

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> was a creep
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> gives him, out of a rather touching and, in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, uncommon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>'s loyalty, too large a benefit of the doubt on the
question. ... Who cares? Does it affect <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s art, or the way we see it?
Here the reviewer needs to drop all pretense of magisterial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX>, jump down
from the bench, and start testifying. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last spring</TIMEX> I went for a walk in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s vast show, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s
portraits.

            A single
visit to an exhibition! All becomes suddenly clear! "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s misogyny was in
evidence on every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gopnik</ENAMEX> writes. "And, along with misogyny, there was
its Siamese twin, an oversweetened vision of family life in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s implied vacancy is really <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>'s."

            It was only a matter of time before family values entered
art criticism. But who would have thought it would be imported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ? It's hard to think of a clearer sign that old-fashioned Comstockian
attitudes are once again in vogue, this time with a new twist. The modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">moralist</ENAMEX> lacks the courage of his convictions. He is reluctant to attack the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s morality directly. Instead, he attacks his morality in the guise of
attacking his art. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> is using the life as a weapon against the
work.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> sign
of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gopnik</ENAMEX> is up to is his tendency, when he is on the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, to err on the side of the prosecution. In making the case against
Picasso you might think there would be no need to exaggerate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s
crimes against his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gopnik</ENAMEX> does, describing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> as "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coward</ENAMEX>, who sat out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> world wars while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were suffering and dying,"
adding that "he may have been right to do this in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First War</ENAMEX>, but he did it
again, in the same way, in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>." ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1881</TIMEX>," notes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fenton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> . "To accuse a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of
cowardice for not having joined up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX> when he was in his late fifties
strikes me as a complete novelty, and it would have been a novelty to those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who, on the liberation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, flocked to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> as
a place of pilgrimage.")

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gopnik</ENAMEX>'s bad faith extends to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography</ENAMEX>, which he faults (unbelievably) for treating <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> too kindly.
Early in his article--which he has called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Escaping Picasso: The Great Master</ENAMEX>
That Never Was"--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> reminds us that there was a time when he devoted
himself to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> studies, how the most trivial academic revelation once
caused him to run off "to a nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> to drink my very first <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX> on the
rocks. ... I passed out and had to be carried home." But he is older <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. He
has put his academic past behind him. He is able to see the world as it is. He
is able to see that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> have been covering up the crimes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> to
protect him from justice. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s need to make <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> into a serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and an honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (instead of the inspired poetic rascal he actually
was) deforms, above all, his account of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," he
writes.

            What is peculiar about this
is that much of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gopnik</ENAMEX> knows about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> he knows from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>. It
would be more true to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gopnik</ENAMEX>'s need to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso as a rascal</ENAMEX> deforms
his view of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s art. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are working with the same set of facts and
accusations. The difference is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> pleads for understanding while
Gopnik brays for outrage.

            Gopnik dismisses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX> as "just another kind of celebrity worship." His piece proves this
point nicely. His is exactly the approach of every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity journalist</ENAMEX> to his
subject. Why bother with the art on its terms when you can have it on your
own?

         
      
   
