
   
   
      
         
            

            
               ASK
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRUDENCE</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, drawing on her rich experience of life, will answer questions
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. She will respond to questions about manners, personal
relations, politics, economics, and other subjects. Questions should be sent to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
They should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your
letter to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Are there any ticklish
questions of etiquette attached to wearing a wire and recording conversations
with one's supposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> for the benefit of, say, a special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>?
            

            

               Incidentally, at a time when it is suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is living
out his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX> difficulties--only it's interns thankfully and
not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Guides</ENAMEX>--is it a good idea for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to stage a small war with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yours</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wired</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tapped</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Internally AmusedSydney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Wired</ENAMEX>,
Tapped, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amused</ENAMEX>,

            Whether
it's a ticklish question depends on where one wears the wire. He'd better not
attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>. Too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, debugged,
tapped-out, and appalled

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have
a problem that often leaves me frustrated and angry at myself: I am very bad at
small talk. It's amazing to me how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can slip in and out of frivolous talk
(though I know it serves a socially useful purpose) with seeming ease. No
matter how hard I try, I feel that I say the wrong thing or something
inappropriate. What concerns me most, however, is that I'll soon be entering
the work world, and the ability to make light conversation is paramount in
business relationships. Do you have any suggestions?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.S.Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.S.</ENAMEX>,

            You are making too much of
this. What everyone wants in a conversationalist is not a good talker but a
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX>. You could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>, and no one would go home from a party
saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> was witty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>." Many would go home saying, "I was sure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">witty</ENAMEX> tonight."

            Cultivate listening, laughing
at the right points, and occasionally saying: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right on</ENAMEX>!" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How true</ENAMEX>!" In
business it is not the glib <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talker</ENAMEX> who gets the most respect. It is the person
who can sit quietly through a meeting and then cogently synthesize the
issues.

            Don't
worry about what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are thinking about you. Mostly they are not
thinking about you at all. Don't worry about saying the wrong thing. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't know what the right thing is. If what you say is bizarre enough,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will think that you are very deep.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
consolingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years ago</TIMEX>, whenever we
bought something using cash in a retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> would return our
change by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> placing the coins safely in the palm of our hand, followed by
any bills. The receipt, of course, would have already been tucked inside, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stapled</ENAMEX> to, the bag. This way, we could easily grip the coins while putting the
extra bills away into our wallets, and then drop the coins into our pockets or
coin purses.
            

            
               These
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, it seems the standard procedure is to hand out the bills <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, followed
by the receipt, and then the coins, perched precariously on top. We are then
left standing there to sort out this unwieldy stack. When and why did this
practice start, and who could we contact to try to get it changed?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purchasing</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Purchasing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>,

            You indeed have a problem.
It is not universal, however. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> has just been through a cafeteria line
where the cashier gave change in coins <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and then in bills. But the
practice of which you complain is very common, especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarkets</ENAMEX>. The
reason for it is to speed up the checkout process. If the cashier is to give
you coins <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, he must either make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> passes at you, first with the coins
and then with the bills, or he must hold the coins in his hand while he fishes
the bills out of the cash register. In the latter case the risk that he will
drop the coins is increased. By doing it his way the risk that you will drop
the coins is increased. That is what we mean by "the service economy." The
customer performs the service.

            There are several ways to
cope with this problem:

            a) You can come with an
assortment of coins and pay with the exact change.

            b) You can deposit the coins
in the bottle near the cash register, where they will be collected to help the
needy.

            c) You can pay with a credit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX>, irritating the hell out of everyone in line behind you.

            d) You can stuff the wad of
coins, bills, and receipts in your pocket or purse to be sorted out at home
later. (That is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>'s method.)

            If you
want to get the practice changed, I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> suggestions for you: You can write
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>; I am sure that he would be glad to attack this evil inflicted
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> by the capitalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exploiters</ENAMEX>. Or, you can write to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>;
he might include a legal prohibition of the practice in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with
Trivial <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Irritations Act</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
unchangeably

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have
a silly little problem that I want to share with you. The problem is that I am
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> who has never kissed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> (other than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>) in
my whole life, since it is not a norm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> I come from. So now that I
am in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, how should I go about overcoming my shyness and nervousness
about the possibility of having to kiss a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, or even having to ask for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kiss</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Confused</ENAMEX> and
Pondering
            

            Dear
Confused and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pondering</ENAMEX>,

            Try it,
you'll like it. You ask what you should do if you ever "have" to kiss a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
If that situation arises, you will have no problem. Perhaps you will "have" to
kiss her because she has kissed you. In that case your spontaneous, unpondered
reaction will be to kiss her back. Your problem will not be hesitancy about
kissing but addiction to it.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
confidently

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have
the hots for a pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> where I eat. She is so
beautiful, and I would love to ask her out, but I am shy, and she is always
working when I see her. I want to know how to approach her and pop the
question--would she be willing to go out with me?--without looking like a fool
and without disturbing her at work. If you have any ideas, they would be
greatly appreciated.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncertain</ENAMEX> and
Unsure
            

            Dear
Uncertain and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unsure</ENAMEX>,

            The only
correction for shyness is to summon up your courage and do it. If your
attraction to her is very strong it will overcome your shyness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> are
seldom offended by an expression of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s interest in them if it is expressed
in a respectful manner. You should, however, drop the word "hots" from your
thinking about her.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
encouragingly

         
      
   
