
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puzzle No. 8</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frikik to Free Kick</ENAMEX>"
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanna</ENAMEX> play? Click for the
rules.

            This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s puzzle comes from 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Degrees of Francis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacon" devotee Tamara Glenny</ENAMEX>. Here it is, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glenny</ENAMEX>'s own words:

            This one
is based on a site that someone linked to in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" for a joke. The idea is
to go from the (dirty) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> meaning of the word "frikik" to the official
definition of "free kick" in the game of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>. You start at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off-Color</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> and scroll down to the letter F to find
the extra meaning that frikik (free kick) carries in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s
warning: Some of the language on this page is mildly offensive. ] You have
to end up at the official <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FIFA Laws of the Game</ENAMEX> section featuring the free-kick rule.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glenny</ENAMEX> went from offensive
kicks to offensive kicks in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> links. If you can tie or beat that, e-mail your
solution (with instructions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URLs</ENAMEX>) to FrancisBacon@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 14</TIMEX>. (All submissions will become the property of

                  Slate
                and will be published at 
                  Slate
               's discretion.

                  Slate
                may publish your name on its site in connection with your
submission.)

            Results will be announced
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 16</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 5 p.m. PT</TIMEX>, along with a new puzzle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> are
also encouraged to submit their own puzzles (with a solution path).

            Happy
surfing!

            
               Solution
to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Puzzle No. 7</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Georges Feydeau to Celine Dion</ENAMEX>"
            

            Last week
we challenged you to go from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georges Feydeau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> farceur , to Celine
Dion, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">farceuse</ENAMEX> , in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> links. Though no one could beat
it, a gaggle of puzzle-solvers tied our score: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael C. Miller</ENAMEX> (who did it
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara Glenny</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Harvey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Nussbaumer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Painter</ENAMEX> (who
wrote in all the way from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Ruthfield</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. Vijay</ENAMEX>. Here's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruthfield</ENAMEX>'s solution:

            This one ended up being
surprisingly easy! We start with the fine review of a shockingly funny comedy about eye <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. From here,
we go to the bottom to the semi-compass and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">click Jam</ENAMEX>! to go to ...

            this page. From there
we follow the left column down and click <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Encyclopedia</ENAMEX> in the
Databases category. This leads to ...

            this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, which provides links to some excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and also to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celine Dion</ENAMEX>. Not bad at all!

            
Congratulations to all our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>. I believe that your hearts will go on.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
