
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I have been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX>. Everything about our relationship is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>, except for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very minor problem: We sleep in a king-size bed, and I
feel we both might sleep better in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> double beds. (I would for sure.) I am
thinking of a setup like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in I Love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> , where they slept in the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> but in separate beds. We both move around a lot in our sleep, and
I really don't like it when a toenail pokes me somewhere unpleasant just as I
am drifting off. I hesitate to bring it up with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, because I don't want
to hurt her feelings and have her think I don't want to be near her, and I
don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to think we are even weirder than they already
believe we are (married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>). I would appreciate any
suggestions.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSR</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Walton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dear F</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> can relate, having
been socked a time or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> by the beloved when he's dead to the world. A good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">night</ENAMEX>'s sleep, however, should be your paramount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, and not everyone is a
neat sleeper.

            A single
bed is no barometer of a relationship. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (and
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>) that you are as crazy about her as ever but
think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> beds might improve sleep for both of you. And don't forget to point
out that "visiting" can certainly spice up the nighttime situation.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, conjugally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I wake
up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> with a terrible thought that leaves me so ashamed
I feel I should be sent to the moral equivalent of a re-education <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. For a
long time I've wondered why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, who once promised to tell us the
whole truth about l'affaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> , is so silent while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is
active at the meanest level in riling a sizable portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> with
stonewalling tactics. Truly, I believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is in the best of hands, but
how do I rid myself of these impure thoughts?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashamed</ENAMEX> and
Embarrassed
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ash,</ENAMEX>

            If you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, you
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confess</ENAMEX>. If you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, you simply hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> comes to terms
with his heat-seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>.

            As to why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> promised an explanation that seems not to be forthcoming,
this is apparently the strategy he thinks best for self-protection. If silence
is golden, it is also sometimes the best way to maintain decorum. And really,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">dear Ash</ENAMEX>, what would you care to hear him say? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks this might be one
union we do not need to hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of. And regarding the stonewalling
staff, just think of them as the collective <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Cop</ENAMEX>. As for feeling ashamed and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embarrassed</ENAMEX>, you have much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Try to get a good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">night</ENAMEX>'s sleep.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, somnolently

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Hi! This is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
writing to you. I am <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> and work in an embassy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>. I
need your advice.
            

            
               I have been telling lies
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, basically because I want him to think highly of me. It's not that I
lack confidence or that I feel I'm not bright--I speak <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> languages. I've
been lying because I had this bitterness toward a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, who made me
feel nothing about me was good enough.
            

            
               The
point is, I think this new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> has fallen for me, and I want to be truthful. I
think he ought to know, not because I have fallen for him as well, but simply
to do the right thing. What do you think?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Jak,

            Oh what a
tangled web we weave when first we fib to act out against old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you tell this new chap you made up a bunch of stuff for a dumb
reason and want to set the record straight. Make just a short explanation. He
may or may not flee, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees with you that doing the right thing, for
its own sake, has value.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, honestly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Are you
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudy Crowther</ENAMEX> who graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryn Mawr</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'68</TIMEX>? I am <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary O'Hara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kane</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>. Is it proper to ask such a question via e-mail?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yours</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O'Hara</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MO'H</ENAMEX>,

            I am not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudy Crowther</ENAMEX>,
though I wish I had gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryn Mawr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bryn Mawr</ENAMEX> girls being so polite
and smart. And yes, your query is perfectly proper for e-mail. (You should see
some of the questions sent in.)

            It just
dawned on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> that she should perhaps say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryn Mawr</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>" instead of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>," which is, alas, a hint that 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Prudie</ENAMEX> was a little
before the class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'68</NUMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
collegially

         
      
   
