
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Slate readers</ENAMEX>
have expressed regret that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> has abandoned her advice column in favor of
her needlework. Sensitive to the continuing need for guidance among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> has prevailed upon her niece and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">namesake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, to assume the responsibility. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> (as
she is known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) will begin to respond to some of the unanswered
e-mails that have piled up in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>'s queue as well as to new inquiries that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may submit. Like her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will be drawing upon her rich
experience of life in responding to questions about manners, personal
relations, politics, and other subjects. Unlike her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, she does not do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macroeconomics</ENAMEX>--though, in the family tradition, she does do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">needlepoint</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               As
before, you should send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries
should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be
signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
my favorite aunts proposed to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young nieces
when they vacation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>. Ordinarily, I wouldn't give this
matter further thought, but since I've read so much about scandalous behavior
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>, I think maybe they should skip the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and spend
more time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> instead. Mostly I am concerned that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nieces</ENAMEX>'
reputations will suffer when they return home to the inevitable questions from
curious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Please help me: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> or no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle</ENAMEX>
Cautious
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unc</ENAMEX>,

            Oh, by all
means, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels certain that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> are safe from the
alleged scandalous behavior. You do not say how old your nieces are, so just a
small caveat: If they are in the intern age bracket, simply advise them that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> is not on the tour.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
prophylactically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I
couldn't wait to get e-mail at my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, because I hate returning phone calls.
Now I find I hate returning e-mails. What do I do? And what's the proper
etiquette for an e-mail kiss-off? How long can I keep saying, "Oh, I didn't get
it. Can you resend?"
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,--Anxious in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Anxious,

            You have definitely
identified a problem for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. I don't think an etiquette has yet been
formulated for this problem, so here are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">jerry</ENAMEX>-built options: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Ignore
things you wish to ignore, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) fluff off troublesome e's with a brief
reply. Something like "in haste" or "gotta run, but I got your message."

            And, dare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prudie</ENAMEX> say this in an online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>? You can always say that your server
screwed up ... sort of the electronic version of "the dog ate my homework."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, briskly

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               With
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">winter</ENAMEX> comes a most embarrassing problem--incredible static cling. Static
electricity, which not only turns A-line skirts into minis, but also affects
hair and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, resulting in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX> that stands out unattractively, and makes
sparks fly whenever my body touches another. What can one do?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clung</ENAMEX> to in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Clung,</ENAMEX>

            Write to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heloise</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hasn't the faintest idea how to solve this dilemma. However I
do remember that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few nights ago</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> confided that her dress
was clingy and electric, so she wore a light flannel nightgown underneath. She
went on to say that this approach had the added benefit that should someone ask
her to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>, she would be prepared.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, statically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My
boyfriend wears totally unsexy underwear--plain white briefs that are too big
for him and bag in the back. I've tried giving him subtle hints like "I think
boxers are sexy" and "boxers really turn me on," but they just seem to go over
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. I even bought him a pair of boxers, but he just wears them to sleep
in--with his yucky briefs underneath. What can I do?
            

            
               --Turned off in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Turned,

            He wears
the baggy briefs underneath ? I offer you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> suggestions. Since things
are going over his head, try under his nose. Write him a short love note saying
it would mean a lot to you if he--forgive the pun--bagged his lucky underpants
and only wore boxers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, the alternative is to forget it. Would you think
Prudie salacious if she were to suggest that it's what's inside the briefs or
boxers that counts?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, briefly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               In the
initial stages of dating, it is usual to assume that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are probably
dating others. I prefer to describe my other dates as "having plans." I also
take pains so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I date remain clueless about others I may be
dating. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> I am currently seeing has asked me to dinner at a
particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that he's been eager to try. I accepted, but when I
looked up the address, I found it was located in the same (very small) building
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I am seeing. I am on the verge of suggesting
another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, lest I "collide" with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Should I change the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">venue</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dating</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Date,

            Prudie
thinks it would be wonderful to be seen by another swain and cannot
imagine why you would want to pretend to be otherwise dateless in what you
describe as "the initial stages of dating" this new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
strategically

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Postscript From</ENAMEX>
Prudie
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX>,

            I am honored that my dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Prudence</ENAMEX> has entrusted me to continue her service to the lorn of all
stripes. I feel as though I am stepping into the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, as it
were.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Happily,</ENAMEX>
I have no feeling that I am trying to fill her shoes. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX> to tell, Auntie
wears a rather large size.) Being of a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, I may be a little
less delicate in my approach but I hope of no less use to you.

            Yours,--Prudie

         
      
   
