
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.,</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               There
is another bald, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in sales in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. He's located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>.
Whenever I attend a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> sales meeting, there are inevitably several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know me who start talking about how they love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. I
politely tell them I live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, but I get very irritated. As much as I
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">love Mad magazine's "Snappy Answers to Stupid Questions</ENAMEX>," I can never
bring myself to snap at these retards. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the frustration is mine,
when it's they who should be apologizing. Can you offer me some wit to help
diffuse these situations?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Still Black</ENAMEX>, Still
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ShavingLos Angeles</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Still,

            Your letter comes at a
cosmic time for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>, who recently made the mistake you write about. Having
been on the wrong end of the situation, let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> point out that such mistakes
come from unfamiliarity, perhaps thoughtlessness, but not bigotry.

            The rejoinder Prudie
suggests is, granted, an old standby, but it defuses the situation and
everybody gets the message. It is what a prominent black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> said when
Prudie greeted him by another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>'s name: "We all look alike."

            It was
said with wry humor, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> felt <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about as</NUMEX> tall as a toadstool and will
never again be careless in her address, which is, after all, what you're
after, isn't it?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, penitently

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, and both of us share a similar interest, namely politics. However, we are
on completely opposite ends of the political spectrum: She's a liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>
and I'm a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. When we discuss our common interest it turns
into a fiery political debate. We disagree on every issue from gun control to
tax policy to our views on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. I've even considered changing my political
views for her.
            

            

               Recently, I've considered becoming intimate with her, but I don't know how
we would fare as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, considering the area of political tension. Is it
possible to close this political gender gap? How do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Matalin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Carville</ENAMEX> do it?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,Too
Conservative for Her
            

            Dear
Too,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> can relate, though she
doesn't see how you can turn a switch and change your views. Your voter
registration, maybe, but not your views. For you to become a born-again
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> would probably take a deprogrammer.

relationship with someone with wildly divergent politics, it is like walking
with oatmeal in your shoe: It's not easy, but it's possible. The deciding
factor is how the rest of the relationship functions. You might simply agree to
disagree on this one subject.

            As for
those shrinking violets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matalin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville, Prudie</ENAMEX> has a hunch they have
knockdown drag-out fights about their different affiliations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> in mind that
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> thrive on volatility and friction. Now you must figure out if you
are in that category.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, politically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
my pet peeves when dining with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> is the constant thanking that
goes on. When the waiter brings <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cocktails</ENAMEX> for a table of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> there is a
ridiculous rhapsody of "thank you" and "you're welcome." Then there are
appetizers, salads, main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverage refills</ENAMEX>, desserts, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thousand</ENAMEX> thanks for doing one's job? I choose to thank once at the end of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> and to provide a generous tip. I have been a waiter and preferred the
artistry of being both attentive and discreet. The trick is to clear the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX>
plate and place the dinner plate without being noticed.
            

            
               --Sign meNoshing on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Shore</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Nosh,

            Prudie
had no idea about the depth of feeling on the subject of when and how much
thanking of waitpersons is appropriate. Your letter is just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> example. The
fact that you yourself have experienced both positions relative to the dining
chair lends authority to your opinion. Prudie, imagining herself waiting on
tables, concurs that an appreciative gratuity is, indeed, preferable to
repeated thank yous and now considers the problem solved.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, conclusively

            

               
                  Prudie!
               
            

            
               You
racy minx! "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX> caught in a wringer." "Ex post
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fucto</ENAMEX>." Goodness me; what would Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX> say? (Oh yes, and that's not
even counting your comment on "the oatmeal disability," in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 26</TIMEX>
column.) Where will it all end?
            

            
               --Mikeberla
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mi</ENAMEX>,

            As to the
racy minx business, don't you hope it will never end?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
naughtily

         
      
   
