
   
   
      
         
            Protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> haven't
been easy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Secret Service</ENAMEX>. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were blamed for spreading
rumors about marital spats--involving household furniture--between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>. Then they drew jeers for closing part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Avenue</ENAMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> near-assaults on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last fall</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">muckraker Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>'s book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s sexual exploits relied
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> from whistle-blowing ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>. Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> are being
forced to tell all about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s alleged affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            It's an uncomfortable role
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that prides itself on its low profile--indeed, on its secrecy. From
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zapruder</ENAMEX> film to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> film, the popular image of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>--stiff posture, of dark suit and shades, the walkie-talkies, the
microphone in the sleeve--is one of laconic, unflappable, and self-abnegating
cool. Though always at the center of things, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> cherishes his anonymity;
he's expected to sacrifice not just life but also ego to protect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            Who are
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, anyway? And how did they develop such importance and mystique?

            From the beginning, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> have been
thought to have pretty sexy jobs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George B. McClellan</ENAMEX>
conceived of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX> as an espionage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.
Under the control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>, its first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> was the legendary
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Pinkerton</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClellan</ENAMEX>'s who had learned
of--and helped avert--an attempt on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s life in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> fired
the famously inept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClellan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinkerton</ENAMEX> went, too. He was replaced eventually
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brigadier general</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Fayette C. Baker</ENAMEX>, who recorded his exploits of
derring-do in a memoir called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Secret Service in the Late War</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX>)--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in a long line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' kiss-and-tells (click for a brief
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX>). Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> ran afoul of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX> for having
allegedly set up his own espionage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
abolished the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> wound up testifying against the president
during his impeachment hearings.

            Meanwhile,
another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>--the forerunner of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s--was created as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14, 1865</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> met with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh McCullough</ENAMEX> about the need to fight rampant wartime counterfeiting. During
the war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had issued its first paper money, or "greenbacks"
(previously, only private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> had issued paper notes), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">one-half</ENAMEX> of all paper currency in circulation was believed to be "queer."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCullough</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln</ENAMEX> discussed setting up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> to root out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterfeiters</ENAMEX>. It didn't occur to them, unfortunately, to have this new
division protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and that very night <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> was assassinated
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> assigned to guard him wandered out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Theater</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tavern</ENAMEX> down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Fayette</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>,
coincidentally, helped bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wilkes Booth</ENAMEX> to justice.) The assassination
delayed things, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCullough</ENAMEX> swore in the new service's first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>,
the appropriately named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William P. Wood</ENAMEX>.

            
In the absence of other federal law enforcement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>--there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> over time took on new jobs:
combating the terrorist acts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX>, which had sprung up in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconstruction South</ENAMEX>; conducting espionage during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>; investigating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teapot Dome</ENAMEX> scandal;
and helping to apprehend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Capone</ENAMEX> for tax fraud. Its main job,
though, has always remained fighting counterfeiting and other forms of fraud:
check, credit card, postage stamp, food stamp, and the like. Which is to say,
if you cash your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> check, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> that
will come after you.

            
Conspicuously absent from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s duties was the job of presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX>. Until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s murder, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had been assassinated. When,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1835</TIMEX>, a would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> pointed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pugnacious</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> simply charged at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailant</ENAMEX>, brandishing his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX>. To
his good fortune, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and a backup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> failed to fire. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1881</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Garfield</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to be killed, and during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX>--a time of fierce labor unrest--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> finally
began using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, informally, for defense. Only when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> took office following the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX> assassination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William McKinley</ENAMEX> did
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX> authorize full-time presidential protection. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years</TIMEX>
later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sundry Civil Expenses Act</ENAMEX>, which made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>'s
protective duties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62 years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> ably sheltered the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> from danger, despite assassination attempts on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> (as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">president-elect, in 1933) and Harry Truman</ENAMEX> (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s
assassination, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>'s greatest failure, nonetheless brought it
renewed acclaim for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' heroics. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> leapt onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s moving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limousine</ENAMEX> to shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Kennedy</ENAMEX>, while another, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rufus Youngblood</ENAMEX>, gained
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fame</ENAMEX> for covering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> with his own. (Likewise,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agent Timothy McCarthy</ENAMEX> was celebrated for taking a bullet for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> assassination thus marked the arrival of the romantic myth
of the self-sacrificing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>--the myth that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Cockell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> trade on when they publicize their anguish over having to betray the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>.

            In the
'60s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'70s</ENAMEX>, the danger of assassination seemed suddenly to expand--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX> were murdered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX> was
crippled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX> was targeted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>'s custodial duties expanded accordingly.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection</ENAMEX> had been unofficially extended to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>-elect in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>. Now,
others came under the shield: former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice presidents</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice presidents</ENAMEX>-elect (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>), former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>),
presidential and vice presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>), visiting foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of
state (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice presidents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>), foreign diplomatic missions
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>). Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Lisa</ENAMEX> got
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> guardianship during her visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>.

            
Naturally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s size and budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploded</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s explanation in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedfellow</ENAMEX>"). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> it had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">520</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 4,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$590 million</NUMEX> budget, and
field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> around the world. This massive growth has periodically elicited
cries from lean-government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>. What's more, in our egalitarian times people
resent the privilege that serves to insulate a somewhat random
quasi-aristocracy from contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. This same egalitarianism <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>
the feeling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> shouldn't serve, in the mot du jour ,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Praetorian Guard</ENAMEX>"--that it shouldn't take metaphorical
bullets to protect his dalliances.

            Even that unpleasant task,
however, has some precedent. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dark Side of Camelot</ENAMEX> , of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who told him about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s reckless sexual escapades
and about how they were pressed into providing cover. Less well known, if less
salacious, is the fact that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian</ENAMEX> moralist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodrow Wilson</ENAMEX>,
then a recent widower, used <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to run interference for him in his amorous
pursuits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Starling</ENAMEX>, who guarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>, wrote in his memoir: "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
was in love. He was courting a handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Bolling Galt</ENAMEX> ... it
was all taking place at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, where Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galt</ENAMEX> was brought by her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>." Soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starling</ENAMEX> was conscripted into following the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> on their
walks through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Creek Park</ENAMEX> (for more details, click ) and
fending off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> was unmarried, dating another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> so
soon after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s death seemed vaguely scandalous in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>, especially
because, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starling</ENAMEX> discreetly put it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> was afraid "another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--a
Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peck</ENAMEX>, whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> had known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before--would make trouble if an
engagement were announced." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starling</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> held their tongues, at
least until he penned his memoir.

            History
teaches few practical lessons, but here it may have a small <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to offer: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Cockell, call your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.

            
               If you
missed the review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> kiss-and-tell memoirs and other useful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, click . For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s chaste pursuit of Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galt</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">click</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
