
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Just what does a gentleman
do when suspected of having been unfaithful to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>? Is the answer to lie,
lie, lie in order to keep peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, shelter the self-esteem of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and protect the reputation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in question? Or is it as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>
and some of our laws say: Do not bear false <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               I think
I know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> would reply. I'm interested in learning how the next
generation looks at a question like this.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Taylor</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>,

            You do not say suspected by
whom . If the transgressor is called on the carpet by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX>'s admonition is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to follow.

            While Prudie admires concern
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>'s self-esteem, peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and the reputation of the
illicit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, she must point out that all are jeopardized by the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>'s" actions.

            Your use
of the phrase "having been unfaithful" suggests the affair may be over. If this
is the case, the gentleman might take his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> for a drive and ask, "Will you
forgive me, or should I drive right to a jewelry store?"

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
generationally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               It would be fair to say
that like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa</ENAMEX>, the central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chasing Amy</ENAMEX> , I have until now
led an experimental life. I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> and have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> criminal conviction for hacking,
Recently, however, I have settled down and become decidedly less
experimental.
            

            
               My
problem is this: I am extremely bright and possess an advanced degree in
philosophy. Now I wish to go to medical school, law school, or apply for a
government job. What do I say at the interview about my previous experimental
life? In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chasing Amy</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa</ENAMEX> says, when confronted with her past sexual
behavior, "We are not born with maps inside us," but somehow I think an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interviewer</ENAMEX> will want a more comprehensive answer. Can you suggest a metaphor
for rationalizing my past? I need to be my own spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N.F.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zealand</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.</ENAMEX>,

            Whatever you do, don't use
dialogue from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chasing Amy</ENAMEX> at any interviews.

            As for
your sexual experimentation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels certain that the subject will not
come up. You might, however, have a problem with the conviction and the credit
history. I wish I could come through for you in the metaphor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, but I
am feeling metaphorically challenged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Just try to act reformed.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, spinningly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>,
and during the warmer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> I have a habit of not wearing shoes. I feel more
lively and energetic when I'm barefoot. The good points outweigh the bad (such
as dirty soles), and that's why I do it. Checking on the Internet, I have found
there to be no health laws in any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to wear shoes in
public.
            

            
               My
question is this: Why do some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> look at me as if I'm doing something
indecent by simply not wearing shoes? Also, why do most major fast food chains
post a sign saying, "No shirt, no shoes, no service, by order of health
department"? Do you find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who is shoeless in public to be dressed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indecently</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie T.</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.T.</ENAMEX>,

            For the word "indecent" I
would substitute "unappetizing." The idea of entering a place of food service
without shoes (or a shirt) seems vaguely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> stands
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shacks</ENAMEX> at beaches excepted.)

            Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in all manner of shapes and degrees of cleanliness, a decorous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would support even a fraudulent health code advisory.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, properly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Not long ago I learned
from "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trish"</ENAMEX> (not her real name), a co-worker, that the pregnancy of another
co-worker, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina"</ENAMEX> (also not her real name), had ended in a miscarriage. After
delivering this bit of news, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trish</ENAMEX> assured me it was "OK with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>" that we all
be told the bad news. I found this odd, since none of us had even known Trish
was expecting.
            

            
               Is
gossip now the preferred method of office communication? If so, has gossip
replaced the memo? Will my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> whisper my work assignments to my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">co-workers</ENAMEX>, who will then whisper them to me? Or is gossip only sanctioned when
the topic is of a private, personal nature? I guess my question is: How do I
distinguish "sanctioned" gossip from regular old slander?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanging</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grapevine</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dickenson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.D.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Hang,

            Slander
is a false report meant to do harm and is legally actionable. "I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>
had a face lift" is not such an example. And no, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does not think gossip
has replaced the memo, but it is somehow delivered faster.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, idly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I need
your advice on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following</TIMEX>. I received gifts from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> (delivered by my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mom</ENAMEX>). There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> gifts in the bag but none for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> have told
me this was a slight to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. My problem is what to do about the gifts. I
could return one or all of them and use the credit to buy a gift for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
or I could return the gifts to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, explaining that I take the presents
being just for me as an act of hostility.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Confused</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Con,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is
not sure your problem is what to do about the gifts, but perhaps what to do
about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. Subtle she is not. The solution for you may be to do both
the things you mentioned, with a slight modification. I would tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mumsy</ENAMEX> that
you take umbrage at her acting out, and I would return the gifts for credit,
buying a treat for both you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
subtextually

         
      
   
