
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Long
ago I read, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tiffany Manners for Teenagers</ENAMEX> book, that a gentleman
should never wipe up anything he accidentally spills in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s lap. This
suggests to me that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> IS a perfect gentleman, but should this point
of etiquette always be followed in cases of possibly impeachable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">offenses</ENAMEX>?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thoughtfully</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Easton</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Thought,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> believes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany Manners</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be pleased to update their book to keep up
with developments ... however , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> suspects that impeachable offenses
would be applicable to so few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> that the lap etiquette will remain
unchanged.

            You were
nice to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "a perfect gentleman." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is betting that's the
only compliment he's received on his manners since, oh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, primly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               If only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> had had the
sense to write her <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Prudie</ENAMEX>, perhaps none of this might have
happened!
            

            
               How'd
you like to be in the powder <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with them when she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> bump into
each other next time?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.F.</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear M.</ENAMEX>,

            You are too kind about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s persuasive abilities. Perhaps you will be cheered to know that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't seek advice before they enter an affair, only after. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s
case, though, it is tempting to think, "What if?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks: What if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> weren't so keen on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>?

            In any
case, something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> doesn't want to think about is the powder room
scene you fantasize. It would no doubt make the roller derby look demure.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, modestly

            

               
                  Dear
                
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I'm often asked to
contribute to various (and numerous) causes. However, I am currently limiting
my donations to a select few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. Despite the tax benefits that are
available from deducting such contributions, I am ambivalent about giving. The
reasons are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) I do not want to wind up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> lists and be badgered for
more donations. I want to give whenever and wherever I choose. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) I do not want
to be put on mailing lists that are shared among other charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. This
only compounds the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> problem.
            

            
               I've tried to think of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to contribute anonymously, but can't think of a good way. Can you?
            

            
               Thank
you in advance. Wanting to stay
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anonymous</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anywhere</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Anon,

            With a
check to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> of your choice can go a note asking that your name not be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> or put on a list and that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> list show your gift as having come
from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anonymous</ENAMEX>." You can make these requests a condition of your continued
support. If you want to remain really unknown, your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> can issue a
draft, akin to a cashier's check, or you can arrange a money order.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, charitably

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Why
does everyone keep insisting this whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> mess is a "sex thing"? It isn't
a sex thing. It's a "lying thing," and we need to take it seriously. A leader
needs credibility, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to be able to trust his judgment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
has lost that. Instead, every decision out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will now be
viewed by the world with a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog cynicism</ENAMEX>. Do we really want to be
the laughingstock of the world? Let's get him out so we can maintain what
little credibility <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has left.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truthful</ENAMEX> in
Torrance
            

            Dear
Truth,

            Prudie
would not disagree with you and finds Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is only an embarrassment on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days ending in</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX>"

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
sympathetically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the good old days</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> retired after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, it was usually a
moderately festive occasion. A going away gift and cards would be presented,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would say nice things.
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it seems that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are often hustled out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in the dead of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, and we learn
of their departure by accident. Of course many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> have legitimate
concerns about security and trade secrets and the like. And perhaps there is a
human resources professional somewhere who says that cutting the cord quickly
is best.
            

            
               But
the question remains: Should a group organize and bid adieu to someone who has
suddenly disappeared?
            

            
               --Your Advice,
Please
            

            Dear
Your,

            What with
"downsizing" as commonplace as it is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would be engaged in one
continuous "retirement" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> if everyone did as you suggest. Good-hearted of
you, though, to want to organize a proper farewell. If a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> has
been found redundant, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> say, by all means take that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to lunch
and include other interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mourners</ENAMEX>, I mean, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
festively

         
      
   
