
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            

               
                  Prud,
               
            

            
               I'm assisting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in
wedding prep and have made a number of requests to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomingdale's</ENAMEX> for a digital
version of the bridal registry. They offered to fax me information. I told them
I don't do faxes anymore. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>, the to-be-wedded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, are true
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digerati</ENAMEX> and have the expectation of electronic invitations with embedded links
(to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomie's</ENAMEX>, for example) for this bicoastal event in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>.
            

            
               Do you
think I'm expecting too much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomie</ENAMEX>'s? Their Web site is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>, and they
don't seem to understand e-commerce in the e-world. I do not want to be
impolite, but I do want them to understand the lucrativeness of this burgeoning
market. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>'s wedding helper needs your guidance.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wedded</ENAMEX>,
digitally
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wed,</ENAMEX>

            Ah, yes, trouble with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cybergifts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is sorry for your frustration with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomie</ENAMEX>'s being behind
the e-commerce curve. Would you feel better to know that they sometimes screw
up their plain old-fashioned mail-order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>? A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie's</ENAMEX> ordered
an expensive lamp as a wedding gift, and the embarrassed groom inquired why she
had sent an embroidered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">footstool</ENAMEX> bearing the wrong initials.

            In defense of some high-end
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> steering clear of the Web, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saks</ENAMEX> announced they were aborting their
Net effort because the results were next to nil. This, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> believed, was
due to the fact that catalogs show the merchandise more clearly and that
selecting "things" is a touching and feeling exercise.

            The Tish
Baldridge part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s brain is a little put off by the idea of imbedded
Web links to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. This makes the invitation seem a little more like an
invoice than usual. But by all means send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s best to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, festively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               My problem is one that I'm
sure affects many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> than you'd believe. I was widowed when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>
and have been on my own for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. My situation is something of a good
news-bad news thing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> who were our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have been wonderful to
me. They include me in everything--something I know is unusual for a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. The problem, though, is that not one of them has ever fixed me up with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. And it's not that they don't know any. I'm assuming they never think of me
in this context because to them I was the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX>,"
and it would somehow be disloyal on their part to introduce me to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               I do
not wish to seem aggressive, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are well connected, and I don't
know how to tell them that I am ready for introductions. Any ideas?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnne</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jo</ENAMEX>,

            It sounds
as if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are keeping you in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> longer than is necessary.
Ideally, you would be able to include a gentleman you've met independently in a
function involving all the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, thereby making a statement. If no one
suitable has crossed your radar, mention to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--that you are ready to meet appropriate escorts and perhaps they know of
someone. In other words, spread the word. And the reason to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, not
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, is that it's been observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> cannot accept the idea of any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> being on his own. So once you've "deputized" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> predicts results.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
providentially

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I feel so hopelessly
clueless! I'm seeing an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who works in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> I do. He is
paid at least twice what I am (and is well aware of that fact) and dips into
his salary only when he runs short of trust fund money. He's obviously made a
killing in the latest stock market boom. Yet when we go out we split
expenses.
            

            
               When
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and I first started seeing one another I would offer to split the
check, not being of the persuasion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> should automatically pay. But
it's been almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> now, and we've grown close, if you get my drift. What's
going on?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wish I Were Making</ENAMEX>
This Up
            

            Dear
Wish,

            What's going on is that your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gentleman</ENAMEX> is close with a buck. To louse up a well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> phrase, he is
fui generis--in this case meaning "What's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> is mine."

            Unfortunately, to be
politically correct in the beginning, you suggested going <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>. Now that you
have become "close" (drift received), and your significant other is way better
fixed than you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you have a heart-to-heart. An opening gambit
might be "I can no longer afford our romance." Explain that when you started
dating you didn't know it would lead to something serious and wished to be
correct. Now, however, you think it would be appropriate for him to assume the
expenses incurred when you are a twosome.

            As, of
course, you know, money can be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Triangle</ENAMEX> of relationships. If this
is a thorn in your side, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> believes it is, state your case, but be
prepared to be disappointed. If he doesn't see it your way, just e-mail him a
farewell, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cheapskate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, fiscally

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Is it
moral for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to refuse to provide sterile needles to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intravenous drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> in order to prevent the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>? Does the excuse
that needle exchange encourages and condones <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use seem reasonable?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David WorlRochester</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>,

            You have
pressed one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s buttons with this one. Statistics show that needle
exchange programs, among other benefits, are a way of getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rehab</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is being both foolish and cowardly, afraid of being
attacked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> for doing anything that might be labeled "immoral."
The real immorality, of course, is failing to do whatever is possible to lessen
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. To imagine that withholding clean needles from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>
will keep them away from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is like telling the tides to stay still.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, disdainfully

         
      
   
