
   
   
      
         
            

            
               ASK
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRUDENCE</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, drawing on her rich experience of life, will answer questions
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. She will respond to questions about manners, personal
relations, politics, economics, and other subjects. Questions should be sent to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
They should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your
letter to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               At
what point, and how, should one tell one's new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> about one's medical
history? (And it's not the history you may think.) Bluntly put, when does he
need to know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> I take every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>? It's easy enough to tell
acquaintances that the reason I'm not having a beer at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office party</ENAMEX> is that
I'm "on some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>," and leave it at that. Is a more detailed explanation
needed for a more continuous relationship? Or should I just assume he'll find
the bottle in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> cabinet when he gets a headache?
            

            
               --Not D/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-free in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Dear
D/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>,
            

            A lot
depends on what you mean by a "more continuous relationship." If you mean that
you will be with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost daily</TIMEX>, for a significant period,
with the possibility that it will be for the rest of your lives, you should
certainly tell him. You will both be more free with each other if he knows. You
will not have to try to hide your condition or make up false explanations of
it. He will understand you better if he knows. He will know to try to avoid
exacerbating your condition and may be able to help alleviate it by sympathetic
and understanding behavior. If he can't accept that, you should consider
whether you want a "more continuous relationship" with him.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, openly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Won't
you come out to play?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark TullyMadison</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatles Fan</ENAMEX>,
            

            I am at
play right now. Play is activity engaged in for the enjoyment of it without
regard to the financial remuneration. My remuneration is so trivial that what I
am doing qualifies as play.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, playfully

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I had a youthful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indiscretion</ENAMEX> and was married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months almost 18 years ago</TIMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July of this year</TIMEX>, I received a phone call from a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who professed to
be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. When we divorced, I knew her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was pregnant, but through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> I was told the unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> belonged to her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. In fact, out
of the blue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> she left me and remarried him.
            

            
               This young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, whom I
met in person over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>, is undoubtedly my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. But, she's a very
troubled and angry young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. She has been abused sexually, emotionally; was
put out of her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 12</TIMEX> by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>; has been pregnant but suffered a
miscarriage. Beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 15</TIMEX>, she had an affair for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two years</TIMEX> with a
35-year-old married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>; has attempted suicide some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times; was
hospitalized for psychiatric problems for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>; was arrested for
assault and is currently on probation; and the list goes on.
            

            
               My advice to her was that
she needed to deal with her anger and learn to love herself before she could
even begin to think about loving me, her half <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. She
said some pretty mean things to me while she was here. I requested that we not
have a relationship unless and until she gets herself some help.
            

            
               I am
totally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> with a spinal-cord <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and I have limited emotional,
financial, and physical capabilities. Did I do the right thing?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hopeless</ENAMEX> in the
SoutheastSanford, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Dear
It's Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hopeless</ENAMEX>,
            

            What a sad story! But I
think you are shortchanging your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and yourself. I accept what you say
about having limited financial and physical capabilities. I don't think you are
right about having limited emotional capabilities. You should not cut off your
relationship with her but rather should offer her sympathy, understanding,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, and companionship. It will be hard. Obviously, after the life she has led
she is going to say some mean things. She may feel that the absence of her
natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> during her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX>, however well that might be explained,
contributed to her present condition. Treating her lovingly will not only be
helpful to her. It will also be helpful to you. The emotional capabilities you
describe as limited will grow as they are used.

            You may
not be able to sustain this attitude, but it will be worth a very hard try.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, hopefully

         
      
   
