
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Endless</TIMEX> Summer

            
               (Note:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plot Holes</ENAMEX>" is an occasional series assessing the narrative logic of
movies.)
            

            It was a busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> for the
Logic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squad</ENAMEX>. The assaults on plausibility began in the first frames of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Con</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX> , as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> returned home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Desert Storm</ENAMEX>
in a tugboat, and did not subside until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Neill</ENAMEX> mutated into some kind of
space devil at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Event Horizon</ENAMEX> , whereupon his face inexplicably
broke out in a crosshatched design that made him look like a slab of grilled
ahi tuna.

            None of
this should be surprising. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summer</ENAMEX> is the season of action movies, and in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> velocity has always been a greater virtue than coherence. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
most damning things that can be said about a script is that it is "episodic,"
meaning that it dawdles when it should accelerate, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> is less
interested in the ruthless propulsion of the story than in leisurely details of
tone and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. As long as a movie is kept at a high enough idle, the
thinking goes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> won't mind an engine knock or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> when it comes to
credibility.

            Sometimes this theory works, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force One</ENAMEX> .
Though the movie asked us to believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
was a superhuman jungle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> of unyielding principle, it didn't
significantly insult our intelligence further. And it's probably unsporting to
take a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like Face/Off</ENAMEX> to task for issues of verisimilitude. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woo</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, has long demonstrated a rousing indifference to mere
reality, and this movie--in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> routinely somersault through
the air firing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> from both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX>--is just his latest salute to impossible,
operatic violence. (Still, haunting questions linger. I'm happy to buy the
notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX> were able to swap faces--after all,
they were aided by a "state-of-the-art morpho-genetic template"--but I never
quite understood how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>, who is as lean as a rattlesnake, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travolta</ENAMEX>, who
has the sort of gentlemanly proportions that inspired relaxed-fit jeans,
managed to trade bodies as well.)

            It is
certainly worth a passing mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX> gets shot in the same arm
in both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face/Off and Con Air</ENAMEX> , though neither wound interferes
with his ability to hang from firetruck ladders or leap from speeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>.
These two movies, along with the incomparable Speed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , make up what film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> may <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> deem the improbability trilogy of all time. Though there
is not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in cyberspace to catalog all the ways in which these films
part <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with reality, special mention must be made of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed 2</ENAMEX> 's
villain, who, as richly embodied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem Dafoe</ENAMEX>, is a buzzing hive of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">befuddlement</ENAMEX>. When he steps onto a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> carrying a set of explosive golf
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clubs</ENAMEX> and a jar of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">leeches</ENAMEX>, when he murmurs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">leeches</ENAMEX> in the bathtub as he
applies them to his skin ("You take care of me, and I'll take care of the
ship"), we know we have entered a world that the light of reason will never
penetrate.

            C>ontact was supposed to be an antidote to all this
summer nonsense, a passionate think piece about the possibility of alien life
and the existence of God. It is to be applauded for trying to make us think
instead of just react, but sometimes too many brain waves are just as bad as
too few. I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> suspected that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact</ENAMEX> 's logic circuits might be fried
when, early in the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew McConaughey</ENAMEX>, as a roving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Zen</ENAMEX> master
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer Joss</ENAMEX>, strolls through a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Costa Rican</ENAMEX> palapa nibbling from a
box of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cracker Jack</ENAMEX>. While it is certainly possible that a box of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cracker Jack</ENAMEX>
might be for sale in a remote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central American</ENAMEX> jungle, I submit that the
chances of finding one are no greater than stumbling upon, say, a Zagnut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>.
(To be fair, though, I did believe it when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McConaughey</ENAMEX>'s callow, mushy
character is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> as a spiritual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Contact 's central premise is intriguing: A radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronomer</ENAMEX>, played by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>, receives a blizzard of binary mathematical data from a
civilization in distant space. The task of decrypting these data stymies the
most brilliant minds on earth, but when the puzzle is finally solved the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> behold a set of blueprints for building a highly unconventional
space transport. For all its earnest credibility about radio astronomy,
Contact is breezy in the extreme when it comes to almost everything
else. We are asked to believe not only that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (shanghaied by
the filmmakers into a notorious cameo) could inspire the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to spend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trillions</ENAMEX> of dollars on this machine without even a raised eyebrow from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>, but also that a cross-eyed, homicidal doomsday prophet would be hired to
put the finishing touches on it; and that after he sabotages the whole project
in the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, it would be rebuilt at a secret location on the island of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hokkaido</ENAMEX> by a zillionaire eccentric who floats around in orbit aboard his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">custom-made Mir</ENAMEX>.

            Even more troubling are the cryptic motives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX> finally sets forth in the transport--read no further if you
don't want to hear the movie's ending--she lands on a peaceful tropical beach
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thoughtfully</ENAMEX> provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> to cushion her culture shock. The aliens
themselves take the form of her beloved dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who holds the weeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earthling</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and tells her she'll never walk alone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incredibly</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> don't have much more to say than that, and she can't seem to think of
much more to ask. She's traveled halfway across the universe to be patted on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and told to run on home. And another thing: If these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> are so
adept at replicating the many moods of our planet, if they can speak
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> , how come they had to communicate with us in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
through a byzantine binary code? That's like God deciding to communicate to us
via that cinnamon <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bun</ENAMEX> shaped like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>: way too coy.

         
      
   
