
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I don't know what I am
going to do. Maybe move to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiji</ENAMEX>. I am only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>, but I know my life is over. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, the same one I've had all through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX>, just dumped me. I know I am the laughingstock of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and
that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will look at me because "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim"</ENAMEX> didn't want me.
            

            
               I am
considering changing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and telling new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> was
killed in a car wreck. That way they won't feel sorry for me. Can you think of
a better excuse for why one would be boyfriendless?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frantic</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Fran,

            You are being Molière than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thou</ENAMEX>--far more dramatic than the situation warrants. There is no stigma to
being cut loose from a relationship. It happens all the time.

            Prudie
strongly recommends that you not bop out of your college or change your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Your romance, after all, was not as important to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> as it
was to you. If you feel you must say something, state that you mutually decided
to explore a wider world. And a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX>: Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose to be
"boyfriendless."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
encouragingly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               My wedding is set for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> I used to work with, and we still keep in touch. He
invited me to his wedding, though I was unable to attend.
            

            
               I'm not sure whether to
invite him to mine. I think he perceives our friendship as being stronger than
it is. Normally, I simply wouldn't invite him and would explain that it was a
small ceremony (which it is). But I am inviting other former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> whom he
knows.
            

            
               So, do you think I am
obligated to invite him? If I don't, how should I handle it, given that we'll
see each other around?
            

            
               While
I'm not writing you from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, that's where I normally am, so sign
me ...
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uninviting</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Uninvite,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> understands that
you're in a bind: your wishes vs. his feelings. If yours were to have been a
large wedding, which it is not, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would advise you to invite him. A mercy
invitation, if you will.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> also, however,
believes that one should not be maneuvered into invitations--particularly to
one's wedding. Meaningful occasions are not meant to be tit for tat. That way,
you're liable to get your tat caught in a wringer. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> sees no need to
explain yourself to him.

            Of course,
after the fact, you could say the invitation was ex post fucto --lost in
the mail. Only kidding, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does not endorse falsehoods. And mazel
ton (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of luck).

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
matrimonially

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>
your
views on needle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>: It's fine if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wants to give out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> needles to intravenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to reduce the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, but I
would then expect a full refund on my tax return for my share of the cost,
because that's not why I pay taxes. It's bad enough that I have to pay more in
federal taxes alone than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> even grossed--and I'm far from making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
figures! When I'm able to save for a decent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, put aside money for my
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s education, ensure my retirement funds, and buy the gadgets I
want, then maybe I'll consider putting aside a dime for some miscreant fool
whose need for attention drove him to illicit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. Until then, how dare
anyone force me to be generous.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
TerryStamford, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>,

            Putting aside the fact that
you sound like you have a heart the size of a navy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> must point out
that the cost of needle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> is hugely less than the care of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.

            We do not
pay taxes for any one reason, nor do we have veto power over particular
expenditures. It would, of course, be an impossibility to get the citizenry to
agree on expenditures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacifists</ENAMEX> would object to defense budgets, childless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would balk at school taxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX>, needless to say, cetera. This is where
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> come in, and over them we do have veto
power.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
realistically

         
      
   
