
   
   
      
         
            

            
               ASK
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRUDENCE</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, drawing on her rich experience of life, will answer questions
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. She will respond to questions about manners, personal
relations, politics, economics, and other subjects. Questions should be sent to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
They should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your
letter to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Once I
have asked the "how do I tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> how much I love the way he screws
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">me?</ENAMEX>" question, what other questions are there that deal with "love, etiquette,
AND macroeconomic policy"?
            

            
               --Nit-pickingly,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nelson</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Nit-pickingly,

            I'm sure a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as clever
as you can find many questions that meet the standard you have read into our
instructions. Here's one: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How</ENAMEX> should a capital-gains tax cut be dressed up to
make it seem an act of lovingkindness to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have no capital?"

            Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who read our instructions were not deterred by the defect you discovered
and have sent us heartfelt questions on a number of subjects. Unrelenting
attention to syntax can be an obstacle to communication.

            
               -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
inexactly

            
               
                  My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dear Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is dragging me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of hers to celebrate
the new year. The problem is that they are total teetotalers, and to me, a day
(much less <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX>) without a drink is no day at all! Would it be rude
if I took a nice bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> (OK, maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>)?? And would a corkscrew
and proper glasses be pushing it????
            

            
               --Jakeman
            

            Dear
Jakeman,

            It would
indeed be rude, unless you called <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and asked whether it would be OK. It is
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, their party, and their rules. If they say no, which would be quite
within the bounds of propriety, you should either restrain yourself at the
party or not go to it.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, teetotally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I see
that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is trying to copy the tone of the wonderful advice
given by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sainted</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Killen</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> . Tell me, why do you
think this is? It can't be because they have no brilliant ideas of their own,
can it?
            

            
               --Yours
expectantly,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael ElliottWashington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, one of
my favorite newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> has become less and less interesting. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eppie</ENAMEX>"
(not her real name) used to write an advice column. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> would write her
with their questions on life, love, and (usually) microeconomics, and she would
give them really great advice, e.g., "Wake up and smell the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>!"
            

            

               Lately, however, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> seem to have decided to become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
Nannies, mailing in all sorts of precatory silliness--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eppie</ENAMEX>, tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
never to leave a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> alone in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> on a hot day with the windows rolled
up!" Or, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eppie</ENAMEX>, please, please tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> not to make fun of fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX>! They're human too, you know!" And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, she
prints that stuff in her column! Every &@<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#</NUMEX>^ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>! Advice? Fahgeddaboutit,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buster</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, will they ever put "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eppie</ENAMEX>" out of her misery? Do you
represent the next evolutionary step in journalism? Or are you nothing more
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Zaslow</ENAMEX> ...
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popo</ENAMEX> (not my real
name)
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popo</ENAMEX>,

            Your letters raise related
questions, and I hope you won't mind if I answer them both at once. "Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence"</ENAMEX> did not originate with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> searching for a new idea. It was a
response to the overwhelming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> demand for advice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> seek answers to
their real problems, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> enjoy and profit from reading the
problems submitted and the answers given. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>--"real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," that is--are
more interested in those problems than in the questions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> make up
just so they will have something to write about, questions selected so that the
answer requires little thought and no research.

            As for my antecedents, I
must confess that I have never heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Killen</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eppie</ENAMEX>," or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zaslow</ENAMEX>. I trace my lineage back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delphic Oracle</ENAMEX>,
Cassandra, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin Franklin</ENAMEX>. (I deliberately omit that old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> of an advice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polonius</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banks</ENAMEX> thrive by being both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX>.) Thus, I consider myself part of the constants of history, not part of
an evolutionary trend.

            But hey,
it's a free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and a free market. If no problems are submitted, there will
be no answers. And if there are problems and answers but no one reads them,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> will go back to her needlepoint.

            
               -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
modestly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (and how are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>?),
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boyfriend</ENAMEX> broke up with her via a note. That she was pregnant at the time makes
the situation with respect to his morality quite clear: He had and has the
morals of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana slug</ENAMEX>. (That he cringes at salt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shakers</ENAMEX> only bolsters this
conclusion.) The question that I find interesting concerns the etiquette of
breaking up. I contend that the only way <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should kiss off another is
face to face. I've a number of reasons to support this view, but my fundamental
reasoning is moral (as morality is the basis of so much mannerly behavior): In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>, the kissed-off, as the offended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, should have the right to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confront</ENAMEX> (and possibly to throw sharp objects at) the kisser-off.
            

            
               Any
other way (by telephone, by note) smacks of cowardice. Further, it seems to me
that my preferred mode serves a useful societal function as well, by making
romantic relationships somewhat more stable since somewhat more difficult to
dissolve during temporary difficulties. This last point, of course, presumes
that society has an interest in stable romantic relationships; if you accept
that society has an interest in marriage, and that stable romantic
relationships both include and lead to marriage, you must conclude that society
does indeed have such an interest. Have you any thoughts on this? A nation
holds its breath (well, except for those holding others at gunpoint).
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Post</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meaner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Brother</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX>,

            Whether a face-to-face
encounter is required for a breakup depends on the reason for the breakup. If A
splits from B because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX> has been obviously offensive and fraudulent, the
courtesy of a face-to-face explanation is not required. Suppose, for example,
that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B</ENAMEX> has given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> A every reason to believe that he is not married, but
she learns that he is. B then deserves nothing. In the case to which you refer,
the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> deserves a face-to-face meeting, an apology, and whatever solace
can be offered. Probably the general rule is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> who is seriously
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aggrieved</ENAMEX> owes no consideration to the aggrievor.

            I am surprised that you did
not mention e-mail as a medium for breakups. Isn't there a Web site containing
form e-mail letters for breakups?

            They're
well, thanks.

            
               -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I hate
to start our relations by pointing out little details, but both you and
"Lovelocked" missed another major point of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chivalry</ENAMEX> on the question of opening
the door for your loved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The other point is you don't leave her standing
alone on the far side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and thus more easily jostled and/or assaulted
by the nearest purse snatcher or other criminal element who can often appear
quickly and quietly no matter the time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> ... just a point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m'dear.</ENAMEX>
            

            

               --Saintswrd
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Saintswrd,

            Thanks
for your addition to the reasons for helping your beloved get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
Unfortunately, it is a necessary addition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sentimental Prudence</ENAMEX> prefers to
focus on the romantic side of life, but she cannot deny there is a darker side
also.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, ruefully

         
      
   
