
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am employed in a
leadership position where I meet a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a few times a year.
I have real problems remembering names. Have you heard this one before? I've
tried several ways to compensate. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that works best for me is to review
the list of names I should know and visualize their faces. But I still
fail.
            

            
               So my
question to you is: What is the best way to handle the introduction of somebody
whose name you should know but don't when they join a small conversational
group you're with?
            

            
               --Sign me,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill From La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolla</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>,

            Far worse than picking up
the wrong fork is stumbling around with an introduction. But take heart, you
have a lot of company falling into this particular social pothole.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does not
recommend an association technique. For example, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
name would not stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s memory. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> wore crazy hats--often
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sporting fruit</ENAMEX>--so "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmen Miranda</ENAMEX>" seemed a useful aid ... until Prudie
addressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> as "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda</ENAMEX>."

            You are luckier than most in
that your elevated position gives you something of a pass. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
will assume that you meet so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that name recollection would be tough,
at best. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wagner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.J.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could remember his
name) got around this by calling everyone "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pallie</ENAMEX>." This stunt only works,
however, in direct address, and is no help with introductions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is willing to blow
her cover and offer you her trick: When stuck, just say, "Tell me your
whole name," implying (alas, fraudulently) that she remembers one name, but not
both.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Happily,</ENAMEX>
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pick up on someone's difficulty and introduce themselves. When
nothing happens to relieve the situation, you can say, forthrightly, "I'm so
sorry, your name has gone right out of my head."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, forgetfully

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX> wanted to ask your advice concerning a problem that is certainly not new
to me. I have been in a committed relationship with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. We
have everything going for us, and I feel it's time to marry. It seems to be the
next logical step. We've been talking about this for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a year</TIMEX>, so this is
not a new subject. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> we had a huge fight about our relationship and
getting married. It ended with him storming out and me crying. My question is:
If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> keeps saying he's not ready to marry, is this his way of saying "I'll
never marry you"? In other words, should I just move on?
            

            
               --Impatiently
Waiting
            

            Dear
Imp,

            Oh dear, the beloved is
having trouble with his feet. They're cold. It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX> commitment problem,
which seems to afflict more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The goings-on you describe sound
like a cross between psychodrama and dating, never good for the nerves. You
have these options, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> sees it: You can stick it to him and force a
decision; you can coast along and see if he starts to feel more "ready"; or you
can make a deadline--spoken or unspoken--at which time you will either call a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caterer</ENAMEX> or tell him it's been lovely.

            What some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have done,
though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> doesn't recommend it, is to make the beloved jealous with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. This is sometimes effective in extracting a proposal, but it is also a
little like lassoing a calf, and who wants a groom one is dragging to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">altar</ENAMEX>? The dilemma on whose horns you ride is that sometimes "not ready" means
just that, and at other times it really does mean "not you." The hell of it is
that often the real meaning is unknown to the gentleman himself. As one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philosophes</ENAMEX> put it, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> deserve something better than
each other."

            If things
work out, do let <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> know so that she can wish you mazel ton ... tons
of luck.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, hopefully

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               So one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s
"hot
buttons" is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s failure to provide clean needles to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>?
May I suggest you take your finger off the button, calm down, and review the
history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 year</TIMEX> experiment doing just such a thing.
            

            
               The
results are not encouraging. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> has risen, and the
percentage infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> has gone from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 3 percent to 24 percent</NUMEX>, if
memory serves. Compassionate sounding ideas do not always pan out; it's good to
look at the evidence and be willing to change your mind if necessary.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concerned</ENAMEX> but
Skeptical
            

            Dear
Con,

            Your giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">needle</ENAMEX>, pardon the expression, is understandable. As with all studies, there
are opposite findings to be offered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, it is the nature of the statistical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>.

            Your figures for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX> study are correct, but there is no way to know if the number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> would have gone up without a needle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have also
quarreled with the design of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX> program. The complaints have to do
with the low limits on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>, and poor timing. That is, the
crack epidemic had just taken hold, and according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Sun</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">injected cocaine</ENAMEX> and crack use often require <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 to 40</NUMEX> needles a session. With
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impaired judgment</ENAMEX>, a guaranteed result with injected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, one would not know
how many or whose needles one was using.

            Prudie
thinks it best we agree to disagree, and err on the side of humane
considerations.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, agreeably

         
      
   
