
	
		
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WE HAVE SOME PLANES</ENAMEX>"

    <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>, dawned temperate and nearly cloudless in the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> readied themselves for work. Some made their way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Towers</ENAMEX>, the signature structures of the World <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trade Center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. Others went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>. Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Potomac River</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Congress</ENAMEX> was back in session. At the other end of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pennsylvania Avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> began to line up for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tour. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> went for an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX> run.

    For those heading to an airport, weather conditions could not have been better for a safe and pleasant journey. Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Aziz al Omari</ENAMEX>, who arrived at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INSIDE THE FOUR FLIGHTS</ENAMEX>

Boarding the Flights

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omari</ENAMEX> boarded a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:00 A.M.</TIMEX> flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan International Airport</ENAMEX>.

    When he checked in for his flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> was selected by a computerized prescreening system known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Assisted Passenger Prescreening System</ENAMEX>), created to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who should be subject to special security measures. Under security rules in place at the time, the only consequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s selection by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX> was that his checked bags were held off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> until it was confirmed that he had boarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. This did not hinder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s plans.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omari</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> apparently took a call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marwan al Shehhi</ENAMEX>, a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> who was at another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan Airport</ENAMEX>. They spoke for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX>.

    It would be their final conversation.

    Between <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45 and 7:40</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omari</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satam al Suqami</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wail al Shehri</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waleed al Shehri</ENAMEX>, checked in and boarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>, bound for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. The flight was scheduled to depart at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:45</TIMEX>.

    In another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shehhi</ENAMEX>, joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fayez Banihammad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohand al Shehri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamza al Ghamdi</ENAMEX>, checked in for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight 175, also bound for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of Shehhi</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> were obviously unused to travel; according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, they had trouble understanding the standard security questions, and she had to go over them slowly until they gave the routine, reassuring answers.

    Their flight was scheduled to depart at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00</TIMEX>.

    The security checkpoints through which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, gained access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> 11 gate were operated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe Security</ENAMEX> under a contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>. In a different terminal, the single checkpoint through which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX> passed was controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX>, which had contracted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huntleigh USA</ENAMEX> to perform the screening.

    In passing through these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoints</ENAMEX>, each of the hijackers would have been screened by a walk-through metal detector calibrated to detect items with at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX> content of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">.22-caliber</NUMEX> handgun. Anyone who might have set off that detector would have been screened with a hand wand-a procedure requiring the screener to identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal item</ENAMEX> or items that caused the alarm. In addition, an X-ray machine would have screened the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>' carry-on belongings. The screening was in place to identify and confiscate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and other items prohibited from being carried onto a commercial flight.

    None of the checkpoint <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> recalled the hijackers or reported anything suspicious regarding their screening.

    While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> had been selected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his hijacking team-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Suqami</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wail al Shehri</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waleed al Shehri</ENAMEX>-were selected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. Their selection affected only the handling of their checked bags, not their screening at the checkpoint. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> cleared the checkpoint and made their way to the gate for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omari</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suqami</ENAMEX> took their seats in business class (seats 8D, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8G</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">10B</ENAMEX>, respectively). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> had adjacent seats in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">row 2</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wail</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2A</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waleed</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2B</TIMEX>), in the firstclass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>. They boarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 between 7:31 and 7:40</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> pushed back from the gate at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:40</TIMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, none of whom had been selected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX>, boarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">175 between 7:23 and 7:28</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banihammad</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2A</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehri</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2B</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6C</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamza al Ghamdi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9C</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9D</TIMEX>). Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> pushed back from the gate just before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00</TIMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> Dulles: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> southwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dulles International Airport</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> suburbs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were preparing to take their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX> flight. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:15</TIMEX>, a pair of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Majed Moqed</ENAMEX>, checked in at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> ticket counter for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 77</ENAMEX>, bound for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next 20 minutes</TIMEX>, they would be followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem al Hazmi</ENAMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majed Moqed</ENAMEX> were flagged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> were also selected for extra scrutiny by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX>'s customer service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> at the check-in counter. He did so because one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> did not have photo identification nor could he understand <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> found both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to be suspicious. The only consequence of their selection was that their checked bags were held off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> until it was confirmed that they had boarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.

    All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> hijackers passed through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Main Terminal</ENAMEX>'s west security screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoint</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX>, which was the responsible air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>, had contracted out the work to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argenbright Security</ENAMEX>.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">checkpoint</ENAMEX> featured closed-circuit television that recorded all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, including the hijackers, as they were screened. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:18</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moqed</ENAMEX> entered the security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">checkpoint</ENAMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moqed</ENAMEX> placed their carry-on bags on the belt of the X-ray machine and proceeded through the first metal detector. Both set off the alarm, and they were directed to a second metal detector. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> did not trigger the alarm and was permitted through the checkpoint. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moqed</ENAMEX> set it off, a screener wanded him. He passed this inspection.

    <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> later, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:35</TIMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 77</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX>, placed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two carry-on</NUMEX> bags on the X-ray belt in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Main Terminal</ENAMEX>'s west checkpoint, and proceeded, without alarm, through the metal detector. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">short time</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nawaf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem al Hazmi</ENAMEX> entered the same checkpoint. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem al Hazmi</ENAMEX> cleared the metal detector and was permitted through; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX> set off the alarms for both the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> metal detectors and was then hand-wanded before being passed. In addition, his over-the-shoulder carry-on bag was swiped by an explosive trace detector and then passed. The video footage indicates that he was carrying an unidentified item in his back pocket, clipped to its rim.

    When the local civil aviation security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>) later investigated these security screening operations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screeners</ENAMEX> recalled nothing out of the ordinary. They could not recall that any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> they screened were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX> selectees. We asked a screening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> to review the videotape of the hand-wanding, and he found the quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">screener</ENAMEX>'s work to have been "marginal at best." The screener should have "resolved" what set off the alarm; and in the case of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moqed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX>, it was clear that he did not.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:50</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Majed Moqed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX> boarded the flight and were seated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12A and 12B</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX>, assigned to seat 1B (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class), soon followed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, sitting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5E and 5F</TIMEX>, joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> in the first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newark</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 93</ENAMEX>. Between <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:03 and 7:39</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saeed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Nami</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad al Haznawi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ziad Jarrah</ENAMEX> checked in at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> ticket counter for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX>, going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> checked bags; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> did not. Haznawi was selected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX>. His checked bag was screened for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> and then loaded on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>.

    The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> passed through the security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">checkpoint</ENAMEX>, owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> and operated under contract by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argenbright Security</ENAMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoints</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, it lacked closed-circuit television surveillance so there is no documentary evidence to indicate when the hijackers passed through the checkpoint, what alarms may have been triggered, or what security procedures were administered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> interviewed the screeners later; none recalled anything unusual or suspicious.

    The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> boarded the plane <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 7:39 and 7:48</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All four</NUMEX> had seats in the first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>; their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> had no business-class section. Jarrah was in seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1B</TIMEX>, closest to the cockpit; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nami</ENAMEX> was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3C</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghamdi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3D</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haznawi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6B</TIMEX>.

    The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were aboard <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> transcontinental flights.

    They were planning to hijack these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and turn them into large guided <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, loaded with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 11,400 gallons</NUMEX> of jet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 A.M.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11,2001, they had defeated all the security layers that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s civil aviation security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> then had in place to prevent a hijacking. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijacking of American 11 American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> provided nonstop service from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain John Ogonowski</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas McGuinness</ENAMEX> piloted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">767</ENAMEX>. It carried its full capacity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> boarded the flight with them (including the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.22</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> took off at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:59</TIMEX>. Just before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:14</TIMEX>, it had climbed to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">26,000 feet</NUMEX>, not quite its initial assigned cruising altitude of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">29,000 feet</NUMEX>. All communications and flight profile data were normal. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About this time</TIMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fasten Seatbelt</ENAMEX>" sign would usually have been turned off and the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> would have begun preparing for cabin service.

    At that same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX> had its last routine communication with the ground when it acknowledged navigational instructions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s air traffic control (ATC) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Sixteen seconds</TIMEX> after that transmission, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATC</ENAMEX> instructed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> to climb to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35,000 feet</NUMEX>. That message and all subsequent attempts to contact the flight were not acknowledged. From this and other evidence, we believe the hijacking began at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:14</TIMEX> or shortly thereafter.

    Reports from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> cabin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madeline</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amy</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX>, tell us most of what we know about how the hijacking happened. As it began, some of the hijackers-most likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wail al Shehri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waleed al Shehri</ENAMEX>, who were seated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">row 2</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class-stabbed the two unarmed flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> who would have been preparing for cabin service.

    We do not know exactly how the hijackers gained access to the cockpit; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> rules required that the doors remain closed and locked during flight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> speculated that they had "jammed their way" in. Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> stabbed the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> to get a cockpit key, to force one of them to open the cockpit door, or to lure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> out of the cockpit. Or the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> may just have been in their way.

    At the same time or shortly thereafter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>-the only terrorist on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> trained to fly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>-would have moved to the cockpit from his business-class seat, possibly accompanied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omari</ENAMEX>. As this was happening, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Lewin</ENAMEX>, who was seated in the row just behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omari</ENAMEX>, was stabbed by one of the hijackers-probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satam al Suqami</ENAMEX>, who was seated directly behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewin</ENAMEX> had served <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> military. He may have made an attempt to stop the hijackers in front of him, not realizing that another was sitting behind him.

    The hijackers quickly gained control and sprayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mace</ENAMEX>, pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>, or some other irritant in the first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>, in order to force the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> toward the rear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. They claimed they had a bomb.

    <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> after the hijacking began, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ong</ENAMEX> contacted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines Southeastern Reservations Office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, via an AT&T airphone to report an emergency aboard the flight. This was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of several occasions on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> when flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> took action outside the scope of their training, which emphasized that in a hijacking, they were to communicate with the cockpit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. The emergency call lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 25 minutes</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> calmly and professionally relayed information about events taking place aboard the airplane to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> on the ground.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:19</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> reported:"The cockpit is not answering, somebody's stabbed in business class-and I think there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mace</ENAMEX>-that we can't breathe-I don't know, I think we're getting hijacked." She then told of the stabbings of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:21</TIMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX>'s call in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, alerted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> operations <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> on duty. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marquis</ENAMEX> soon realized this was an emergency and instructed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX>'s dispatcher responsible for the flight to contact the cockpit. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:23</TIMEX>, the dispatcher tried unsuccessfully to contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> later, the air traffic control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s operations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> contacted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Air Traffic Control Center</ENAMEX> about the flight. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> was already aware of the problem.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> knew of a problem on the flight in part because just before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:25</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> had attempted to communicate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. The microphone was keyed, and immediately one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> said, "Nobody move. Everything will be okay. If you try to make any moves, you'll endanger yourself and the airplane. Just stay quiet." Air traffic controllers heard the transmission; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> did not. The hijackers probably did not know how to operate the cockpit radio communication system correctly, and thus inadvertently broadcast their message over the air traffic control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> instead of the cabin public-address <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. Also at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:25</TIMEX>, and again at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:29</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Sweeney</ENAMEX> got through to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Flight Services Office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> but was cut off after she reported someone was hurt aboard the flight. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three minutes</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX> was reconnected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and began relaying updates to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:26</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was "flying erratically." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A minute</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX> turned south. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> also began getting identifications of the hijackers, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> passed on some of the seat numbers of those who had gained unauthorized access to the cockpit.

    Sweeney calmly reported on her line that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> had been hijacked; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class had his throat slashed; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> had been stabbed-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was seriously hurt and was on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> while the other's wounds seemed minor; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> had been requested; the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> were unable to contact the cockpit; and there was a bomb in the cockpit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> that she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> were trying to relay as much information as they could to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the ground.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:38</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was flying erratically again. Around this time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> that the hijackers were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Easterners</ENAMEX>, naming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of their seat numbers. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> spoke very little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> and one spoke excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> had gained entry to the cockpit, and she did not know how. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was in a rapid descent.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:41</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> were under the impression that there was a routine medical emergency in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class. Other flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> were busy at duties such as getting medical supplies while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> were reporting the events.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:41</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s operations <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marquis</ENAMEX> that the air traffic controllers declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX> a hijacking and "think he's [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">11</ENAMEX>] headed toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>]. They're moving everybody out of the way. They seem to have him on a primary radar. They seem to think that he is descending."

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:44</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> reported losing phone contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX>. About this same time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>, "Something is wrong. We are in a rapid descent . . . we are all over the place." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> to look out the window to see if she could determine where they were. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX> responded:"We are flying low. We are flying very, very low. We are flying way too low." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Seconds later</TIMEX> she said,"Oh my God we are way too low." The phone call ended.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:46:40</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> crashed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower of the World Trade Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>.

    All on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, along with an unknown number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, were killed instantly.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijacking</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175 United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight 175 was scheduled to depart for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Victor Saracini</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Horrocks</ENAMEX> piloted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">767</ENAMEX>, which had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. Fifty-six <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> boarded the flight.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX> pushed back from its gate at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:58</TIMEX> and departed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan Airport</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:14</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:33</TIMEX>, it had reached its assigned cruising altitude of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31,000 feet</NUMEX>. The flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> would have begun their cabin service.

    The flight had taken off just as American <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> was being hijacked, and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:42</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> completed their report on a "suspicious transmission" overheard from another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> (which turned out to have been Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) just after takeoff. This was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX>'s last communication with the ground.

    The hijackers attacked sometime <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 8:42 and 8:46</TIMEX>. They used knives (as reported by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and a flight attendant), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mace</ENAMEX> (reported by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> passenger), and the threat of a bomb (reported by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX>). They stabbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> (reported by a flight attendant and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> passenger). Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> had been killed (reported by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> flight attendant). The eyewitness accounts came from calls made from the rear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> originally seated further forward in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>, a sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> had been moved to the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. Given similarities to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> in hijacker seating and in eyewitness reports of tactics and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, as well as the contact between the presumed team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX>, we believe the tactics were similar on both flights.

    The first operational evidence that something was abnormal on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX> came at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:47</TIMEX>, when the aircraft changed beacon codes twice within a minute. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:51</TIMEX>, the flight deviated from its assigned altitude, and a minute later <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> air traffic controllers began repeatedly and unsuccessfully trying to contact it.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:52</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Easton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Hanson</ENAMEX> received a phone call from his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, a passenger on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> told him: "I think they've taken over the cockpit-An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX> has been stabbed- and someone else up front may have been killed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> is making strange moves. Call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX>-Tell them it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LA.</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Hanson</ENAMEX> then called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easton Police Department</ENAMEX> and relayed what he had heard.

    Also at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:52</TIMEX>, a male flight attendant called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">United office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Policastro</ENAMEX>. The flight attendant reported that the flight had been hijacked, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> had been killed, a flight attendant had been stabbed, and the hijackers were probably flying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. The call lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two minutes</TIMEX>, after which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policastro</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> tried unsuccessfully to contact the flight.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:58</TIMEX>, the flight took a heading toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:59</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX> passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian David Sweeney</ENAMEX> tried to call his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>. He left a message on their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> answering machine that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> had been hijacked. He then called his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Sweeney</ENAMEX>, told her the flight had been hijacked, and added that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were thinking about storming the cockpit to take control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> away from the hijackers.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Hanson</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> call from his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>: It's getting bad, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>-A stewardess was stabbed-They seem to have knives and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mace</ENAMEX>-They said they have a bomb-It's getting very bad on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Passengers</ENAMEX> are throwing up and getting sick-The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> is making jerky movements-I don't think the pilot is flying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>-I think we are going down-I think they intend to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> or someplace and fly into a building-Don't worry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>- If it happens, it'll be very fast-My God, my God.

    The call ended abruptly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Hanson</ENAMEX> had heard a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> scream just before it cut off. He turned on a television, and in her home so did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Sweeney</ENAMEX>. Both then saw the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:03:11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight 175 struck the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower of the World Trade Center</ENAMEX>.

    All on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, along with an unknown number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, were killed instantly.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijacking of American 77 American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX> was scheduled to depart from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> Dulles for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:10</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">757</ENAMEX> piloted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Charles F. Burlingame</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Charlebois</ENAMEX>. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, the flight carried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 77</ENAMEX> pushed back from its gate at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:09</TIMEX> and took off at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:20</TIMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:46</TIMEX>, the flight reached its assigned cruising altitude of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35,000 feet</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cabin</ENAMEX> service would have begun. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:51</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> 77 transmitted its last routine radio communication. The hijacking began <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 8:51 and 8:54</TIMEX>. As on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX>, the hijackers used knives (reported by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> passenger) and moved all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> (and possibly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>) to the rear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> (reported by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> flight attendant and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> passenger). Unlike the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> flights, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 77</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> were reported by a passenger to have box cutters. Finally, a passenger reported that an announcement had been made by the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> had been hijacked. Neither of the firsthand accounts mentioned any stabbings or the threat or use of either a bomb or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mace</ENAMEX>, though both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> began the flight in the first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:54</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> deviated from its assigned course, turning south. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Two minutes</TIMEX> later the transponder was turned off and even primary radar contact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was lost. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Air Traffic Control Center</ENAMEX> repeatedly tried and failed to contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX> also tried, without success.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerard Arpey</ENAMEX> learned that communications had been lost with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX>. This was now the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> in trouble. He ordered all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> flights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> that had not taken off to remain on the ground. Shortly before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:10</TIMEX>, suspecting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 77</ENAMEX> had been hijacked, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> concluded that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> might have been Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>. After learning that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> was missing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> extended the ground stop nationwide.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:12</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee May</ENAMEX> called her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy May</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. She said her flight was being hijacked by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who had moved them to the rear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. She asked her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to alert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy May</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> promptly did so.

    At some point <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 9:16 and 9:26</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Olson</ENAMEX> called her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Olson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitor general</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. She reported that the flight had been hijacked, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> had knives and box cutters. She further indicated that the hijackers were not aware of her phone call, and that they had put all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> in the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">About</NUMEX> a minute into the conversation, the call was cut off. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Solicitor General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX> tried unsuccessfully to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashcroft</ENAMEX>.

    Shortly after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> call, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Olson</ENAMEX> reached her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> again. She reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> had announced that the flight had been hijacked, and she asked her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> what she should tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> to do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Olson</ENAMEX> asked for her location and she replied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was then flying over <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> told her they were traveling northeast. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Solicitor General</ENAMEX> then informed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> previous hijackings and crashes. She did not display signs of panic and did not indicate any awareness of an impending crash. At that point, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> call was cut off.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:29</TIMEX>, the autopilot on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX> was disengaged; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7,000 feet</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 38 miles</NUMEX> west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:32</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dulles Terminal Radar Approach Control</ENAMEX> "observed a primary radar target tracking eastbound at a high rate of speed." This was later determined to have been Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:34</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Washington National Airport</ENAMEX> advised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> of an unknown aircraft heading in the direction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 77</ENAMEX> was then <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 miles</NUMEX> west-southwest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and began a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">330</NUMEX>-degree turn. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the turn</TIMEX>, it was descending through <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,200 feet</NUMEX>, pointed toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. The hijacker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> then advanced the throttles to maximum power and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dove</ENAMEX> toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:37:46</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX> crashed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, traveling at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 530 miles per hour</NUMEX>.

    All on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, as well as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> and military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, were killed.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United 93</ENAMEX> At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:42</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX> took off from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liberty International Airport</ENAMEX> bound for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was piloted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Jason Dahl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leroy Homer</ENAMEX>, and there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirty</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, including the hijackers, boarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. Scheduled to depart the gate at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">757</ENAMEX>'s takeoff was delayed because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>'s typically heavy morning traffic.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> had planned to take flights scheduled to depart at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:45</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United 175 and United 93</ENAMEX>), and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:10</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of the flights had actually taken off within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 to 15 minutes</TIMEX> of their planned departure times. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 93</ENAMEX> would ordinarily have taken off <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 15 minutes</TIMEX> after pulling away from the gate. When it left the ground at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:42</TIMEX>, the flight was running <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than 25 minutes</TIMEX> late.

    As <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United 93</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>, the flight's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew members</ENAMEX> were unaware of the hijacking of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. Around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> were facing the staggering realization of apparent multiple hijackings. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:03</TIMEX>, they would see another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> strike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>. Crisis <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> did not yet act to warn other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.

    At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> realized that a message transmitted just before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:25</TIMEX> by the hijacker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> included the phrase, "We have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>."

    No one at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> had ever dealt with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple hijackings</ENAMEX>. Such a plot had not been carried out anywhere in the world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 30 years</TIMEX>, and never in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. As news of the hijackings filtered through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, it does not seem to have occurred to their leadership that they needed to alert other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> in the air that they too might be at risk.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX> was hijacked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 8:42 and 8:46</TIMEX>, and awareness of that hijacking began to spread after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:51</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 77</ENAMEX> was hijacked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 8:51 and 8:54</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> began to comprehend that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attackers</ENAMEX> were going after multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>' nationwide ground stop <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 9:05 and 9:10</TIMEX> was followed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> ground stop. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX>, which had tracked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first two hijackings</TIMEX>, requested at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:07</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herndon Command Center</ENAMEX> "get messages to airborne <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to increase security for the cockpit." There is no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herndon</ENAMEX> took such action. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> immediately began speculating about other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> that might be in danger, leading them to worry about a transcontinental flight-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1989</ENAMEX>-that in fact was not hijacked. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:19</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Herndon</ENAMEX> and asked that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Center</ENAMEX> advise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1989</ENAMEX> to use extra cockpit security.

    Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> air traffic control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> told us it was the air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>' responsibility to notify their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> of security problems. One senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> air traffic control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> said that it was simply not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s place to order the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> what to tell their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>.

    We believe such statements do not reflect an adequate appreciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s responsibility for the safety and security of civil aviation.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> bore responsibility, too. They were facing an escalating number of conflicting and, for the most part, erroneous reports about other flights, as well as a continuing lack of vital information from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> about the hijacked flights. We found no evidence, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> sent any cockpit warnings to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>'s first decisive action to notify its airborne <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to take defensive action did not come until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:19</TIMEX>, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> flight dispatcher, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Ballinger</ENAMEX>, took the initiative to begin transmitting warnings to his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> transcontinental flights: "Beware any cockpit intrusion- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> a/c [<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>] hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the flights that received the warning was <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United 93</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballinger</ENAMEX> was still responsible for his other flights as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX>, his warning message was not transmitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:23</TIMEX>.

    By all accounts, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 46 minutes</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX>'s cross-country trip proceeded routinely. Radio communications from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> were normal. Heading, speed, and altitude ran according to plan. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:24</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballinger</ENAMEX>'s warning to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United 93</ENAMEX> was received in the cockpit. Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:26</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Dahl</ENAMEX>, responded with a note of puzzlement: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>, confirm latest mssg plz-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason</ENAMEX>."

    The hijackers attacked at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:28</TIMEX>. While traveling <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35,000 feet</NUMEX> above eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 93</ENAMEX> suddenly dropped <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">700 feet</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> into the descent, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s air traffic control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> received the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> radio transmissions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. During the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> broadcast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> could be heard declaring "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mayday</ENAMEX>" amid the sounds of a physical struggle in the cockpit. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> radio transmission, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">35 seconds</TIMEX> later, indicated that the fight was continuing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> could be heard shouting:" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX> get out of here-get out of here-get out of here."

    On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United 93-33</ENAMEX> in addition to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> hijackers. This was below the norm for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 2001</TIMEX>. But there is no evidence that the hijackers manipulated passenger levels or purchased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">additional</NUMEX> seats to facilitate their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> who hijacked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other commercial flights on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> operated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-man <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. They initiated their cockpit takeover within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> of takeoff. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX>, however, the takeover took place <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">46 minutes</TIMEX> after takeoff and there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> hijackers. The operative likely intended to round out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for this flight, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed al Kahtani</ENAMEX>, had been refused entry by a suspicious immigration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Orlando International Airport</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.

    Because several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 93</ENAMEX> described <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> hijackers on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, some have wondered whether one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> had been able to use the cockpit jump seat from the outset of the flight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> rules allow use of this seat by documented and approved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, usually air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. We have found no evidence indicating that one of the hijackers, or anyone else, sat there on this flight. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> had assigned seats in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class, and they seem to have used them. We believe it is more likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX>, the crucial pilot-trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, remained seated and inconspicuous until after the cockpit was seized; and once inside, he would not have been visible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:32</TIMEX>, a hijacker, probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX>, made or attempted to make the following announcement to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX>:"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ladies and Gentlemen: Here the captain</ENAMEX>, please sit down keep remaining sitting. We have a bomb on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. So, sit." The flight data recorder (also recovered) indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> then instructed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s autopilot to turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> around and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> east.

    The cockpit voice recorder data indicate that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, most likely a flight attendant, was being held captive in the cockpit. She struggled with one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> who killed or otherwise silenced her.

    Shortly thereafter, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> began a series of calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airphones</ENAMEX> and cellular phones. These calls between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> took place until the end of the flight and provided those on the ground with firsthand accounts. They enabled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to gain critical information, including the news that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> had slammed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:39</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Route Traffic Control Center</ENAMEX> overheard a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> announcement indicating that there was a bomb on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was returning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, and that they should remain seated.

    While it apparently was not heard by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, this announcement, like those on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 77</ENAMEX>, was intended to deceive them. Jarrah, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, may have inadvertently broadcast the message because he did not know how to operate the radio and the intercom. To our knowledge none of them had ever flown an actual airliner before.

    <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> from the flight reported that the hijackers knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were making calls but did not seem to care. It is quite possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> knew of the success of the assault on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>. He could have learned of this from messages being sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> to the cockpits of its transcontinental flights, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX>, warning of cockpit intrusion and telling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> attacks. But even without them, he would certainly have understood that the attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> would already have unfolded, given <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX>'s tardy departure from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> did know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were making calls, it might not have occurred to him that they were certain to learn what had happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, thereby defeating his attempts at deception.

    At least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> crew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> shared vital information with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, or others on the ground. All understood the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> had been hijacked. They said the hijackers wielded knives and claimed to have a bomb. The hijackers were wearing red bandanas, and they forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Callers</ENAMEX> reported that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> had been stabbed and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were lying on the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>, injured or dead-possibly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> reported that a flight attendant had been killed.

    <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United 93</ENAMEX> also reported that he thought the hijackers might possess a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>. But none of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> reported the presence of a firearm. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> of a call from the aircraft recounted specifically asking her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. The passenger replied that he did not see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. No evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">firearms</ENAMEX> or of their identifiable remains was found at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>'s crash site, and the cockpit voice recorder gives no indication of a gun being fired or mentioned at any time. We believe that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> had possessed a gun, they would have used it in the flight's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last minutes</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> fought back.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Passengers</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> flights reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>' claim of having a bomb. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> told us they found no trace of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> at the crash sites. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who mentioned a bomb expressed his belief that it was not real. Lacking any evidence that the hijackers attempted to smuggle such illegal items past the security screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoints</ENAMEX>, we believe the bombs were probably fake.

    During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least five</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>' phone calls, information was shared about the attacks that had occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> calls described the intent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew members</ENAMEX> to revolt against the hijackers. According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> call, they voted on whether to rush the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> in an attempt to retake the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. They decided, and acted.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:57</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> assault began. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> had terminated phone calls with loved ones in order to join the revolt. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> ended her message as follows:"Everyone's running up to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class. I've got to go. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bye</ENAMEX>."

    The cockpit voice recorder captured the sounds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> assault muffled by the intervening cockpit door. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family members</ENAMEX> who listened to the recording report that they can hear the voice of a loved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> among the din. We cannot identify whose voices can be heard. But the assault was sustained.

    In response, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> immediately began to roll the airplane to the left and right, attempting to knock the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> off balance. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:58:57</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> told another hijacker in the cockpit to block the door. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> continued to roll the airplane sharply left and right, but the assault continued. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:59:52</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> changed tactics and pitched the nose of the airplane up and down to disrupt the assault. The recorder captured the sounds of loud thumps, crashes, shouts, and breaking glasses and plates. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00:03</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> stabilized the airplane.

    <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five seconds</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> asked, "Is that it? Shall we finish it off?"A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX> responded,"No. Not yet. When they all come, we finish it off." The sounds of fighting continued outside the cockpit. Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> pitched the nose of the aircraft up and down. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00:26</TIMEX>, a passenger in the background said,"In the cockpit. If we don't we'll die!" <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Sixteen seconds</TIMEX> later, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> yelled,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roll it</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> stopped the violent maneuvers at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10:01:00</TIMEX> and said,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allah</ENAMEX> is the greatest! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allah</ENAMEX> is the greatest!" He then asked another hijacker in the cockpit," Is that it? I mean, shall we put it down?" to which the other replied,"Yes, put it in it, and pull it down."

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> continued their assault and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:02:23</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX> said, "Pull it down! Pull it down!"The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hijackers</ENAMEX> remained at the controls but must have judged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only seconds</TIMEX> from overcoming them. The airplane headed down; the control wheel was turned hard to the right. The airplane rolled onto its back, and one of the hijackers began shouting "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allah</ENAMEX> is the greatest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allah</ENAMEX> is the greatest." With the sounds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> counterattack continuing, the aircraft plowed into an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanksville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">580 miles per hour</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 20 minutes</TIMEX>' flying time from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX>'s objective was to crash his airliner into symbols of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Republic</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. He was defeated by the alerted, unarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> 93.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMPROVISING A HOMELAND DEFENSE</ENAMEX>

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and NORAD

    On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, the defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> airspace depended on close interaction between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Aerospace Defense Command</ENAMEX> (NORAD). The most recent hijacking that involved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> air traffic controllers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and military coordination had occurred in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1993.90</NUMEX> In order to understand how the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> interacted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years later</TIMEX>, we will review their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">command</ENAMEX> and control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>, and working relationship on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA Mission</ENAMEX> and Structure. As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> was mandated by law to regulate the safety and security of civil aviation. From an air traffic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX>'s perspective, that meant maintaining a safe distance between airborne <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.

    Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Route Traffic Control Centers</ENAMEX>. They are grouped under regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and coordinate closely with the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic Control System Command Center</ENAMEX>, located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herndon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, which oversees <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> traffic flow within the entire airspace system. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> is ultimately responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Airspace System</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Operations Center</ENAMEX> located at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> receives notifications of incidents, including accidents and hijackings.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA Control Centers</ENAMEX> often receive information and make operational decisions independently of one another. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> were monitored mainly by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> thus had part of the knowledge of what was going on across the system. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> knew was not necessarily known by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, or for that matter by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Command Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herndon</ENAMEX> or by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

    Controllers track <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX> such as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> aircraft hijacked on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> primarily by watching the data from a signal emitted by each <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>'s transponder equipment. Those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, like all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> traveling above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10,000 feet</NUMEX>, were required to emit a unique transponder signal while in flight.

    On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> turned off the transponders on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. With its transponder off, it is possible, though more difficult, to track an aircraft by its primary radar returns. But unlike transponder data, primary radar returns do not show the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>'s identity and altitude. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Controllers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> rely so heavily on transponder signals that they usually do not display primary radar returns on their radar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">scopes</ENAMEX>. But they can change the configuration of their scopes so they can see primary radar returns. They did this on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> when the transponder signals for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> disappeared.

    Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, it was not unheard of for a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to deviate slightly from its course, or for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> to lose radio contact with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short period of time</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> could also briefly lose a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>'s transponder signal, although this happened much less frequently. However, the simultaneous loss of radio and transponder signal would be a rare and alarming occurrence, and would normally indicate a catastrophic system failure or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> crash. In all of these instances, the job of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> was to reach out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, the parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> in the vicinity in an attempt to reestablish communications and set the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> back on course. Alarm bells would not start ringing until these efforts-which could take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> or more-were tried and had failed.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD Mission</ENAMEX> and Structure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> is a binational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. Its mission was, and is, to defend the airspace of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> and protect the continent. That mission does not distinguish between internal and external threats; but because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> was created to counter the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> threat, it came to define its job as defending against external attacks.

    The threat of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> diminished significantly as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> ended, and the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> alert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> was reduced from its <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> high of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>. Some within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> argued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> that the alert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> should be eliminated entirely. In an effort to preserve their mission, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the air defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> advocated the importance of air sovereignty against emerging "asymmetric threats" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> smuggling, "non-state and state-sponsored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>," and the proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction and ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> technology.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> perceived the dominant threat to be from cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. Other threats were identified during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>' use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. Exercises were conducted to counter this threat, but they were not based on actual intelligence. In most instances, the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> was the use of such <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to deliver <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction.

    Prior to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, it was understood that an order to shoot down a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> would have to be issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Command Authority</ENAMEX> (a phrase used to describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense). Exercise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> also assumed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> would originate from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, allowing time to identify the target and scramble interceptors. The threat of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> hijacking commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>-and using them as guided <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>-was not recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>. Notwithstanding the identification of these emerging threats, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only seven</NUMEX> alert sites left in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, each with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter aircraft</ENAMEX> on alert. This led some NORAD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> to worry that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> was not postured adequately to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

    In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> is divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, all the hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast Air Defense Sector</ENAMEX> (also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEADS</ENAMEX>), which is based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. That <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> NEADS could call on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> alert sites, each with one pair of ready <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Otis Air National Guard</ENAMEX> Base in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Cod</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Langley Air Force Base</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hampton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.

    Other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, not on "alert," would need time to arm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> and organize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEADS</ENAMEX> reported to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental U.S. NORAD Region</ENAMEX> (CONR) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, which in turn reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interagency Collaboration</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> had developed protocols for working together in the event of a hijacking. As they existed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, the protocols for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> to obtain military assistance from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> required multiple levels of notification and approval at the highest levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> guidance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> on hijack procedures assumed that the aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> would notify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> via radio or by"squawking"a transponder code of "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7500</TIMEX>"-the universal code for a hijack in progress. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Controllers</ENAMEX> would notify their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX>, who in turn would inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> all the way up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Headquarters</ENAMEX> had a hijack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>, who was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA Office of Civil Aviation Security</ENAMEX> or his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designate</ENAMEX>.

    If a hijack was confirmed, procedures called for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hijack</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> on duty to contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Military Command Center</ENAMEX> (NMCC) and to ask for a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">escort aircraft</ENAMEX> to follow the flight, report anything unusual, and aid search and rescue in the event of an emergency. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMCC</ENAMEX> would then seek approval from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> to provide military assistance. If approval was given, the orders would be transmitted down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMCC</ENAMEX> would keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> hijack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to date</TIMEX> and help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> centers coordinate directly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> would receive tracking information for the hijacked aircraft either from joint use radar or from the relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> air traffic control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. Every attempt would be made to have the hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> squawk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7500</TIMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> it.

    The protocols did not contemplate an intercept. They assumed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter escort</ENAMEX> would be discreet, "vectored to a position <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> directly behind the hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>," where it could perform its mission to monitor the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>'s flight path.

    In sum, the protocols in place on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> to respond to a hijacking presumed that


the hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> would be readily identifiable and would not attempt to disappear;

there would be time to address the problem through the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>; and

the hijacking would take the traditional form: that is, it would not be a suicide hijacking designed to convert the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> into a guided <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>.


    On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, the existing protocol was unsuited in every respect for what was about to happen.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA Awareness</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> air traffic controller realized at an early stage that there was something wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>, he did not immediately interpret the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s failure to respond as a sign that it had been hijacked. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:14</TIMEX>, when the flight failed to heed his instruction to climb to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35,000 feet</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> repeatedly tried to raise the flight. He reached out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> on the emergency frequency. Though there was no response, he kept trying to contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:21</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX> turned off its transponder, immediately degrading the information available about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> that he thought something was seriously wrong with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, although neither suspected a hijacking. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> instructed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> to follow standard procedures for handling a "no radio" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> checked to see if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> could establish communication with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. He became even more concerned as its route changed, moving into another sector's airspace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Controllers</ENAMEX> immediately began to move <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> out of its path, and asked other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> in the vicinity to look for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> 11.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:24:38</TIMEX>, the following transmission came from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American 11: American 11:</ENAMEX> We have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. Just stay quiet, and you'll be okay. We are returning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> only heard something unintelligible; he did not hear the specific words "we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>." The next transmission came <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> later: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX>: Nobody move. Everything will be okay. If you try to make any moves, you'll endanger yourself and the airplane. Just stay quiet.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> told us that he then knew it was a hijacking. He alerted his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>, who assigned another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> to assist him. He redoubled his efforts to ascertain the flight's altitude. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> didn't understand the initial transmission, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> instructed his quality assurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> to "pull the tape" of the radio transmission, listen to it closely, and report back.

    Between <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:25 and 8:32</TIMEX>, in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> protocol, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> started notifying their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX> had been hijacked. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:28</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Command Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herndon</ENAMEX> to advise that it believed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX> had been hijacked and was heading toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Center</ENAMEX>'s airspace.

    By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX> had taken a dramatic turn to the south. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:32</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Command Center</ENAMEX> passed word of a possible hijacking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations Center</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. The duty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> replied that security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> had just begun discussing the apparent hijack on a conference call with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> began to follow the hijack protocol but did not contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMCC</ENAMEX> to request a fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX>.

    The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herndon Command Center</ENAMEX> immediately established a teleconference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Centers</ENAMEX> so that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> could help the others understand what was happening.

    At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:34</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> transmission from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>:

    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX>: Nobody move please. We are going back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. Don't try to make any stupid moves.

    In the succeeding <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> were attempting to ascertain the altitude of the southbound flight.
