
    
        
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Mani Ahmad al Kahtani</ENAMEX>. Currently in custody, he is the last known <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
                muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to be sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early August 2001</TIMEX>, to round out
                the number of hijackers. As discussed later in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, he was refused entry.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frost</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27, 2004</TIMEX>, available at
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defenselink</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mil</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Threat Threads: Recent Advances in</ENAMEX>
                Understanding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 September</TIMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002-30086CH</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 4</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 3, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid Saeed Ahmad al Zahrani</ENAMEX>. He traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> illegally after being
                prohibited by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> from leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. After being assigned to a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, he secretly reentered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> but failed in an attempt to
                have his name removed from the list of prohibited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> so that he could obtain
                a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of detainee, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 2002</TIMEX>;
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4, 2002</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Abd al Rahman al Faqasi al Ghamdi</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aka</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Bakr al Azdi</ENAMEX>) He reportedly was to
                have been part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> operation but was held in reserve by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> for a
                later, even larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. Like other muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>, he reportedly set out for
                Chechnya but diverted to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Bakr al Azdi</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 25, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 and 5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saeed al Baluchi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Qutaybah al Najdi</ENAMEX>. Both were sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> via
                Bahrain, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Najdi</ENAMEX> was stopped and briefly questioned by airport security
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. Both were so frightened by the experience that they withdrew from the
                operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baluchi</ENAMEX> to obtain a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baluchi</ENAMEX> refused, fearing
                that he might be watchlisted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>,
                Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuhair al Thubaiti</ENAMEX>: He has reportedly admitted membership in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, stating
                "proudly" that he was among a select number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> who had the personal
                endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. He was not ultimately selected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9/11</TIMEX> attacks
                because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> considered him too high-strung and lacking the
                necessary temperament. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Threat Threads</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 3</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17,2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,2002</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reports).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saeed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Saeed</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Jihad"</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Ghamdi</ENAMEX>. He arranged to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX>, swore allegiance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> (agreeing to serve as a suicide
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">operative</ENAMEX>), and was sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad al Haznawi</ENAMEX>
                to obtain a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa, but his visa application was denied because he appeared to be
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intending</ENAMEX> to immigrate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghamdi</ENAMEX> visa application, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analytic</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Threat Threads</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 4</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of detainee, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saud al Rashid</ENAMEX>. Describing him as headstrong and immature, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> says he disappeared
                after being sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa, either because he had second
                thoughts or because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> interceded and confiscated his passport. Passport
                photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashid</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three 9/11</NUMEX> hijackers-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omari</ENAMEX>-were
                found together during a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2002</TIMEX> raid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>. After discovery of the photos in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashid</ENAMEX> turned himself in to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>, but he has since been
                released from custody. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> interview, he has admitted training in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> but denies hearing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> before returning from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> or
                meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, or any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> hijacker other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad al Haznawi</ENAMEX>, whom he
                claims seeing only once or twice at a guesthouse. He has no credible explanation why
                photos of him were found with those of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other hijackers, or why others
                identified him as a candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 11, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saud al Rashid</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mushabib al Hamlan</ENAMEX>. Sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> to acquire a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa, he and his travel
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">companion</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Nami</ENAMEX>, both applied for and received visas on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 28, 2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> never returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, probably dropping out either
                because he changed his mind or because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> intervened.
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>, while still in high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamlan</ENAMEX> became involved
                with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that gathered periodically to watch jihad propaganda tapes, and was
                encouraged by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bandar Marui</ENAMEX> to pursue jihad, especially as practiced
                in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herzegovina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> wars and a book titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gladiator of</ENAMEX>
                Passion. As instructed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> acquired a passport, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 15, 2000</TIMEX>, and agreed
                to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> after the hajj in mid-March <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. He and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> travel companions
                obtained <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> visas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sharjah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX>, and traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">facilitator Hassan Ghul</ENAMEX> took them to a guesthouse managed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>. Days
                later, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hamlan</ENAMEX> cross the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> border.
            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khaldan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> received military training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>. Upon hearing that the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX> was to be closed, he and others traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Faruq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kandahar</ENAMEX>, where
                they received more training. He also met and proclaimed allegiance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> at
                this time. Injured during a further training session, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamlan</ENAMEX> was assigned to guard
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, where he met future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Nami</ENAMEX> (whose recent laser eye
                surgery had interrupted his training). An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Basir al Yemeni</ENAMEX>
                indoctrinated the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s anti-U.S. position and extolled the virtues of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">martyrdom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nami</ENAMEX> eventually agreed to approach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Hafs al Mauritani</ENAMEX> about
                participating in a suicide operation. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> after visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hafs, Hamlan</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nami</ENAMEX> heard from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Basir</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was planning an attack against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. After taking their passports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Basir</ENAMEX> arranged for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nami</ENAMEX> to meet
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and instructed them to use the following phrase to express their desire to
                become martyrs:"I want to be one of this religion's bricks and glorify this
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> accepted both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Basir</ENAMEX>
                took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamlan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nami</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kandahar</ENAMEX> to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, who impressed on them the high
                expectations for martyrs and instructed them on using coded telephone numbers. He
                returned their passports, which had been altered and now contained forged tourism
                stamps for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> told them to meet with Atef
                before returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, where they should contact hijacker future 9/11
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hijacker Waleed al Shehri</ENAMEX> for additional documentation. After meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nami</ENAMEX> traveled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and by air to an address <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> had given them
                inTehran, where arrangements were made for them to fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qatar</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qatar</ENAMEX> they
                traveled onward to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX> and then to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mecca</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nami</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> and received coded
                instructions to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jeddah</ENAMEX>, call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waleed al Shehri</ENAMEX>, and obtain visas at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consulate</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jeddah</ENAMEX>, they briefly shared an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehri</ENAMEX>, who provided
                them with directions to the consulate and showed them how to fill out the visa
                application. After acquiring visas, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nami</ENAMEX> presented their passports to
                Shehri for inspection and returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mecca</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nami</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, who told them to
                return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>. Despite instructions to the contrary, Hamlan
                insisted on calling his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> before leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> because he had begun to
                have second thoughts after acquiring the visa. Told by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that their mother
                had fallen ill. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> decided not to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> even after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nami</ENAMEX> reminded
                him of his allegiance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and commitment to complete the suicide mission.
                In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riyadh</ENAMEX>, he told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> that he had been on jihad in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. Fearing that
                they might ask for his passport, he removed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa-as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> confirmed by
                forensic analysis performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> returned to college and
                resumed living with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, who confiscated his passport. Thereafter, Hamlan
                received a visit at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> from a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Faruq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al</ENAMEX>
                Zahrani, who asked why he had not returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zahrani</ENAMEX> admitted having
                been sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamlan</ENAMEX> to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlan</ENAMEX> never did.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of detainee, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abderraouf Jdey</ENAMEX>, a.k.a. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faruq al Tunisi</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> passport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>, he may have
                trained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX> and received
                instruction from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>. A letter recovered from a safehouse
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, apparently written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sayf al Adl</ENAMEX>, also suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jdey</ENAMEX> was
                initially part of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> at the same time as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. A
                videotape of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jdey</ENAMEX>'s martyrdom statement was found in the rubble of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX> 's house
                near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kabul</ENAMEX> following a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2001</TIMEX> airstrike, together with a martyrdom video of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>. While both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> confirm <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jdey</ENAMEX>'s status as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recruit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jdey</ENAMEX> was slated for a "second wave"of attacks but had dropped out
                by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 2001</TIMEX> while in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> briefing (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">108</NUMEX>. On the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> fully aware of the plot and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Turab</ENAMEX>'s training, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Turab</ENAMEX> was the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ayman al Zawahiri</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zubaydah</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 18, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also taught the muscle hijackers English and provided lessons
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 2, 2004</TIMEX>. Binalshibh
                also has discussed this training in post-capture statements, describing it as
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hand-to-hand</ENAMEX> combat training. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 2004</TIMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, after returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, muscle hijacker
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recruits</ENAMEX> fought on the front lines alongside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> and participated in the
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2001</TIMEX> destruction of the giant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> statues in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bamian Province</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh, Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">109</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23, 2004</TIMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, the
                muscle hijackers learned about the specific targets and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s completed
                operational plan only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late August</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 2, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilitator</ENAMEX>'s comments, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of
                detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 3, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5, 2003</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reports), in which he
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">claims</ENAMEX> also to have assisted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s funding of
                the hijackers, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>'s role and the transit of the hijackers, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 12, 2004</TIMEX>. According to the detainee, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>
                arrived with their own money to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> tickets and anything else they needed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>
                referred them to places where they could obtain travelers checks. He also helped
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX>, one of the earliest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> to transit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubai</ENAMEX>, acquire a mobile
                phone account so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> could use that number as a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> point
                of contact. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">112</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> to participate in a suicide mission and
                offered to travel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and assist the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> there. As discussed
                in a set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> (referred to by the
                nickname "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Losh</ENAMEX>") appears to have contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and expressed the desire to join the
                operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> actually applied for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 27, 2001</TIMEX>, listing his
                intended arrival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 4</TIMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-week</TIMEX> stay. His application was denied
                because he appeared to be an economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> record, visa application of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Aziz Ali</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.27, 2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, documents captured with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRG Research</ENAMEX> Notes," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of Penttbom
                Investigation," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 72</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">113</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8, 2004</TIMEX>. See
                also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawsawi</ENAMEX>'s
                role as financial facilitator appears to have begun when he and hijacker Banihammad
                opened bank accounts at the same UAE bank while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banihammad</ENAMEX> was his way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Banihammad, who was from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX>, was familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s procedures
                and helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawsawi</ENAMEX> complete his account application. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banihammad</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawsawi</ENAMEX> roughly
                <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> and granted him power of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> over his account so that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawsawi</ENAMEX> could
                forward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> card to him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banihammad</ENAMEX> arrived in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawsawi</ENAMEX> deposited <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,900</NUMEX> into the account. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary of</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 29</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX>. All but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15</ENAMEX> muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> were admitted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, affording a
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-month</TIMEX> stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (except in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, who received
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> to arrive were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waleed al Shehri</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>) and Satam
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Suqami</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>), who flew from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23, 2001</TIMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> most likely met them. Suqami was admitted as a business
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visitor</ENAMEX>, allowing him only a onemonth stay and thus making him an illegal overstay
                by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> records, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIIS</ENAMEX> records of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waleed al Shehri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satam al Suqami</ENAMEX>,
                Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 2001</TIMEX>. Suqami was the only hijacker not to obtain a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> identification
                document. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehri</ENAMEX> and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> (presumably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Suqami</ENAMEX>) settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, moving into a motel on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London EC</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2236</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7134</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350, serial 8082</ENAMEX>).
            The next set, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moqed</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 77</ENAMEX>), arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulles</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2, 2001</TIMEX>, on a flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> originating in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubai</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> records,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIIS</ENAMEX> records of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghamdi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moqed</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2, 2001</TIMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> declarations of the
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two</TIMEX> indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moqed</ENAMEX> claimed to be carrying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $10,000</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX>
                Service generated no report of this event. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghamdi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moqed</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyatt</ENAMEX>
                Hotel in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> as their intended destination, but instead moved into the
                apartment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX> had rented.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing flight manifest and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>, referenced in <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2746</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280359-RY</ENAMEX>, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-302</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> ECs dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28, 2001, Sept. 29, 2001</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9776</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350</ENAMEX>-IN, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5151</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-302</ENAMEX>).
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamza al Ghamdi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohand al Shehri</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Nami</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX>) arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28, 2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> records, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIIS</ENAMEX> records of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamza al</ENAMEX>
                Ghamdi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohand al Shehri</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Nami</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28, 2001</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> had taken a
                flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> after starting out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubai</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> probably picked up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> at
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, having rented a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nami</ENAMEX> gave the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheraton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> as their intended destination, but do not appear to have stayed
                there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marwan al Shehhi</ENAMEX> helped them settle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>, Shehhi
                found the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delray Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "Hijackers
                Timeline," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-NK</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2851</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-CG,</ENAMEX>
                serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY- 280350-NK</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2851</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-DL</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1778</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-DL</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">838</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265D-NY-280350</ENAMEX>-A, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-NK</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2851</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-MM-302, serial 11703</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haznawi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wail al Shehri</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight</ENAMEX>
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 8, 2001</TIMEX> using the same route as the
                previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> records, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIIS</ENAMEX> records of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haznawi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wail al Shehri</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 8</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-RY,</ENAMEX>
                serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saeed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banihammad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX>) arrived in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27, 2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> records, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIIS</ENAMEX> records of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saeed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX>
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banihammad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27, 2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saeed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX> was questioned by immigration
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> as a possible intending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX>, as he spoke little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, had no
                return ticket, and listed no address on his arrival record. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> record, inspection
                results for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghamdi</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27, 2001</TIMEX>; primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2004</TIMEX>);
                secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 2004</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghamdi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banihammad</ENAMEX> presumably
                stayed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> who preceded them or with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. Post- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> investigation revealed that during this
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> period <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> also checked into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> or rented <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> with
                unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>, probably the newly arrived muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-302-19615</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">265A-NY-280350-MM</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3255</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">265A-NY-280350-MM-302</ENAMEX>, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34927</NUMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">265A-NY-280350-MM-Sub</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3255</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-RY</ENAMEX>, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-MM-</ENAMEX>
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">302</NUMEX>, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34927</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">265A-NY-280350-MM</ENAMEX>, serials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48418, 2374, 4449, 4696</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350, serials 925, 449, 18695</ENAMEX>).
            The remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem al Hazmi</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 77</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omari</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>) arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29, 2001</TIMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubai</ENAMEX> with a
                connection in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zurich</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> records, arrival records of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem al Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omari</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29, 2001</TIMEX>. They likely were picked up by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX>'s older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf</ENAMEX>-who was then
                living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paterson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX>-the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following day</TIMEX>, for on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nawaf</ENAMEX> had a minor car accident traveling eastbound on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington Bridge</ENAMEX>,
                toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bern EC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 15</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS NIIS</ENAMEX> report; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-302</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7134</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY- 280350-HQ</ENAMEX>, serial
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11297</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bern EC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omari PNR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss Air</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350-302, serial 60839</ENAMEX>). On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Hazmi</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paterson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimi Nouri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 5</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29,2004</TIMEX>, pp<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drucker</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">116</NUMEX>. In some cases, bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> completed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number fields on the
                new account application with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX>'s date of birth or visa control number, but
                did so on their own to complete the form. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Drucker</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12, 2004</TIMEX>).
                Contrary to persistent media reports, no financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> filed a Suspicious
                Activity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> (SAR)-which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to file within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> of a
                suspicious transaction-with respect to any transaction of any of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> hijackers before
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>. A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> did file SARs after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, when the hijackers'names became
                public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Drucker</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sloan</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 14</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). Nor should SARs have been filed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>' transactions themselves were
                not extraordinary or remarkable. See Commission analysis of financial transactions;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Drucker</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Lormel</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 16, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad, Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">118</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 27, 2001</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 5, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-DL</ENAMEX>, serial
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2812</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY- 280350-302</ENAMEX>, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21529</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-NK, serials 21529, 11815,</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4718</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18, 2001</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 2002</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mar. 7, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2003</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation
                of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 30, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Qa'ida</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ties Forged</ENAMEX>
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Extremism</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004- 40009HCX</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2004</TIMEX>, pp. i, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6-12</NUMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20, 2001</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">122</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX> activities, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.11,2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, operative's travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">123</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, hijacker activities, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 29, 2001</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, operative's claimed identification of photos of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX> hijackers, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">124</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, hijacker activities, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 14, 2001</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 2, 2001</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 31</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, hijacker activities, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 19, 2001</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">126</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report;
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">127</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">128</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> activities, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 21, 2001</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hezbollah</ENAMEX> denies involvement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11, Sept. 22, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">129</NUMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX>'s efforts, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of Penttbom
                Investigation," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25-37</NUMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid.</ENAMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29-41</NUMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">131</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302,</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">serials 12436, 7134</ENAMEX>); see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15, 2004</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9, 2004</TIMEX>. Another example of
                unusual travel was a trip by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suqami</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>; he
                stayed at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Buena</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vista</ENAMEX> with an unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 31</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302,</ENAMEX>
                serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27063</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY- 280350-DL</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2245</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> investigation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">133</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2001</TIMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41-44</NUMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> letterhead memorandum, profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah, Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302,</ENAMEX>
                serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7228</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY- 280350-</ENAMEX>F, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-NK, serial 263</ENAMEX>). Documents
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sawyer Aviation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, show Hanjour joining the flight simulator
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23, 2001</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faisal al Salmi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rayed Abdullah</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotfi Raissi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Stangel</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14, 2001</TIMEX>. But the
                documents are inconclusive, as there are no invoices or payment records for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX>,
                while such documents do exist for the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> memo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom</ENAMEX> investigation,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 7, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> memo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom</ENAMEX> investigation, summary of dispatch sheets, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 12</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don W.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve B. interview</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6, 2004</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> identified
                Hanjour as being there during the time period, though she was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 100 percent</NUMEX>
                sure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Arnold</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17, 2001</TIMEX>. Another
                witness identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> as being with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salmi</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> area during the summer
                of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> letterhead memorandum, investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotfi Raissi</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4, 2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. Documentary evidence for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX>, however, shows that he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> for
                most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, and no travel records have been recovered showing that he returned to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> after leaving with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. Nevertheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> office
                believes it plausible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> for additional training. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                electronic communication, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom</ENAMEX> investigation, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">137</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> cable, communications analysis, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">138</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29,2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>. On obtaining photo identification, see ibid.; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report,"Hijackers
                Timeline,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-NK</ENAMEX>, serial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1243</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-BS,</ENAMEX>
                serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">352</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302, serials 33059, 64343</ENAMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">139</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 47</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> moving the muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9, 2004</TIMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, he took each of
                the muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> shopping for clothes and set them up with email accounts during
                their time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>. For meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 18, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> has
                provided inconsistent information about who else was present during his meeting with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. In one interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> claimed he attended <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different meetings,
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of which was attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atef</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Turab al Jordani</ENAMEX>, and the
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of which was attended just by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atef</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>. More recently,
                however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> has mentioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> meeting and has claimed he alone met with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> were busy with other matters. Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11, 2002</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 18, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">530</NUMEX> NOTES <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TO CHAPTER 7</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">141</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>'s meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of
                Binalshibh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 18, 2004</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> claims
                that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX> were both acceptable targets and had been on
                the list since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 1999</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, Apr.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 2004</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>'s receipt of money, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of
                Binalshibh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11, 2002</TIMEX>. In one report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> says that Atef
                provided him with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX>; in another he claims it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">142</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">143</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">144</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 2003</TIMEX>;
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 8, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">145</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 48</ENAMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21, 2002</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> had a stopover in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zurich</ENAMEX>, where he bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss Army</ENAMEX> knives and
                withdrew <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,700 Swiss francs</NUMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SunTrust</ENAMEX> bank account. He may have intended to
                use the knives during the attacks. It is unknown why he withdrew the money. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 47</ENAMEX>.
            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have not uncovered evidence that anyone met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> or
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> contend that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spanish al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> were involved in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> meeting and were connected to the
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> attacks. In an indictment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 17, 2003</TIMEX>,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> relies on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main points. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> trip to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ghasoub al Abrash Ghalyoun</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. During the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trip</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghalyoun</ENAMEX> videotaped a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landmarks</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> indictment alleges that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courier</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ghalyoun</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> shortly after the trip and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courier</ENAMEX> probably delivered the
                tape to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> contends
                that during the relevant time period, an individual named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammed Belfatmi</ENAMEX> was near
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta-Binalshibh</ENAMEX> meeting took place. and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belfatmi</ENAMEX> traveled to
                Karachi shortly before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX> on the same flight as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said Bahaji</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>, and even stayed at the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
                rely on an intercepted telephone conversation between cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imad Eddin Barakat</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yarkas</ENAMEX> and an individual named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Shakur</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>, in which "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shakur</ENAMEX>" describes
                himself as entering "the field of aviation" and "slitting the throat of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bird</ENAMEX>.""<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakur</ENAMEX>" has been identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farid Hilali</ENAMEX>. Although
                we cannot rule out the possibility that other facts will come to light as the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> case progresses to trial, we have not found evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> participated in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> meeting or in the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9/11</NUMEX> plot. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baltasar Garzon</ENAMEX>
                interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indictment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Central Investigating Court No.5</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17, 2003</TIMEX>, pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">151-200, 315-366</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Superseding Indictment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Investigating</ENAMEX>
                Court No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 28, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">146</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 2003</TIMEX>;
                Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">147</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 2003</TIMEX>;
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 18, 2004</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> claims to have
                assigned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> specifically to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>'s most experienced
                pilot. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">148</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh, Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11, 2003</TIMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> since has denied that the term electrical engineering was used to refer
                to a potential nuclear target despite having said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so earlier</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has admitted that he considered
                targeting a nuclear power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> as part of his initial proposal for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>
                operation. See chapter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.2</NUMEX>. He has also stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> included a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in
                his preliminary target list, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> decided to drop that idea.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">149</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 2003</TIMEX>;
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 18, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 2003</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">151</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>'s new phones, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Binalshibh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21, 2002</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>'s call to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> cable, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 10</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Group</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">152</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 31, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> may also have intended to include
                these documents as part of the historical file he maintained about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>
                operation. He says the file included letters and email communications among those
                involved with the attacks, but was lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> when he fled after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 15, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">153</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11, 2003</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 31, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">154</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 31, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report interrogation
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> letterhead memorandum, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom</ENAMEX> investigation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302</ENAMEX>, serial
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20874</NUMEX>); Jarrah travel documents (provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">156</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11, 2002</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">157</NUMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh, Jarrah</ENAMEX> was not aware of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moussaoui</ENAMEX> or the wire
                transfers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11, 2002</TIMEX>; Apr.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX> (classified
                version), pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89-90</NUMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">158</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moussaoui, Zacarias</ENAMEX>, a.k.a. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaqil</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2001</TIMEX>, pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 11</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                briefing materials, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penttbom</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 10-11, 2003</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 148</ENAMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302,</ENAMEX>
                serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98252</NUMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">159</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX> (classified
                version), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Weess</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.22,2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                letterhead memorandum,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moussaoui</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zacarias</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.31, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">161</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 8, 2003</TIMEX>. In
                addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moussaoui</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> as candidates
                for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the second</TIMEX> wave of attacks were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abderraouf Jdey</ENAMEX>, a.k.a. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faruq</ENAMEX> alTunisi (a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> passport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>, discussed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> as a candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX>) and Zaini
                Zakaria, a.k.a. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussa</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jemaah Islamiah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> who worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hambali</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stronghold</ENAMEX> and was directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX> to enroll in flight training sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>,
                according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 8, 2003</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali, Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">162</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh, Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2003</TIMEX>. According to
                Binalshibh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> said that the operative had been raised and educated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and
                that his arrest resulted, at least in part, from his having been insufficiently
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discreet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> identified this operative as an exception in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s overall
                record of selecting the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9/11</TIMEX> attacks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 18,2002</TIMEX>. Subsequently, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> has
                sought, somewhat incredibly, to exculpate a host of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, including
                Moussaoui, from complicity in the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9/11</NUMEX> plot. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Binalshibh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 2, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">163</NUMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>'s claims, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 7, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 27, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, see intelligence report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 5, 2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> record, arrival
                record of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 5, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">165</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302</ENAMEX>, serial
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14139</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> electronic communication). The communications were recovered from
                materials seized during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2003</TIMEX> capture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>. For background, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 13, 2002</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cables);
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, documents captured with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">166</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12, 2003</TIMEX>. Binalshibh, however,
                has denied that law and politics referred to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>; he claims that
                both terms referred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX>, even though in the context of the exchange
                it seems clear that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> were contemplated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reports).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">167</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> notes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRG Research</ENAMEX> Notes," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17, 2004</TIMEX>. In another exchange between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 9-two days</TIMEX> before the attacks-it still appears as though
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> would be the primary target for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternate</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> report, Documents captured with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">168</NUMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta-Binalshibh</ENAMEX> communication, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Binalshibh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kahtani</ENAMEX>'s attempt to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> record,
                withdrawal of application for admission of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kahtani</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4, 2001</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawsawi</ENAMEX>, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 3, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">169</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>,"
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>. On arrivals in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report,"Hijackers
                Timeline,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 2004</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350</ENAMEX>, serials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">388, 5860</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-BS,</ENAMEX>
                serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">294</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302, serial 66933</ENAMEX>). On travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, see ibid.
                (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-LV</ENAMEX>, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53299</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302, serial 110</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s
                flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX>'s arrival. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> only <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>,
                departing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 14</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>. (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-DL</ENAMEX>, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">829</NUMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-SD</ENAMEX>, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">569</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">315N-NY-280350-302, serial 165970</ENAMEX>). Detainee
                interviews have not explained the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> meeting site. See, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52-57</NUMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> successfully conducted a challenging certification flight supervised by an
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Air Charters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, landing at a
                small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> with a difficult approach. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> may have had
                training from a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> because he used a terrain recognition system for
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">navigation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Shalev</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">171</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57-60</NUMEX>.
                According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> deliberately selected <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> flights because he
                anticipated that the most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be at work then. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 17, 2002</TIMEX>;
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">173</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s receipt of date of attacks, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogations of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 27, 2003</TIMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> also has claimed that he
                called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the date</TIMEX> after receiving the information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> insists that
                he learned of the date in a letter delivered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Essabar</ENAMEX>, and that it would have been
                a serious breach of communications security to communicate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the date</TIMEX> over the phone.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 17, 2002</TIMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>. Most recently, Binalshibh
                has claimed that he neither called nor sent a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, but rather passed a
                verbal message via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Essabar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, Apr.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 2004</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>'s communication to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Essabar</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 17, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6, 2003</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">174</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>'s travel, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29, 2004</TIMEX> (classified version), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>'s communication with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, Documents captured with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s call to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
