
    
        
            THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOUNDATION</ENAMEX> OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEW TERRORISM</ENAMEX>
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">DECLARATION OF WAR</ENAMEX>
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1998</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> exile <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and a fugitive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayman al Zawahiri</ENAMEX>, arranged from their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> for an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>
                newspaper in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to publish what they termed a fatwa issued in the name of a
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Islamic Front</ENAMEX>." A fatwa is normally an interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> law by a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">respected Islamic</ENAMEX> authority, but neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zawahiri</ENAMEX>, nor the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> others
                who signed this statement were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> law. Claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> had
                declared war against God and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX>, they called for the murder of any
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, anywhere on earth, as the "individual duty for every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> who can do it
                in any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in which it is possible to do it."
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three months later</TIMEX>, when interviewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC-TV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> enlarged on
                these themes.
            
            He claimed it was more important for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> than to kill other
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infidels</ENAMEX>." It is far better for anyone to kill a single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> than to
                squander his efforts on other activities," he said. Asked whether he approved of
                terrorism and of attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, he replied:"We believe that the worst thieves
                in the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Nothing could stop
                you except perhaps retaliation in kind. We do not have to differentiate between
                military or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX>. As far as we are concerned, they are all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>." Note:
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> names often do not follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> practice of the consistent use of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surnames</ENAMEX>. Given the variety of names we mention, we chose to refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> by
                the last word in the names by which they are known: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX>, for
                instance, omitting the article "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al</ENAMEX>" that would be part of their name in their own
                societies. We generally make an exception for the more familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">English</ENAMEX> usage of
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin</ENAMEX>" as part of a last name, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. Further, there is no universally
                accepted way to transliterate <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> words and names into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. We have relied on
                a mix of common sense, the sound of the name in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, and common usage in source
                materials, the press, or government documents. When we quote from a source document,
                we use its transliteration, e.g.,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qida</ENAMEX>" instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>.
            Though novel for its open endorsement of indiscriminate killing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
                declaration was only the latest in the long series of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private calls
                since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> that singled out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for attack. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                had issued his own self-styled fatwa calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
                out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. The long, disjointed document condemned the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> monarchy for
                allowing the presence of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of infidels in a land with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> most sacred to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, and celebrated recent suicide bombings of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>. It praised the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> suicide bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">241</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX>,
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Aden</ENAMEX>, and especially the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> firefight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> after which
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> "left the area carrying disappointment, humiliation, defeat and
                your dead with you."
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> said in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> interview that he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> had been preparing in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> for another long struggle, like that against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, but
                "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> rushed out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> in shame and disgrace." Citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
                army's withdrawal from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> as proof that a ragged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>
                could overcome a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX>, he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>: "We are certain that we
                shall-with the grace of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Allah</ENAMEX>-prevail over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>." He went on to warn that
                "If the present injustice continues . . . , it will inevitably move the battle to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> soil."
            
            Plans to attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> were developed with unwavering singlemindedness
                throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> saw himself as called "to follow in the footsteps of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Messenger</ENAMEX> and to communicate his message to all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>," and to serve as the rallying point and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> of a new kind of war to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">destroy America</ENAMEX> and bring the world to Islam.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIN LADIN</ENAMEX>'S APPEAL IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">ISLAMIC WORLD</ENAMEX> 
            It is the story of eccentric and violent ideas sprouting in the fertile ground of
                political and social turmoil. It is the story of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> poised to seize its
                historical moment. How did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>-with his call for the indiscriminate killing of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>-win <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> and some degree of approval from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> more?
            The history, culture, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of beliefs from which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> has shaped and spread
                his message are largely unknown to many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Seizing on symbols of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>'s
                past greatness, he promises to restore pride to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who consider themselves the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of successive foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>. He uses cultural and religious allusions to
                the holy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qur'an</ENAMEX> and some of its interpreters. He appeals to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> disoriented by
                cyclonic change as they confront modernity and globalization. His rhetoric
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">selectively</ENAMEX> draws from multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, history, and the region's political
                and economic malaise. He also stresses grievances against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> widely
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world. He inveighed against the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>'s holiest sites. He spoke of the suffering of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as a result of sanctions imposed after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, and he protested
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> support of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam Islam</ENAMEX> (a word that literally means "surrender to the will of God") arose in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX> with what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> believe are a series of revelations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prophet Mohammed</ENAMEX>
                from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and only God, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God of Abraham and of Jesus</ENAMEX>. These revelations,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conveyed by the angel Gabriel</ENAMEX>, are recorded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qur'an</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> believe that
                these revelations, given to the greatest and last of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of prophets stretching
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, complete God's message to humanity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadith</ENAMEX>, which
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recount Mohammed</ENAMEX>'s sayings and deeds as recorded by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>, are another
                fundamental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> key element is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharia</ENAMEX>, the code of law derived from
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qur'an</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadith</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> is divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shia</ENAMEX>.
                Soon after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prophet</ENAMEX>'s death, the question of choosing a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, or caliph,
                for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ummah</ENAMEX>, arose. Initially, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> could be drawn
                from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prophet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>, but with time, this was no longer possible. Those
                who became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shia</ENAMEX> held that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ummah</ENAMEX> must be a direct descendant of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prophet</ENAMEX>; those who became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunni</ENAMEX> argued that lineal descent was not required
                if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> met other standards of faith and knowledge. After bloody struggles,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunni</ENAMEX> became (and remain) the majority sect. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shia</ENAMEX> are dominant in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>.)
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caliphate</ENAMEX>-the institutionalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ummah</ENAMEX>-thus was a Sunni
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> that continued until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>, first under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> and eventually under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> control. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> look back at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> after the revelations to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prophet Mohammed</ENAMEX> as a golden age. Its memory is strongest among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>. What
                happened then-the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islam</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arabian Peninsula</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Africa</ENAMEX>, and even into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within less than a century</TIMEX>- seemed, and
                seems, miraculous.
            
            Nostalgia for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>'s past glory remains a powerful force.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> is both a faith and a code of conduct for all aspects of life. For many
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would be one guided by the moral principles of their
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>. This does not necessarily translate into a desire for clerical rule and the
                abolition of a secular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. It does mean that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> tend to be
                uncomfortable with distinctions between religion and state, though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>
                throughout history have readily separated the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>, however, such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>, as well as the existence of parliaments and
                legislation, only prove these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> to be false <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> usurping God's authority
                over all aspects of life. Periodically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> world has seen surges of what,
                for want of a better term, is often labeled "fundamentalism."
            
            Denouncing waywardness among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX> have appealed for a return to
                observance of the literal teachings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qur'an</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadith</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> from the
                fourteenth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> from whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> selectively quotes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ibn Taimiyyah</ENAMEX>, condemned
                both corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX> who failed to criticize them. He urged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>
                to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qur'an</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadith</ENAMEX> for themselves, not to depend solely on learned
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interpreters</ENAMEX> like himself but to hold one another to account for the quality of
                their observance.
            
            The extreme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamist</ENAMEX> version of history blames the decline from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>'s golden age on
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who turned away from the true path of their religion, thereby
                leaving Islam vulnerable to encroaching foreign powers eager to steal their land,
                wealth, and even their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s Worldview Despite his claims to universal leadership, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> offers an
                extreme view of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> history designed to appeal mainly to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunnis</ENAMEX>. He
                draws on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> who blame the eventual destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caliphate</ENAMEX> on
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who abandoned the pure path of religious devotion.
            
            He repeatedly calls on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> to embrace martyrdom since "the walls of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oppression</ENAMEX> and humiliation cannot be demolished except in a rain of bullets." For those yearning for a lost sense of order in an older,
                more tranquil world, he offers his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Caliphate</ENAMEX>" as an imagined alternative to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
                uncertainty. For others, he offers simplistic conspiracies to explain their world.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> also relies heavily on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sayyid Qutb</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muslim Brotherhood</ENAMEX> executed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> on charges of
                attempting to overthrow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qutb</ENAMEX> mixed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> scholarship with a very
                superficial acquaintance with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> history and thought. Sent by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
                government to study in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1940s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qutb</ENAMEX> returned with an
                enormous loathing of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> society and history. He dismissed Western achievements
                as entirely material, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> society possesses "nothing that will
                satisfy its own conscience and justify its existence."
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> basic themes emerge from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qutb</ENAMEX>'s writings. First, he claimed that the world was
                beset with barbarism, licentiousness, and unbelief (a condition he called jahiliyya,
                the religious term for the period of ignorance prior to the revelations given to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prophet Mohammed</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qutb</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> can choose only between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jahiliyya</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, he warned that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, were attracted to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jahiliyya</ENAMEX> and its material comforts than to his view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>; jahiliyya could
                therefore triumph over Islam. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, no middle ground exists in what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qutb</ENAMEX> conceived
                as a struggle between God and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>-as he defined them-therefore must
                take up arms in this fight. Any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> who rejects his ideas is just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more
                nonbeliever worthy of destruction.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> shares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qutb</ENAMEX>'s stark view, permitting him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> to rationalize
                even unprovoked mass murder as righteous defense of an embattled faith. Many
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have wondered, "Why do 'they' hate us?" Some also ask, "What can we do to
                stop these attacks?"
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> have given answers to both these questions. To the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, they
                say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> had attacked Islam; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is responsible for all conflicts
                involving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are blamed when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> fight with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>,
                when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> fight with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> fight with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmiri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, and
                when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> fights ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> in its southern islands.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is also held responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, derided by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> as "your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> has stated flatly,"Our fight against these
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> is not separate from our fight against you."
                These charges found a ready <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> angry at
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> because of issues ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
                support for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' repressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s grievance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> may have started in reaction to specific
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policies but it quickly became far deeper. To the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question, what America
                could do, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s answer was that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should abandon the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, convert
                to Islam, and end the immorality and godlessness of its society and culture:"It is
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saddening</ENAMEX> to tell you that you are the worst civilization witnessed by the history
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>." If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> did not comply, it would be at war with the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> said "desires death more than you
                desire life."
            
            History and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Context</ENAMEX> Few fundamentalist movements in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> world
                gained lasting political power. In the nineteenth and twentieth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> helped articulate anticolonial grievances but played little role in
                the overwhelmingly secular struggles for independence after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX>-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> led most independence movements,
                and clerical influence and traditional culture were seen as obstacles to national
                progress. After gaining independence from Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> followed an arc from initial pride and optimism to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s mix of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indifference</ENAMEX>, cynicism, and despair. In several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, a dynastic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> already
                existed or was quickly established under a paramount tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monarchies</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> still survive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Those in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> were eventually overthrown by secular nationalist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>.
            The secular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regimes</ENAMEX> promised a glowing future, often tied to sweeping ideologies
                (such as those promoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gamal Abdel Nasser</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Socialism</ENAMEX> or
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ba'ath Party</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>) that called for a single, secular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
                However, what emerged were almost invariably autocratic regimes that were usually
                unwilling to tolerate any opposition-even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, that had a
                parliamentary tradition. Over time, their policies- repression, rewards, emigration,
                and the displacement of popular anger onto scapegoats (generally foreign)-were
                shaped by the desire to cling to power.
            The bankruptcy of secular, autocratic nationalism was evident across the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world
                by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>. At the same time, these regimes had closed off nearly all paths
                for peaceful opposition, forcing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> to choose silence, exile, or violent
                opposition. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> revolution swept a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theocracy</ENAMEX> into power. Its success
                encouraged Sunni <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> elsewhere. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, awash in sudden oil
                wealth, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> competed with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shia Iran</ENAMEX> to promote its Sunni fundamentalist
                interpretation <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">of Islam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wahhabism</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, always conscious of its
                duties as the custodian of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>'s holiest places, joined with wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> from
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> bordering the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> in donating money to build
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosques</ENAMEX> and religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that could preach and teach their interpretation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> doctrine. In this competition for legitimacy, secular regimes had no
                alternative to offer. Instead, in a number of cases their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> sought to buy off
                local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamist</ENAMEX> movements by ceding control of many social and educational issues.
                Emboldened rather than satisfied, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamists</ENAMEX> continued to push for power-a trend
                especially clear in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. Confronted with a violent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> that killed
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anwar Sadat</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> combined harsh repression of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> militants with harassment of moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, driving
                many into exile. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> sought to justify its seizure of
                power by a pious public stance and an embrace of unprecedented <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamist</ENAMEX> influence on
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and society.
            These experiments in political Islam faltered during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolution</ENAMEX> lost momentum, prestige, and public support, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> found
                that most of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> had little enthusiasm for fundamentalist Islam. Islamist
                revival movements gained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world, but failed to secure
                political <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX> except in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, where in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamists</ENAMEX> seemed
                almost certain to win power through the ballot box, the military preempted their
                victory, triggering a brutal civil war that continues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> have few, if any, ways to participate in the existing political system. They
                are thus a ready <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for calls to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> to purify their society, reject
                unwelcome modernization, and adhere strictly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social and Economic</ENAMEX>
                Malaise In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1980s</TIMEX>, an unprecedented flood of wealth led the then
                largely unmodernized oil <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to attempt to shortcut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of development. They
                funded huge infrastructure projects, vastly expanded education, and created
                subsidized social welfare programs. These programs established a widespread feeling
                of entitlement without a corresponding sense of social obligations. By the late
                1980s, diminishing oil revenues, the economic drain from many unprofitable
                development projects, and population growth made these entitlement programs
                unsustainable. The resulting cutbacks created enormous resentment among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>
                who had come to see government largesse as their right. This resentment was further
                stoked by public understanding of how much oil income had gone straight into the
                pockets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and their helpers.
            Unlike the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, where real economic development has barely
                begun), the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> once had seemed headed toward balanced
                modernization. The established commercial, financial, and industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> in
                these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, supported by an entrepreneurial spirit and widespread understanding of
                free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, augured well. But unprofitable heavy industry, state monopolies,
                and opaque <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX> slowly stifled growth. More importantly, these
                state-centered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">regimes</ENAMEX> placed their highest priority on preserving the elite's grip
                on national wealth. Unwilling to foster dynamic economies that could create jobs
                attractive to educated young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> became economically stagnant and
                reliant on the safety valve of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> emigration either to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> oil <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> or to
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, the repression and isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have not only seriously limited individual opportunity but also crippled
                overall economic productivity.
            
            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, high birthrates and declining rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> mortality had produced a
                common problem throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world: a large, steadily increasing population
                of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> without any reasonable expectation of suitable or steady employment-a
                sure prescription for social turbulence. Many of these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, such as the
                enormous number trained only in religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, lacked the skills needed by their
                societies. Far more acquired valuable skills but lived in stagnant economies that
                could not generate satisfying jobs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX>, pursuing secular as well as religious
                studies, were products of educational systems that generally devoted little if any
                attention to the rest of the world's thought, history, and culture. The secular
                education reflected a strong cultural preference for technical fields over the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humanities</ENAMEX> and social sciences. Many of these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, even if able to study
                abroad, lacked the perspective and skills needed to understand a different culture.
            Frustrated in their search for a decent living, unable to benefit from an education
                often obtained at the cost of great family sacrifice, and blocked from starting
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of their own, some of these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were easy targets for radicalization.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Opportunity</ENAMEX> Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> prefer a peaceful and inclusive
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> of their faith, not the violent sectarianism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> are commonly nicknamed takfiri, or "those who define other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>
                as unbelievers," because of their readiness to demonize and murder those with whom
                they disagree. Beyond the theology lies the simple human fact that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>,
                like most other human beings, are repelled by mass murder and barbarism whatever
                their justification.
            "All <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> must recognize that the face of terror is not the true face of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>,"
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> observed." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> is a faith that brings comfort to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a billion</NUMEX> people
                around the world. It's a faith that has made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> of every race.
                It's a faith based upon love, not hate." Yet as
                political, social, and economic problems created flammable societies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> used
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>'s most extreme, fundamentalist traditions as his match. All these
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>-including religion-combined in an explosive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>.
            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> had, and have, followings of their own. But in appealing to
                societies full of discontent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> remained credible as other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and
                symbols faded. He could stand as a symbol of resistance-above all, resistance to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. He could present himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> as victorious warriors
                in the one great successful experience for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">militancy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>: the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jihad</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> occupation.
            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> had a distinctive appeal, as he focused on attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. He
                argued that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>, who aimed at local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, did not go far
                enough. They had not taken on what he called "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the snake."
            
            Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> had another advantage: a substantial, worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. By
                the time he issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his February 1998</TIMEX> declaration of war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> had nurtured that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly ten years</TIMEX>. He could attract, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, and use <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> for
                ever more ambitious attacks, rallying new adherents with each demonstration that his
                was the movement of the future.
            THE <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RISE OF BIN</ENAMEX> LADIN AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AL QAEDA</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988-1992</TIMEX>)
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade</TIMEX> of conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979 to 1989</TIMEX>, gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> a
                rallying point and training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> gained
                power in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> but was unable to establish enduring control. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1979</TIMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> sent in military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> to ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would remain
                securely under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>'s influence. The response was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> national resistance
                movement that defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>.
            
            Young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> from around the world flocked to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> to join as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> in
                what was seen as a "holy war"-jihad-against an invader. The largest numbers came
                from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. Some were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saudis</ENAMEX>, and among them was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-three</NUMEX> when he arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was the seventeenth of
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> feet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and thin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                appeared to be ungainly but was in fact quite athletic, skilled as a horseman,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">runner</ENAMEX>, climber, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. He had attended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Aziz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>. By some accounts, he had been interested there in religious studies,
                inspired by tape recordings of fiery sermons by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Azzam</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> and a
                disciple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qutb</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was conspicuous among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> not because he
                showed evidence of religious learning but because he had access to some of his
                family's huge fortune. Though he took part in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> actual battle, he became
                known chiefly as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who generously helped fund the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jihad</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> understood better than most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> the extent to which the
                continuation and eventual success of the jihad in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> depended on an
                increasingly complex, almost worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> included a
                financial support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> that came to be known as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Golden Chain</ENAMEX>," put together
                mainly by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financiers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Donations flowed
                through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> or other nongovernmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> (NGOs). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and the
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan Arabs</ENAMEX>" drew largely on funds raised by this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> roamed
                world markets to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and supplies for the mujahideen, or "holy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX>."
            
            Mosques, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and boardinghouses served as recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in many parts of
                the world, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Some were set up by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> or
                their financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> had an important part in this activity. He and
                the cleric <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azzam</ENAMEX> had joined in creating a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Services</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mektab al Khidmat</ENAMEX>,
                or MAK), which channeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
            
            The international environment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s efforts was ideal. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> supplied <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> worth of secret assistance to rebel
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> fighting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> occupation. This assistance was funneled
                through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> military intelligence service (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inter- Services</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Directorate</ENAMEX>, or ISID), helped train the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> and distribute the arms.
                But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> had their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of support and training, and
                they received little or no assistance from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1988</TIMEX> brought victory for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jihad</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> declared it would pull its
                military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next nine months</TIMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> began
                their withdrawal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jihad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> debated what to do next. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and Azzam
                agreed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> successfully created for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> should not be
                allowed to dissolve. They established what they called a base or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaeda</ENAMEX>) as a potential general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> for future jihad.
            
            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azzam</ENAMEX> had been considered number one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAK</ENAMEX>, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was
                clearly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> (emir) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s structure included as its
                operating arms an intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component</ENAMEX>, a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, a financial
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, a political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> in charge of media affairs and
                propaganda. It also had an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisory Council</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shura</ENAMEX>) made up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s inner
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circle</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s assumption of the helm of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> was evidence of his growing
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-confidence</ENAMEX> and ambition. He soon made clear his desire for unchallenged control
                and for preparing the mujahideen to fight anywhere in the world. Azzam, by contrast,
                favored continuing to fight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> until it had a true <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
                And, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>, he saw <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> as the top priority for the next stage.
            
            Whether the dispute was about power, personal differences, or strategy, it ended on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 24, 1989</TIMEX>, when a remotely controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car bomb</ENAMEX> killed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Azzam</ENAMEX> and both of his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sons</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> were assumed to be rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX>. The outcome left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indisputably</ENAMEX> in charge of what remained of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>.
            
            Through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qutb</ENAMEX>, and the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> Islamist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> educational system, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamists</ENAMEX> already had a strong intellectual influence on
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> Islamist
                movement-badly battered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> crackdown following <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sadat</ENAMEX>'s
                assassination-was centered in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Group</ENAMEX> and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian Islamic Jihad</ENAMEX>. A spiritual guide for both, but especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>, was the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Sheikh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Abdel Rahman</ENAMEX>. His preaching had inspired
                the assassination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sadat</ENAMEX>. After being in and out of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> during the
                1980s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdel Rahman</ENAMEX> found refuge in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. From his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey City</ENAMEX>, he distributed messages calling for the murder of unbelievers.
            
            The most important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s circle was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayman al Zawahiri</ENAMEX>,
                who led a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Jihad</ENAMEX>. Many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> became
                important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, and his own close ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> led
                many to think of him as the deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. He would in fact become Bin
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s deputy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years later</TIMEX>, when they merged their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin Moves</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> had sufficient stature among
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan al Turabi</ENAMEX>, urged him to
                transplant his whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Turabi</ENAMEX> headed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Islamic Front</ENAMEX>
                in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> that had recently seized power in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khartoum</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> agreed to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turabi</ENAMEX> in an ongoing war against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African Christian</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and also to do some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road building</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turabi</ENAMEX> in return
                would let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> use <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> as a base for worldwide business operations and for
                preparations for jihad.
            
            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> began to buy property in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> himself moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. In
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, whose efforts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> had earned
                him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> and respect, proposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> monarchy that he summon mujahideen
                for a jihad to retake <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>. He was rebuffed, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudis</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-led
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coalition</ENAMEX>. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudis</ENAMEX> agreed to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> armed forces to be based in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX> began to publicly denounce the
                arrangement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> government exiled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX> and undertook to silence Bin
                Ladin by, among other things, taking away his passport. With help from a dissident
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, he managed to get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> under the pretext
                of attending an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> gathering in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1991.33</TIMEX> By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
                government would freeze his financial assets and revoke his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>.
            
            He no longer had a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> he could call his own.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> and set up a large and complex set of intertwined
                business and terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>. In time, the former would encompass numerous
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and a global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of bank accounts and nongovernmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>.
                Fulfilling his bargain with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turabi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> used his construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to build
                a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khartoum</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Sudan</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> coast. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> used their positions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s businesses
                to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>, and technical equipment for terrorist purposes. One
                founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hajer al Iraqi</ENAMEX>, used his position as head of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to carry out procurement trips from western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wadi al Hage</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mubarak Douri</ENAMEX>, who had become acquainted in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, went as far afield as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, and the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belarus</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s impressive array of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> covertly provided financial and other support
                for terrorist activities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> included a major business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX>; a "services" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zagreb</ENAMEX>; an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benevolence International</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarajevo</ENAMEX>, which supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> in their conflict with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Croatia</ENAMEX>; and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGO</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baku</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azerbaijan</ENAMEX>, that was employed as well by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian Islamic Jihad</ENAMEX> both as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> and conduit for finances and as a support
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. He also made use of the
                already-established Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relief Agency</ENAMEX> (TWRA) headquartered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>, whose
                branch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> locations included <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zagreb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Budapest</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> later set up an NGO
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> as a cover for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> there.)
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> now had a vision of himself as head of an international jihad
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confederation</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, he established an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Army Shura</ENAMEX>" that was to serve as
                the coordinating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> with which he was
                forging alliances. It was composed of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda Shura</ENAMEX> together with leaders
                or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that were still independent. In
                building this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, he enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tunisia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eritrea</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaeda</ENAMEX> also established cooperative but less formal relationships with other
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist groups</ENAMEX> from these same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>; from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chad, Mali</ENAMEX>,
                Niger, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>; and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> maintained <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian</ENAMEX> conflict as
                    well.
            
            The groundwork for a true global terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> was being laid.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> also provided equipment and training assistance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moro Islamic</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation Front</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> and also to a newly forming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> group
                that called itself the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Sayyaf Brigade</ENAMEX>, after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> jihadist
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jemaah Islamiya</ENAMEX> (JI), a nascent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
                Islamists with cells scattered across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>. It also aided a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> engaged in insurrectionist attacks in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1991</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> dispatched a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> to the northern
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> border to assist the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tajikistan Islamists</ENAMEX> in the ethnic conflicts that
                had been boiling there even before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
                became independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
            
            This pattern of expansion through building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliances</ENAMEX> extended to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. A
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Khifa</ENAMEX> had numerous branch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, the largest of
                which was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farouq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid- 1980s</TIMEX>, it had been set up as
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the first outposts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azzam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAK</ENAMEX>.
            
            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Khifa</ENAMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>,
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tucson</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Khifa</ENAMEX> recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Muslims</ENAMEX> to fight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>; some of them would
                participate in terrorist actions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> elsewhere, including the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BUILDING</ENAMEX> AN <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORGANIZATION</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">DECLARING WAR ON</ENAMEX> THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED STATES</ENAMEX>
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-1996</TIMEX>)
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> began delivering diatribes against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> before he left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>. He continued to do so after he arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1992</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al</ENAMEX> Qaeda
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> issued a fatwa calling for jihad against the Western "occupation" of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> lands. Specifically singling out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> for attack, the language
                resembled that which would appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s public fatwa in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1996</TIMEX>. In
                ensuing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> delivered an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">often-repeated</ENAMEX> lecture on the need to cut off
                "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the snake."
            
            By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was well-known and a senior figure among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>,
                especially those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arabian Peninsula</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
                border region. Still, he was just one among many diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist barons</ENAMEX>. Some of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> were more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX>. For example, Usama
                Asmurai, also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wali Khan</ENAMEX>, worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX> and
                helped him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tajikistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> spiritual guide based
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Sheikh</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> admired, was also in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>.
                Among sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> were a few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlords</ENAMEX> still fighting for
                power and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>, who helped operate a popular terrorist training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> near
                the border with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. There were also rootless but experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>, such
                as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid Sheikh Mohammed</ENAMEX>, who-though not necessarily formal
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of someone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>-were traveling around the world and joining
                in projects that were supported by or linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Ladin, the Blind Sheikh</ENAMEX>, or
                their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>.
            
            In now analyzing the terrorist programs carried out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, it
                would be misleading to apply the label "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>" too often in these
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>. Yet it would also be misleading to ignore the significance of these
                connections. And in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s agenda stood out. While his allied
                Islamist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were focused on local battles, such as those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> concentrated on attacking the "far enemy"-the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.
            Attacks <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Known and Suspected</ENAMEX>
            After <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> deployed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> formulated a
                fatwa demanding their eviction. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, bombs exploded at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Aden</ENAMEX>
                where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> routinely stopped en route to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, but no
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> are reported to have belonged to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> from southern
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yemen</ENAMEX> headed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yemeni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Army Shura</ENAMEX>; some in the group
                had trained at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> and used it to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainers</ENAMEX> to
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Somali</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlords</ENAMEX> battling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, an operation directly supervised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.
            
            Scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainers</ENAMEX> flowed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> over the ensuing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, including most of the
                senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> training <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. These
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainers</ENAMEX> were later heard boasting that their assistance led to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1993</TIMEX>
                shootdown of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Hawk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Somali</ENAMEX> militia group
                and to the subsequent withdrawal of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1994</TIMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1995</TIMEX>, a car bomb exploded outside a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riyadh</ENAMEX>
                for training the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi National Guard</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
                were killed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> government arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX>, who admitted being
                inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. They were promptly executed. Though nothing proves that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX> ordered this attack, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence subsequently learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> had decided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</TIMEX> to attack a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, and had
                shipped explosives to the peninsula for this purpose. Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s associates
                later took credit.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1996</TIMEX>, an enormous truck <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> detonated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Khobar Towers</ENAMEX> residential
                complex in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dhahran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, that housed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. Nineteen
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were killed, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">372</NUMEX> were wounded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> was carried out
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">principally</ENAMEX>, perhaps exclusively, by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi Hezbollah</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that had
                received support from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. While the evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
                involvement is strong, there are also signs that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> played some role, as yet
                    unknown.
            
            In this period, other prominent attacks in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s involvement is at best
                cloudy are the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>, a plot that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same year</TIMEX> to
                destroy landmarks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air plot to blow up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                airliners over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>. Details on these plots appear in chapter 3.
            Another scheme revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> sought the capability to kill on a mass scale.
                His business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> received word that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who had been a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the previous government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> was offering to sell weapons-grade
                <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX>. After a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> were made through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediaries</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
                set the price at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX>, which did not deter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> asked to inspect the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> and were shown a cylinder <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3</NUMEX> feet
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, and one thought he could pronounce it genuine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX> apparently purchased
                the cylinder, then discovered it to be bogus.
            
            But while the effort failed, it shows what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and his associates hoped to do.
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> explained his mission: "it's easy to kill more
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX>."
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> seemed willing to include in the confederation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> from almost every
                corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world. His vision mirrored that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
                Turabi, who convened a series of meetings under the label <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular Arab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
                Conference around the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s arrival in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Delegations</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">violent Islamist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> came from all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> represented in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Army Shura</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> also came from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> such as the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine Liberation Organization</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turabi</ENAMEX> sought to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunnis</ENAMEX> to put aside their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> and join
                against the common enemy. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991 or 1992</TIMEX>, discussions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaeda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> led to an informal agreement to cooperate in providing
                support-even if only training-for actions carried out primarily against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Not long afterward, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainers</ENAMEX>
                traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> to receive training in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1993</TIMEX>, another
                such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bekaa Valley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> for further training in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explosives</ENAMEX> as well as in intelligence and security. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> reportedly showed
                particular interest in learning how to use truck bombs such as the one that had
                killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">241</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>. The relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunni-Shia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> did not necessarily pose an
                insurmountable barrier to cooperation in terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. As will be described
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 7</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> contacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> continued in ensuing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was also willing to explore possibilities for cooperation with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, even
                though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, had never had an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamist</ENAMEX> agenda-save for
                his opportunistic pose as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX> against "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX>" during the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> had in fact been sponsoring anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi Kurdistan</ENAMEX>, and sought to attract them into his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>.
            
            To protect his own ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turabi</ENAMEX> reportedly brokered an agreement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX> would stop supporting activities against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> apparently honored
                this pledge, at least for a time, although he continued to aid a group of Islamist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> operating in part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurdistan</ENAMEX>) outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>'s control. In
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist groups</ENAMEX> suffered major defeats by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. In
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s help they re-formed into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ansar al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>. There are indications that by then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> tolerated and may even
                have helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ansar al Islam</ENAMEX> against the common <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>.
            
            With the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> acting as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> himself met with a senior
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khartoum</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1994</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> is said
                to have asked for space to establish training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, as well as assistance in
                procuring weapons, but there is no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> responded to this
                    request.
            
            As described below, the ensuing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> saw additional efforts to establish
                connections.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sudan Becomes a Doubtful Haven</ENAMEX>
            Not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> did <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> undertake a major terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> of its own, in
                large part because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> lost his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>. Ever since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamist</ENAMEX> regime
                came to power in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khartoum</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and other Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> had
                pressed it to stop providing a haven for terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
                in the region, such as those of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, which were
                targets of some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, added their own pressure. At the same time, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> began to change. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turabi</ENAMEX> had been its inspirational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar al Bashir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, had never been entirely under his
                thumb. Thus as outside pressures mounted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bashir</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> began to displace
                those of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turabi</ENAMEX>.
            The attempted assassination in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hosni Mubarak</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> appears to have been a tipping point. The would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>, who came from the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian Islamic Group</ENAMEX>, had been sheltered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and helped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>.
            
            When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> refused to hand over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> identified as involved in
                the assassination plot, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN Security Council</ENAMEX> passed a resolution criticizing
                their inaction and eventually sanctioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khartoum</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1996</TIMEX>.
            
            A clear signal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> were numbered came when the
                government advised him that it intended to yield to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>'s demands to stop giving
                sanctuary to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> had to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyans</ENAMEX> who had been part of his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> that he could no longer protect them and that they had to leave the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outraged</ENAMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda and the Islamic Army</ENAMEX> Shura
                renounced all connections with him.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> also began to have serious money problems. International pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>,
                together with strains in the world economy, hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>'s currency. Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> ran short of funds. As <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> became less obliging,
                normal costs of doing business increased. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> pressures on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> family
                also probably took some toll. In any case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> found it necessary both to cut
                back his spending and to control his outlays more closely. He appointed a new
                financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, whom his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> saw as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">miserly</NUMEX>.
            
            Money problems proved costly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> in other ways. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamal Ahmed al Fadl</ENAMEX>, a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>, had spent time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and had been recruited for
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> war through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farouq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>. He had joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> and
                taken the oath of fealty to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, serving as one of his business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Then
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> discovered that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX> had skimmed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $110,000</NUMEX>, and he asked for
                restitution. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fadl</ENAMEX> resented receiving a salary of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $500</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> while some of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> were given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,200</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>. He defected and became a star
                informant for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Also testifying about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> was
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, who told of breaking with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                professed inability to provide him with money when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> needed a caesarian
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>.
            
