
    
        
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunting Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS Frontline</ENAMEX> broadcast, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1998</TIMEX> (online at
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pbs</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/wgbh/pages/frontline/ shows/binladen/</ENAMEX>who/interview.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Against the Americans Occupying</ENAMEX> the Land of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Holy Places</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23, 1996</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trans.</ENAMEX>, online at
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">terrorismfiles</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/individuals/declaration_of_jihad1.html</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunting Bin</ENAMEX>
                Ladin," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS Frontline</ENAMEX> broadcast, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1998</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. For a classic passage conveying the nostalgic view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>'s spread, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri</ENAMEX>
                Pirenne, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A History</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, trans. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Miall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Books</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>), pp.
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25-26</NUMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Marty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Scott Appleby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eds.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fundamentalism Observed</ENAMEX>, vol. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Press</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmanuel Sivan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Radical Islam: MedievalTheology and Modern Politics</ENAMEX>, enlarged
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ed</ENAMEX>.(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Univ</ENAMEX>. Press, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. From the perspective of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>, history, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad Caliphate</ENAMEX>'s
                destruction by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mongols</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1292</TIMEX> marks the end not of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> greatness but of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> dominance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world. Moghul <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safavid Persia</ENAMEX>, and, above all,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman Empire</ENAMEX> were great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> powers that arose long after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>
                Caliphate fell.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of War</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23, 1996</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Brotherhood</ENAMEX>, which arose in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> as a Sunni
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">religious/</ENAMEX>nationalist opposition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> monarchy, spread
                throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-twentieth century</TIMEX>. In some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, its
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oppositional</ENAMEX> role is nonviolent; in others, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, it has alternated
                between violent and nonviolent struggle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sayyid Qutb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milestones</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmericanTrust Publications</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qutb</ENAMEX> found sin
                everywhere, even in rural midwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qutb</ENAMEX>'s views were best set out in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sayyid Qutb</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The America I Have Seen"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>), reprinted in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kamal Abdel-Malek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ed.,</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab Mirror</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Images of America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">ArabicTravel Literature</ENAMEX>: An
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palgrave</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. For a good introduction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qutb</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> broadcast, "Sayyid
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qutb</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6, 2003</TIMEX> (online at
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">npr</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/display_pages/features/feature</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1253796.html</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s 'Letter
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>,'" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer Worldview</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 24, 2002</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trans.</ENAMEX>, online at
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://observer.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guardian</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">co.uk/worldview/</ENAMEX>story<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">/0,11581,845725,00</NUMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al</ENAMEX> Qaeda
                letter was released in conjunction with the release of an audio message from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ladin</ENAMEX> himself.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab Human Development</ENAMEX> Report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>), a report prepared
                by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> that examines not only standard statistical data but also more sensitive
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> indicators recently identified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amartya</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">It</ENAMEX> says little, however, about the political dimensions of economic and social
                trends. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Le Vine</ENAMEX>, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN Arab Human Development</ENAMEX> Report: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Critique</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Report</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26, 2002</TIMEX> (online at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">merip</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org/mero/mer0072602.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, remarks at roundtable with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 10, 2002</TIMEX> (online at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whitehouse</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/news/</ENAMEX>releases<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/2002/09/20020910-7.html</ENAMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. See, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zubaydah</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 29, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analytic</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Ladin's Terrorist Operations: Meticulous and Adaptable</ENAMEX>," CTC
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">00-40017CSH, Nov. 2, 2000</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>." Open resistance flared so quickly that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> after the invasion . . . almost the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kabul</ENAMEX> climbed on
                their rooftops and chanted with one voice,'God is great.'This open defiance of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> who could physically destroy their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was matched throughout the
                countryside." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ret</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Yahya Nawwroz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester W. Grau</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Soviet</ENAMEX>
                War in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Afghanistan; History and Harbinger of Future War?</ENAMEX>" Military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leavenworth Foreign Military Studies Office</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept./Oct. 1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 2</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rohan Gunaratna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inside Al Qaeda</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Network</ENAMEX> ofTerror (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Univ</ENAMEX>. Press,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), pp<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>. Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UBL</ENAMEX>'s access to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s fortune, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Newcomb</ENAMEX>
                interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 4, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wechsler</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>. Government's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evidentiary Proffer Supporting the Admissibility of Co-Conspirator</ENAMEX>
                Statements, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enaam Arnaout</ENAMEX>, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-CR-892 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.D. Ill.</ENAMEX> filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Links</ENAMEX> to 'Abdallah
                Azzam, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 1997</TIMEX>. By most accounts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> initially viewed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azzam</ENAMEX> as a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mentor</ENAMEX>, and became in effect his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> by providing financial backing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAK</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>. In his memoir, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ayman al Zawahiri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contemptuously</ENAMEX> rejects the claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
                mujahideen were financed (even "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one penny</NUMEX>") or trained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. See
                Zawahiri,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knights Under the Prophet's Banner</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharq al Awsat</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.2,2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> involved in aiding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> regard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and his "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghans</ENAMEX>" as having been militarily insignificant in the war and recall having little
                to do with him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Schroen</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3, 2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Azzam</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Qaeda al Sulbah"</ENAMEX> (The solid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Jihad</ENAMEX>, Apr.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1988, p. 46</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>. A wealth of information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s evolution and history has been obtained
                from materials seized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, including files labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tareekh Usama</ENAMEX>"
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usama</ENAMEX>'s history) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tareekh al Musadat"</ENAMEX> (History of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Bureau</ENAMEX>). For
                descriptions of and substantial excerpts from these files, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evidentiary Proffer Supporting the Admissibility of Co-Conspirator Statements</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnaout</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6, 2003</TIMEX>. See also Intelligence report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism</ENAMEX>:
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Background of the Islamic Army</ENAMEX> and bin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s Move from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 26, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> document, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Qaeda</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AFGP-2002-000080</ENAMEX> (translated). For a
                particularly useful insight into the evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>-written by an early Bin
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX> associate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adel Batterjee</ENAMEX>, under a pseudonym- see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basil Muhammad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Ansar al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> fi <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> (The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benevolence International</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> (BIF) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Association of Muslim Youth</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>. Government's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evidentiary Proffer Supporting the Admissibility of Co-Conspirator</ENAMEX>
                Statements, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnaout</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamal al Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1996</TIMEX>;
                Gunaratna, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inside Al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 23</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Benjamin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Age of SacredTerror</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>),
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6-7</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57-63</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83-85</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">189 F.3d 88</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">104-105, 123-124</ENAMEX> (2d
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16, 1996</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>. Gunaratna, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inside Al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25-27</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> document, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Agreement</ENAMEX> between
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jama'at Qaedat Ansar Allah</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Base Group of Allah Supporters</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jama'at Al-</ENAMEX>Jihad
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jihad Group</ENAMEX>)," <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AFGP-2002-000081</ENAMEX>, undated; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred Terror</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 103</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. Trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamal al Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. S</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cr</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1023</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D. N.Y.</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">218-219, 233</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13, 2001</TIMEX>
                (transcript pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">514-516</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2001</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcript p. 890</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fadl</ENAMEX> says this
                invitation was delivered by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> that visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. See also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Qa</ENAMEX>'ida in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-1996</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
                School <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ties Lead Down Dangerous Paths</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003- 40028CHX</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Background of the Islamic Army</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s Move from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 26, 1996</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>. Trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">220-224</ENAMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s confrontation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, see, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter L. Bergen</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy War Inc.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inside the Secret World of Osama bin Ladin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Touchstone</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>), pp.
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80-82</NUMEX>. On aid provided by a dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Khallad, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 26, 2003</TIMEX>. See also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1996</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>. Gunaratna, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inside Al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 34</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s business activities in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1994</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Background of the Islamic Army</ENAMEX> and bin
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s Move from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 26, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old</ENAMEX>
                School <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ties</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>. Trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">301-302, 305-306, 315-317, 367-368</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism</ENAMEX>: Historical
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Background of the Islamic Army</ENAMEX> and bin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s Move from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old School Ties</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s business activities in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1994</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shipment of Arms and Boats</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> for Use by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Extremist</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Responsibilities</ENAMEX> and
                Background of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Army Shura Council</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old</ENAMEX>
                School <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ties</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation, interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1996</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 12, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Qa'ida</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Links</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002-40066CH</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 6, 2002</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian</ENAMEX> conflicts, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan F. Kohlmann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Qaida's</ENAMEX> Jihad
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian Network</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berg</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>. Trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7, 2001</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcript p.</ENAMEX>
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">354</NUMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation, interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1996</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>;"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">RP Cops Aware of Long-Term Rightwing Muslim Connection</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>, Apr.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>. Trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">354-355</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 4, 1998</TIMEX>. See also
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic of Singapore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of Home Affairs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, "The Jemaah
                <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Islamiyah Arrests and the Threat of Terrorism</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred Terror</ENAMEX>, pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100, 235</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arizona: Long-Term Nexus For Islamic Extremists</ENAMEX>," CTC
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002-30037H</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Emerson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Jihad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Press</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">129-137</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">468</NUMEX> NOTES <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TO CHAPTER 2</ENAMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatwa</ENAMEX> to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and movement
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8 1997</TIMEX>; trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265-266</ENAMEX>); trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>'Houssaine
                Kherchtou, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21, 2001</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcript p. 1163</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                reports of investigation, interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1996</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 12, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                report of investigation, interview of confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 1999</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wali Khan</ENAMEX>'s relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usama Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Historical Links to 'Abdallah Azzam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of
                investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Ansar al Arab</ENAMEX> fi
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Sheikh, Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> eventually spoke publicly of his
                admiration. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> interview, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Terror's Source</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28, 1998</TIMEX>. In late
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> confided to his diary that he was getting ready to go to one of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>:"Perhaps later I will tell you about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qa'ida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, translation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>'s diary, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid Sheikh Mohammed</ENAMEX> masterminded the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air plot,
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> helped fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> 's attempt to blow up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9,2004</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blind Sheikh</ENAMEX> was linked
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> attack, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wali Khan</ENAMEX> was convicted
                together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air conspiracy.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usama Bin Ladin Links</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Yemeni Group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old School Ties</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 2003</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 4</ENAMEX>. 45.U.<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.</ENAMEX> intelligence did not learn of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Activities</ENAMEX>
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> NIF Support, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1997</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Activities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eritrea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report
                of investigation, interview of confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of
                investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Essam Mohamed al Ridi</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7, 1999</TIMEX>; trial testimony of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Essam Mohamed al Ridi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">578-593</ENAMEX>); trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 2001</TIMEX>
                (transcript pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">279-285</ENAMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was indicted on charges arising
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>. For background about the attack on the training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, see, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred Terror</ENAMEX>, pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">132, 242</TIMEX>. On the proposed attack in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>,
                see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatwa</ENAMEX> to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and movement
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8, 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation,
                interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 12, 1996</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13, 1998</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> taking credit, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report made available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khobar Bombing</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi Shia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Usama Bin Ladin All</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Suspects</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96- 30015, July 5, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IntelligenceThreat Review</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96-007, July 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report made available to
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>. See also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred Terror</ENAMEX>, pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">224-225,</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">300-302</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Usama Bin Ladin's Attempts to Acquire Uranium, Mar. 18</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Usama Bin Ladin Trying to Develop WMD Capability?</ENAMEX>" CTC
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-30002</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6, 1997</TIMEX>; trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">357-366</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">528-529</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2001</TIMEX>
                (transcript pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">982-985</ENAMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>. Trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13, 2001</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcript p.</ENAMEX>
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">528</NUMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old School Ties</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Establishment of a Tripartite Agreement Among Usama Bin</ENAMEX>
                Ladin, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIF</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31, 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooperation</ENAMEX> Among
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIF</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of
                investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1996</TIMEX>; trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">290-293</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of
                investigation, interview of confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 1999</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ansar al-Islam</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Qa'ida</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ally</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northeastern Iraq</ENAMEX>," CTC
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003-40011CX, Feb. 1, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 1, 1997</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24, 2003</TIMEX>. At
                least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these reports dates the meeting to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, but other evidence indicates
                the meeting may have occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> memoranda of information from a foreign government report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s intelligence service and a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in bomb making met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khartoum</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 30, 1996</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                asked for and received assistance from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>, who remained there
                giving training until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1996</TIMEX>, which is when the information was passed to
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports made available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>. The
                information is puzzling, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1996</TIMEX>, and
                there is no evidence he ventured back there (or anywhere else) for a visit. In
                examining the source material, the reports note that the information was received
                "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">third</NUMEX> hand," passed from the foreign government service that "does not meet
                directly with the ultimate source of the information, but obtains the information
                from him through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediaries</ENAMEX>, one of whom merely delivers the
                information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>." The same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> had
                been seen in the area of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1995</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Possible Islamic Army Foreknowledge</ENAMEX> of an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
                Operation" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Logistical and Security Assistance Provided for the Attackers</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 4, 1997</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carney</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4, 2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX>. Trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1280-1282</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> economy, see, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred Terror</ENAMEX>, pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">114-115, 132-133</ENAMEX>. For details about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, see,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">e.g., Frank G.</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 2004</TIMEX>). Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                finances, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Qa'ida</ENAMEX>'s Financial
                Facilitators,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IA 2001-134-HXC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaykh Sa'id</ENAMEX>:
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Qa'ida</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Loyal Senior Accountant</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003-30072H</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                reports, interrogations of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17, 1998</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4, 1999</TIMEX>. On the financial
                crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> at this time, see trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1282-1284</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>. Trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">165-174, 190-205, 255-258</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">382-391</ENAMEX>); trial testimony
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1282-1284</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khartoum</ENAMEX> had been closed in response to terrorist
                threats, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> was working out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>. The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> notified him there by fax. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carney</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4, 2003</TIMEX>);
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Petterson</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 30, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> cable, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7020</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>:
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Developments re Terrorism and Peace</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 1996</TIMEX>. On the
                attempted assassination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 15, 2000</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of
                confidential source, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 1999</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23, 2003</TIMEX>.
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Univ</ENAMEX>. Press, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 133</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Coll</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ghost Wars: The Secret History of the</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, and bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soviet Invasion</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 10, 2001</TIMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penguin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 9</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>;
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27, 2003</TIMEX>. The
                current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> told us that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> landed in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX> for refueling. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Abdullah</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23, 2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">64</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88-90</NUMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Bennet Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eye</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Storm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Univ</ENAMEX>. Press, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>);
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raffat Pasha</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban; Waleed Ziad</ENAMEX>, "How the Holy
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warriors Learned to Hate</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18, 2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. A31.</ENAMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX>. See, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Weinbaum</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Milam</ENAMEX> interview
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 29, 2003</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milam</ENAMEX> described "strategic depth" as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s need for a
                friendly, pliable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> on the west due to its hostile relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> on
                the east.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s consent, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Rashid</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27, 2003</TIMEX>); see also
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 139</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Activities of Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14, 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> investigation, interview of
                former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>. On the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>-centered network of guesthouses and training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analytic</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sketch</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX>-Based <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Terrorist Training</ENAMEX> and Logistic
                Network,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DI TR</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95-12</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1995</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UBL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Qa</ENAMEX>'ida
                and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Community Response</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 2004</TIMEX> (draft), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 11</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s money problems, see trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21, 2003</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1282-1286</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank G.</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary S. briefing</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> cable, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> 11468, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major Usama Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin Asset Deregistered</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 6, 1996</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 30, 2003</TIMEX>. See also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Block</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In War on Terrorism, Sudan Struck a Blow by</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleecing Bin Laden</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. A1.</ENAMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">69</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 1999</TIMEX>;
                trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashif Juma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">626-627</ENAMEX>); trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1264-1267</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 28, 2000</TIMEX>. See also Intelligence report, interrogation of
                Khallad, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX>. See trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1282-1286</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunaratna</ENAMEX>, Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
                Qaeda, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19-21</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">133</NUMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> fatwa, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of War</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23, 1996</TIMEX>. On
                constraints from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 2004</TIMEX>. On warnings from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> monarchy, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timeline</ENAMEX> of
                events from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> (citing cables from Apr.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s promise to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, see government exhibit no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1559</NUMEX>-T,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> interview, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> broadcast,
                interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Arnett</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mar. 20, 1997</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 9, 1997</TIMEX> (available
                online at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://</ENAMEX>news.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">findlaw</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/cnn/docs/binladen/binladenintvw-cnn.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pdf</ENAMEX>).
                According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kandahar</ENAMEX> "by order of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emir Al-Mouminin</ENAMEX>," that
                is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mullah Omar</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>. On
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>'s invitation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UBL</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> briefing (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 12, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 129</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashid</ENAMEX> has also described the move as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s plan to solidify
                his relationship with, and eventually gain control over, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Rashid</ENAMEX>
                interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27, 2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">74</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, unsuccessful <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> probes for contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s efforts to repair relations with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> approach to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">76</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ansar al-Islam</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Qa'ida</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ally</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northeastern Iraq</ENAMEX>," CTC
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003-40011CX, Feb. 1, 2003</TIMEX>. See also DIA analytic report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Analysis</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inconclusive Ties to Al-Qaida</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old School</ENAMEX>
                Ties," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 2003</TIMEX>. We have seen other intelligence reports at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> about 1999
                contacts. They are consistent with the conclusions we provide in the text, and their
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reliability</ENAMEX> is uncertain. Although there have been suggestions of contacts between
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> regarding chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and explosives training, the most
                detailed information alleging such ties came from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> operative who recanted
                much of his original information. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">operative</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14,2004</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> have adamantly denied that
                any such ties existed between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zubaydah</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> (cited in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> letter, response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Douglas</ENAMEX>
                Feith memorandum,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Requested Modifications to 'Summary of Body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                Reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>-al <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qaida Contacts</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-2003</TIMEX>),'" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 10, 2003</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 5</ENAMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank G.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary S. briefing</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>-Based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Support for Terrorist</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizations</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002-40117CH, Nov. 14, 2002</TIMEX>. On the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2002</TIMEX>.
                On relations between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>, see ibid. On
                financial relations, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ariana Afghan Airlines</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assets</ENAMEX> and
                Activities,"OTI IR <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999-170CX</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29, 1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NID</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Near East: UAE: Imposition</ENAMEX>
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sanctions Could Disrupt Bin Ladin's Finances</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9, 1999</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Afghanistan: An Incubator</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Terrorism</ENAMEX>," CTC
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01-40004</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Qa</ENAMEX>'ida <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Still Well Positioned to</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recruit Terrorists</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 1</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">79</TIMEX>. The number of actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> seems to have been relatively small during
                the period before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, although estimates vary considerably, from the low <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
                to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 5,000</NUMEX>. For the low <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3, 2003</TIMEX>. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 26, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> added that because pledging bayat was secret, the number of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> can only be speculative. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s training and indoctrination,
                see <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1988</TIMEX> meeting leading to the official formation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                Qaeda, cited in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evidentiary Proffer Supporting the Admissibility of</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coconspirator Statements</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnaout</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6, 2003</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 36</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> apparently had established cooperative relationships with at
                least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sunni Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist groups</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Asia</ENAMEX>, as well as with elements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> opposition. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old School Ties</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 2003</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 3</ENAMEX>. On ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> JI, see, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> militant ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>,"Terrorism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extremists Planning Attacks Against US Interests</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>,"
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 29, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 1</ENAMEX> and appendix B; see also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunaratna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inside Al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">169-171</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred Terror</ENAMEX>, pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">286-287</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, see,
                e.g., trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript
                pp<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.301,315</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">316</NUMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7, 2001</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcript p. 368</ENAMEX>). On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, see, e.g.,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17, 1997</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>, see
                Government's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evidentiary Proffer Supporting the Admissibility of Co-Conspirator</ENAMEX>
                Statements, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnaout</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohlmann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Qaida's Jihad</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81</TIMEX>. See, e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tareekh Usama</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tareekh al Musadat"</ENAMEX> (described in note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>). See
                also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammad Rashed Daoud al 'Owhali</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 22-25, 1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nasser Ahmad Nasser al</ENAMEX>
                Bahri, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 3, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 8</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">82</TIMEX>. The merger was de facto complete by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1998</TIMEX>, although the formal "contract"
                would not be signed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incorporation</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zawahiri's Organization</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bin Ladin's Al-Qa'ida</ENAMEX>, and Recent [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Activities</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian Associates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Qa'ida</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22, 1998</TIMEX>; see also Intelligence report,
                interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">83</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 1999</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 28, 2000</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacred Terror</ENAMEX>, pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">123-124</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84</TIMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s surveillance and photography activities, see trial testimony of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1499-1500</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation, interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'Houssaine Kherchtou</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 2000</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18, 2000</TIMEX>; see also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of
                confidential source, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 1999</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s use of technical equipment to
                promote his intelligence/security capabilities, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism</ENAMEX>:
                <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Usama Bin Ladin's Intelligence Capabilities and Techniques</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5, 1996</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85</TIMEX>. On the surveillance reports and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX> training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of
                investigation, interview of confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 1999</TIMEX>; see also
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Qaeda Targeting Study of U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>, prepared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1993</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 5, 1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Establishment</ENAMEX> of a Tripartite
                Agreement Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIF</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31, 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooperation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Among Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIF</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> told
                his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> he wanted them to study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1983</ENAMEX> truck bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marines</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">241</NUMEX> and led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pullout from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>.
                See, e.g., statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Mohamed</ENAMEX> in support of change of plea, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Mohamed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. S</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cr</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1023</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D. N.Y.</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 20, 2000</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcript p. 30</ENAMEX>);
                trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">292-293</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fadl, Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report
                of investigation, interview of confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16, 1999</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">86</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Davies</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saudis Detain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anti-American Terror Group</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2, 1997</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">87</TIMEX>. For general information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hage</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oriana Gill</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hunting Bin Laden: A Portrait</ENAMEX>
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wadih El Hage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Accused Terrorist</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS Frontline</ENAMEX> broadcast, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2001</TIMEX>. On
                returning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hage</ENAMEX> was met at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interrogated</ENAMEX>, and called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> before the federal grand jury then
                investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. Because he lied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> about his association
                with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, he was arrested immediately after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>. Testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 21, 2003</TIMEX>, pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-4</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hage</ENAMEX>'s phone taps, see introduction of stipulation
                (government exhibit no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 27, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pp</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1575-1576</TIMEX>). For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harun</ENAMEX>'s fax, see government exhibit no. 300A-T, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">88</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Islamic Front</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statement Urging Jihad</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Quds al Arabi</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23, 1998</TIMEX>;
                closing statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asst</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Karas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5369, 5376-5377</TIMEX>). On related activities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed Sadeeq Odeh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-28, 1998</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">89</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed Sadeeq Odeh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 15-28, 1998</TIMEX>;
                closing statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asst</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Karas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5239, 5408, 5417</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX> fax, see government exhibit no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1636</NUMEX>-T, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>.
                For the fatwa, see government exhibit no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1602</NUMEX>-T, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. bin Laden
                (translation of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clergymen in Afghanistan Issue a Fatwa</ENAMEX> calling for the Removal of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Forces</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Quds al Arabi</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14, 1998</TIMEX>). For the interview,
                see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> interview,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Terror's Source</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28, 1998</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">91</TIMEX>. See closing statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asst</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Karas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. bin
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5426-5439</TIMEX>); see also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation,
                interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammad Rashed Daoud al 'Owhali</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 22-25, 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 9</ENAMEX>. Copies of
                the declarations issued by "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Army</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation</ENAMEX> of the Holy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Places</ENAMEX>"
                taking credit for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> were recovered from a raid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baku</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azerbaijan</ENAMEX>,
                after the bombings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1998</TIMEX>. See also government exhibit no. 1557C-T,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX> ("The formation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Army</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation of</ENAMEX>
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Holy Places"</ENAMEX>); government exhibit no. 1557D-T, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. bin Laden
                ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Aqsa Mosque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>"); government exhibit no. 1557E-T, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. bin
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> ("The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Ka</ENAMEX>'ba <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>").
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">92</TIMEX>. Closing statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asst</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Karas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>,
                May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 2001</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcript p. 5445</ENAMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">93</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> interview, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Terror Suspect: An Interview with Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> (conducted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahimullah Yousafsai</ENAMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Counterterrorism Evolves</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Brief of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Ahmed Yousef</ENAMEX>, Lead No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1041</NUMEX>
                (2d <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>. filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.25, 2000</TIMEX>), pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42-43</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Stone</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cell: Inside the 9/11 Plot</ENAMEX>, and Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> Failed to Stop It
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyperion</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95, 99</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tasking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 18</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). On the role of different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Coll</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ghost War</ENAMEX>:
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Secret History</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, and bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soviet Invasion</ENAMEX>
                to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 10, 2001</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penguin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 251</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Trial testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Parr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX>, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S12 93</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CR 180</ENAMEX> (KTD)
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D. N.Y.</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 22, 1997</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcript p. 4694</ENAMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. On the process of identification, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Malone</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salameh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">152 F.3d 88</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">107</NUMEX>-108 (2d <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>,
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell</ENAMEX>, pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">104-105, 107,</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">109</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abouhalima</ENAMEX> had fled to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> after the bombing, and was picked up by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1993</TIMEX>. Brief of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed A. Salameh</ENAMEX>, Lead No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1312</TIMEX> (2d <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>.
                filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17, 1997</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p. 64 and n. ***</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salameh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">152 F.3d</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">107-108, n. 2</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">327</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">F.3d 56</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78-79</NUMEX> (2d <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 119</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Benjamin</ENAMEX>
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Age of Sacred Terror</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 12</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rahman</ENAMEX>'s ties to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farouq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cell</ENAMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54-55</NUMEX>.
                On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rahman</ENAMEX>'s message, see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">189 F.3d 88</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX> (2d <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>);
                Brief for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siddig Ibrahim Siddig Ali</ENAMEX>, Lead No.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96-1044</TIMEX> (2d <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>. filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3, 1997</TIMEX>), pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 15</TIMEX>. See also DOS <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review of the Visa-Issuance Process Phase I: Circumstances Surrounding the</ENAMEX>
                Issuance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sheikh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Ali Ahmed Abdel Rahman</ENAMEX>,"Mar.<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, pp<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6,8</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>. On
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">informant</ENAMEX>'s reports, see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahman,189 F.3d</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">106-107</ENAMEX>. On the
                landmarks plot, see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">189 F.3d</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">108-111, 123-127</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 116</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. These prosecutions also had the unintended consequence of alerting some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s interest in them. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1995</TIMEX>, the government
                filed a confidential court document listing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and scores of other
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as possible co-conspirators in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> landmarks plot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Mohamed</ENAMEX>,
                who was on the list, obtained a copy and faxed it to a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> for
                distribution. Statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Mohamed</ENAMEX> in support of change of plea, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. Ali Mohamed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. S</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cr</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1023</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D. N.Y.</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 20, 2000</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcript p. 29</ENAMEX>);
                Statements of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. S</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cr</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1023</TIMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D. N.Y.</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 2001</TIMEX> (transcript pp. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3338-3339</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> interview
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajaj</ENAMEX>'s travels to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khaldan</ENAMEX> and interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v.
                Salameh, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">152 F.3d</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">107-108</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajaj</ENAMEX> had entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX> tourist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visa</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 9, 1991</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> alien file, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A72215823</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 9</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> 's capture and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air plot, see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">327</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">F.3d</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79-82</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Inquiry</ENAMEX> report (classified version), pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">324-328</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytical report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WTC 1993: The Solid Case</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Qa'ida Involvement</ENAMEX>," CTC
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002-40084H</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 27, 2003</TIMEX>;
