
    
        
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">THE SYSTEM WAS BLINKING RED</ENAMEX>"
            THE <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">SUMMER OF</ENAMEX> THREAT
            As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> began, counterterrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were receiving frequent but fragmentary
                reports about threats. Indeed, there appeared to be possible threats almost
                everywhere the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had interests-including at home.
            To understand how the escalation in threat reporting was handled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> of
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, it is useful to understand how threat information in general is collected and
                conveyed. Information is collected through several methods, including signals
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> and interviews of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, and gathered into intelligence
                reports. Depending on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> and nature of the reporting, these reports may be
                highly classified-and therefore tightly held-or less sensitive and widely
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disseminated</ENAMEX>, either through individual reports or through threat advisories. Such
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">advisories</ENAMEX>, intended to alert their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, may address a specific threat or be
                a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> warning.
            Because the amount of reporting is so voluminous, only a select fraction can be
                chosen for briefing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence GeorgeTenet</ENAMEX> was briefed regularly regarding threats and other
                operational information relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>.
            
            He in turn met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, who was briefed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> through what is
                known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Daily Brief</ENAMEX> (PDB). Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDB</ENAMEX> consists of a series of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> relatively short articles or briefs covering a broad array of topics; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
                staff decides which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> are the most important on any given day. There were
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 40</NUMEX> intelligence articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDBs</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 20 to September 10</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, that related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDB</ENAMEX> is considered highly sensitive and is
                distributed to only a handful of high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Intelligence Brief</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEIB</ENAMEX>), distributed to a broader <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, has a similar format and generally covers the same subjects as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDB</ENAMEX>.
                It usually contains less information so as to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and methods. Like
                their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Council</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>) counterterrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>, all received the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SEIB</ENAMEX>,
                not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDB</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> had extensive access to terrorism reporting, but they did not
                have access to internal, nondisseminated information at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drumbeat Begins</ENAMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 2001</TIMEX>, the level of
                reporting on terrorist threats and planned attacks increased dramatically to its
                highest level since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> alert. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of March</TIMEX>, the intelligence
                community disseminated a terrorist threat advisory, indicating a heightened threat
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist terrorist</ENAMEX> attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and other
                    interests.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>, in connection with discussions about possibly reopening <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenue</ENAMEX> in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Advisor</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Condoleezza Rice</ENAMEX> that domestic or foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> might use a truck <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-their
                "weapon of choice"-on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pennsylvania Avenue</ENAMEX>. That would result, he said, in the
                destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Wing</ENAMEX> and parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> He also told her that he
                thought there were terrorist cells within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>.
            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> was briefed on the activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> and on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> efforts
                to locate him. As pointed out in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> had been a major figure in
                the millennium plots. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> repeatedly issued
                warnings-including calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI Tenet</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>-that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> was planning an
                operation in the near future. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> report cited a source indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>
                was planning an attack in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> thought might be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, or
                perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> relayed these reports to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX>.
            
            In response to these threats, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> sent a message to all its field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX>, summarizing reporting to date. It asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> to task all resources,
                including human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and electronic databases, for any information pertaining to
                "current operational activities relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunni</ENAMEX> extremism." It did not suggest
                that there was a domestic threat.
            
            The interagency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Security Group</ENAMEX> (CSG) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> chaired discussed
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> reports on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, a briefing to top officials
                reported "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> planning multiple operations." When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> discussed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaeda</ENAMEX> policy on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30</TIMEX>, they began with a briefing on the threat.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>, the drumbeat of reporting grew louder with reports to top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> public profile may presage attack" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s plans
                advancing." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early May</TIMEX>, a walk-in to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> claimed there was a plan to launch
                attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashcroft</ENAMEX> was briefed
                by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX> regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> generally and the current threat reporting
                specifically. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> brought a report that a phone call to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> had
                warned that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> were planning an attack in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> using
                "high explosives." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>, based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous day</TIMEX>'s report, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> item on
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX>'s agenda was "UBL: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Planned</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>" The
                anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>'s tip could not be corroborated.
            Late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> brought reports of a possible hostage plot against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> abroad to force
                the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sheikh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Abdel Rahman</ENAMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Sheikh</ENAMEX>,"
                who was serving a life sentence for his role in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> plot to blow up sites in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. The reporting noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> might opt to hijack an aircraft
                or storm a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>. This report led to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>)
                information circular to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> noting the potential for "an airline hijacking to
                free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> incarcerated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." Other reporting mentioned that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> was planning an attack, possibly against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and expected to carry
                out several more if things went well. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24</TIMEX> alone, counterterrorism officials
                grappled with reports alleging plots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, as well as a report about a
                cell in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> that an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> had claimed might be planning an attack
                against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            
            Reports similar to many of these were made available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> briefings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI Tenet</ENAMEX>, usually attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Advisor Rice</ENAMEX>. While these briefings discussed general
                threats to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interests, the specific threats mentioned in
                these briefings were all overseas.
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> Tenet what more the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> could
                do to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> from launching"a series of major terrorist attacks,"
                probably on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, but possibly on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX>
                and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hadley</ENAMEX>, "When these attacks occur, as they likely will, we
                will wonder what more we could have done to stop them." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> Counterterrorist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> (CTC) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cofer Black</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> that the current threat level was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> on a
                scale of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 to 10</TIMEX>, as compared to an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>.
            
            High <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Probability of Near-Term "Spectacular" Attacks</ENAMEX>
            Threat reports surged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June and July</TIMEX>, reaching an even higher peak of urgency. The
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> threats seemed to be focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahrain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>,
                and possibly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, but the danger could be anywhere- including a possible attack on
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genoa</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> report passing along biographical background
                information on several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> mentioned, in commenting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid Sheikh</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX>, that he was recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to travel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to meet with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> already there so that they might conduct terrorist attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                behalf. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> notified all its station <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> about intelligence
                suggesting a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> suicide attack on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> over the next few
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCITenet</ENAMEX> asked that all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX> be briefed.
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That same day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> notified all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> of the terrorist threat
                and updated its worldwide public warning. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> initiated
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa Express</ENAMEX> program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> as a security measure, in order to keep
                long lines of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> away from vulnerable embassy spaces. The program permitted
                visa applications to be made through travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, instead of directly at the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX> or consulate.
            
            A terrorist threat advisory distributed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late June</TIMEX> indicated a high probability of
                near-term "spectacular" terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attacks</ENAMEX> resulting in numerous casualties. Other
                reports' titles warned,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin Attacks May be Imminent</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Making Near-Term Threats</ENAMEX>." The latter reported <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple attacks</ENAMEX> planned
                over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming days</TIMEX>, including a "severe blow" against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> "interests"
                during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two weeks</TIMEX>.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>, near the height of the threat reporting, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Command</ENAMEX> raised the
                force protection condition level for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to the highest
                possible level, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Fifth Fleet</ENAMEX> moved out of its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahrain</ENAMEX>, and a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> exercise in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> was halted.<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>
                conducted an emergency security review, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> was closed. The CSG
                had foreign emergency response <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FESTs</ENAMEX>, ready to move on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX>'
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> and kept up the terrorism alert posture on a "rolling <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hour</TIMEX> basis."
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadley</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> separate intelligence reports
                showed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> warning of a pending attack. An <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> television station
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reported Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s pleasure with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who were saying that the next
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> "will witness important surprises" and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> will be
                targeted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX> also released a new recruitment and fund-raising tape. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Clarke</ENAMEX>
                wrote that this was all too sophisticated to be merely a psychological operation to
                keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on edge, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> agreed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">intelligence</ENAMEX> reporting
                consistently described the upcoming attacks as occurring on a calamitous level,
                indicating that they would cause the world to be in turmoil and that they would
                consist of possible multiple-but not necessarily simultaneous-attacks.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> that the pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> activity indicating attack
                planning over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six weeks</TIMEX> "had reached a crescendo.""A series of new reports
                continue to convince me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIA</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>], and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> that a major terrorist attack or series of attacks is likely in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>," he noted. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> intelligence report warned that something "very, very,
                very, very" big was about to happen, and most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> was reportedly
                anticipating the attack. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> ordered all its station <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> to
                share information on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> with their host <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and to push for immediate
                disruptions of cells.
            
            The headline of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX> briefing to top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> was stark:"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin Planning</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">High-Profile Attacks</ENAMEX>." The report stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> expected
                near-term attacks to have dramatic consequences of catastrophic proportions. That
                same day, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> declared its highest level of terror alert. Despite evidence
                of delays possibly caused by heightened <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> security, the planning for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attacks</ENAMEX> was
                    continuing.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI Counterterrorism Division</ENAMEX> sent a message to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and
                state and local law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> summarizing information regarding threats
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. It warned that there was an increased volume of threat reporting,
                indicating a potential for attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> abroad from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> "aligned
                with or sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>." Despite the general warnings, the message
                further stated, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has no information indicating a credible threat of
                terrorist attack in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." However, it went on to emphasize that the
                possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attack</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> could not be discounted. It also noted
                that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4 holiday</TIMEX> might heighten the threats. The report asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>
                to"exercise extreme vigilance" and "report suspicious activities" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. It did
                not suggest specific actions that they should take to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attacks</ENAMEX>.
            
            Disruption <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>-affiliated cells were launched involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist operatives</ENAMEX> were detained by foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>,
                possibly disrupting operations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and perhaps averting attacks
                against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> and others told us of a particular
                concern about possible attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. After it passed uneventfully,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> decided to maintain the alert.
            
            To enlist more international help, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi Crown Prince</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadley</ENAMEX> apparently called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>
                worked with senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, because of threats, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
                closed the airspace over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genoa</ENAMEX> and mounted antiaircraft batteries at the Genoa
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> summit, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> attended.
            
            At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> arranged for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to brief intelligence and security officials
                from several domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX>,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> to discuss the current threat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attendees</ENAMEX> report
                that they were told not to disseminate the threat information they received at the
                meeting. They interpreted this direction to mean that although they could brief
                their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>, they could not send out advisories to the field. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> official
                recalls a somewhat different emphasis, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> were asked to take the
                information back to their home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and "do what you can" with it, subject to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classification</ENAMEX> and distribution restrictions. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> asked
                for a summary of the information that she could share with field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. She never
                received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That same day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> briefed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> threat,
                warning that a significant terrorist attack was imminent. Ashcroft was told that
                preparations for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple attacks</ENAMEX> were in late stages or already complete and that
                little additional warning could be expected. The briefing addressed only threats
                outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> believed the
                upcoming attack would be "spectacular," qualitatively different from anything they
                had done to date.
            
            Apparently as a result of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX> meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>, the interagency committee
                on federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> security was tasked to examine security measures. This committee
                met on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> were briefed on
                the "current threat level" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. They were told that not only the
                threat reports from abroad but also the recent convictions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Africa</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombings</ENAMEX> trial, the conviction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Ressam</ENAMEX>, and the just-returned KhobarTowers
                indictments reinforced the need to "exercise extreme vigilance." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attendees</ENAMEX> were
                expected to determine whether their respective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> needed enhanced security
                    measures.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 18, 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> provided a warning to the public regarding
                possible terrorist attacks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arabian Peninsula</ENAMEX>.
            
            Acting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pickard</ENAMEX> told us he had one of his periodic conference
                calls with all special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in charge on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX>. He said one of the items he
                mentioned was the need, in light of increased threat reporting, to have evidence
                response <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> ready to move at a moment's notice, in case of an attack.
            
            He did not task field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> to try to determine whether any plots were being
                considered within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or to take any action to disrupt any such plots.
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-July</TIMEX>, reporting started to indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s plans had been delayed,
                maybe for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long as two months</TIMEX>, but not abandoned. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23</TIMEX>, the lead item for
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> discussion was still the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> threat, and it included mention of suspected
                terrorist travel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> circular appeared alerting the aviation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to "reports of
                possible near-term terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> . . . particularly on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arabian Peninsula</ENAMEX>
                and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>." It stated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> had no credible evidence of specific plans to
                attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> civil aviation, though it noted that some of the "currently active"
                terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were known to "plan and train for hijackings"and were able to build
                and conceal sophisticated explosive devices in luggage and consumer products.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenet</ENAMEX> told us that in his world "the system was blinking red." By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late July</TIMEX>, Tenet
                said, it could not "get any worse." Not everyone was
                convinced. Some asked whether all these threats might just be deception. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEIB</ENAMEX> contained an article titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Bin Ladin Threats Are Real</ENAMEX>." Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadley</ENAMEX> told
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenet</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Paul Wolfowitz</ENAMEX> questioned the
                reporting. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was trying to study <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> reactions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenet</ENAMEX> replied that
                he had already addressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>'s questions on this point; the
                reporting was convincing. To give a sense of his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX> at the time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> senior
                official in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> told us that he and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> were
                considering resigning in order to go public with their concerns.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Calm Before the Storm</ENAMEX>
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadley</ENAMEX> that the spike in intelligence about a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">near-term al Qaeda</ENAMEX> attack had stopped. He urged keeping readiness high during the
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August vacation</TIMEX> period, warning that another report suggested an attack had just
                been postponed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> "but will still happen."
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> issued an advisory that in light of the increased volume of
                threat reporting and the upcoming anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Africa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings,
                increased attention should be paid to security planning. It noted that although most
                of the reporting indicated a potential for attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests abroad, the
                possibility of an attack in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> could not be discounted.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 3</TIMEX>, the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> issued an advisory concluding that the threat
                of impending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> attacks would likely continue indefinitely. Citing threats in
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arabian Peninsula</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the advisory suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                Qaeda was lying in wait and searching for gaps in security before moving forward
                with the planned attacks.
            
            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had on several occasions asked
                his briefers whether any of the threats pointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Reflecting on
                these questions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> decided to write a briefing article summarizing its
                understanding of this danger. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> involved in preparing this briefing
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> believed it represented an opportunity to communicate their view that the
                threat of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> attack in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> remained both current and
                    serious.
            
            The result was an article in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Daily</ENAMEX> Brief titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Bin</ENAMEX> Ladin
                Determined to Strike in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>." It was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">36th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDB</ENAMEX> item briefed so far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> that
                related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> devoted to the possibility of an
                attack in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> told us the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6</TIMEX> report was
                historical in nature. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said the article told him that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> was
                dangerous, which he said he had known since he had become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
                said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> had long been talking about his desire to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. He recalled
                some operational data on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, and remembered thinking it was heartening that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
                investigations were under way. As best he could recollect, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> had mentioned that
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yemenis</ENAMEX>' surveillance of a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> had been looked into in
                May and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, but there was no actionable intelligence. He did not recall discussing
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6</TIMEX> report with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> or whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> had done so. He said
                that if his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> had told him there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, they would
                have moved to take care of it. That never happened.
            
            Although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following day</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SEIB</ENAMEX> repeated the title of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDB</ENAMEX>, it did not contain
                the reference to hijackings, the alert in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the alleged casing of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the threat phoned in to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>, or the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had
                <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX> ongoing bin Ladin-related investigations.
            
            The following is the text of an item from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Daily Brief</ENAMEX> received by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2001.37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Redacted</ENAMEX> material is indicated by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brackets</ENAMEX>.
            
                <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Ladin Determined To Strike in US Clandestine</ENAMEX>, foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and media
                    reports indicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> has wanted to conduct terrorist attacks in
                    the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> implied in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> television interviews in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 and 1998</TIMEX> that his
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> would follow the example of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bomber Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> and
                    "bring the fighting to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> missile strikes on his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> in
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> he wanted to retaliate in
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, according to a [-] service.
                An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Jihad</ENAMEX> (EIJ) operative told an [-] service at the same time
                    that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was planning to exploit the operative's access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> to mount
                    a terrorist strike.
                The millennium plotting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> may have been part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s first
                    serious attempt to implement a terrorist strike in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. Convicted plotter
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Ressam</ENAMEX> has told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> that he conceived the idea to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Airport</ENAMEX> himself, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> lieutenant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>
                    encouraged him and helped facilitate the operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> also said that in
                    <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> was planning his own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> attack.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was aware of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>.
                Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> has not succeeded, his attacks against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Embassies</ENAMEX> in
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> demonstrate that he prepares operations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in
                    advance and is not deterred by setbacks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> surveilled our
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dar es Salaam</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 1993</TIMEX>, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
                    Nairobi cell planning the bombings were arrested and deported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Qa'ida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>-including some who are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>-have resided in or traveled
                    to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> apparently maintains a support structure that
                    could aid attacks. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Qua</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> found guilty in the conspiracy to bomb
                    our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Africa</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, and a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> lived in
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX>. A clandestine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                    cell in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> was recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> youth for attacks.
                We have not been able to corroborate some of the more sensational threat
                    reporting, such as that from a [-] service in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> wanted
                    to hijack a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to gain the release of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Shaykh</ENAMEX>" 'Umar 'Abd
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Rahman</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>-held <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>.
                Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> information since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX> indicates patterns of suspicious
                    activity in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> consistent with preparations for hijackings or other
                    types of attacks, including recent surveillance of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> is conducting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 70</NUMEX> full field investigations throughout the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> that it considers <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>-related. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> are investigating a call
                    to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> saying that a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> was
                    in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> planning attacks with explosives.
            
            No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CSG</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> meeting was held to discuss the possible threat of a strike in
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as a result of this report.
            Late in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX>, a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> was considering
                mounting terrorist attacks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, after postponing possible
                operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, timing, or method of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attack</ENAMEX> were provided.
            
            We have found no indication of any further discussion before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX> among the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and his top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> of the possibility of a threat of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> attack
                in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI Tenet</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crawford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> and participated in PDB briefings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between August 31</TIMEX> (after the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> had returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 10</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenet</ENAMEX> does not recall
                any discussions with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the domestic threat during this period.
            
            Most of the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> recognized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 2001</TIMEX> that the number
                and severity of threat reports were unprecedented. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> told us that they
                knew something terrible was planned, and they were desperate to stop it. Despite
                their large number, the threats received contained few specifics regarding time,
                place, method, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>. Most suggested that attacks were planned against targets
                overseas; others indicated threats against unspecified "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests." We cannot
                say for certain whether these reports, as dramatic as they were, related to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>
                attacks.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Response</ENAMEX> to the Threats
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Advisor Rice</ENAMEX> told us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> was the "nerve center" for
                running the crisis, although other senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were involved over the course of
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. In addition to his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, and weekly
                meetings to go over other issues with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenet</ENAMEX> was speaking regularly with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Rumsfeld</ENAMEX>. The
                foreign policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> routinely talked on the telephone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> on a variety
                of topics.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hadley</ENAMEX> told us that before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> did not feel they had the job of
                coordinating domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. They felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> (part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>)
                were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>'s bridge between foreign and domestic threats.
            
            There was a clear disparity in the levels of response to foreign versus domestic
                threats. Numerous actions were taken overseas to disrupt possible attacks- enlisting
                foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> to upset terrorist plans, closing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>, moving military assets
                out of the way of possible harm. Far less was done domestically- in part, surely,
                because to the extent that specifics did exist, they pertained to threats overseas.
                As noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, a threat against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> quickly resulted in its
                closing. Possible domestic threats were more vague. When reports did not specify
                where the attacks were to take place, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> presumed that they would again be
                overseas, though they did not rule out a target in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Each of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> threat advisories made this point.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> mentioned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Advisor Rice</ENAMEX> at least twice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                sleeper cells were likely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> forwarded a
                strategy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> warning that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> had a presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. He
                noted that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> involved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>
                plot were naturalized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and that one jihadist suspected in the East
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa</ENAMEX> bombings had "informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> that an extensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qida</ENAMEX> 'sleeper
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' currently exists in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>." He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s abortive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>
                attack revealed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            
            His analysis, however, was based not on new threat reporting but on past experience.
            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX> attacks fell into the void between the foreign and domestic threats.
                The foreign intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were watching overseas, alert to foreign threats
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests there. The domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were waiting for evidence of a
                domestic threat from sleeper cells within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. No one was looking for
                a foreign threat to domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. The threat that was coming was not from
                sleeper cells. It was foreign-but from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> who had infiltrated into the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
            A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> cause of this disparity in response is that domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> did not know
                what to do, and no one gave them direction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cressey</ENAMEX> told us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> did not
                tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> how to respond to the threats. He noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that
                were operating overseas did not need direction on how to respond; they had
                experience with such threats and had a "playbook." In contrast, the domestic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> did not have a game plan. Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX>) nor anyone
                else instructed them to create one.
            
            This lack of direction was evident in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX> meeting with representatives from
                the domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The briefing focused on overseas threats. The domestic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were not questioned about how they planned to address the threat and were
                not told what was expected of them. Indeed, as noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, they were specifically
                told they could not issue advisories based on the briefing. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> The domestic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' limited response indicates that they did not perceive a call to action.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> reflected a different perspective in an email to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 15, 2001</TIMEX>.
                He summarized the steps taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> to alert domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to the
                possibility of an attack in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> concluded that domestic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>, knew that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> believed a major <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> attack was
                coming and could be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> had authority to issue security directives mandating new security
                procedures, none of the few that were released during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 2001</TIMEX> increased
                security at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoints</ENAMEX> or on board <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. The information circulars mostly urged
                air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to "exercise prudence" and be alert. Prior to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> did present
                a CD-ROM to air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> and airport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> describing the increased threat to
                civil aviation. The presentation mentioned the possibility of suicide hijackings but
                said that "fortunately, we have no indication that any group is currently thinking
                in that direction." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> conducted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27</TIMEX> special security
                briefings for specific air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1, 2001</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>. Two
                of these briefings discussed the hijacking threat overseas. None discussed the
                possibility of suicide hijackings or the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. No new security
                measures were instituted.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> told us she understood that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had tasked its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> to
                increase surveillance of suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and to reach out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">informants</ENAMEX> who
                might have information about terrorist plots. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> document at the time
                describes such a tasking as having occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late June</TIMEX> but does not indicate
                whether it was generated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. Other than the previously described
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX> communication sent to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> could not
                find any record of having received such a directive. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX> document asking
                field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> to gather information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremism</ENAMEX> did not mention any possible
                threat within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and did not order surveillance of suspected
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> did not specify what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s directives should contain and did
                not review what had been issued earlier.
            
            Acting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pickard</ENAMEX> told us that in addition to his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX> conference call,
                he mentioned the heightened terrorist threat in individual calls with the special
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in charge of field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> during their annual performance review
                discussions. In speaking with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, we found little evidence
                that any such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> had reached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Field</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of counterterrorism at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Watson</ENAMEX>, said he had many discussions
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> possible attacks with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cofer Black</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. They had expected an attack on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX> said he felt deeply that something was going to happen. But he told
                us the threat information was "nebulous." He wished he had known more. He wished he
                had had "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> threat information instead of
                    <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>."
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> was briefed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pickard</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early July</TIMEX>
                about the danger. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pickard</ENAMEX> said he met with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> once a week in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late June</TIMEX>,
                through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, and twice in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. There is a dispute regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX>'s interest
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pickard</ENAMEX>'s briefings about the terrorist threat situation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pickard</ENAMEX> told us that
                after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> such briefings <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> told him that he did not want to hear about the
                threats anymore. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> denies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pickard</ENAMEX>'s charge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pickard</ENAMEX> says he continued to
                present terrorism information during further briefings that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, but nothing
                further on the "chatter" the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was receiving.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> told us he asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pickard</ENAMEX> whether there was intelligence about
                attacks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pickard</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">no. Pickard</ENAMEX> said he replied that
                he could not assure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> that there would be no attacks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
                although the reports of threats were related to overseas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> said he
                therefore assumed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> was doing what it needed to do. He acknowledged that in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retrospect</ENAMEX>, this was a dangerous assumption. He did not ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> what it was
                doing in response to the threats and did not task it to take any specific action. He
                also did not direct the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>, then still part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>, to take
                any specific action.
            
            In sum, the domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> never mobilized in response to the threat. They did not
                have direction, and did not have a plan to institute. The borders were not hardened.
                Transportation systems were not fortified. Electronic surveillance was not targeted
                against a domestic threat.
            
            State and local law enforcement were not marshaled to augment the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s efforts. The
                public was not warned.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> exploited deep institutional failings within our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The
                question is whether extra vigilance might have turned up an opportunity to disrupt
                the plot. As seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 7</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> made mistakes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least two</NUMEX>
                such mistakes created opportunities during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late August</TIMEX>.
            LATE LEADS-MIHDHAR, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOUSSAOUI</ENAMEX>, AND KSM
            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 6</ENAMEX> we discussed how intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> successfully detected some of the
                early travel in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> operation, picking up the movements of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX>
                and identifying him, and seeing his travel converge with someone they perhaps could
                have identified but did not-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>-as well as with less easily identifiable
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Bara</ENAMEX>. These observations occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>
                and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> had been lost in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX> without a clear
                realization that it had been lost, and without much effort to pick it up again. Nor
                had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> placed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s watchlist for suspected
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrorists</ENAMEX>, so that either an embassy or a port of entry might take note if Mihdhar
                showed up again.
            On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> occasions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, or both had apparent opportunities to
                refocus on the significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and reinvigorate the search for
                them. After reviewing those episodes we will turn to the handling of the Moussaoui
                case and some late leads regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid Sheikh Mohammed</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Identification</ENAMEX> of Khallad
            Almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> after the original trail had been lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> were working on the investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> bombing. They learned of the link
                between a captured conspirator and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX>." They also learned that
                Khallad was a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">security official</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> who had helped direct the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombing</ENAMEX> (we introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Khallad</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 5</ENAMEX>, and returned to his role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX>
                bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 6</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.55 One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>
                realized that he had heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> before, from a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI/CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> four
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months earlier</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> obtained from a foreign government a photo of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> believed to have directed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> bombing. It was shown to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, and
                he confirmed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in that photograph was the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX> he had
                    described.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX>, on the basis of some links associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX> might be one and
                the same.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> asked that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> surveillance photo of Mihdhar be shown to the joint
                source who had identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX>. In early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> photographs from the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> meeting were shown to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. One was a known photograph of
                Mihdhar, the other a photograph of a then unknown subject. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> did not
                recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>. But he indicated he was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> certain that the other
                individual was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX>.
            
            This meant that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It also meant that
                there was a link between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> seem even more
                suspicious<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.59</NUMEX>Yet we found no effort by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to renew the long-abandoned search
                for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> or his travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX>.
            In addition, we found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> did not notify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> of this identification.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCITenet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cofer Black</ENAMEX> testified before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Inquiry</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> that
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had access to this identification from the beginning. But drawing on an
                extensive record, including documents that were not available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> personnel
                who drafted that testimony, we conclude this was not the case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s primary
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cole investigators</ENAMEX> had no knowledge that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and others until after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX> attacks. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had not
                been informed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s possession of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa, it had not
                then started looking for him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Because it did not know of the
                links between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, it did not start looking for him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
                    <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
            
            This incident is an example of how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> gaps in information sharing can emerge
                even when there is mutual goodwill. The information was from a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI/CIA</ENAMEX> source
                who spoke essentially no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and whose languages were not understood by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> on the scene overseas. Issues of travel and security necessarily kept short
                the amount of time spent with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> usually did
                not translate either questions or answers for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.
            
            For interviews without simultaneous translation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> on the scene received
                copies of the reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> disseminated to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> regarding the
                interviews. But he was not given access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s internal operational reports,
                which contained more detail. It was there-in reporting to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
                did not have access-that information regarding the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX> identification of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> appeared. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> does not recall this particular identification and
                thus cannot say why it was not shared with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>. He might not have
                understood the possible significance of the new identification.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. It is possible that if,
                in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had resumed its search for him, placed him on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIPOFF</ENAMEX> watchlist, or provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> with the information, he might
                have been found-either before or at the time he applied for a new visa in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX>,
                or when he returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spring 2001</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Looking Again</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>
            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-May 2001</TIMEX>, as the threat reports were surging, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> detailed to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Terrorism Operations Section</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> wondered where the attacks
                might occur. We will call him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>." Recalling the episode about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>
                travel of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and his associates, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John"</ENAMEX> searched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s databases for
                information regarding the travel. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX>, he and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
                reexamined many of the old cables from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2000</TIMEX>, including the information that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> had come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 15</TIMEX>,
                    <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who reviewed the cables took no action regarding them. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>,"
                however, began a lengthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, whom we will call "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>," to
                figure out what these cables meant. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John"</ENAMEX> was aware of how dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX> was-at
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point calling him a "major league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>." He concluded that "something bad was
                definitely up." Despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> links evident in this traffic,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>" made no effort
                to determine whether any of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. He did not
                raise that possibility with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>. He was focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>.
            
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John"</ENAMEX> described the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that tended to play a "zone defense." He was
                worrying solely about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In contrast, he told
                us, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> tends to play "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."
            
            Desk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> did not have "cases" in the same sense as
                an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who works an investigation from beginning to end. Thus, when the trail
                went cold after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>, the desk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> moved on
                to different things. By the time the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX> cable arrived with information that
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> had flown to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, the case <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> was no longer
                responsible for follow-up. While several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> opened
                the cable when it arrived in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX>, no action was taken.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s zone defense concentrated on "where,"not "who." Had its information been
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, a combination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s zone defense and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man-to-man</ENAMEX> approach might have been productive.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Meeting</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s" review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> meeting did set off some more sharing of
                information, getting the attention of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> whom we will call "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>."
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane"</ENAMEX> was assigned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> investigation. She knew that another terrorist
                involved in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd al Quso</ENAMEX>, had traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX> to
                give money to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>.
            
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>," had been working together on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colerelated</ENAMEX> issues.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chasing Quso</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave"</ENAMEX> suggested showing some photographs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> who were working on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> case and had interviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quso</ENAMEX>.
            
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John"</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> surveillance pictures to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>" to show to the New
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. She was told that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in the photographs was someone
                named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX>. She did not know why the photographs had been taken or why
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> travel might be significant, and she was not told that someone had
                identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX> in the photographs. When "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane"</ENAMEX> did some research in a database
                for intelligence reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Intelink</ENAMEX>, she found the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> reports on the
                planning for the meeting. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had not disseminated reports on its
                tracking of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane"</ENAMEX>did not pull up any information about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa
                or about travel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>.
            
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>,""<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>," and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> who was on detail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> went
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 11</TIMEX> to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> case. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane"</ENAMEX> brought
                the surveillance pictures. At some point in the meeting she showed the photographs
                to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and asked whether they recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quso</ENAMEX> in any of them. The agents
                asked questions about the photographs- Why were they taken? Why were these people
                being followed? Where are the rest of the photographs?
            
            The only information "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane"</ENAMEX> had about the meeting-other than the photographs-were the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> reports that she had found on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelink</ENAMEX>. These reports, however, contained
                caveats that their contents could not be shared with criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> without
                the permission of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Intelligence Policy and Review</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIPR</ENAMEX>). Therefore "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane"</ENAMEX> concluded that she could not pass on information from those
                reports to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. This decision was potentially significant, because the
                signals intelligence she did not share linked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> to a suspected terrorist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> would have established a link to the
                suspected facility from their work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings case. This link would
                have made them very interested in learning more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>.
            
            The sad irony is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who found the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> were being kept from obtaining
                the fruits of their own work. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, knew more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuala</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lumpur</ENAMEX> meeting. He knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> possessed a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa, that his visa
                application indicated that he intended to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> had
                traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, and that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> had put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>. No one at the meeting asked him what he knew; he did not volunteer
                anything. He told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, he was not authorized to
                answer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> questions regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> information." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>" said she assumed that if
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave"</ENAMEX> knew the answers to questions, he would have volunteered them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> left the meeting without obtaining information that might have started them
                looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> had been a weak link in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s operational planning. He had left the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2000</TIMEX>, a mistake <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> realized could endanger the entire
                plan-for to continue with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> would have to travel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> again. And unlike other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> was not "clean": he had jihadist
                connections. It was just such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> that had brought him to the attention of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>.
            Nevertheless, in this case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s fears were not realized. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> received a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                visa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. He flew to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX>. No one was looking for him.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Search for Mihdhar and Hazmi Begins</ENAMEX> and Fails
            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 2001</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>," following a good instinct but not as part of any
                formal assignment, asked "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>," an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> detailed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                unit, to review all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> materials <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time. She had been at the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> meeting with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>" but had not looked into the issues yet
                herself." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John"</ENAMEX> asked her to do the research in her free time.
            
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary"</ENAMEX> began her work on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That day</TIMEX>, she found the cable reporting that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> had a visa to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week later</TIMEX>, she found the cable reporting
                that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s visa application-what was later discovered to be his first
                application-listed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> as his destination. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 21</TIMEX>, she located the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">March</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> cable that "noted with interest" that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> had flown to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. She immediately grasped the significance of this information.
            
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane"</ENAMEX> promptly met with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. On
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 22</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> told them that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> had entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2000</TIMEX>, and again on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4, 2001</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary"</ENAMEX> also learned that there was
                no record that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> had left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>, and they assumed he
                had left with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2000</TIMEX>. They decided that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, he should be found.
            
            They divided up the work." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary"</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> to draft a cable requesting
