
    
        
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> knew each other from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Soviet</ENAMEX> campaign of the
                1980s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> apparently did not begin working with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> until after the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1998 East</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa embassy</ENAMEX> bombings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21, 2003</TIMEX>;
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Those detainees are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid Sheikh Mohammed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah, Riduan Isamuddin</ENAMEX> (also
                known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abd al Rahim al Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tawfiq bin Attash</ENAMEX> (also known as
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed al Kahtani</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad Khalil Ibrahim Samir al Ani</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Abd al Rahman al Faqasi al Ghamdi</ENAMEX> (also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Bakr al Azdi</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghul</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s relationship to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> and his ethnicity, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, Khalid
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheik Muhammad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nephews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003-300013, Jan. 31, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s biography, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12,2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> electronic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>, requests for information on KSM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. In an uncorroborated post-capture claim that may be mere bravado, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has stated
                that he considered assassinating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Meir Kahane</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kahane</ENAMEX> lectured in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greensboro</ENAMEX> at some point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1984 and 1986</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s connection to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sayyaf</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> electronic communication,
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Summary of Information</ENAMEX> . . . with regard to . . . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8,1999</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s battle
                experience and his electronics work, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Soviet</ENAMEX> activities, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17, 2004</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> says he apparently met Bin
                Ladin for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sayyaf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> mujahideen group
                were next to each other along the front line).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also notes
                that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> continued fighting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jalalabad</ENAMEX> area, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abid</ENAMEX> was
                killed there). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGO</ENAMEX>'s establishment in
                Jalalabad while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> was undergoing training. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> adds that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1993 and 1996</TIMEX>,
                he traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> (a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. Most, if not all, of this travel appears to have been related
                to his abiding interest in carrying out terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> claims
                that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheikh Abdallah</ENAMEX> was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX>, or supporter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, he
                admits that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abdallah</ENAMEX> underwrote a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> trip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> took to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> jihad.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s learning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> 's plans, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> never divulged to him the
                intended target of the attack). On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM/Yousef</ENAMEX> phone conversations, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17, 2004</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also says that most of his
                phone conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> were social in nature, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> did discuss
                mixing explosives <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX> once or twice and that on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> occasion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> asked
                him to send the passport <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> had in his true name, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Basit</ENAMEX>). On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s money
                transfer, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tradebom</ENAMEX> investigation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 1993</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Evidence gathered at the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1995</TIMEX> arrest included dolls
                wearing clothes containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nitrocellulose</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> evidence, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air investigation.
                On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s rationale for attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (in this regard, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s statements echo those of
                Yousef, who delivered an extensive polemic against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy at his
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX> sentencing). On the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air plot, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also says bojinka
                is not Serbo-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian</ENAMEX> for "big bang," as has been widely reported, but rather a
                nonsense word he adopted after hearing it on the front lines in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>).
                According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, the plot was to receive financing from a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>,
                including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> of co-conspirator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wali Khan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s own funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 26, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>. On
                activities during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1994</TIMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21, 2004</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. On recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wali Khan</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Hakim Murad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 1995</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 2003</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> recounts how he knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wali Khan</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>). On the
                testing of the timer, see Brief for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States of America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramzi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Yousef</ENAMEX>, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1041</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>) (2d <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>. filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25, 2000</TIMEX>), pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85-86</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88-91</NUMEX>.
                The latter explosion caused the death of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> and extensive damage to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX>, which was forced to make an emergency landing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okinawa</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, Yousef
                was convicted on charges arising out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bojinka</ENAMEX> plot, including the bombing of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philippine Airlines</ENAMEX> flight. See <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ibid., p. 8</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s travels, see generally
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> managed to escape
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, but his accomplice, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Murad</ENAMEX>-whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> claims to have sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yousef</ENAMEX> with
                <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> to help fund the operation-was arrested and disclosed details of the plot
                while under interrogation. Contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murad</ENAMEX>'s confession, in which he described his
                intended role as one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> who would plant bombs on board the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">targeted</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murad</ENAMEX>'s role was limited to carrying the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX>
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubai</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>;
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reports); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24, 2004</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 2004</TIMEX>. This aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s account is not
                credible, as it conflicts not just with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murad</ENAMEX>'s confession but also with physical
                evidence tying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murad</ENAMEX> to the very core of the plot, and with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s own statements
                elsewhere that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murad</ENAMEX> was involved in planning and executing the operation.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also claims that while he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qatar</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1995</TIMEX>, he and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> consulted by telephone regarding the cargo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> plan, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> proceeded
                with the operation despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s advice that he hide instead). We have uncovered no
                evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> was present at the guesthouse in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> 's arrest
                took place, as has been suggested in the press.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>
                coincided with a police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zagreb</ENAMEX> where the timing device of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX> (a modified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Casio</ENAMEX> watch) resembled those manufactured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philippines</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air investigation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1999</TIMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> trip and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also claims to have encountered
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sayf al Adl</ENAMEX> while in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>; apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has not divulged the substance of this
                meeting).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX>. In another interrogation
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> downplays the significance of his relationship to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> in
                enabling him to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. Specifically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> was not a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> never met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,2004</NUMEX>. With respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s additional proposal to bomb cargo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> by shipping
                jackets containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nitrocellulose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> expressed interest in
                changing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> so that it would involve a suicide operative. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. Probably inflating his own role, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> says he and a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>,
                including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wali Khan</ENAMEX>, were among the earliest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of attacking the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and some of the other jihadist leaders
                concentrated on overthrowing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> regimes and argued for limiting confrontation with
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to places like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                agenda, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 2003</TIMEX>. As discussed
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 2</ENAMEX>, we do not agree with this assessment. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s reactions to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s proposal, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 2004</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s intent to target the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s independence, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. Even after he began working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> concealed from
                them his ongoing relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sayyaf</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 30, 2003</TIMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> says he would have accepted the support of another
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> to stage a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>-type operation, there is no evidence he ever peddled
                this idea to any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. On his travels after meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX> also was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Konsojaya</ENAMEX>, a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> run by a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wali Khan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air
                investigation, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23, 1999</TIMEX>. Hambali claims he was asked to serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> as a formality and insists that he did not recognize the
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>"who were to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or play any role in its operations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
                reports). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> maintains that he provided similar services for other mujahideen
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> at this time, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Fighting Group</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> headed
                by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s commitment, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reports). On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s decision to approve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has observed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Africa</ENAMEX> bombings and the
                subsequent bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Cole</ENAMEX> yielded a recruiting bonanza for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, as
                increasing numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> youth became enamored of the idea of waging jihad against
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s decision to move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kandahar</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX>. On the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2003</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also says that as head of the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, he
                would take charge of producing the propaganda video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> issued following the
                bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Cole</ENAMEX>). On the oath, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 2003</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also claims his reluctance stemmed from a concern
                that he would lose the ability to persevere with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                subsequently decide to cancel it).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. On a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 4, 2003</TIMEX>. On a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14, 2003</TIMEX>. On a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
                operation, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 2003</TIMEX>. On other
                possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> discussed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Hambali, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 4, 2003</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, Apr.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 2004</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maldives</ENAMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. For an example of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s popularity, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                Qaeda facilitator, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11, 2002</TIMEX>. See also Intelligence report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu</ENAMEX>
                Zubaydah, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 7, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 14, 2003</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rohan Gunaratna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inside Al Qaeda</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Network</ENAMEX> of Terror (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Univ</ENAMEX>. Press,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), pp. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">187, 199</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>. On the trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>'s relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX> and receipt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> funds, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali, Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX> began
                providing funds to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JI</ENAMEX> for terrorist operations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 1999</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mar. 3, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>'s role as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                detainee, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4,2004</NUMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sufaat</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>,
                Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of detainee, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 2003</TIMEX>. In
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sufaat</ENAMEX> received a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree in biological sciences, with a minor in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemistry</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California State University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sufaat</ENAMEX> did not start on the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> biological weapons program until after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JI</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX> church bombings
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, in which he was involved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Hambali, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sufaat</ENAMEX>'s schooling, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 14, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> also maintains that
                he persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX> to focus on "soft" targets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, such as oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tankers</ENAMEX>,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>, and Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>. As discussed in greater detail in section <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX> was sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> to case <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> airline flights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX> for possible future
                attacks there, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> were on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> leg of their travel from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, where they would arrive on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 15, 2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali's</ENAMEX> assistance at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s
                request, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8, 2003</TIMEX>. On assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moussaoui</ENAMEX>, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr.9, 2002</TIMEX>. According to statements attributed to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sufaat</ENAMEX>, in each of these instances the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> were lodged at
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sufaat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominium</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> on the outskirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 22, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>'s relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.29, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5, 2003</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX> also
                explains his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> as follows: he received his marching orders
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JI</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> would lead any joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of both
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>). On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>'s objections, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 8, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s coordination with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s recognition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>'s domain, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, his
                close relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX> prompted criticism from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bashir</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, who
                thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX> should focus more directly on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> instead of
                involving himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s broader terrorist program. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> describes
                Hambali as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.18,2003</TIMEX>. Nashiri observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda's</ENAMEX> standard
                security practice dictated that no senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> could manage terrorist activities
                in a location where another senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> was operating. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 14, 2003</TIMEX>. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s deference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>'s turf
                apparently had limits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX> says he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hambali</ENAMEX> never discussed the intended
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> portion of the original <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/11</NUMEX> plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad, Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s recruitment, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nasser</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad Naser al Bahri</ENAMEX>, a.k.a. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Jandal</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17-Oct. 2, 2001</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s refusal
                to swear allegiance, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21, 2003</TIMEX>.
                On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s idea for his first terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> and his travels, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 26, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 26, 2002</TIMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s
                account of this episode dates his return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 date</TIMEX> is
                likely more accurate. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the missilesmuggling and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX>-bombing plots, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, seizure of antitank <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14, 1998</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammad</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashed Daoud al Owahli</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 9, 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 6</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri's</ENAMEX> version, which may not be true, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 26, 2002</TIMEX>. On communication between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri and Bin</ENAMEX>
                Ladin about attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Nashiri, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21, 2002</TIMEX>. The reporting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s statements on this subject is
                somewhat inconsistent, especially as to the exact timing of the original proposal.
                Some corroboration does exist, however, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s claim that the original
                proposal was his. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detainee</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX> told him
                about the maritime operation sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1999</TIMEX> and credited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nashiri</ENAMEX> as its
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">originator</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27, 2003</TIMEX>. Nashiri claims not
                to have had any telephone or email contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> while planning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX>
                operation; rather, whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> wanted to meet, he would have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                member travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to summon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX> by telephone. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>. As an example of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s status, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Jandal</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17-Oct. 2, 2001</TIMEX> (in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX> is described as widely known to
                be one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s most committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and, according to one of his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mujahideen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, so extreme in his ferocity in waging jihad that he "would
                commit a terrorist act 'in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mecca</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ka'aba</ENAMEX> itself ' [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiest</TIMEX> site in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>] if he believed there was a need to do so"). On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s role on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arabian</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peninsula</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 14, 2004</TIMEX>. Nashiri
                also enjoyed a reputation as a productive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruiter</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 29, 2002</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s discretion, see,
                e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 20, 2002</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nashiri</ENAMEX>
                seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s approval, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 2004</TIMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Nashiri, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>'s security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s learning from the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bombing and his interest in
                a more novel form of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attack</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and speculation about striking the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has stated that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> at this time never advanced the notion of
                using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> as weapons past the idea stage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 2, 2004</TIMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> claimed that
                while in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> custody in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air plot co-conspirator
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Hakim Murad</ENAMEX> had confessed having discussed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> the idea of attacking
                targets, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>, with hijacked commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX> flown
                by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-trained <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lance</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Years for Revenge:</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Terrorism</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FBI-the Untold Story</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>), pp.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">278-280</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Murad</ENAMEX>'s initial taped confession, he referred to an idea of crashing a
                plane into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance</ENAMEX> gave us his copy of an apparent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philippine</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Police</ENAMEX> document on an interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murad</ENAMEX>. That document reports Murad
                describing his idea of crashing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, but in this report
                Murad claims he was thinking of hijacking a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to do it, saying the
                idea had come up in a casual conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> with no specific plan for its
                execution. We have seen no pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murad</ENAMEX> referred in interrogations
                to the training of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>, or referred in this casual conversation to targets
                other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, who after
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">9/11</ENAMEX> offered the much more elaborate account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murad</ENAMEX>'s statements reported in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance</ENAMEX>'s book, claims to have passed this added information to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. But
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance</ENAMEX> states the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> declined to identify these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2004</TIMEX>). If such information was provided to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                official, we have seen no indication that it was written down or disseminated within
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Incidentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> says he never discussed his idea for the
                planes operation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murad</ENAMEX>, a person <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> regarded as a minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 2, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX> study on airplane hijacking operations, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 26</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12,2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6,2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu</ENAMEX>
                Zubaydah, who worked closely with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, has stated that KSM
                originally presented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> with a scaled-down version of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9/11</TIMEX> plan, and that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> to expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> with the comment, "Why do you use an axe
                when you can use a bulldozer<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>,
                May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 2003</TIMEX>. The only possible corroboration we have found for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>'s
                statement is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s suggestion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> may have expanded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s original
                idea for an attack using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, Apr.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 2004</TIMEX>. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX> claims to have been present when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> says
                he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> pitched his proposal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>. For the scheme's lukewarm reception, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s response, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">492</NUMEX> NOTES <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TO CHAPTER 5</ENAMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has provided inconsistent information about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> first
                approved his proposal for what became the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> attacks in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1998</TIMEX> or in early
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3, 2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s antipathy to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX> 's role, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atef</ENAMEX> 's death, see DOS
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comprehensive List of Terrorists and Groups Identified Under Executive</ENAMEX>
                Order <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13224</NUMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>; Apr.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 2004</TIMEX>. An earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> interrogation report, however, states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                preferred the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> as a target. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has admitted that his statement in a
                post-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Jazeera</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yosri Fouda</ENAMEX>-that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                "reconnaissance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>" had identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
                during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX>-was a lie designed to inflate the perceived scale of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>
                operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23, 2004</TIMEX>. For the
                specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, selection of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> targets, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 13, 2003</TIMEX>
                (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> interrogation).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Bara al Yemeni</ENAMEX> is also known by the names <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu al Bara al Taizi</ENAMEX>, Suhail
                Shurabi, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barakat</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has also stated that he did not learn of the
                selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 2, 2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eagerness</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> . For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s instruction, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>. Hazmi obtained a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-1/B-2</ENAMEX> multiple-entry visa issued at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiddah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 3, 1999</TIMEX>; Mihdhar obtained the same type of visa at the same
                location on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 7, 1999</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> records, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> details for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8, 2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> both obtained new passports shortly before they
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> for visas. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31, 2003</TIMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 9</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of birth, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 September</TIMEX>:
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plot and the Plotters</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003-40044HC</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 2003</TIMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49-50</NUMEX>. For their
                travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 3, 2001</TIMEX>. For their visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 5, 2002</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 11, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 2, 2001</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s visa application under a false name and its rejection, see DOS
                record, visa application of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salah Saeed Mohammed bin Yousaf</ENAMEX> (alias for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>),
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 3, 1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20, 2003</TIMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s visa denial was based not on terrorism concerns but apparently on his
                failure to submit sufficient documentation in support of his application. See DOS
                record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> detail, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> mission to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>,
                see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20, 2003</TIMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> point
                of contact, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 22, 2003</TIMEX>.
                Khallad claims he cannot remember his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX>'s full name but says it sounded
                like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barzan</ENAMEX>." According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barzan</ENAMEX>" is possibly identifiable with Sarbarz
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who resided at the address in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bothell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, that Khallad
                listed on his visa application as his final destination. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>. For his contacts with
                "Barzan" and his arrest, see ibid.; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX> has confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> had been assigned to help procure
                explosives for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>-bombing plot, and that his arrest caused work on the
                operation to stop temporarily. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashiri</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>. For the interventions, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> has provided inconsistent information as to his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">release date</TIMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1999</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6, 2004</TIMEX>
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1999</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> reportedly has confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX> was released
                from custody only after negotiations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yemeni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for political security
                in which a deal was struck prohibiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> from conducting
                operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of detainee, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2002</TIMEX>.
                For his giving up on a visa and his return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 22, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s realization of visa complications, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>. According to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Bara</ENAMEX>
                never applied for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> has noted
                that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yemeni</ENAMEX> slated early on to participate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9/11</TIMEX>
                attacks, likewise would prove unable to acquire a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7, 2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s desire to keep
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Bara</ENAMEX> involved, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saudis</ENAMEX> being chosen for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> operation, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7, 2004</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 23, 2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s splitting the
                operation into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad, Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. For the alternate scenario, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>,
                Apr. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21,2004</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> has provided contradictory statements about the number of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> to be destroyed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Asia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of
                Khallad, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 13, 2003</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 2004</TIMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> were likely origins of the flights because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yemenis</ENAMEX> did not
                need visas to enter them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 13</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. For the importance of simultaneity, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>' training, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>. For the elite nature of the course and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nibras</ENAMEX>'s participation, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2003</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s view, see ibid.;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s visit, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>. For a description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and the commando course, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s interest and the decision on
                the number of trainees, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>. For the nature of the commando course, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Khallad, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> claims that the course proved so rigorous that Mihdhar
                quit after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and returned to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.18,2003</TIMEX>. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who
                were present during the training have provided different accounts. Khallad
                apparently has stated both that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> pulled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX> out of
                the course early and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> actually completed the course. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 2004</TIMEX>. See also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report
                of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Jandal</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 2, 2001</TIMEX> (indicating that Mihdhar
                completed the course).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>. For instruction on Western culture and travel, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1999</TIMEX> activity and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                payment, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>. According to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, he received a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>-related expenses.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 5, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Bara</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX>'s travels, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> has provided a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> version, namely
                that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> traveled together to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Khallad, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s simultaneous presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quetta</ENAMEX>, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>; Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 2004</TIMEX>. KSM
                maintains it was a coincidence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">31,2004</NUMEX>. In his initial
                post-capture statements, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> did not have to attend the
                training because he had previously received similar training from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> subsequently expressed uncertainty
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atef excused Mihdhar</ENAMEX> from the training. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>. For the varying accounts of the course's length, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports,
                interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s description, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s description, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 5, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> says that he permitted the trainees to view <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> films about
                hijackings only after he edited the films to cover the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 2003</TIMEX>. For the use of game
                software and discussions of casing flights, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s instructions regarding casing, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>. For visits to travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 13, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55</TIMEX>. For the travels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Bara</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hazmi</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s travel from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 14, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">265ANY- 280350</ENAMEX>, serial
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24808</NUMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives'knowledge</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> being sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29, 2003</TIMEX>. For passport doctoring, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>. For casing, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Bara</ENAMEX>'s departure, as well
                as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX>'s travel, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> maintains that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Bara</ENAMEX> did not participate in the casing operation and
                simply traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s companion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX>. For the trip's original purpose and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s suggestion, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Endolite</ENAMEX>, and the
                financing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s trip, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX>. On informing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hambali</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali's</ENAMEX> assistance, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 4, 2003</TIMEX>. For the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> who spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX>. For the dates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s travel, his mistake in seating, and his other efforts
                to case flights, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>;
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21, 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX> says he put the box cutter alongside tubes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> and
                shaving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> with metallic exteriors, so that if the metal detector at the airport
                was triggered, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> would attribute the alarm to the other items. He also
                carried art supplies, which he hoped would explain the presence of a box cutter if
                anyone asked. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                Khallad, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX>'s arrival and stay at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s arrival, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 14, 2003</TIMEX> (citing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">265A-NY-280350, serial 24808</ENAMEX>).
                For their stay at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sufaat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Plot and the</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotters</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 2003</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s discussions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s knowledge of the
                operation, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> meeting, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> analytic report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Plot and the Plotters</ENAMEX>,"
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 2003</TIMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49-50</NUMEX>. For relocation of the meeting to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd al Quso</ENAMEX>, a
                close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad's</ENAMEX>, accompanied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nibras</ENAMEX> on the trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> to take money
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>. Quso claims that the amount was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation,
                interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quso</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31, 2001</TIMEX>. Khallad claims that it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $10,000</NUMEX> to
                <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> has identified contradictory purposes for the money: a donation to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> benefiting amputees, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.8,2003</TIMEX>; and to advance the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>-bombing operation, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report,
                interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> has explicitly denied giving any of
                the money he received from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nibras and Quso to Hazmi and Mihdhar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                reports, interrogations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.8, 2003</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7, 2004</TIMEX>. Given the separate
                reporting from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> that he gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX> each before they traveled
                to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, we have insufficient evidence to conclude that the Nibras/Quso
                money helped finance the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15, 2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s interest in traveling to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7, 2004</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambali</ENAMEX>'s
                assistance, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bara</ENAMEX>'s return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX>. For the hotel arrangements, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>,
                Jan. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,2004</NUMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> not meeting with each other, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>'s subsequent actions,
                see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s cancellation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s departure, see
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report, interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8, 2003</TIMEX>. For their arrival in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijackers Timeline</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 14, 2003</TIMEX> (citing
