
    
        
            HEROISM AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HORROR</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PREPAREDNESS AS OF SEPTEMBER 11</ENAMEX>
            Emergency response is a product of preparedness. On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, the last best hope for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working in or visiting the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> rested not with national policymakers but with private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and
                local public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>, especially the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> responders: fire, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, emergency
                medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, and building safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>.
            Building Preparedness
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> (WTC) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was built for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority of New York</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. Construction began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> began to occupy its space in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Towers</ENAMEX> came to occupy a unique and symbolic place in the culture of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> actually consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, spread across <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
                acres of land. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were connected by an underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> (the concourse).
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Towers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX>) were the
                signature structures, containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10.4 million square feet</NUMEX> of office space. Both
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">towers</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> stories, were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 1,350 feet</NUMEX> high, and were square; each wall
                measured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">208</NUMEX> feet in length. On any given workday, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 50,000</NUMEX> office workers
                occupied the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> passed through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
            
            Each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stairwells</ENAMEX>, which ran essentially from top to
                bottom, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX>. Generally, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators originating</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> ran to "sky
                lobbies" on higher floors, where additional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> carried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to the tops
                of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Stairwells A</ENAMEX> and C ran from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">110th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> to the raised mezzanine level of the
                lobby. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stairwell</ENAMEX> B ran from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">107th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> to level <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B6</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> below ground,
                and was accessible from the West Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> level, which was one floor below the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mezzanine</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stairwells</ENAMEX> ran essentially straight up and down, except for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
                deviations in stairwells A and C where the staircase jutted out toward the perimeter
                of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. On the upper and lower boundaries of these deviations were transfer
                hallways contained within the stairwell proper. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX> contained smoke doors
                to prevent smoke from rising from lower to upper portions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>; they were
                kept closed but not locked. Doors leading from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> space into the stairwells were
                never kept locked; reentry from the stairwells was generally possible on at least
                every <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>.
            
            Doors leading to the roof were locked. There was no rooftop evacuation plan. The
                roofs of both the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX> were sloped and cluttered surfaces
                with radiation hazards, making them impractical for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> landings and as
                staging areas for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower roof</ENAMEX> had a helipad, it did not
                meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> guidelines.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1993 Terrorist Bombing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Response</ENAMEX>. Unlike most
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and specifically the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> had been the
                target of terrorist attacks before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:18 P.M.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 26, 1993</TIMEX>, a
                <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,500-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> stashed in a rental <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> was detonated on a parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> ramp
                beneath theTwinTowers. The explosion killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, injured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,000</NUMEX> more,
                and exposed vulnerabilities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>'s and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s emergency
                    preparedness.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> lost power and communications capability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Generators</ENAMEX> had to be shut down
                to ensure safety, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> stopped. The public-address system and emergency
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lighting</ENAMEX> systems failed. The unlit stairwells filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> and were so dark as
                to be impassable. Rescue efforts by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department of New York</ENAMEX> (FDNY) were
                hampered by the inability of its radios to function in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> as large as the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Towers</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> emergency call system was overwhelmed. The general evacuation
                of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>' occupants via the stairwells took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than four hours</TIMEX>.
            
            Several small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were physically unable to descend the stairs were
                evacuated from the roof of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX> (NYPD)
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was lifted from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> roof by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> in
                a dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> rappel operation<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">- 15 hours</TIMEX> after the bombing. General
                knowledge that these air rescues had occurred appears to have left a number of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> who worked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Towers</ENAMEX> with the false impression that helicopter
                rescues were part of the WTC evacuation plan and that rescue from the roof was a
                viable, if not favored, option for those who worked on upper floors. Although they
                were considered after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> evacuations in fact were not incorporated
                into the WTC fire safety plan.
            
            To address the problems encountered during the response to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> bombing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an initial $100 million</NUMEX> to make physical, structural, and
                technological improvements to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>, as well as to enhance its fire safety plan
                and reorganize and bolster its fire safety and security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>.
            
            Substantial enhancements were made to power sources and exits. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluorescent</ENAMEX> signs and
                markings were added in and near stairwells. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> also installed a
                sophisticated computerized fire alarm system with redundant electronics and control
                panels, and state-of-the-art fire command <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> were placed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> of each
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tower</ENAMEX>.
            
            To manage fire emergency preparedness and operations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> created the
                dedicated position of fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> supervised a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of deputy
                fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, one of whom was on duty at the fire command <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in the
                lobby of each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> at all times. He or she would be responsible for communicating
                with building occupants during an emergency.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> also sought to prepare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> better for future emergencies.
                Deputy fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> conducted fire drills at least twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, with
                advance notice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>." Fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>"were selected from among civilian
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> and consisted of a fire warden, deputy fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wardens</ENAMEX>, and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">searchers</ENAMEX>. The standard procedure for fire drills was for fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wardens</ENAMEX> to lead
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> in their respective areas to the center of the floor, where they would
                use the emergency intercom phone to obtain specific information on how to proceed.
                Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> have told us that their evacuation on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX> was greatly aided
                by changes and training implemented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> in response to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
                    bombing.
            
            But during these drills, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> were not directed into the stairwells, or provided
                with information about their configuration and about the existence of transfer
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hallways</ENAMEX> and smoke doors. Neither full nor partial evacuation drills were held.
                Moreover, participation in drills that were held varied greatly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tenant</ENAMEX>. In general, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> were never told not to evacuate up. The standard fire
                drill announcement advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> that in the event of an actual emergency,
                they would be directed to descend to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> below the fire. Most
                civilians recall simply being taught to await the instructions that would be
                provided at the time of an emergency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Civilians</ENAMEX> were not informed that rooftop
                evacuations were not part of the evacuation plan, or that doors to the roof were
                kept locked. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> acknowledges that it had no protocol for rescuing
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trapped <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above</NUMEX> a fire in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>.
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six weeks</TIMEX> before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX> attacks, control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> was transferred by net
                lease to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silverstein Properties</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Select Port Authority</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were designated to assist with the transition. Others remained on-site but
                were no longer part of the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>. However, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, most
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority World Trade Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>-including those not on the
                designated "transition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>"- reported to their regular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> to provide
                assistance throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silverstein Properties</ENAMEX> was in charge of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, the WTC fire safety plan remained essentially the
                    same.
            
            Preparedness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Responders</ENAMEX>
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, the principal <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> responders were from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department of New York</ENAMEX>,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority Police Department</ENAMEX> (PAPD), and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Emergency Management</ENAMEX> (OEM).
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority Police Department</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority of New</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX> consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,331</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, many of whom were
                trained in fire suppression methods as well as in law enforcement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPD</ENAMEX> was led
                by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX>. There was a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPD</ENAMEX> command for each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority's</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>.
            
            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> police commands used ultra-high-frequency radios. Although all
                the radios were capable of using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, most PAPD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> used one
                local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. The local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> were low-wattage and worked only in the immediate
                vicinity of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPD</ENAMEX> also had an agencywide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, but not all
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commands</ENAMEX> could access it.
            
            As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> lacked any standard operating procedures to
                govern how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> from multiple commands would respond to and then be staged and
                utilized at a major incident at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>. In particular, there were no standard
                operating procedures covering how different commands should communicate via radio
                during such an incident.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> NYPD was headed by a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>, whose duties were not
                primarily operational but who retained operational authority. Much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>'s
                operational activities were run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. In the event of a major
                emergency, a leading role would be played by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Operations Division</ENAMEX>. This
                division included the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviation Unit</ENAMEX>, which provided <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> for surveys and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rescues</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergency Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> (ESU), which carried out specialized rescue
                missions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> had specific and detailed standard operating procedures for the
                dispatch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to an incident, depending on the incident's magnitude.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> were divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> different radio zones, with a central radio
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatcher</ENAMEX> assigned to each. In addition, there were several radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> for
                citywide operations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX> had portable radios with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> or more available
                channels, so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> could respond outside his or her precinct. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> also
                had these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> but at an operation would use a separate point-to-point channel
                (which was not monitored by a dispatcher)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> also supervised the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s 911
                emergency call system. Its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 1,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>, radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX>, and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> were civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>. They were trained in the rudiments
                of emergency response. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">911</ENAMEX> call concerned a fire, it was transferred to FDNY
                    dispatch.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department of New York</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> was headed by a fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> who, unlike the police
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>, lacked operational authority. Operations were headed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of
                department- the sole five-star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> was organized in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> separate geographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> was
                further divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between four</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> battalions. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">battalion</ENAMEX> contained
                typically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between three and four</NUMEX> engine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to four</NUMEX> ladder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
                In total, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> had 205 engine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">133</NUMEX> ladder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. On-duty ladder
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> consisted of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX>; on-duty engine
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> consisted of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant</ENAMEX> and normally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX>.
                Ladder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' primary function was to conduct rescues; engine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> focused
                on extinguishing fires.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Specialized Operations Command</ENAMEX> (SOC) contained a limited number of units
                that were of particular importance in responding to a terrorist attack or other
                major incident. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad companies</ENAMEX>
                performed specialized and highly risky rescue operations.
            
            The logistics of fire operations were directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Dispatch Operations Division</ENAMEX>,
                which had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> boroughs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All 911</NUMEX> calls concerning fire
                emergencies were transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> dispatch.
            
            As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> responding to a fire used analog,
                point-to-point radios that had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> normal operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. Typically, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would operate on the same tactical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> on the scene
                would monitor and use to communicate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chiefs</ENAMEX> at a fire
                operation also would use a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command channel</ENAMEX>. Because these point-to-point
                radios had weak signal strength, communications on them could be heard only by other
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> in the immediate vicinity. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> had a dispatch
                frequency for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> boroughs; these were not point-to-point <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and
                could be monitored from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX>'s radios performed poorly during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1993</TIMEX> WTC bombing for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons.
                First, the radios signals often did not succeed in penetrating the numerous steel
                and concrete floors that separated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> attempting to communicate; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>,
                so many different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were attempting to use the same point-to-point channel
                that communications became unintelligible.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> installed, at its own expense, a repeater system in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> to
                greatly enhance FDNY radio communications in the difficult high-rise environment of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Towers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> recommended leaving the repeater system on at
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX> times. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> requested, however, that the repeater be turned on only when it
                was actually needed because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> could cause interference with other FDNY
                operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower Manhattan</ENAMEX>. The repeater system was installed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX>
                Authority police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>, to be activated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> responding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> so requested. However, in
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring of 2000</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> asked that an activation console for the repeater system
                be placed instead in the lobby fire safety desk of each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, making FDNY
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> entirely responsible for its activation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> complied.
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1998 and 2000</TIMEX>, fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died from fires in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> than in any
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> period since accurate measurements began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firefighter</ENAMEX> deaths-a
                total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX>-compared favorably with the most tranquil periods in
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s history.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergency Management and Interagency Preparedness</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> created the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Emergency Management</ENAMEX>,
                which had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> basic functions. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch Command</ENAMEX> was to monitor the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s key communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>-including radio frequencies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> dispatch and
                the NYPD-and other data. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX> was to improve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s
                response to major incidents, including terrorist attacks, by planning and conducting
                exercises and drills that would involve multiple city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, particularly the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX> would play a crucial role in managing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
                overall response to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The World Trade Center Radio Repeater System Rendering</ENAMEX> by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Crupi</ENAMEX> incident. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergency Operations Center</ENAMEX> was activated,
                designated liaisons from relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> and his or her
                senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, would respond there. In addition, an OEM field responder would be sent
                to the scene to ensure that the response was coordinated.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> was located at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7WTC</TIMEX>. Some questioned locating it both so close
                to a previous terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> and on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">23rd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> (difficult to
                access should <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> become inoperable). There was no backup <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> updated a directive titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Direction and Control of</ENAMEX>
                Emergencies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX>." Its purpose was to eliminate "potential
                conflict among responding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> which may have areas of overlapping expertise and
                responsibility." The directive sought to accomplish this objective by designating,
                for different types of emergencies, an appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Incident Commander</ENAMEX>."
                This Incident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commander</ENAMEX> would be "responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>'s
                response to the emergency," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX> was "designated the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'On Scene Interagency</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coordinator</ENAMEX>.'"
            
            Nevertheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> each considered itself operationally autonomous. As
                of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, they were not prepared to comprehensively coordinate their efforts
                in responding to a major incident. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX> had not overcome this problem.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SEPTEMBER 11, 2001</TIMEX>
            As we turn to the events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, we are mindful of the unfair perspective
                afforded by hindsight. Nevertheless, we will try to describe what happened in the
                following <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">102 minutes</TIMEX>:
            
                the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17 minutes</TIMEX> from the crash of the hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> into
                    <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:46</TIMEX> until the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX> was hit
                the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">56 minutes</TIMEX> from the crash of the hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight 175 into
                    <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:03</TIMEX> until the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tower</ENAMEX>
                the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29 minutes</TIMEX> from the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:59</TIMEX> until the collapse
                    of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:28 From 8:46 until 9:03 A.M.</TIMEX>
            
            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:46:40</TIMEX>, the hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> flew into the upper portion of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>, cutting through floors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">93 to 99</TIMEX>. Evidence suggests that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>
                of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>'s stairwells became impassable from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">92nd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> up. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> were killed instantly by the impact. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> more remained alive but
                    trapped.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Civilians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Safety Personnel</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> Calls
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Tower</ENAMEX>.
            
            A jet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> fireball erupted upon impact and shot down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX>.
                The fireball exploded onto numerous lower floors, including <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 77th and 22nd</TIMEX>; the
                West Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> level; and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B4</TIMEX> level, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> stories below ground. The burning
                jet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> immediately created thick, black smoke that enveloped the upper floors and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">roof of the North Tower</ENAMEX>. The roof of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX> was also engulfed in smoke
                because of prevailing light winds from the northwest.
            
            Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">911</ENAMEX> system was flooded with eyewitness accounts of
                the event. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> correctly identified the target of the attack. Some
                identified the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> as a commercial airliner.
            
            The first response came from private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
                in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Everything that would happen to them during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next few minutes</TIMEX>
                would turn on their circumstances and their preparedness, assisted by building
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> on-site.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> trapped on or above the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">92nd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> gathered in large and small
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, primarily between the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">103rd</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>. A large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was reported on
                the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">92nd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, technically below the impact but unable to descend. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Civilians</ENAMEX> were
                also trapped in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> below the impact zone-mostly on floors in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 70s and 80s</TIMEX>, but also on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least the 47th</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22nd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>-were either trapped
                or waiting for assistance.
            
            It is unclear when the first full building evacuation order was attempted over the
                public-address system. The deputy fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, while
                immediately aware that a major incident had occurred, did not know for approximately
                <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> that a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> had directly hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Following protocol,
                he initially gave announcements to those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> that had generated computerized
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alarms</ENAMEX>, advising those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> to descend to points of safety-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>
                below the smoke or fire-and to wait there for further instructions. The deputy fire
                safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> has told us that he began instructing a full evacuation within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> of the explosion. But the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> FDNY <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> to arrive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> were
                advised by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>-who had reported to the lobby
                although he was no longer the designated fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>-that the full building
                evacuation announcement had been made within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> being
                    hit.
            
            Because of damage to building systems caused by the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>,
                public-address announcements were not heard in many locations. For the same reason,
                many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> may have been unable to use the emergency intercom phones, as they
                had been advised to do in fire drills. Many called 911.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">911</ENAMEX> system was not equipped to handle the enormous volume of calls it received.
                Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> were unable to connect with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>, receiving an "all circuits
                busy"message. Standard operating procedure was for calls relating to fire
                emergencies to be transferred from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> dispatch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> in the
                appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">borough</ENAMEX> (in this case, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>). Transfers were often plagued by
                delays and were in some cases unsuccessful. Many calls were also prematurely
                    disconnected.
            
            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX> had no information about either the location
                or the magnitude of the impact zone and were therefore unable to provide information
                as fundamental as whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> were above or below the fire. Because the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> were not informed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Aviation</ENAMEX>'s determination of the impossibility of
                rooftop rescues from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Towers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, they could not knowledgeably
                answer when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> asked whether to go up or down. In most instances, therefore,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX> relied on standard operating procedures for
                high-rise fires-that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> should stay low, remain where they are, and wait for
                emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to reach them. This advice was given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tower</ENAMEX> for locations both above and below the impact zone. Fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> told us that
                the evacuation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from skyscrapers can create many new
                problems, especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who are disabled or in poor health. Many of the
                injuries after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> bombing occurred during the evacuation.
            
            Although the guidance to stay in place may seem understandable in cases of
                conventional high-rise fires, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> determined at
                once that all building occupants should attempt to evacuate immediately. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:57</TIMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> had instructed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPD</ENAMEX> and building <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to evacuate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tower</ENAMEX> as well, because of the magnitude of the damage caused by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s
                    impact.
            
            These critical decisions were not conveyed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> or to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX>.
                Departing from protocol, a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> that they could break
                windows, and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> to evacuate if they could.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Civilians</ENAMEX> who called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> located at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> were advised to
                leave if they could.
            
            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> who were not obstructed from proceeding began evacuating without
                waiting for instructions over the intercom system. Some remained to wait for help,
                as advised by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>. Others simply continued to work or delayed to collect
                personal items, but in many cases were urged to leave by others. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian employees</ENAMEX> remained on various upper floors to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> who were
                trapped and to assist in the evacuation.
            
            While evacuating, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> had trouble reaching the exits because of damage
                caused by the impact. Some were confused by deviations in the increasingly crowded
                stairwells, and impeded by doors that appeared to be locked but actually were jammed
                by debris or shifting that resulted from the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. Despite these
                obstacles, the evacuation was relatively calm and orderly.
            
            Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> of impact, smoke was beginning to rise to the upper floors in
                debilitating volumes and isolated fires were reported, although there were some
                pockets of refuge. Faced with insufferable heat, smoke, and fire, and with no
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> for relief, some jumped or fell from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Tower</ENAMEX>.
            
            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX> were initially unaware of what had happened in the
                other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>. Some believed an incident had occurred in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>; others were
                aware that a major explosion had occurred on the upper floors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>.
                Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> decided to leave, and some were advised to do so by fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wardens</ENAMEX>. In
                addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan Stanley</ENAMEX>, which occupied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX>,
                evacuated its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> by the decision of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>.
            
            Consistent with protocol, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:49</TIMEX> the deputy fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Tower</ENAMEX>
                told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> that he would wait to hear from "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
                from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> or somebody" before ordering an evacuation.
            
            At about this time, an announcement over the public-address system in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Tower</ENAMEX>
                stated that the incident had occurred in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>,
                generally, that their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was safe and that they should remain on or return to
                their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> or floors. A statement from the deputy fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> informing
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> that the incident had occurred in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was consistent with
                protocol; the expanded advice did not correspond to any existing written protocol,
                and did not reflect any instruction known to have been given to the deputy fire
                safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>. We do not know the reason for the announcement, as both
                the deputy fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> believed to have made it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of fire
                safety for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex perished</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX>'s collapse. Clearly, however,
                the prospect of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> hitting the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was beyond the
                contemplation of anyone giving advice. According to one of the first fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> to
                arrive, such a scenario was unimaginable, "beyond our consciousness." As a result of
                the announcement, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> remained on their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>. Others reversed their
                evacuation and went back up.
            
            Similar advice was given in person by security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in both the groundfloor
                lobby-where a group of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> that had descended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> was personally
                instructed to go back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX>-and in the upper sky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, where many waited for
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> to take them down. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who gave this advice were
                not part of the fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.
            
            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">occupants</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>. Some
                were advised to stand by for further instructions; others were strongly advised to
                    leave.
            
            It is not known whether the order by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> to evacuate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX> was
                received by the deputy fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> making announcements there. However, at
                <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 9:02-less than a minute</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was hit-an instruction
                over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX>'s public-address system advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, generally, that they
                could begin an orderly evacuation if conditions warranted. Like the earlier advice
                to remain in place, it did not correspond to any prewritten emergency
                    instruction.
            
            FDNY Initial Response
            Mobilization.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> response began within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five seconds</TIMEX> of the crash. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, many senior FDNY
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> most highly ranked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, as well
                as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> and many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> and assistants, had begun responding
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>. While en route over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brooklyn Bridge</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX> had a clear view of the situation on the
                upper floors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>. They determined that because of the fire's
                magnitude and location near the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, their mission would be
                primarily one of rescue. They called for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> alarm, which would bring additional
                engine and ladder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, as well as for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more elite rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. The Chief
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> arrived at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 9:00</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general FDNY Incident Command</ENAMEX> was transferred
                to his location on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Side</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Highway</ENAMEX>. In all, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commissioners</ENAMEX> arrived at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00</TIMEX>.
            
            As of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that were dispatched (including senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> responding to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>) included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 235</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>
                engine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> ladder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s elite rescue
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hazmat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad companies</ENAMEX>,
                and support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. In addition, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:53 nine</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> were staged on the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>-BatteryTunnel to await possible dispatch orders.
            
            Operations.
            
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">battalion chief</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ladder and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> engine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> arrived at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>
                at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 8:52</TIMEX>. As they entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, they encountered badly burned
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> who had been caught in the path of the fireball. Floor-to-ceiling windows
                in the northwest corner of the West Street level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> had been blown out;
                some large marble tiles had been dislodged from the walls; one entire elevator bank
                was destroyed by the fireball. Lights were functioning, however, and the air was
                clear of smoke.
            
            As the highest-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> on the scene, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">battalion chief</ENAMEX> initially was the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> incident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> later, the on-duty division <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> arrived and took over. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> immediately began speaking with the
                former fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and other building <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to learn whether building
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> were working. They were advised that all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>
                appeared to be out, and there were no assurances that sprinklers or standpipes were
                working on upper floors. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX> also spoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and
                an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>.
            
            After conferring with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, one engine and one ladder company
                began climbing stairwell C at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 8:57</TIMEX>, with the goal of approaching the impact
                zone as scouting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and reporting back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>. The radio
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> they used was tactical <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Following FDNY high-rise fire protocols, other
                units did not begin climbing immediately, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> worked to formulate a plan
                before sending them up. Units began mobilizing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, lining up and awaiting
                their marching orders.
            
            Also by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 8:57</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> had asked both building <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX>
                Authority police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> to evacuate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX>, because in their judgment the
                impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NorthTower</ENAMEX> made the entire complex unsafe-not because
                of concerns about a possible <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> in the increasingly crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> were confronting
                critical choices with little to no information. They had ordered units up the stairs
                to report back on conditions, but did not know what the impact floors were; they did
                not know if any stairwells into the impact zone were clear; and they did not know
                whether <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for firefighting would be available on the upper floors. They also did
                not know what the fire and impact zone looked like from the outside.
            
            They did know that the explosion had been large enough to send down a fireball that
                blew out <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> and windows in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> and that conditions were so dire that
                some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> on upper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> were jumping or falling from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. They also
                knew from building <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> were trapped in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> and on
                specific floors. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower Manhattan Peter Hayden</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
                had a very strong sense we would lose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> and that we were in deep trouble,
                but we had estimates of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000 to 50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, and we had to try to rescue
                    them."
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> concluded that this would be a rescue operation, not a firefighting
                operation. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> present explained: 
            
                We realized that, because of the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, that there was some
                    structural damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, and most likely that the fire suppres sion
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> were probably damaged and possibly inoperable. . . .
                    We knew that at the height of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
                    this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. We had a large volume of fire on the upper floors. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> was
                    <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> an acre in size. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Several</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> of fire would have been beyond the
                    fire-extinguishing capability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> that we had on hand. So we
                    determined, very early on, that this was going to be strictly a rescue mission.
                    We were going to vacate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, get everybody out, and then we were going
                    to get out.
                
            
            The specifics of the mission were harder to determine, as they had almost no
                information about the situation <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80 or more</NUMEX> stories above them. They also received
                advice from senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> might eventually suffer a
                partial collapse on upper floors, such structural failure was not imminent. No one
                anticipated the possibility of a total collapse.
            
            Emergency medical services (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> were directed to one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> triage areas
                being set up around the perimeter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>. Some entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> to respond to
                specific casualty reports. In addition, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramedics</ENAMEX> from private
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> were rushing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
            
            NYPD Initial Response
            Numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> strike the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> and immediately reported
                it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX>.
            
            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:58</TIMEX>, while en route, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> raised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>'s mobilization
                to level <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>, thereby sending to the WTC <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeants</ENAMEX>,
                and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> arrived at
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vesey</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>.
            
            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:01</TIMEX>, the NYPD patrol mobilization point was moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vesey</ENAMEX> in order to
                handle the greater number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrol officers</ENAMEX> dispatched in the higher-level
                mobilization. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> would be stationed around the perimeter of the complex
                to direct the evacuation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. Many were diverted on the way to the scene by
                intervening emergencies related to the attack.
            
            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:50</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> dispatched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> to
                report on conditions and assess the feasibility of a rooftop <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landing</ENAMEX> or of special
                rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. En route, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> communicated with air traffic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> at the area's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> and informed them of the commercial
                airplane crash at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>. The air traffic controllers had been
                unaware of the incident.
            
            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:56</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD ESU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> asked to be picked up at the Wall Street heliport to
                initiate rooftop rescues. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:58</TIMEX>, however, after assessing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> roof, a
                helicopter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> advised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that they could not land on the roof,
                because"it is too engulfed in flames and heavy smoke condition."
            
            By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> NYPD <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> was responding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> remained on the scene throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>, prepared to commence
                rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> on the roof if conditions improved. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> protocols
                called for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to be placed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> in the event of an
                attempted rooftop rescue at a high-rise fire. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> were placed in NYPD
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>.
            
            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX> were not advised that rooftop rescues were not
                being undertaken. They thus were not able to communicate this fact to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX>, some
                of whom spoke of attempting to climb to the roof.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> on-duty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> were on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:46</TIMEX>. They
                climbed to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">29th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> to evacuate, but did not locate a group
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> trapped on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">22nd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>.
            
            Just before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> began to walk from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vesey</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>
                lobby, with the goal of climbing toward and setting up a triage center on the upper
                floors for the severely injured. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> ESU <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> would follow them to assist in
                removing those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
            
            Numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> responded in order to help injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and to urge those who
                could walk to vacate the area immediately. Putting themselves in danger of falling
                debris, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plaza</ENAMEX> and successfully rescued at least one
                injured, nonambulatory civilian, and attempted to rescue others.
            
            Also by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 9:00</TIMEX>, transit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> began shutting down subway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in the
                vicinity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> and evacuating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> from those
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX>.
            
            Around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> cleared major thoroughfares for emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> to
                access the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPD</ENAMEX> coordinated the closing of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX>
                into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>.
            
            PAPD Initial Response
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX>'s on-site commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police officer</ENAMEX> was standing in the concourse
                when a fireball erupted out of elevator shafts and exploded onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall concourse</ENAMEX>,
                causing him to dive for cover. The on-duty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> initially instructed the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC Command</ENAMEX> to meet at the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>. Soon thereafter, he
                instructed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> arriving from outside commands to meet him at the fire safety
                desk in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>. A few of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> from outside commands were
                given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC Command</ENAMEX> radios.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> immediately began climbing stairwell C
                in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>.
            
            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> began performing rescue and evacuation operations on the ground floors
                and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PATH</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> Trans-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> below the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
            Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of impact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PATH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tunnels</ENAMEX>, and airport commands began responding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPD</ENAMEX> lacked written
                standard operating procedures for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> responding from outside commands to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> during a major incident. In addition, offi cers from some PAPD commands lacked
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interoperable</ENAMEX> radio frequencies. As a result, there was no comprehensive
                coordination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPD</ENAMEX>'s overall response.
            
            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, the PAPD commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> ordered an evacuation of all
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in the World <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trade Center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, because of the magnitude of the
                calamity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>. This order was given over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>,
                which could not be heard by the deputy fire safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX>.
            
            Also at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPD Superintendent</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> arrived separately and
                made their way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>.
            
            OEM Initial Response
            By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:48</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">23rd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> WTC-just to the north
                of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>-began to activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergency Operations Center</ENAMEX> by calling such
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDNY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Hospital</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> and instructing them to send their designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> to the
                asked to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least five</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Urban Search and Rescue Teams</ENAMEX> (such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are
                located throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 8:50</TIMEX>, a senior
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX> arrived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX> and began to act
                as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OEM</ENAMEX> field responder to the incident. He soon was joined by several other OEM
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>.
            
            Summary
            In the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17-minute</TIMEX> period <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 8:46 and 9:03 A.M.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority of New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> had mobilized the largest rescue
                operation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s history. Well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a thousand first responders</TIMEX> had been
                deployed, an evacuation had begun, and the critical decision that the fire could not
                be fought had been made.
            Then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> hit.
            From <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:03 until 9:59 A.M.</TIMEX>
            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:03:11</TIMEX>, the hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight 175 hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Tower</ENAMEX>) from
                the south, crashing through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 77th</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>. What had been the largest and
                most complicated rescue operation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">city</ENAMEX> history instantly doubled in magnitude.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> banked as it hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, leaving portions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> undamaged
                on impact floors. As a consequence-and in contrast to the situation in the
                NorthTower-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the stairwells (A) initially remained passable from at least the
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">91st</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> down, and likely from top to bottom.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Civilians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Safety Personnel</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> Calls
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Tower</ENAMEX>.
            
            At the lower end of the impact, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78th</NUMEX>-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sky lobby</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> had been waiting
                to evacuate when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> hit. Many had attempted but failed to squeeze into packed
                express <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX>. Upon impact, many were killed or severely injured; others were
                relatively unharmed. We know of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> who seized the initiative and
                shouted that anyone who could walk should walk to the stairs, and anyone who could
                help should help others in need of assistance. As a result, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> small
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> descended from that floor. Others remained on the floor to help
                the injured and move <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> who were unable to walk to the stairwell to aid their
                    rescue.
            
            Still others remained alive in the impact zone above the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">78th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>. Damage was
                extensive, and conditions were highly precarious. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> known to have
                escaped from the heart of the impact zone described the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">81st</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>-where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> had sliced through his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>-as a "demolition" site in which everything
                was "broken up" and the smell of jet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> was so strong that it was almost
                impossible to breathe. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> escaped by means of an unlikely rescue, aided by
                a civilian fire warden descending from a higher floor, who, critically, had been
                provided with a flashlight.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were able to descend stairwell A from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">81st</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> or above.
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> left the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">84th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> immediately after the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was hit. Even at that point,
                the stairway was dark, smoky, and difficult to navigate; glow strips on the stairs
                and handrails were a significant help. Several flights down, however, the evacuee
                became confused when he reached a smoke door that caused him to believe the stairway
                had ended. He was able to exit that stairwell and switch to another.
            
            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in and above the impact zone ascended the stairs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> small group
                reversed its descent down stairwell A after being advised by another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> that
                they were approaching a floor "in flames." The only known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> has told us that
                their intention was to exit the stairwell in search of clearer air. At the 91st
                floor, joined by others from intervening floors, they perceived themselves to be
                trapped in the stairwell and began descending again. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, the stairwell was
                "pretty black," intensifying smoke caused many to pass out, and fire had ignited in
                the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82nd</NUMEX>-floor transfer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>.
            
            Others ascended to attempt to reach the roof but were thwarted by locked doors. At
                <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30</NUMEX> a "lock release" order-which would unlock all areas in the
                complex controlled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>' computerized security system, including doors
                leading to the roofs-was transmitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Command Center</ENAMEX> located on the
                22nd floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>. Damage to the software controlling the system,
                resulting from the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, prevented this order from being
                    executed.
            
            Others, attempting to descend, were frustrated by jammed or locked doors in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stairwells</ENAMEX> or confused by the structure of the stairwell deviations. By the lower
                70s, however, stairwells A and B were well-lit, and conditions were generally
                    normal.
            
            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> remained on affected <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> ascended from a lower
                point into the impact zone, to help evacuate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> or assist the injured.
            
            Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> after the impact, debilitating smoke had reached at least one
                location on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">100th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, and severe smoke conditions were reported throughout
                floors in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s and 100s</TIMEX> over the course of the following <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30</TIMEX>, a
                number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> who had failed to reach the roof remained on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">105th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>,
                likely unable to descend because of intensifying smoke in the stairwell. There were
                reports of tremendous smoke on that floor, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> area remained less
                affected until shortly before the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> collapsed. There were several areas
                between the impact zone and the uppermost <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> where conditions were better. At
                least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> remained alive on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 88th</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>, in some cases
                calling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> for direction.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">911</ENAMEX> system remained plagued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>' lack of awareness of what was
                occurring. Just as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> from below and above the impact zone
                were advised to remain where they were and wait for help. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> were not
                given any information about the inability to conduct rooftop rescues and therefore
                could not advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> that they had essentially been ruled out. This lack of
                information, combined with the general advice to remain where they were, may have
                caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> above the impact not to attempt to descend, although stairwell A
                may have been passable.
            
            In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">911</ENAMEX> system struggled with the volume of calls and rigid standard
                operating procedures according to which calls conveying crucial information had to
                wait to be transferred to either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> or FDNY dispatch.
            
            According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> who was evacuating down stairwell A from the heart of the
                impact zone and who stopped on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">31st</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> in order to call <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX>, I told them when
                they answered the phone, where I was, that I had passed somebody on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">44th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>,
                injured-they need to get a medic and a stretcher to this floor, and described the
                situation in brief, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> then asked for my phone number, or something, and
                they said-they put me on hold. "You gotta talk to one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX>"-and
                suddenly I was on hold. And so I waited a considerable amount of time. Somebody else
                came back on the phone, I repeated the story. And then it happened again. I was on
                hold a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time, and needed to repeat the story for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time. But I told the
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that I am only telling you once. I am getting out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, here
                are the details, write it down, and do what you should do.
            
            Very few <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> calls were received from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> below the impact, but at least one
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was advised to remain on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">73rd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>'s protests that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> was running out. The last known <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">911</ENAMEX> call from this location came at
                    <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:52</TIMEX>.
            
            Evidence suggests that the public-address system did not continue to function after
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was hit. A group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trapped on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">97th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, however, made
                repeated references in calls to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> to having heard "announcements" to go down the
                stairs. Evacuation tones were heard in locations both above and below the impact
                    zone.
            
            By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:35</TIMEX>, the West Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SouthTower</ENAMEX> was becoming overwhelmed by
                injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had descended to the lobby but were having difficulty going on.
                Those who could continue were directed to exit north or east through the concourse
                and then out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
            
            By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:59</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> had descended from as high as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">91st</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> of that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tower</ENAMEX>, and stairwell A was reported to have been almost empty. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stairwell</ENAMEX> B was also
                reported to have contained only a handful of descending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> at an earlier
                point in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>. But just before the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> collapsed, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of NYPD ESU
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> encountered a stream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> descending an unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stairwell</ENAMEX> in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20s</TIMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> may have been descending from at or above the impact
                    zone.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Tower</ENAMEX>.
            
            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Tower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> continued their evacuation. On the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">91st</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, the
                highest floor with stairway access, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> but one were uninjured and able to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">descend</ENAMEX>. While some complained of smoke, heat, fumes, and crowding in the
                stairwells, conditions were otherwise fairly normal on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> below the impact. At
                least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> stairwell was reported to have been "clear and bright" from the upper 80s
                    down.
            
            Those who called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">911</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> below the impact were generally advised to remain in
                place. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> trapped on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">83rd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> pleaded repeatedly to know whether the
                fire was above or below them, specifically asking if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> had any
                information from the outside or from the news. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> were transferred back and
                forth several times and advised to stay put. Evidence suggests that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX>
                    died.
            
            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:59</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> police desk at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newark Airport</ENAMEX> told a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group of Port Authority</ENAMEX> civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">64th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> should evacuate. (The
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> was not at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTC</ENAMEX>, but had been in phone contact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> on the
                64th floor.) At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:10</TIMEX>, in response to an inquiry from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> themselves, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey City</ENAMEX> confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">64th</NUMEX> floor
                should "be careful, stay near the stairwells, and wait for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to come up."
