
    
        
            THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ATTACK LOOMS</ENAMEX>
            FIRST ARRIVALS IN <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CALIFORNIA</ENAMEX>
            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 5</ENAMEX> we described the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> travels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al</ENAMEX>
                Mihdhar, and others in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> operation." In
                that chapter we also described how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> was spotted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> early in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> who were not identified, and then was lost to
                sight when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> passed through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 15</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and Mihdhar
                arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. They spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks</TIMEX> there before moving on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>.
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two Weeks</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, we do not know for certain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Khalid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheikh</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX> (KSM), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> operation, explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> was
                a convenient point of entry from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and had the added benefit of being far away
                from the intended target area.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> were ill-prepared for a mission in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Their only
                qualifications for this plot were their devotion to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, their veteran
                service, and their ability to get valid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visas. Neither had spent any
                substantial time in the West, and neither spoke much, if any, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
            
            It would therefore be plausible that they or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> would have tried to identify, in
                advance, a friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> for them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In detention, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> denies
                that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> had any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>. We do not credit this
                denial<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>We believe it is unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>-neither of whom, in
                contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, had any prior exposure to life in the West-would have
                come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> without arranging to receive assistance from one or more
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> informed in advance of their arrival.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> says that though he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> involved in the conspiracy to stay away from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosques</ENAMEX> and to avoid establishing personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX>, he made an exception in this
                case and instructed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> to pose as newly arrived <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
                seek assistance at local mosques. He counted on their breaking off any such
                relationships once they moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>.
            
            Our inability to ascertain the activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> during their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> may reflect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> tradecraft designed to protect the
                identity of anyone who may have assisted them during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and Mihdhar
                were directed to enroll in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English-language</ENAMEX> classes upon arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, so that they could begin pilot training as soon as possible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> claims
                to have steered the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> on the basis of his own research, which
                supposedly included thumbing through a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> phone book acquired at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>
                flea market. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contradicting</ENAMEX> himself, he also says that, as instructed, they attempted
                to enroll in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>.
            
            After the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> cleared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Customs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Los Angeles International Airport</ENAMEX>,
                we do not know where they went<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>They appear to have obtained assistance from the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, specifically the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culver City</ENAMEX>, one of the most prominent mosques in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>.
            It is fairly certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> spent time at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> and
                made some acquaintances there. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> interviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> after the
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX> attacks has said he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> met the hijackers at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in early
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Furthermore, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would befriend them-a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohdar</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah-</ENAMEX>recalled a trip with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> when, on
                their arrival, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>. There Hazmi and Mihdhar
                greeted various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> whom they appeared to have met previously, including a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallam</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>'s telling, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallam</ENAMEX> visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al</ENAMEX> Qaeda
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> at their motel <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> was asked to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> so that
                Hazmi, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallam</ENAMEX> could meet in private. The identity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallam</ENAMEX> and his
                purpose in meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> remain unknown.
            
            To understand what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> did in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
                evidently staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, we have investigated whether anyone associated
                with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> assisted them. This subject has received substantial
                attention in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. Some have speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahad al Thumairy</ENAMEX>-an imam at the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosque</ENAMEX> and an accredited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi Arabian</ENAMEX> consulate from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> until
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003-</TIMEX>may have played a role in helping the hijackers establish themselves on their
                arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. This speculation is based, at least in part, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thumairy</ENAMEX>'s
                reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist faction</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>.
            
            A well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> and within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Muslim</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community, Thumairy</ENAMEX> was reputed to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> fundamentalist and a strict
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adherent</ENAMEX> to orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wahhabi</ENAMEX> doctrine. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> concerned about his preaching
                have said he "injected non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> themes into his guidance/prayers at the [King
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosque</ENAMEX>" and had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> "supportive of the events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>,
                    <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thumairy</ENAMEX> appears to have associated with a
                particularly radical faction within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of local worshippers, and had a
                network of contacts in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thumairy</ENAMEX>'s
                conduct was a subject of internal debate among some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. He apparently
                lost his position at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, possibly because of his immoderate
                reputation. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6, 2003</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thumairy</ENAMEX> attempted to reenter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> but was refused entry, based on a determination by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>
                that he might be connected with terrorist activity.
            
            When interviewed by both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thumairy</ENAMEX> has denied
                preaching anti-Western sermons, much less promoting violent jihad. More to the
                point, he claimed not to recognize either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hazmi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>. Both denials are
                somewhat suspect. (He likewise denied knowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar al Bayoumi</ENAMEX>-a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
                we will discuss shortly-even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and telephone records establish that
                the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had contact with each other. Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thumairy</ENAMEX>'s claim not to know
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohdar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> is belied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>'s contrary assertion.) On the other hand,
                Thumairy undoubtedly met with and provided religious counseling to countless
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> during his tenure at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, so he might not remember two
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">transients</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and Mihdhar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years later</TIMEX>.
            
            The circumstantial evidence makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thumairy</ENAMEX> a logical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to consider as a possible
                contact for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>. Yet, after exploring the available <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads</ENAMEX>, we have not
                found evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thumairy</ENAMEX> provided assistance to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>.
            
            We do not pick up their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1, 2000</TIMEX>, when they encountered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caysan Bin Don</ENAMEX> at a halal food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Venice Boulevard</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Culver</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, a few blocks away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Don</ENAMEX> have both
                told us that they had driven up from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> so that Bayoumi
                could address a visa issue and collect some papers from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> consulate. Bayoumi
                heard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and Mihdhar speaking in what he recognized to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> and struck
                up a conversation. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Don</ENAMEX> knew only a little <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, he had to rely heavily
                on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> to translate for him.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> said they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> who had just arrived in
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to study <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. They said they were living in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> near
                the restaurant but did not specify the address. They did not like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and
                were having a hard time, especially because they did not know anyone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> told
                them how pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> was and offered to help them settle there. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pairs
                then left the restaurant and went their separate ways.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Don</ENAMEX> have been interviewed many times about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1, 2000</TIMEX>,
                lunch. For the most part, their respective accounts corroborate each other. However,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> has said that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Don</ENAMEX> attempted to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> after
                lunch but could not find it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Don</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, recalls visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>
                twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> for prayers, both before and after the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Don</ENAMEX>'s recollection
                is spotty and inconsistent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi's</ENAMEX> version can be challenged as well, since the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosque</ENAMEX> is close to the restaurant and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> had visited it, and the surrounding
                area, on multiple occasions, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks of February 1</TIMEX>. We do
                not know whether the lunch encounter occurred by chance or design. We know about it
                because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> told law enforcement that it happened.
            
            Bayoumi, then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42 years old</TIMEX>, was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, supported
                by a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi Civil Aviation Authority</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> had
                worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 20 years</TIMEX>.
            
            The object of considerable media speculation following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, he lives now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>, well aware of his notoriety. Both we and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> have interviewed him and
                investigated evidence about him.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> is a devout <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, obliging and gregarious. He spent much of his spare time
                involved in religious study and helping run a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Cajon</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 15 miles</NUMEX>
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. It is certainly possible that he has dissembled about some aspects
                of his story, perhaps to counter suspicion. On the other hand, we have seen no
                credible evidence that he believed in violent extremism or knowingly aided extremist
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
            
            Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> who have dealt directly with him and studied his background find
                him to be an unlikely candidate for clandestine involvement with Islamist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>. The Move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> had come to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, possibly driven by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohdar Abdullah</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yemeni</ENAMEX>
                university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 20s</TIMEX>, is fluent in both <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and was
                perfectly suited to assist the hijackers in pursuing their mission.
            
            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> was interviewed many times by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. He admitted knowing of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist leanings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s involvement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
                Army <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">of Aden</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>) back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> clearly was
                sympathetic to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> views. During a post-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> search of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">possessions</ENAMEX>,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> found a notebook (belonging to someone else) with references to planes
                falling from the sky, mass killing, and hijacking. Further, when detained as a
                material <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9/11</TIMEX> attacks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> expressed hatred for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                government and "stated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> brought 'this' on themselves."
            
            When interviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> denied having advance knowledge of
                attacks. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2004</TIMEX>, however, we learned of reports about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> bragging to
                fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September- October 2003</TIMEX> that he had known
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> were planning a terrorist attack. The stories attributed to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> are not entirely consistent with each other. Specifically, according to one
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inmate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> claimed an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> had notified him that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> would be arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> with plans to carry out an attack. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>
                allegedly told the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> that he had driven the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, but did not say when this occurred. We have been unable to
                corroborate this account.
            
            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> has recalled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> claiming he first heard about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>'
                terrorist plans after they arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, when they told him they planned to
                fly an airplane into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and invited him to join them on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. According
                to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> also claimed to have found out about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> attacks three
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> in advance, a claim that appears to dovetail with evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> may
                have received a phone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> around that time, that he stopped making calls
                from his telephone after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 25, 2001</TIMEX>, and that, according to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, he
                started acting strangely.
            
            Although boasts among prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> often tend to be unreliable, this evidence is
                obviously important. To date, neither we nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> have been able to verify
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>'s alleged jailhouse statements, despite investigative efforts. We thus do
                not know when or how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> first came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. We do know that on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 4</TIMEX>, they went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Center of San Diego</ENAMEX> to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar al Bayoumi</ENAMEX> and
                take him up on his offer of help. Bayoumi obliged by not only locating an apartment
                but also helping them fill out the lease application, co-signing the lease and, when
                the real estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> refused to take cash for a deposit, helping them open a bank
                account (which they did with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9,900</NUMEX> deposit); he then provided a certified check
                from his own account for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> reimbursed him on the spot
                for the deposit. Neither then nor later did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> give money to either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hazmi</ENAMEX> or
                Mihdhar, who had received money from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> moved in with no furniture and practically no possessions. Soon
                after the move, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> used their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> for a party attended by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 20</NUMEX> male
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> community. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX>'s request, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Don</ENAMEX> videotaped the
                gathering with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi's</ENAMEX> video camera. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> did not mingle with the
                other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> and reportedly spent most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> by themselves off camera, in a
                back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> immediately started looking for a different place to stay. Based on
                their comment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> being expensive, one might infer
                that they wanted to save money. They may also have been reconsidering the wisdom of
                living so close to the video camera-wielding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayoumi</ENAMEX>, who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> seemed to think was
                some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just over a week</TIMEX> after moving in, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> filed a
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-day</TIMEX> notice of intention to vacate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayoumi</ENAMEX> apparently loaned them his cell phone
                to help them check out possibilities for new accommodations.
            
            Their initial effort to move turned out poorly. An acquaintance arranged with his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> take over his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> put down a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$650</NUMEX> deposit
                and signed a lease for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several weeks later</TIMEX>, Mihdhar
                sought a refund of his deposit, claiming he no longer intended to move in because
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> was too messy. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> refused to refund the deposit,
                Mihdhar became belligerent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> remembers him "ranting and raving" as if he
                were "psychotic."
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> finally found a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to rent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of an individual they had
                met at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX>, the future hijackers moved
                in on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10, 2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> moved out after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only about a month</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>, he left
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. Hazmi, on the other hand, stayed at this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for the
                rest of his time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-December</TIMEX>; he would then leave for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
                with a newly arrived <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker-pilot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX>.
            
            While in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> played the part of recently arrived foreign
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. They continued to reach out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> community for help.
                At least initially, they found well-meaning new acquaintances at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Center</ENAMEX>
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, which was only a stone's throw from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> where they first
                lived. For example, when they purchased a used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> (with cash), they bought it from
                a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who lived across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Center</ENAMEX> and who let them use his
                address in registering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>, an accommodation "to help a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>." Similarly, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, when their cash supply may have been dwindling, Hazmi
                persuaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Center</ENAMEX> to let him use the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>'s
                bank account to receive a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> wire transfer from someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubai</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emirates</ENAMEX> (this was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Abdul Aziz Ali</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and Mihdhar
                visited other mosques as well, mixing comfortably as devout worshippers. During the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>' critical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first weeks</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohdar Abdullah</ENAMEX> helped them.
                Translating between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, he assisted them in obtaining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX>'s licenses and with applying to language and flight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> also
                introduced them to his circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>; he shared an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> with some of those
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Mesa</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>'
                    residence.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> has emerged as a key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. Detained
                after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> as a material <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, then on immigration charges), he was
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> declined to prosecute him on charges arising out of his alleged
                jailhouse admissions concerning the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>
                declined to delay his removal pending further investigation of this new
                    information.
            
            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> also translated for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and helped them
                adjust to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. Some held <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> beliefs or were well acquainted
                with known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>. For example, immediately after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Awadallah</ENAMEX>, a
                Yemeni whose telephone number was found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hazmi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> Dulles
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Airport</ENAMEX>, was found to possess photos, videos, and articles relating to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Awadallah</ENAMEX> also had lived in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s fatwas
                and other similar materials were distributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Bakarbashat</ENAMEX>, a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>, also met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>. He admitted helping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hazmi</ENAMEX> to
                learn <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and taking over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> after
                they moved out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bakarbashat</ENAMEX> apparently had downloaded stridently <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> Web
                pages to his computer's hard drive.
            
            Another potentially significant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> contact for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anwar</ENAMEX>
                Aulaqi, an imam at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>. Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and thus a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>,
                Aulaqi grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> and studied in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yemeni</ENAMEX> government
                scholarship. We do not know how or when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> first met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aulaqi</ENAMEX>. The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> may even have met or at least talked to him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> they first moved
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> reportedly respected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aulaqi</ENAMEX> as a religious figure
                and developed a close relationship with him.
            
            When interviewed after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aulaqi</ENAMEX> said he did not recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX>'s name but did
                identify his picture. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aulaqi</ENAMEX> admitted meeting with Hazmi several times, he
                claimed not to remember any specifics of what they discussed. He described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> as
                a soft-spoken <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who used to appear at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> but
                who did not have a large circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aulaqi</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-2000</TIMEX>, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2001</TIMEX> had relocated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. As we
                will discuss later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> eventually showed up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aulaqi's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, an
                appearance that may not have been coincidental. We have been unable to learn enough
                about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aulaqi</ENAMEX>'s relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> to reach a conclusion.
            
            In sum, although the evidence is thin as to specific motivations, our overall
                impression is that soon after arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> sought out
                and found a group of young and ideologically like-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> with roots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> mainly associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohdar Abdullah</ENAMEX> and the Rabat
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mosque</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> lived openly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> under their true names,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">listing Hazmi</ENAMEX> in the telephone directory. They managed to avoid attracting much
                attention.
            Flight <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Training Fails</ENAMEX>; Mihdhar Bails Out
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to learn <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, take flying lessons,
                and become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> as quickly as possible. They turned out, however, to have no
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">aptitude</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>. Even with help and tutoring from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohdar Abdullah</ENAMEX> and other
                bilingual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s efforts to learn proved futile. This lack of
                language skills in turn became an insurmountable barrier to learning how to
                    fly.
            
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> they consulted at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> school, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorbi Flying Club</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, spoke
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>. He explained to them that their flight instruction would begin with small
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> emphasized their interest in learning to fly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX> in particular, and asked where they might enroll to train on jets right
                away. Convinced that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were either joking or dreaming, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> responded
                that no such school existed. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> who worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and Mihdhar
                remember them as poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who focused on learning to control the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> in
                flight but took no interest in takeoffs or landings. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of May 2000</TIMEX>, Hazmi
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> had given up on learning how to fly.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s mind seems to have been with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>, as evidenced by
                calls he made from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> telephone. When news of the birth of his first
                child arrived, he could stand life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> no longer. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and early
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June of 2000</TIMEX>, he closed his bank account, transferred the car registration to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX>,
                and arranged his return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> was bored in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
                and foresaw no problem in coming back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> since he had not
                overstayed his visa. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohdar Abdullah</ENAMEX> accompanied him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>. After visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last time with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, Mihdhar
                left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following day</TIMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> kept in fairly close touch with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>, using a variety of methods. When
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 2000</TIMEX>, KSM
                asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khallad</ENAMEX> (whom we introduced in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 5</ENAMEX>) to maintain email contact with Hazmi
                in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s decision to strand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> enraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>,
                who had not authorized the departure and feared it would compromise the plan. KSM
                attempted to drop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> operation and would have done so, he says,
                had he not been overruled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>.
            
            Following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s departure, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hazmi</ENAMEX> grew lonely and worried that he would have
                trouble managing by himself. He prayed with his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">housemate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each morning</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:00 A.M.</TIMEX>
                and attended services at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Center</ENAMEX>. He borrowed his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">housemate</ENAMEX>'s computer
                for Internet access, following news coverage of fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>.
                With his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">housemate</ENAMEX>'s help, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> also used the Internet to search for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (after
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obtaining KSM</ENAMEX>'s approval to marry). This search did not succeed. Although he
                developed a close relationship with his housemate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> preferred not to use the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">house</ENAMEX> telephone, continuing the practice he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> had adopted of going outside
                to make phone calls.
            
            After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> left, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> moved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of these, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yazeed al</ENAMEX>
                Salmi, stands out. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salmi</ENAMEX> purchased <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>'s checks at a
                bank in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riyadh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 5</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> deposited <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,900</NUMEX> of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traveler</ENAMEX>'s checks into his bank account, after withdrawing the same amount in cash.
                It is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> was simply cashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>'s checks for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. We
                do not know; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salmi</ENAMEX> claims not to remember the transaction. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, Salmi
                reportedly confided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohdar Abdullah</ENAMEX> that he had previously known terrorist pilot
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX>. After living in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX>, Salmi
                moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Mesa</ENAMEX> apartment shared by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> and others.
            
            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> no longer even pretended to study <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> or take flying
                lessons. Aware that his co-conspirators in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> would be sending
                him a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> shortly, he bided his time and worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> at a gas
                station in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Mesa</ENAMEX> where some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>, were employed. On
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> occasion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> told a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> that he was planning to find a better
                job, and let slip a prediction that he would become famous.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 8, 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, having traveled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubai</ENAMEX>
                via <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>. Hazmi likely picked up Hanjour at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. We do not
                know where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> stayed; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days later</TIMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. Before
                departing, they visited the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Mesa</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> reportedly
                introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hanjour</ENAMEX> as a "long time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> told his
                housemate that he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani</ENAMEX>" were headed for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> to take flying
                lessons and told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that he would stay in touch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> promised to return
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> soon, and he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> drove off.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> did not sever all contact with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>,
                after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX>, he telephoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> twice: in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> said he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and would be
                attending flight school there; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks later</TIMEX>, he said he was attending
                flight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>. Some evidence, which we will discuss later, indicates that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hazmi</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> again, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>. In addition, during the month
                following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX>'s departure from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, he emailed his housemate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times,
                including a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX> email that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> signed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smer</ENAMEX>," an apparent attempt to
                conceal his identity that struck the housemate as strange at the time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> also
                telephoned his housemate that he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> had decided to take flight lessons
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> was now back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. That was their last contact.
                When the housemate emailed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March of 2001</TIMEX> to find out how he
                was faring, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> did not reply.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housemate</ENAMEX> who rented the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> is an apparently
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">law-abiding citizen</ENAMEX> with long-standing, friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> among local police and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. He did not see anything unusual enough in the behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> or
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> to prompt him to report to his law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX>. Nor did those
                contacts ask him for information about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>/housemates.
            THE <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">PILOTS</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED STATES</ENAMEX>
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hamburg Pilots Arrive</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early summer of 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> arrived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to begin
                flight training. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marwan al Shehhi</ENAMEX> came on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29</TIMEX>, arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX> on a flight
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>. He went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and waited there for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed Atta</ENAMEX> to join
                him. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> traveled to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX> by bus from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and then
                flew from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> did not
                meet with anyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>; he simply believed it would contribute to operational
                security to fly out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX>, the departure point for much of
                his previous international travel.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> had not settled on where they would obtain their flight training. In
                contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ziad Jarrah</ENAMEX> had already arranged to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX> Flight Training
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> (FFTC) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27</TIMEX> and then flew
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>. He immediately began the private pilot program at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFTC</ENAMEX>, intending to get
                a multi-engine license. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> moved in with some of the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affiliated</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
            
            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> quickly settled into training in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> kept searching
                for a flight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. After visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airman Flight School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
                (where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zacarias Moussaoui</ENAMEX> would enroll <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months later</TIMEX> and where another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qaeda</ENAMEX> operative, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ihab Ali</ENAMEX>, had taken lessons in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid1990s</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> started flight
                instruction at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffman Aviation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and Shehhi
                subsequently enrolled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accelerated Pilot Program</ENAMEX> at that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, both of them took solo flights, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-August</TIMEX> they passed the private
                pilot airman test. They trained through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffman</ENAMEX>, while Jarrah
                continued his training at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFTC</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> paid for their flight training primarily with funds wired from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubai</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Abdul Aziz Ali</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between June 29 and September 17, 2000</TIMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$114,500</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> transfers ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>
                to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> relied on the unremarkable nature of his transactions, which were
                essentially invisible amid the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> flowing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> across the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">globe</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> was not required to provide identification in sending this money and the aliases
                he used were not questioned.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-September</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shehhi</ENAMEX> applied to change their immigration status from
                tourist to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, stating their intention to study at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffman</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, they decided to enroll at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones Aviation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 20 miles</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, the
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were aggressive, rude, and sometimes even fought with him to take over the
                controls during their training flights. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early October</TIMEX>, they took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stage</ENAMEX> I exam
                for instruments rating at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones Aviation</ENAMEX> and failed. Very upset, they said they were
                in a hurry because jobs awaited them at home. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> then returned to
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffman</ENAMEX>.
            
            In the meantime, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> obtained a single-engine private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> certificate in early
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. Having reached that milestone, he departed on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> foreign
                trips he would take after first entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, he flew back
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> to visit his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aysel Senguen</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> before
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 29</TIMEX>. His relationship with her remained close
                throughout his time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In addition to his trips, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> made
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of phone calls to her and communicated frequently by email.
            
            Jarrah was supposed to be joined at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFTC</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, who even sent the
                school a deposit. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> could not obtain a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa. His first
                applications in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2000</TIMEX> were denied because he lacked established ties in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> ensuring his return from a trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, he went
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> to apply for a visa from there, but was denied on grounds that he also
                lacked sufficient ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, he tried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last time, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>,
                applying for a student visa to attend "aviation language school," but the prior
                denials were noted and this application was denied as well, as incomplete.
            
            Unable to participate directly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> instead took on the role
                of coordinating between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Apart from
                sending a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $10,000</NUMEX> in wire transfers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> during the
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 2000</TIMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Binalshibh</ENAMEX>'s first tasks in his new role as plot coordinator
                was to assist another possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zacarias Moussaoui</ENAMEX>.
            
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>.
            
            Confronting training or travel problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi, Mihdhar, Binalshibh</ENAMEX>, and
                Moussaoui, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> was looking for another possible pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. A new recruit
                with just the right background conveniently presented himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth Pilot</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ta'if</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, first came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> to
                study at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for English</ENAMEX> as a Second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arizona</ENAMEX>.
                He seems to have been a rigorously observant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>. According to his older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hani Hanjour</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, as a
                teenager, to participate in the jihad and, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> had already
                withdrawn, worked for a relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> there.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to pursue flight training, after being
                rejected by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. He checked out flight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>; and he briefly started at a couple of them before returning
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, he returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and then, along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>,
                went back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> and began his flight training there in earnest. After about
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> was able to obtain his private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>'s license. Several more
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of training yielded him a commercial pilot certificate, issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1999</TIMEX>. He then returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> reportedly applied to the civil aviation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jeddah</ENAMEX> after returning
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, but was rejected. He stayed home for a while and then told his family he was
                going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Arab Emirates</ENAMEX> to work for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX>. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> actually
                traveled during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time</TIMEX> period is unknown. It is possible he went to the training
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
            
            The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> spent so much time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> may be significant. A number of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">important al Qaeda</ENAMEX> figures attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arizona</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tucson</ENAMEX> or lived in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucson</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX>.
            
            Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX>'s known <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> from the time of his flight training in
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX> have also raised suspicion.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> may have directed other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> area to enroll in aviation training. It is clear that when
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hanjour</ENAMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, he associated with several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
                holding extremist beliefs who have been the subject of counterterrorism
                investigations. Some of them trained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>. Others had apparent
                connections to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, including training in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
            
            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> was back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> was
                sent to him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX> for inclusion in the plot after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> was identified in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Faruq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> as a trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>, on the basis of background information he
                had provided. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> had been at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atef</ENAMEX> apparently realized that he was a trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>; he was told to report
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX>, who then trained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> in the use of code words.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 20</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> returned home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. He obtained a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> visa on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 25</TIMEX> and told his family he was returning to his job in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> did
                go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX>, but to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">facilitator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Abdul Aziz Ali</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> opened a bank account in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubai</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> and providing the initial funds for
                his trip. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 8</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. His supposed destination was
                an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, which he had
                scheduled before leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> but never attended. Instead, as mentioned
                earlier, he joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> almost immediately and drove to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>. Settling in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mesa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> began refresher training at his old school, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Aviation</ENAMEX>. He
                wanted to train on multi-engine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, but had difficulties because his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> was
                not good enough. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> advised him to discontinue but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> said he could
                not go home without completing the training. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2001</TIMEX>, he started training on a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">737</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulator</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am International Flight Academy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mesa</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX>
                there found his work well below standard and discouraged him from continuing. Again,
                Hanjour persevered; he completed the initial training by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of March 2001</TIMEX>. At
                that point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> vacated their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and started driving east,
                anticipating the arrival of the "muscle hijackers"-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> who would storm
                the cockpits and control the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as April 4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> and Hazmi
                had arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> continued with their training. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> finished
                up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffman</ENAMEX> and earned their instrument certificates from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. In
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-December 2000</TIMEX>, they passed their commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> tests and received their
                licenses. They then began training to fly large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> on a flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulator</ENAMEX>. At about
                the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> began simulator training, also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> but at a different
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2000</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than six months</TIMEX> after their arrival, the three
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> were simulating flights on large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>.
            
            Travels in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Early 2001</TIMEX>
            Jarrah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX>, having progressed in their training, all took foreign trips
                during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jarrah</ENAMEX> flew through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks later</TIMEX>, he returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aysel Senguen</ENAMEX>.
                She stayed with him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX>, even accompanying him to a flight
                training session. We do not know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> knew about
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX>'s trips and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senguen</ENAMEX>'s visit. The other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> had broken off regular
                contact with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of January 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> again flew to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX>, to visit his sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. After staying there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX>, Jarrah
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visited Senguen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> before returning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> at
                the end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>.
            
            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> took his personal trips, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>
                for a progress meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramzi Binalshibh</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> told him to
                report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> had
                completed their flight training and were awaiting orders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> also disclosed that a
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanjour</ENAMEX>, had joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX>. Upon returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> wired
                Binalshibh travel money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binalshibh</ENAMEX> proceeded to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, made his report, and
                spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next several months</TIMEX> there and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.
            
            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> left for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>, traveling to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Casablanca</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mid-January</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, concerned about not having heard from him, reported
                him missing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in turn contacted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> tried to find him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mosques</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX>'s last address in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX>. After learning that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was looking for
                him, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> telephoned them on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 20</TIMEX> and said he was still living and studying
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> then told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> they could call off the
                    search.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi both</ENAMEX> encountered some difficulty reentering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 10 and January 18</TIMEX>, respectively. Because neither presented a student visa,
                both of them had to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> that they should be admitted so that
                they could continue their flight training. Neither operative had any problem
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clearing Customs</ENAMEX>.
            
            After returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> from their trips, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, staying
                briefly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norcross</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Decatur</ENAMEX>, and renting a single-engine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> to fly with an
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instructor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lawrenceville</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 19</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. They
                rented a mailbox in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Beach</ENAMEX>, cashed a check, and then promptly returned to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>, staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Mountain</ENAMEX>. We have found no explanation for these travels.
                In mid-March, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> as well, staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Decatur</ENAMEX>. There is no
                evidence that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> met, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> apparently spoke on the
                phone. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> again and visited
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senguen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>. In early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> returned to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Beach</ENAMEX> and closed the mailbox they had opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>.
            
            By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Beach</ENAMEX> from their travels in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> had also arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls Church</ENAMEX>. They made their way
                to a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dar al Hijra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, sometime in early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>.
            
            As we mentioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, one of the imams at this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> was the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anwar Aulaqi</ENAMEX>
                with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> had spent time at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aulaqi</ENAMEX> had moved to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>. He remembers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> but has denied having
                any contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.
            
            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dar al Hijra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> met a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eyad al Rababah</ENAMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rababah</ENAMEX> says he had gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> to speak to the imam, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aulaqi</ENAMEX>, about finding
                work. At the conclusion of services, which normally had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400 to 500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rababah</ENAMEX> says he happened to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hazmi and Hanjour</ENAMEX>. They were looking for an
                apartment; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rababah</ENAMEX> referred them to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to rent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and Hanjour
                moved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, which was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>.
            
            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rababah</ENAMEX>'s story. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aulaqi</ENAMEX> may
                have tasked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rababah</ENAMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX>. We share that suspicion, given the
                remarkable coincidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aulaqi's</ENAMEX> prior relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX>. As noted above,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> was unable to locate and interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aulaqi</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rababah</ENAMEX> has been deported
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, having been convicted after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> in a fraudulent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license
                    scheme.
            
            Rababah, who had lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
                that he had recommended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paterson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, as a place with an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>-speaking
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> might want to settle. They asked for his help in
                getting them an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paterson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rababah</ENAMEX> tried without success. He says he
                then suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hanjour</ENAMEX> travel with him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> where they
                could look for a place to live.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 8</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rababah</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> to pick them up for the trip
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>. There he says he found them with new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Majed Moqed</ENAMEX>. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had been sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to serve as muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> and
                had arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dulles Airport</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rababah</ENAMEX> drove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanjour</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfield</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX>, who had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moqed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghamdi</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. After a short
                stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, where they apparently called area flight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and real
                estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rababah</ENAMEX> drove the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paterson</ENAMEX> to have dinner and show them
                around. He says that they returned with him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfield</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, and that he
                never saw them again.
            
            Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanjour, Hazmi</ENAMEX>, and several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paterson</ENAMEX>
                and rented a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. When their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> later paid a visit, he found
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> living there-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>, now joined by his younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem</ENAMEX>,
                Hanjour, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moqed</ENAMEX>, probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed al Ghamdi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Aziz al Omari</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX>'s old
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX> would soon join them.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> had already returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 11</TIMEX>, they moved into an
                apartment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coral Springs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, awaiting the arrival of the
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX>.
            
            Shehhi, on the other hand, bought a ticket to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> and flew there from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18</TIMEX>. We do not know much more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX>'s reason for traveling to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> than we know about his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> did meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who stated in a post-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> interview that Shehhi
                just wanted to pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license and some money. This
                story is not credible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> already had the license with him and presented it during
                a traffic stop on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> was still abroad. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> spent about two
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, obviously more time than would have been needed just to meet with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> could have traveled elsewhere during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, but no records
                indicating additional travel have been discovered.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehhi</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jarrah</ENAMEX> were together, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 30</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX> to the north, visiting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Motor Vehicles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lauderdale</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lakes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, to get <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s licenses. Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and
                Hanjour were about to leave for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. As the summer
                approached, the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> were settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, waiting for
                the rest of their contingent to join them.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASSEMBLING THE TEAMS</ENAMEX>
            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn of 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> started selecting the muscle hijackers-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> who would storm
                the cockpits and control the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. Despite the phrase widely used to describe
