
    
        
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COUNTERTERRORISM EVOLVES</ENAMEX>
            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 2</ENAMEX>, we described the growth of a new kind of terrorism, and a new terrorist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>-especially from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988 to 1998</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> declared war and
                organized the bombing of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, we trace the parallel
                evolution of government efforts to counter terrorism by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> against
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            We mention many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> in this report. As in any study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
                some of the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. We will introduce various
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, and how they adapted to a new kind of terrorism.
            FROM THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OLD TERRORISM</ENAMEX> TO THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEW</ENAMEX>: THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIRST WORLD TRADE CENTER</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOMBING</ENAMEX>
            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 minutes</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 26,1993</TIMEX>, a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> went off beneath the two
                towers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>. This was not a suicide attack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>
                parked a truck <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> with a timing device on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Level B-2</ENAMEX> of the underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>,
                then departed. The ensuing explosion opened a hole <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> stories up. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> people
                died. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than a thousand</NUMEX> were injured. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> at the scene described the
                relatively low number of fatalities as a miracle.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> ordered his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Council</ENAMEX> to coordinate the
                response. Government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> swung into action to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">culprits</ENAMEX>. The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> located at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> combed its files and queried sources
                around the world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>), the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>
                signals collection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, ramped up its communications intercept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and
                searched its databases for clues.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Field Office of the FBI</ENAMEX> took control of the local investigation and, in
                the end, set a pattern for future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of terrorist incidents.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> features of this episode have significance for the story of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>. First, the
                bombing signaled a new terrorist challenge, one whose rage and malice had no limit.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> who planted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, said later that he had hoped
                to kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> did excellent work investigating the
                bombing. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> identified a truck remnant as part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX> rental
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van</ENAMEX> reported stolen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey City</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before the bombing.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Salameh</ENAMEX>, who had rented the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and reported it stolen, kept calling the
                rental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to get back his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> deposit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> arrested him there on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. In short order, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> had several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plotters</ENAMEX> in custody, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nidal</ENAMEX>
                Ayyad, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> who had acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahmoud Abouhalima</ENAMEX>,
                who had helped mix the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> identified another conspirator, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmad Ajaj</ENAMEX>, who had been arrested by
                and charged with document fraud. His traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX>, who had
                also entered with fraudulent documents but claimed political asylum and was
                admitted. It quickly became clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> had been a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the
                attack. He had fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> immediately after the bombing and would remain at
                large for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly two years</TIMEX>.
            
            The arrests of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salameh, Abouhalima</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayyad</ENAMEX> led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farouq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, where a central figure was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sheikh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Abdel Rahman</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> Sunni
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cleric</ENAMEX> who had moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. In speeches and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">writings</ENAMEX>, the sightless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahman</ENAMEX>, often called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Sheikh</ENAMEX>," preached the
                message of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sayyid Qutb's Milestones</ENAMEX>, characterizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as the
                oppressor of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> worldwide and asserting that it was their religious duty to
                fight against God's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> informant learned of a plan to bomb major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> landmarks, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX>. Disrupting this
                "landmarks plot," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1993</TIMEX> arrested <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rahman</ENAMEX> and various
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confederates</ENAMEX>.
            
            As a result of the investigations and arrests, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
                District of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> prosecuted and convicted multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ajaj</ENAMEX>,
                Salameh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayyad, Abouhalima, the Blind Sheikh</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX>, for crimes related
                to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bombing and other plots. An unfortunate consequence of
                this superb investigative and prosecutorial effort was that it created an impression
                that the law enforcement system was well-equipped to cope with terrorism. Neither
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, his principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, nor the news media felt
                prompted, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, to press the question of whether the procedures that put the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blind Sheikh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> behind bars would really protect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> against the
                new virus of which these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were just the first symptoms.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the successful use of the legal system to address the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>
                bombing had the side effect of obscuring the need to examine the character and
                extent of the new threat facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The trials did not bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                Ladin network to the attention of the public and policymakers.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> assembled, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> put forward, some evidence showing
                that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> were not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plotters</ENAMEX>. Materials taken from Ajaj
                indicated that the plot or plots were hatched at or near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khaldan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, a
                terrorist training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> border. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajaj</ENAMEX> had left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1992</TIMEX> to go there to learn how to construct bombs. He had met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, where they discussed bombing targets in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and assembled a
                "terrorist kit" that included <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-making manuals, operations guidance, videotapes
                advocating terrorist action against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and false identification
                    documents.
            
            Yousef was captured in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> following the discovery by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>
                in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1995</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air plot, which envisioned placing bombs on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> a
                dozen <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">trans-Pacific</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX> and setting them off simultaneously. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Khalid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheikh</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed-Yousef</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, then located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qatar</ENAMEX>-was a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plotter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef 's</ENAMEX> in
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air plot and had also wired him some money prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trade Center</ENAMEX>
                bombing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> obtained an indictment against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSM</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1996</TIMEX>, but
                an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qatar</ENAMEX> probably warned him about it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Khalid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheikh</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX> evaded capture (and stayed at large to play a central part in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9/11</TIMEX>
                attacks)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> The law enforcement process is concerned with proving the guilt of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons apprehended</ENAMEX> and charged. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> could not present all
                the evidence of possible involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> other than those charged,
                although they continued to pursue such investigations, planning or hoping for later
                prosecutions. The process was meant, by its nature, to mark for the public the
                events as finished-case solved, justice done. It was not designed to ask if the
                events might be harbingers of worse to come. Nor did it allow for aggregating and
                analyzing facts to see if they could provide clues to terrorist tactics more
                generally-methods of entry and finance, and mode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, although the bombing heightened awareness of a new terrorist danger,
                successful prosecutions contributed to widespread underestimation of the threat. The
                government's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> stressed the seriousness of the crimes, and put forward
                evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yousef</ENAMEX> 's technical ingenuity. Yet the public image that persisted was
                not of clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> but of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salameh</ENAMEX> going back again and again to reclaim his
                <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> truck rental deposit.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ADAPTATION-AND NONADAPTATION-IN THE LAW ENFORCEMENT COMMUNITY</ENAMEX>
            Legal processes were the primary method for responding to these early manifestations
                of a new type of terrorism. Our overview of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> capabilities for dealing with it
                thus begins with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s vast complex of law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> At the federal level, much law enforcement
                activity is concentrated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>. For countering terrorism, the
                dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Bureau of Investigation</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> does
                not have a general grant of authority but instead works under specific statutory
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authorizations</ENAMEX>. Most of its work is done in local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> called field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.
                There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> of them, each covering a specified geographic area, and each quite
                separate from all others. Prior to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in charge was in general
                free to set his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s priorities and assign personnel accordingly.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s priorities were driven by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. First, performance in
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> was generally measured against statistics such as numbers of arrests,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indictments</ENAMEX>, prosecutions, and convictions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Counterterrorism</ENAMEX> and counterintelligence
                work, often involving lengthy intelligence investigations that might never have
                positive or quantifiable results, was not career-enhancing. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who reached
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management ranks</ENAMEX> had little counterterrorism experience. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, priorities were
                driven at the local level by the field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> centered on
                traditional crimes such as white-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenses</ENAMEX> and those pertaining to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>. Individual field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> made choices to serve local priorities, not national
                    priorities.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> also operates under an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of origin" system. To avoid duplication and
                possible conflicts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> designates a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to be in charge of an entire
                investigation. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Field Office</ENAMEX> indicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> prior to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Africa</ENAMEX> bombings, it became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of origin for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> cases,
                including the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Africa</ENAMEX> bombings and later the attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Cole</ENAMEX>. Most of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s institutional knowledge on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> resided there. This office
                identify, arrest, prosecute, and convict many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> of the attacks and
                plots. Field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> other than the specified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of origin were often reluctant
                to spend much energy on matters over which they had no control and for which they
                received no credit.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s domestic intelligence gathering dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
                looming, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Roosevelt</ENAMEX> ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX> to
                investigate foreign and foreign-inspired subversion-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX> added investigation of possible espionage, sabotage, or subversion to the
                duties of field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. After the war, foreign intelligence duties were assigned to
                the newly established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX>. Hoover jealously guarded the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s domestic portfolio against all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX> felt he was accountable only to
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s domestic intelligence activities kept growing. In the
                1960s, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> was receiving significant assistance within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Intelligence</ENAMEX>. The legal basis for some of this assistance was
                dubious.
            Decades of encouragement to perform as a domestic intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> abruptly ended
                in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoover</ENAMEX>'s death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, congresCOUNTERTERRORISM
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sional</ENAMEX> and news media investigations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> scandals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon</ENAMEX>
                administration expanded into general investigations of foreign and domestic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>.
            
            They disclosed domestic intelligence efforts, which included a covert action program
                that operated from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956 to 1971</TIMEX> against domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and, eventually,
                domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had spied on a wide range of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>,
                especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX> wanted to discredit (notably the Reverend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther King, Jr.</ENAMEX>), and had authorized unlawful wiretaps and surveillance. The shock
                registered in public opinion polls, where the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> declaring a
                "highly favorable" view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84 percent to 37 percent</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s
                Domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Division</ENAMEX> was dissolved.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Levi</ENAMEX> adopted domestic security guidelines to
                regulate intelligence collection in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and to deflect calls for even
                stronger regulation. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William French Smith</ENAMEX> revised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>
                guidelines to encourage closer investigation of potential terrorism. He also
                loosened the rules governing authorization for investigations and their duration.
                Still, his guidelines, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi's</ENAMEX>, took account of the reality that suspicion of
                "terrorism," like suspicion of "subversion," could lead to making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
                targets for investigation more because of their beliefs than because of their acts.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s guidelines also took account of the reality that potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> were
                often <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and that investigation of
                terrorism could cross the line separating state and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> authorized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> to investigate terrorist attacks against
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> that occur outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years later</TIMEX>, it added
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> to make arrests abroad without consent from the host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
                Meanwhile, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George H.W. Bush</ENAMEX> had endorsed a
                concept already urged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Casey</ENAMEX>-a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> could work
                together on international terrorism. While it was distinctly a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                detailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> and obtained leads that helped in the
                capture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> wanted for trial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            The strengths that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> brought to counterterrorism were nowhere more brilliantly
                on display than in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan American</ENAMEX> Flight 103, bound from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, which blew up over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lockerbie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1988</TIMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
                Initial evidence pointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and, later, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> reserved judgment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> of the attack.
                Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX>, working with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> security services, gathered and
                analyzed the widely scattered fragments of the airliner. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, with the help of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX>, they identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> small fragment as part of a timing
                device-to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX>, as distinctive as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. It was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> device. Together
                with other evidence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> put together a case pointing conclusively to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX>
                government. Eventually <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> acknowledged its responsibility.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103</NUMEX> became a cautionary tale against rushing to judgment in attributing
                responsibility for a terrorist act. It also showed again how-given a case to
                solve-the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> remained capable of extraordinary investigative success.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI Organization</ENAMEX> and Priorities In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX> as the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>. Freeh, who would remain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX>, believed
                that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s work should be done primarily by the field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. To emphasize this
                view he cut headquarters <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and decentralized operations. The special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in
                charge gained power, influence, and independence.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX> recognized terrorism as a major threat. He increased the number of legal
                attach� <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> abroad, focusing in particular on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. He also urged
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> not to wait for terrorist acts to occur before taking action. In his first
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> request to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bombing, he stated that
                "merely solving this type of crime is not enough; it is equally important that the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> thwart terrorism before such acts can be perpetrated." Within <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, he
                created a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Division</ENAMEX> that would complement the Counterterrorist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and arranged for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> of senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> counterterrorism
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. He pressed for more cooperation between legal attach�s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> stations
                    abroad.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX>'s efforts did not, however, translate into a significant shift of resources to
                counterterrorism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said
                that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> seemed unwilling to shift resources to terrorism from other
                areas such as violent crime and drug enforcement; other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> blamed
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for a lack of political will and failure to understand the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s counterterrorism resource needs. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> did not impose his views
                on the field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. With a few notable exceptions, the field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> did not apply
                significant resources to terrorism and often reprogrammed funds for other
                    priorities.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> issued a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> strategic plan led by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bear</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> designated national and economic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>, including counterterrorism, as its top priority. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Watson</ENAMEX>, who would
                later become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Division</ENAMEX>, said that after the East
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa</ENAMEX> bombings,"the light came on" that cultural change had to occur within the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. The plan mandated a stronger intelligence collection effort. It called for a
                nationwide automated system to facilitate information collection, analysis, and
                dissemination. It envisioned the creation of a professional intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadre</ENAMEX> of
                experienced and trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. If successfully implemented, this would
                have been a major step toward addressing terrorism systematically, rather than as
                individual unrelated cases. But the plan did not succeed.
            
            First, the plan did not obtain the necessary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human resources</ENAMEX>. Despite
                desCOUNTERTERRORISM
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ignating</ENAMEX> "national and economic security" as its top priority in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> did
                not shift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human resources</ENAMEX> accordingly. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s counterterrorism budget
                tripled during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> counterterrorism spending remained fairly constant
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between fiscal years 1998 and 2001</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, there were still twice as many agents
                devoted to drug enforcement as to counterterrorism.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> intended to strengthen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s strategic analysis
                capability faltered. It received insufficient resources and faced resistance from
                senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s operational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> was supposed to
                identify trends in terrorist activity, determine what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> did not know, and
                ultimately drive collection efforts. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had little appreciation for
                the role of analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> continued to be used primarily in a tactical
                fashion-providing support for existing cases. Compounding the problem was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s
                tradition of hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> from within instead of recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with the
                relevant educational background and expertise.
            
            Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> had difficulty getting access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and intelligence
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> information they were expected to analyze. The poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s
                information systems meant that such access depended in large part on an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>'s
                personal relationships with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in the operational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squads</ENAMEX> where the
                information resided. For all of these reasons, prior to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> relatively few
                strategic analytic reports about counterterrorism had been completed. Indeed, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had never completed an assessment of the overall terrorist threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">homeland</ENAMEX>.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> did not have an effective intelligence collection effort. Collection
                of intelligence from human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> was limited, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were inadequately
                trained. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only three days</TIMEX> of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> were devoted to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterintelligence</ENAMEX> and counterterrorism, and most subsequent training was received
                on the job. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> did not have an adequate mechanism for validating source
                reporting, nor did it have a system for adequately tracking and sharing source
                reporting, either internally or externally. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> did not dedicate sufficient
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to the surveillance and translation needs of counterterrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. It
                lacked sufficient translators proficient in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> and other key languages,
                resulting in a significant backlog of untranslated intercepts.
            
            Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s information systems were woefully inadequate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> lacked the
                ability to know what it knew: there was no effective mechanism for capturing or
                sharing its institutional knowledge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> did create records of interviews and
                other investigative efforts, but there were no reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to condense the
                information into meaningful intelligence that could be retrieved and
                    disseminated.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> created separate Counterterrorism and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterintelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Watson</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Division</ENAMEX>, recognized the
                urgent need to increase the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s counterterrorism capability. His plan, called
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAXCAP</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">05</TIMEX>, was unveiled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>: it set the goal of bringing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> to its
                "maximum feasible capacity" in counterterrorism by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. Field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> told
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX> that they did not have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>, linguists, or technically trained
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to carry out the strategy. In a report provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mueller</ENAMEX>
                in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2001</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> presented his plan to field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>,
                almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was assessed to be operating below "maximum capacity."
                The report stated that "the goal to 'prevent terrorism' requires a dramatic shift in
                emphasis from a reactive capability to highly functioning intelligence capability
                which provides not only leads and operational support, but clear strategic analysis
                and direction."
            
            Legal Constraints on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Wall" The FBI</ENAMEX> had different tools for law
                enforcement and intelligence.
            
            For criminal matters, it could apply for and use traditional criminal warrants. For
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> matters involving international terrorism, however, the rules were
                different. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> could authorize surveillance of
                foreign powers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> without any court review, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Intelligence Surveillance</ENAMEX> Act<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.29</NUMEX>This law regulated
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> collection directed at foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> in
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In addition to requiring court review of proposed surveillance
                (and later, physical searches), the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> act was interpreted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to
                require that a search be approved only if its "primary purpose" was to obtain
                foreign intelligence information. In other words, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> law
                could not be used to circumvent traditional criminal warrant requirements. The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> interpreted these rulings as saying that criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
                could be briefed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> information but could not direct or control its
                    collection.
            
            Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> had informal arrangements
                for obtaining information gathered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> process, the understanding being that
                they would not improperly exploit that process for their criminal cases. Whether the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> shared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> information pertinent to possible criminal
                investigations was left solely to the judgment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>.
            
            But the prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich Ames</ENAMEX> for espionage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> revived concerns about the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' role in intelligence investigations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Policy and Review</ENAMEX> (OIPR) is responsible for reviewing and presenting
                all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> applications to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA Court</ENAMEX>. It worried that because of the numerous
                prior consultations between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> might rule that
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> warrants had been misused. If that had happened, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> might have escaped
                conviction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Scruggs</ENAMEX>, the acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIPR</ENAMEX>, complained to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attorney General</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> about the lack of information-sharing controls. On his own, he began
                imposing informationsharing procedures for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> material. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                Policy and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> became the gatekeeper for the flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> information to criminal
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> issued formal procedures aimed at managing
                information sharing between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. They were
                developed in a working <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> led by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Office of</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX>, overseen by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Gorelick</ENAMEX>.
            
            These procedures-while requiring the sharing of intelligence information with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>-regulated the manner in which such information could be shared from the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to the criminal side.
            These procedures were almost immediately misunderstood and misapplied. As a result,
                there was far less information sharing and coordination between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Division</ENAMEX> in practice than was allowed under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s procedures.
                Over time the procedures came to be referred to as "the wall." The term "the wall"
                is misleading, however, because several factors led to a series of barriers to
                information sharing that developed.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Intelligence Policy and Review</ENAMEX> became the sole gatekeeper for passing
                information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Division</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s procedures did
                not include such a provision, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> assumed the role anyway, arguing that its
                position reflected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royce Lamberth</ENAMEX>, then chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> threatened that if it could not
                regulate the flow of information to criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, it would no longer present
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s warrant requests to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA Court</ENAMEX>. The information flow withered.
            
            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> procedures dealt only with sharing between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>,
                not between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, those working on intelligence matters and those
                working on criminal matters. But pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Intelligence Policy</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA Court</ENAMEX> built barriers between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>-even agents
                serving on the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squads</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> reinforced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>'s
                caution by informing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> that too much information sharing could be a career
                stopper. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Agents</ENAMEX> in the field began to believe-incorrectly-that no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> information
                could be shared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> working on criminal investigations.
            
            This perception evolved into the still more exaggerated belief that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> could not
                share any intelligence information with criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, even if no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX>
                procedures had been used. Thus, relevant information from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> often failed to make its way to criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. Separate
                reviews in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999, 2000</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> concluded independently that information sharing was
                not occurring, and that the intent of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> procedures was ignored
                    routinely.
            
            We will describe some of the unfortunate consequences of these accumulated
                institutional beliefs and practices in chapter 8.
            There were other legal limitations. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> argued that they
                were barred by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> rules from sharing grand jury information, even though the
                prohibition applied only to that small fraction that had been presented to a grand
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>, and even that prohibition had exceptions. But as interpreted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> field
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, this prohibition could conceivably apply to much of the information
                unearthed in an investigation. There were also restrictions, arising from executive
                order, on the commingling of domestic information with foreign intelligence. Finally
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> began putting caveats on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>-related reports that required prior
                approval before sharing their contents with criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>.
                These developments further blocked the arteries of information sharing.
            
            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Enforcement Agencies The Justice Department</ENAMEX> is much more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. It
                also has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Marshals Service</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 4,000</NUMEX> strong on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> and especially expert
                in tracking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fugitives</ENAMEX>, with much local police knowledge. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enforcement Administration</ENAMEX> had, as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 4,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.
            
            There were a number of occasions when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were able to introduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> for counterterrorism use.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> immigration special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, had perhaps the
                greatest potential to develop an expanded role in counterterrorism. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>
                was focused on the formidable challenges posed by illegal entry over the southwest
                border, criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, and a growing backlog in the applications for naturalizing
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, and above all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
                reinforced these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. In addition, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Meissner</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS Commissioner</ENAMEX>
                in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, she found an agency seriously hampered by outdated technology and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insufficient human resources</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were still using manual
                typewriters; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> of entry were using a paper watchlist; the asylum
                and other benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> did not effectively deter fraudulent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meissner</ENAMEX> responded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bombing by
                providing seed money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consular Affairs Bureau</ENAMEX> to automate
                its terrorist watchlist, used by consular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and border <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>
                assigned an individual in a new "lookout" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> to work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">watchlisting</ENAMEX> suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and with the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> in
                determining how to deal with them when they appeared at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> of entry. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suspected</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> had been denied admission at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> of entry because of the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">watchlist</ENAMEX>.
            
            How to conduct deportation cases against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who were suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> caused
                significant debate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> had immigration law expertise and authority to bring the
                cases, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> possessed the classified information sometimes needed as
                evidence, and information-sharing conflicts resulted. New laws in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> authorized
                the use of classified evidence in removal hearings, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> removed only a
                handful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> with links to terrorist activity (none identified as
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>) using classified evidence.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midlevel INS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> proposed comprehensive counterterrorism proCOUNTERTERRORISM
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">posals</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986, 1995</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. No action was taken on them. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> was set up to handle alerts, track potential terrorist cases
                for possible immigration enforcement action, and work with the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>. It focused on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s priorities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>, and began to
                examine how immigration laws could be brought to bear on terrorism. For instance, it
                sought unsuccessfully to require that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> security checks be completed before
                naturalization applications were approved.
            
            Policy questions, such as whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> alien status should be revoked upon the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s conviction of a terrorist crime, were not addressed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, with the
                support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, doubled the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX> agents
                required along the border with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every quarter</TIMEX> mile by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. It
                rejected efforts to bring additional resources to bear in the north. The border with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> for every <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13.25 miles</NUMEX>. Despite examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> entering
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, awareness of terrorist activity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and its more lenient
                immigration laws, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector general</ENAMEX>'s report recommending that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border</ENAMEX>
                Patrol develop a northern border strategy, the only positive step was that the
                number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> was not cut any further.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspectors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> of entry were not asked to focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. Inspectors
                told us they were not even aware that when they checked the names of incoming
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> against the automated watchlist, they were checking in part for
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. In general, border <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> also did not have the information they
                needed to make fact-based determinations of admissibility. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> initiated but
                failed to bring to completion <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> efforts that would have provided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> with
                information relevant to counterterrorism-a proposed system to track foreign student
                visa compliance and a program to establish a way of tracking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>' entry to and
                exit from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, a new law enabled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> to enter into agreements with state and local law
                enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> through which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> provided training and the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
                exercised immigration enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. Terrorist watchlists were not available
                to them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> with large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant populations</ENAMEX> sometimes imposed limits
                on city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> cooperation with federal immigration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. A large population
                lives outside the legal framework. Fraudulent documents could be easily obtained.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> kept the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> static in the face of the overwhelming
                    problem.
            
            The chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> and for state and local participation in law enforcement
                was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Terrorism Task Force</ENAMEX> (JTTF), first tried out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>
                in response to a spate of incidents involving domestic terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. This
                task <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> was managed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Field Office of the FBI</ENAMEX>, and its existence
                provided an opportunity to exchange information and, as happened after the first
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bombing, to enlist local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, as well as other agency
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> expanded the number
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">JTTFs</ENAMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>. While useful, the JTTFs
                had limitations. They set priorities in accordance with regional and field office
                concerns, and most were not fully staffed. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> believed
                they had little to gain from having a full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JTTF</ENAMEX>.
            
            Other federal law enforcement resources, also not seriously enlisted for
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counterterrorism</ENAMEX>, were to be found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> housed the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco</ENAMEX>, and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firearms</ENAMEX>. Given the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>'s mission to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and other high
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> did become involved with those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> whenever terrorist
                assassination plots were rumored. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX> deployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> at all points
                of entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> worked alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, and the two
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> sometimes cooperated. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter of 1999-2000</TIMEX>, as will be detailed in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 6</ENAMEX>, questioning by an especially alert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> led to the arrest of
                an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> whose apparent mission was to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport</ENAMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATF</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> and analysis were critical to the investigation of
            
            Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, with the exception of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, very little of the
                sprawling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> was engaged in countering terrorism.
                Moreover, law enforcement could be effective only after specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were
                identified, a plot had formed, or an attack had already occurred. Responsible
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> had to be located, apprehended, and transported back to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for
                prosecution. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> emphasized to us, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> do
                not have cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. They declare war by indicting someone. They took on the
                lead role in addressing terrorism because they were asked to do so.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>) within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Transportation</ENAMEX> had
                been vested by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> with the sometimes conflicting mandate of regulating the
                safety and security of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> civil aviation while also promoting the civil aviation
                industry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> had a security mission to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of commercial air
                transportation against terrorism and other criminal acts. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years before 9/11</TIMEX>,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> perceived sabotage as a greater threat to aviation than hijacking. First, no
                domestic hijacking had occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the commercial aviation system
                was perceived as more vulnerable to explosives than to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> such as firearms.
                Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> were perceived as deadlier than hijacking and therefore of
                greater consequence. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> on aviation safety and
                security chaired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> reinforced the prevailing concern about
                sabotage and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gore Commission</ENAMEX> also flagged, as a new
                danger, the possibility of attack by surface-to-air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. Its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 final</TIMEX> report
                did not discuss the possibility of suicide hijackings.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> set and enforced aviation security rules, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> were
                required to implement. The rules were supposed to produce a "layered" system of
                defense. This meant that the failure of any one layer of security would not be
                fatal, because additional layers would provide backup security. But each layer
                and onboard security-was seriously flawed prior to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>. Taken together, they did
                not stop any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> hijackers from getting on board <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> at
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s policy was to use intelligence to identify both specific plots and general
                threats to civil aviation security, so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> could develop and deploy
                appropriate countermeasures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>-person intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> was supposed to
                receive a broad range of intelligence data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> so
                that it could make assessments about the threat to aviation. But the large volume of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> contained little pertaining to the presence and activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. For example, information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s effort in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> to assess the
                potential use of flight training by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX> electronic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">communication of 2001</ENAMEX> warning of radical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Easterners</ENAMEX> attending flight school
                were not passed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. Several top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> called
                the domestic threat picture a serious blind spot.
            
            Moreover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> did not receive much attention from the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Garvey</ENAMEX> nor her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX> routinely
                reviewed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> intelligence, and what they did see was screened for them. She was
                unaware of a great amount of hijacking threat information from her own intelligence
                unit, which, in turn, was not deeply involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s policymaking process.
                Historically, decisive security action took place only after a disaster had occurred
                or a specific plot had been discovered.
            
            The next aviation security layer was passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">prescreening</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> directed air
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> not to fly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> known to pose a "direct" threat to civil aviation.
                But as of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s "no-fly" list contained the names of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 12</NUMEX> terrorist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suspects</ENAMEX> (including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mastermind Khalid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sheikh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX>), even though government
                watchlists contained the names of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> of known and suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>.
                This astonishing mismatch existed despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gore Commission</ENAMEX>'s having called on the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years earlier</TIMEX> to provide terrorist watchlists to improve
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prescreening</ENAMEX>. The longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s civil aviation security division
                testified that he was not even aware of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'sTIPOFF list of known
                and suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 60,000</NUMEX> before <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>) until he heard it mentioned
                during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 26, 2004</TIMEX>, public hearing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> had access to some
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIPOFF</ENAMEX> data, but apparently found it too difficult to use.
            
            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of prescreening called on the air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to implement an
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>-approved computerized algorithm (known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Assisted Passenger</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prescreening System</ENAMEX>) designed to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> whose profile suggested they
                might pose more than a minimal risk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. Although the algorithm included
                hijacker profile data, at that time only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> checking bags were eligible to
                be selected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX> for additional scrutiny. Selection entailed only having one's
                checked baggage screened for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> or held off the airplane until one had
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boarded</ENAMEX>. Primarily because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> regarding potential discrimination and the
                impact on passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">throughput</ENAMEX>, "selectees" were no longer required to undergo
                extraordinary screening of their carry-on baggage as had been the case before the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> was computerized in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1997.55</NUMEX> This policy change also reflected the perception
                that nonsuicide sabotage was the primary threat to civil aviation.
            Checkpoint screening was considered the most important and obvious layer of security.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walk-through</ENAMEX> metal detectors and X-ray machines operated by trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screeners</ENAMEX> were
                employed to stop prohibited items. Numerous government reports indicated that
                checkpoints performed poorly, often failing to detect even obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> test items.
                Many deadly and dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">items</ENAMEX> did not set off metal detectors, or were hard to
                distinguish in an X-ray machine from innocent everyday items.
            
            While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> rules did not expressly prohibit knives with blades under <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 inches</NUMEX> long,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>' checkpoint operations guide (which was developed in cooperation with
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>), explicitly permitted them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s basis for this policy was (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> did not consider such items to be menacing, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) most local laws did not
                prohibit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> from carrying such knives, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) such knives would have been
                difficult to detect unless the sensitivity of metal detectors had been greatly
                increased. A proposal to ban <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">knives</ENAMEX> altogether in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> had been rejected because
                small cutting implements were difficult to detect and the number of innocent
                "alarms" would have increased significantly, exacerbating congestion problems at
                    checkpoints.
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years</TIMEX> prior to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> requirement for screeners to conduct "continuous"
                and "random" hand searches of carry-on luggage at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoints</ENAMEX> had been replaced by
                explosive trace detection or had simply become ignored by the air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>.
                Therefore, secondary screening of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and their carry-on bags to identify
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weapons</ENAMEX> (other than bombs) was nonexistent, except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who triggered the
                metal detectors. Even when small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knives</ENAMEX> were detected by secondary screening, they
                were usually returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>. Reportedly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9/11</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> were
                instructed to use items that would be undetectable by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport checkpoints</ENAMEX>.
            
            In the pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> security system, the air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> played a major role. As the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ofTransportation</ENAMEX> told us, there were great
                pressures from the air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> to control security costs and to "limit the impact
                of security requirements on aviation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, so that the industry could
                concentrate on its primary mission of moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. . . . [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]hose
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterpressures</ENAMEX> in turn manifested themselves as significant weaknesses in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>." A longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> described the air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>' approach to
                security regulation as "decry, deny and delay" and told us that while "the air
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> had seen the enlightened hand of self-interest with respect to safety, they
                hadn't seen it in the security arena."
            
            The final layer, security on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, was not designed to counter
                suicide hijackings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>-approved "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Strategy</ENAMEX>" had been elaborated over
                decades of experience with scores of hijackings, beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. It taught
                flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> that the best way to deal with hijackers was to accommodate their
                demands, get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> to land safely, and then let law enforcement or the military
                handle the situation. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>, the record had shown that the longer a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hijacking</ENAMEX> persisted, the more likely it was to end peacefully. The strategy operated
                on the fundamental assumption that hijackers issue negotiable demands (most often
                for asylum or the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>) and that, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> put
                it,"suicide wasn't in the game plan" of hijackers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> training material provided no
                guidance for flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> should violence occur.
            
            This prevailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Strategy</ENAMEX> of cooperation and nonconfrontation meant that even a
                hardened cockpit door would have made little difference in a hijacking. As the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Committee of the Air Line Pilots Association</ENAMEX> observed when
                proposals were made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2001</TIMEX> to install reinforced cockpit doors in commercial
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX>, "Even if you make a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vault</ENAMEX> out of the door, if they have a noose around my
                flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX>'s neck, I'm going to open the door." Prior to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> regulations
                mandated that cockpit doors permit ready access into and out of the cockpit in the
                event of an emergency. Even so, rules implemented in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> required air <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> to
                keep the cockpit door closed and locked in flight. This requirement was not always
                observed or vigorously enforced.
            
            As for law enforcement, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 33</NUMEX> armed and trained federal air marshals as
                of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>. They were not deployed on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> domestic flights, except when in transit to
                provide security on international departures. This policy reflected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s view
                that domestic hijacking was in check-a view held confidently as no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> had
                hijacked a U.S.commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> anywhere in the world since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>.
            
            In the absence of any recent aviation security incident and without "specific and
                credible" evidence of a plot directed at civil aviation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s leadership
                focused elsewhere, including on operational concerns and the ever-present issue of
                safety. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA Administrator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garvey</ENAMEX> recalled that "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day in 2001</TIMEX> was like the day
                before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heeding</ENAMEX> calls for improved air service, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> concentrated
                its efforts on a "passenger bill of rights," to improve capacity, efficiency, and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> satisfaction in the aviation system. There was no focus on terrorism.
            
             . . . AND IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTELLIGENCE COMMUNITY</ENAMEX>
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">National Security Act of 1947</ENAMEX> created the position of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> (DCI). Independent from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, and
                other policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> heads the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and provides
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
            The sole element of the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> independent from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet agency</ENAMEX> is
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. As an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, it collects, analyzes, and disseminates
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, who also has the authority to direct it to conduct covert
                    operations.
            
            Although covert actions represent a very small fraction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>'s entire
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> have at times been controversial and over time have
                dominated the public's perception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> is confirmed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> but
                is not technically a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s power under
                federal law over the loose, confederated "intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>" is limited.
            
            He or she states the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s priorities and coordinates development of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> budget requests for submission to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
            This responsibility gives many the false impression that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> has line authority
                over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and has the power to shift resources within these
                budgets as the need arises. Neither is true. In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX>'s real authority has
                been directly proportional to his personal closeness to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, which has
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">waxed</ENAMEX> and waned over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, and to others in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, especially the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> account for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 80</TIMEX>
                percent of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> spending for intelligence, including some that supports a
                national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer base</ENAMEX> and some that supports specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> or
                military service needs.
            
            As they are housed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are keenly attentive to
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s strategic and tactical requirements.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> with a national customer base is the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX>, which intercepts and analyzes foreign communications and
                breaks codes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> also creates codes and ciphers to protect government
                information. Another is the recently renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGA</ENAMEX>), which provides and analyzes imagery and produces a wide array of products,
                including maps, navigation tools, and surveillance intelligence. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> such agency
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Reconnaissance Office</ENAMEX>. It develops, procures, launches,
                and maintains in orbit information-gathering satellites that serve other government
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX> supports the secretary of defense, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX>, and military field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX>. It does some collection through
                human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as well as some technical intelligence collection. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> have their own intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> that collect
                information, help them decide what <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to acquire, and serve the tactical
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> needs of their respective services.
            In addition to those from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> include the national security parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence and Research</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>; the intelligence component of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Intelligence</ENAMEX> and
                Counterintelligence, the former of which, through leveraging the expertise of the
                national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory system</ENAMEX>, has special competence in nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence of the Coast Guard</ENAMEX>; and, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directorate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                Analysis and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infrastructure Protection</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Homeland Security</ENAMEX>.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency The National Security Agency</ENAMEX>'s intercepts of terrorist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> often set off alarms elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Often, too, its
                intercepts are conclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>'s jigsaw puzzle. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>
                build technical systems to break ciphers and to make sense of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s complex
                signals environment. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> listen to conversations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> not
                meant for them. They also perform "traffic analysis"-studying technical
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> systems and codes as well as foreign organizational structures,
