
    
        
            NOTES
            For simplicity, we have adopted the following citation conventions in these endnotes.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> with more
                than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5 million</NUMEX> pages of documents and other materials, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,000</NUMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of audiotapes. In general, we cite documents and other materials by providing
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> of origin, the type of document (e.g., memo, email, report, or
                record), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX>, the title (in quotes) or a description of the
                subject, and the date. We use the following abbreviations for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and
                entities that produced the bulk of these documents: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL-American Airlines</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX>; DCI-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS-Department of Homeland Security; DOD-Department of Defense; DOJ-Department of</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice; DOS-Department of State; DOT-Department of Transportation</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Bureau of Investigation; FDNY-Fire Department of New York; GAO</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
                Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS-Immigration and Naturalization Service</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEADS-Northeast Air</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Sector; NSA-National Security Agency</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC-National Security Council</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM-Office of Emergency Management</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">PANYNJ</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority of New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAPD-Port Authority Police Department</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Treasury</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>.
            Interviews, meetings, briefings, and site visits conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioners</ENAMEX> or by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> are cited, for example, as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Tenet</ENAMEX> interview
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 22, 2004</TIMEX>)." Testimony by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Com</ENAMEX>- mission's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> public
                hearings is cited as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Condoleezza Rice</ENAMEX> testimony, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Apr. 8, 2004</TIMEX>." Written statements
                for the record provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our public hearings are cited as
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Ridge</ENAMEX> prepared statement, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19, 2004</TIMEX>."
            At the request of intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community agencies</ENAMEX> (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>), we use the
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name and last initial, only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name, or in a few instances an alias or
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> when referring to working-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. At the request of
                several intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, we cite most reports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and other
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> generically as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> report," followed by a
                description of the subject and date. In a few instances in which we were given
                access to highly sensitive documents or information, we cite generically to
                documents or information provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>.
            Our investigation built on the work of many others, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Inquiry of</ENAMEX>
                on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Community Activities</ENAMEX> Before and After theTerrorist
                Attacks of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11,2001, which we refer to as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Inquiry</ENAMEX>." We cite as
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Inquiry</ENAMEX> report, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2002</TIMEX>" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate Select Committee on</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">107-351</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.R.</ENAMEX> Rep. No. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">107-792, 107th Cong., 2d sess.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>), indicating "classified
                version" where appropriate. Testimony presented during hearings conducted by the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Inquiry</ENAMEX> is cited as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Inquiry</ENAMEX> testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeorgeTenet</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17, 2002</TIMEX>,"
                indicating "closed hearing" where appropriate. We cite interviews conducted by the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Inquiry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Inquiry</ENAMEX> interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cofer Black</ENAMEX>," with the date of
                the interview.
            Another major source for our investigation were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of interviews conducted
                by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Bureau of Investigation</ENAMEX> during its investigation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> attacks,
                which it refers to as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penttbom</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> write up their interviews on forms
                called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">302s</ENAMEX>, which we cite as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Smith</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4, 2001</TIMEX>," using the date of the interview. We cite interviews conducted by
                other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> name and date of the interview; for example, an interview
                conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> is cited as "DOJ
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Jones</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 2002</TIMEX>."
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Have Some Planes</ENAMEX>"
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. No physical, documentary, or analytical evidence provides a convincing explanation
                of why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omari</ENAMEX> drove to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 10</TIMEX>, only to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX> on Flight 5930 on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>.
                However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> reacted negatively when informed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> that he would have to
                check in again in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Touhey</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 27, 2004</TIMEX>). Whatever their
                reason, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland Jetport</ENAMEX> was the nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9/11</ENAMEX> flight
                that would have arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan</ENAMEX> in time for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to transfer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>, which had a scheduled departure time of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:45 A.M.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">See Tom Kinton</ENAMEX>
                interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Jetport</ENAMEX> site visit (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 2003</TIMEX>).
            Like the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> used by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9/11 hijackers</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newark Liberty International</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport</ENAMEX> was a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Category X</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>: i.e., among the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> liable to
                highest threat, and generally subject to greater security requirements. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Aviation Security Reference Handbook</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1999</TIMEX>, pp<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.117</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">118</NUMEX>. Though
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX> was selected for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the hijackings (as were both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX>), we found no evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> targeted particular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> or
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>. Nothing stands out about any of them with respect to the only security
                layer that was relevant to the actual hijackings: checkpoint screening. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>
                briefing materials, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testing Data</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EWR</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IAD</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. Despite security problems at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan</ENAMEX> (see, e.g., <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> television
                investigative reports in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX>, and an email in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX> from a
                former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> regarding his concerns about lax
                security at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>), no evidence suggests that such issues entered into the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>' targeting: they simply booked heavily fueled east-to-west
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcontinental</ENAMEX> flights of the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> they trained to fly that were
                scheduled to take off at nearly the same time. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Carroll</ENAMEX>, "Fighting Terror
                <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sense of Alarm; Airlines Foiled Police Logan Probe</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.</ENAMEX>
                B1.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>-approved automated system run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> that scored each
                passenger's profile to identify those who might pose a threat to civil aviation. The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> also chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> at random to receive additional security scrutiny. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Ten</TIMEX>
                out of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> hijackers (including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> flights)
                were identified via the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX> system. According to the procedures in place on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>,
                in addition to those flagged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPPS</ENAMEX> algorithm, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were
                to mark as "selectees" those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who did not provide correct responses to the
                required security questions, failed to show proper identification, or met other
                criteria. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Carrier Standard Security Program</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>, pp<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.75</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> record of interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Thompson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 23, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Severance</ENAMEX> interview
                (Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Dillon</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Graney</ENAMEX> interview (Apr.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 2004</TIMEX>). It appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> was selected at random. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hickson</ENAMEX> briefing
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 8, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The call was placed from a pay phone in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terminal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> (between the screening
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">checkpoint</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX>'s boarding gate). We presume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shehhi</ENAMEX> made the call, but we
                cannot be sure. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan International Airport</ENAMEX> site visit (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 15, 2003</TIMEX>); see also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> briefing request no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, undated (topic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>).
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> pushed back from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate 32</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terminal B</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:40</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> response to the
                Commission's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 3, 2004</TIMEX>, requests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> letter, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175-11Sep01 Passenger</ENAMEX> ACI <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Check-in History</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. Customer service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Jawahir</ENAMEX> recalled that her encounter with
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghamdis</ENAMEX> occurred at "shortly before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 A.M.</TIMEX>," and when shown photos of the
                hijackers, she indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohand al Shehri</ENAMEX> resembled one of the two she checked
                in (suggesting they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banihammad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shehri</ENAMEX>). However, she also recalled that the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had the same last name and had assigned seats on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">row 9</TIMEX> (i.e., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghamdis</ENAMEX>), and
                that account has been adopted here. In either case, she almost certainly was dealing
                with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of the Flight 175 hijackers. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation,
                interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Jawahir</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 21, 2001</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28, 2001</TIMEX>. Even had the hijackers
                been unable to understand and answer the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> standard security questions, the only
                consequence would have been the screening of their carry-on and checked bags for
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explosives</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Carrier Standard Security Program</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 76</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoints</ENAMEX> provided access to the gate. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> was opened
                at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:15 A.M.</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> conducted many screener evaluations between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11,1999,
                and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11,2001. At the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">checkpoints</ENAMEX>, in aggregate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screeners</ENAMEX> met or
                exceeded the average for overall, physical search, and X-ray detection, while
                falling below the norm for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal detection</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA Special Assessments</ENAMEX> (by "red
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>") were done at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan</ENAMEX> security checkpoints during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two years</TIMEX> prior to
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> briefing materials,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testing Data</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOS</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EWR</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IAD</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Transport Association/Regional Airlines Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATA/RAA</ENAMEX>) report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Air</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Carriers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Checkpoint Operations Guide</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Carrier Standard</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Program</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>, appendix <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Carol Turano</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation,
                interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nilda Cora</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4, 2001</TIMEX>; interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Thomas</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14, 2001</TIMEX>;
                interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Gore</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2001</TIMEX>; interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudia Richey</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 15</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosarito Rivera</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 25, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selectee Status</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijackers</ENAMEX>," undated. For
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boarding</ENAMEX> and seating information, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SABRE</ENAMEX> information on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>. These boarding times from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system are approximate only;
                for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>, they indicated that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> "boarded" after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> had
                pushed back from the gate. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 3, 2004</TIMEX>,
                requests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2004</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">452</NUMEX> NOTES <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TO CHAPTER 1</ENAMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selectee Status</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijackers</ENAMEX>," undated; see also
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> letter,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175- 11</ENAMEX> Sep01 <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Passenger ACI Check-in History</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmis</ENAMEX> checked in at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:29</TIMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> has not yet been able to confirm the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time of Hanjour</ENAMEX>'s checkin. However, it had to have taken place by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:35</TIMEX>, when he
                appears on the checkpoint videotape. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SABRE</ENAMEX> information for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77, Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 3, 2004</TIMEX>, requests,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal checkpoints</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selectee Status</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijackers</ENAMEX>," undated; see also
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selectee List AALA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#77</NUMEX>," undated; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaughn Allex</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaughn Allex</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> conducted many screener evaluations at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dulles</ENAMEX> between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 1999</TIMEX>,
                and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>. While the test results for physical search exceeded the
                national average, both the metal detector and X-ray results were below average. See
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> briefing materials, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testing Data</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EWR</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IAD</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority</ENAMEX> videotape, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulles</ENAMEX> main terminal
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">checkpoints</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; see also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Jackson</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority</ENAMEX> videotape, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulles</ENAMEX> main terminal
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">checkpoints</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; see also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Jackson</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. For investigation findings, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#77</NUMEX>:
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijacking</ENAMEX> and Crash into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>," undated. For screener
                evaluations, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Jackson</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SABRE</ENAMEX> information for Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77, Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> response to
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 3, 2004</TIMEX>, requests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX> EWR bag loading status, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight</ENAMEX>
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EWR ACI</ENAMEX> passenger history, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX> EWR full bag
                history, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selectee Status</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijackers</ENAMEX>,"
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undated; FBI</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Final 24 Hours</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 8, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> conducted many screener evaluations at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newark</ENAMEX> between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 1999</TIMEX>,
                and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>. Detection rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal detection</ENAMEX>, physical searches, and
                X-rays all met or exceeded the national averages. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> briefing materials,
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testing Data</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EWR</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IAD</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24, 2001</TIMEX>; see also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Report</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 30</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93 EWR ACI</ENAMEX> passenger history, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; see also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Final 24 Hours</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 8, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>. While Flights <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 and 77</TIMEX> were at or slightly above the average number of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> for the respective flights that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flights 175</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX> were well
                below their averages. We found no evidence to indicate that the hijackers
                manipulated the passenger loads on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> they hijacked. Financial records did
                not reveal the purchase of any tickets beyond those the hijackers used for
                themselves. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> briefing request no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, undated (topic
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Average Load Factor by Day</ENAMEX>-of<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-Week</TIMEX>," undated (for Flights <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 and 77</TIMEX>
                from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 11, 2001, to Sept. 9, 2001</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s supplemental
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">document</ENAMEX> requests, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 20, 2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175 BOS-LAX Load Factors</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undated</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from June 1, 2001, to Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explanation of Load</ENAMEX>
                Factors," undated.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 3, 2004</TIMEX>, requests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2004</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch Environmental Control/Weekly Flight Summary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flight Attendant Jump Seat Locations During Takeoff And</ENAMEX>
                Flight <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Attendant Typical Cabin Positions During Start of Cabin Service</ENAMEX>," undated;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Passenger Name List</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11/September 11</ENAMEX>," undated.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>. Commission analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> air traffic control and radar data. See AAL
                record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch Environmental Control/Weekly Flight Summary</ENAMEX> for Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, Sept.</TIMEX>
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,2001</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Halleck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy Houck</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8, 2004</TIMEX>). The initial service
                assignments for flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX> would have placed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Martin</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bobbi Arestegui</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Low</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Roger</ENAMEX> in business class; Dianne
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snyder</ENAMEX> in the midcabin galley; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Sweeney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Nicosia</ENAMEX>
                in the aft galley. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Collman</ENAMEX> would have been assigned to work in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, but to
                assist in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class if needed. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flight Attendant Jump Seat</ENAMEX>
                Locations During <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Takeoff And Flight Attendant Typical Cabin Positions During Start</ENAMEX>
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabin Service</ENAMEX>," undated; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Jordan</ENAMEX> briefing (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 20, 2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic Control Recording-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic Control Recording-United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight 175, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21, 2001</TIMEX>. Given that the cockpit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American 11</ENAMEX> had been acknowledging all
                previous instructions from air traffic control that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> within a matter of
                <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>, and that when the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> reporting of the hijacking was received a short
                time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the 8:19</TIMEX> call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ong</ENAMEX>) a number of actions had already been taken
                by the hijackers, it is most likely that the hijacking occurred at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:14 A.M.</TIMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>. An early draft of an executive summary prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> for the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> referred to an alleged report of a shooting aboard <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>. We
                believe this report was erroneous for a number of reasons- there is no evidence that
                the hijackers purchased firearms, use of a gun would be inconsistent with the
                otherwise common tactics employed by the hijackers, the alleged shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> was
                seated where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> accounts place the stabbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9B</NUMEX>), and, most important,
                neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ong</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Sweeney</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who communicated to the
                ground from aboard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, reported the presence of a gun or a shooting. Both
                reported knives and stabbings. AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ong</ENAMEX> to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX>
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Wyatt</ENAMEX> to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Howland</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25, 2004</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
                Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> looked into the gun story and was unable to corroborate it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, summary of briefing re investigation, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Dillon</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2004</TIMEX>). See also AAL transcript, telephone call
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ong</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>. At the time of the hijacking,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> all carried cockpit keys on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. See
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Parfitt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Bertapelle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Mulcahy</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>. AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obituary</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Lewin</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. B7.</ENAMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>. AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ong</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>;
                AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
                Regarding the claim of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>. Calls to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s reservations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> are routed to the first open line at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
                of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, among them the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX> See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX>
                interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19, 2003</TIMEX>). On standard emergency training, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Air</ENAMEX>
                Carrier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Security Program</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>, pp. 139j-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">139o</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Dillman</ENAMEX> briefing
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 18, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Jordan</ENAMEX> briefing (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 20, 2003</TIMEX>). The call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> was received
                initially by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanessa Minter</ENAMEX> and then taken over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Sadler</ENAMEX>; realizing the
                urgency of the situation, he pushed an emergency button that simultaneously
                initiated a tape recording of the call and sent an alarm notifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>, to pick up on the line. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> was paged to respond to the alarm and
                joined the call a short time later. Only <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first four minutes</TIMEX> of the phone call
                between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ong</ENAMEX> and the reservations <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minter, Sadler</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>) was recorded
                because of the time limit on the recently installed system. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX>
                interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> testimony, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ong</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX> interviews (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch Environmental Control/Weekly</ENAMEX> Flight
                Summary for Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Halleck</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOS ATC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Carrier Standard Security Program</ENAMEX>
                required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> to immediately notify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> upon receiving information
                that an act or suspected act of airplane piracy was being committed.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> recording, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Air Route Traffic Control Center</ENAMEX>, position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46R</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:25</TIMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.M.; Air Traffic Control Recording-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21, 2001</TIMEX>.
                Starting at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:22</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Sweeney</ENAMEX> attempted by airphone to contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>
                flight services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan</ENAMEX>, which managed the scheduling and operation of
                flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX>'s first attempt failed, as did a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:24</TIMEX>. When she
                got through to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nunez</ENAMEX>, the latter thought she had reported her flight number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as 12</NUMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, hearing that a problem had been
                reported aboard an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> airplane, went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s gate area at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan</ENAMEX> with his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colleague Beth Williams</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> noted that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of flights had all
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departed Boston</ENAMEX> and the gate area was quiet. He further realized that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 12</ENAMEX> had
                not even departed yet, so he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to try to clarify
                the situation. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines Airphone Usage</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20, 2001</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25,2004</TIMEX>). The phone call between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 12 minutes</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:32-8:44</TIMEX>) and was not taped. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> email,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward to Schmidt</ENAMEX>,"Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> Account of events,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 19, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> notes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> handwritten notes, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> report, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Wyatt</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Howland</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>. See AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Wyatt</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Howland</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>. AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX> notes, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 2001</TIMEX>. Also at this time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> completed its "lockout" procedure for
                Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>, which restricted access to information about a hijacked flight in
                accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Carrier Standard Security</ENAMEX> program. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Air</ENAMEX>
                Carrier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Security Program</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 110</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>. AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Wyatt</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Howland</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11,2001</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>. AAL transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">454</NUMEX> NOTES <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TO CHAPTER 1</ENAMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Woodward</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> represented a load factor of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33.33 percent</NUMEX> of the airplane's
                seating capacity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">168</NUMEX>, below the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49.22 percent</NUMEX> for Flight 175 on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> in the
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-month</TIMEX> period prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175 BOS-LAX</ENAMEX>
                Load Factors, undated (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from June 1, 2001, to Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>
                holding reservations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX> did not show for the flight. They were
                interviewed and cleared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Executive Summary</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2001</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Executive Summary, Chronology of a Multiple Hijacking Crisis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 2001</TIMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX> ACARS report, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX>
                record, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX> Flight Data Recap, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Executive Summary</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12,2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Executive Summary</ENAMEX>,
                Chronology of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Multiple Hijacking Crisis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11,2001,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17,2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-United Airlines</ENAMEX> 175," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19,2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AirTraffic Control Recording-United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight 175, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21,2001</TIMEX>. At or around
                this time, flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Laborie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Marchand</ENAMEX> would have begun
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cabin</ENAMEX> service in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class; with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy King</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fangman</ENAMEX> in business class;
                and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Tarrou</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Jarret</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alicia Titus</ENAMEX> in economy class. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175 Flight Attendant Positions/Jumpseats</ENAMEX>," undated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> flight
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>, unlike those at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, did not carry cockpit keys. Instead, such keys
                were stowed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>-on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX>, in the overhead bin above seats <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1A and 1B</TIMEX> in
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Dillman</ENAMEX> briefing (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 18, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Jordan</ENAMEX> briefing (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 20</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>. Asked by air traffic controllers at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:37</TIMEX> to look for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> 767
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX> reported spotting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:38</TIMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:41</TIMEX>, the flight
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> reported having "heard a suspicious transmission" from another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> shortly
                after takeoff,"like someone keyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mike</ENAMEX> and said everyone stay in your seats."
                See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic Control Recording-United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight 175, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Policastro</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation,
                interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Hanson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Policastro</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Sweeney</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28, 2001</TIMEX>; interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald May</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 2001</TIMEX>. On both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">767 double</TIMEX>-aisled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, the
                hijackers arrayed themselves similarly: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> seated in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class close to the
                cockpit door, the pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX> seated close behind them, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> other
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX> seated close behind the pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX>. Hijackers were seated next to both
                the left and right aisles. On <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">77 and United 93</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">757</ENAMEX> single-aisle
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX>, the pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX> sat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first row</TIMEX>, closest to the cockpit door. See
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penttbom Investigation</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67-69</NUMEX>; AAL
                schematics for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 77</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> schematics for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX> and Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-United Airlines</ENAMEX> 175," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic Control Recording-United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight 175, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Hanson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>. Flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">board UAL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> could contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">United office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> (SAMC) simply by dialing *<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">349</NUMEX> on an airphone. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of
                investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Price</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 24, 2002</TIMEX>. At some point before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAMC</ENAMEX> notified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of the emergency call from the flight attendant.
                See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Policastro</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation,
                interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Policastro</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.11,2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich Miles</ENAMEX> interiew (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21, 2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-United Airlines</ENAMEX> 175," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Sweeney</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 2, 2001</TIMEX>;
                interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Sweeney</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Hanson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>. See ibid.; interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Sweeney</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-United Airlines</ENAMEX> 175," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flight Attendant Jump Seat Locations During Takeoff And Flight</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Attendant Typical Cabin Positions During Start of Cabin Service</ENAMEX>," undated; AAL
                email, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Crews</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch</ENAMEX>
                Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control/Weekly Flight Summary</ENAMEX> for Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">System Operations Command Center</ENAMEX> (SOCC) log, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 2</ENAMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>. Flight
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attendant Renee May</ENAMEX> would likely have started working in the first-class galley;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Heidenberger</ENAMEX> would have been in the aft galley; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Lewis</ENAMEX> would have
                been in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Lewis</ENAMEX> would have been in the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>. On cabin
                service, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flight Attendant Jump Seat Locations During Takeoff And</ENAMEX>
                Flight <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Attendant Typical Cabin Positions During Start of Cabin Service</ENAMEX>," undated.
                For cruising altitude, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>. On events in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> recording, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Air</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traffic Control Center</ENAMEX>, position <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNN R</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation,
                interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Olson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy May</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch Environmental</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control/Weekly Flight Summary</ENAMEX> for Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>. Air traffic control notified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of the problem, and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airline</ENAMEX> began attempts to contact the flight by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:59</TIMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACARS</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report,
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>, the
                transponder signal was turned off at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:21</TIMEX>; on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX>, the code was changed at
                <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:47</TIMEX>; on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX>, the signal was turned off at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:56</TIMEX>; and on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United 93</ENAMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> was turned off at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:41</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary of AirTraffic Hijack Events:</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Byard</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Povinelli</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24, 2003</TIMEX>); see also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic Control</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recording-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch</ENAMEX>
                Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control/Weekly Flight Summary</ENAMEX> for Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerard Arpey</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Wansley</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8, 2004</TIMEX>);
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">System Operations Command Center</ENAMEX> (SOCC) log, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines Airphone Usage</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of
                investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy May</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX>. The records available for the phone calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX> do not allow for a
                determination of which of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> "connected calls to unknown numbers" represent the
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbara</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Olson</ENAMEX>, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> believe that all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
                represent communications between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Olson</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> (all family
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> were canvassed to see if they had
                received any phone calls from the hijacked flight, and only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee May</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Olson</ENAMEX> indicated that they had received such calls). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> calls were at
                <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:15:34</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 minute</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">42 seconds</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:20:15</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 minutes</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">34 seconds</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:25:48</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">34 seconds</TIMEX>; and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30:56</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 minutes</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 seconds</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airlines Airphone Usage</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Olson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Voss</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s supplemental document
                request, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 20, 2004</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines Airphone Usage</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of
                investigation, interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Olson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report, "Report of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aircraft Accident</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hendershot</ENAMEX>
                interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic Hijack</ENAMEX> Events:
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flight Path Study-American</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> analysis of radar data.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic Hijack</ENAMEX> Events: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"Report of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aircraft Accident</ENAMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight Path Study-American Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19, 2002</TIMEX>;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Acts Against Civil Aviation</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20, 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 41</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX>. The flight attendant assignments and seating included <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Flight Attendant</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Welsh</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class, seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">J1</TIMEX> at takeoff); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bradshaw</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">J5</TIMEX>);
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda Green</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class, seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">J4</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorraine Bay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">J3</TIMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CeeCee Lyles</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">J6</TIMEX>). See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> questions for the record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronology</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Attacks and Subsequent Events</ENAMEX>
                Through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 24, 2001</TIMEX>," undated; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> records, copies of electronic boarding
                passes for Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">93, Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Varcadipane</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4, 2004</TIMEX>);
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newark Tower</ENAMEX> briefing (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63</TIMEX>. Although the flight schedule indicates an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 A.M.</TIMEX> "departure," this was the
                time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> left the gate area. Taxiing from the gate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runway</ENAMEX> normally took
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Varcadipane</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4, 2004</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newark Tower</ENAMEX> briefing
                (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4, 2004</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">64</TIMEX>. Commission analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> air traffic control data. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s awareness of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple hijackings</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> transcript, telephone call from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nydia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>
                Marquis, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Marquis</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> record, System
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations Command Center</ENAMEX> (SOCC) log, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11,2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL System Operations Control</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">briefing</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 20, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich Miles</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> report,
                "Timeline: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch/SMFDO Activities-Terrorist Crisis</ENAMEX>," undated.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> audio file, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX>, position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46R</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:24:38 and 8:24:56</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Zalewski</ENAMEX>
                interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 23, 2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 6, 1970</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular Front for the Liberation of</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine</ENAMEX> hijacked a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan American Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">747</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">707</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swissair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC-8</ENAMEX>.
                On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 9</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> airliner was hijacked as well. An attempt to hijack an
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airliner</ENAMEX> was thwarted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> landed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> and was blown
                up after its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were released. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> were flown to Dawson
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were held captive, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> were
                destroyed. The international hijacking crisis turned into a civil war, as the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> used <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to restore its control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Aviation Reference Handbook</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1999</TIMEX>, appendix D.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> knew or strongly suspected that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX> was a hijacking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 minutes</TIMEX> after it
                was taken over; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 minutes</TIMEX> after it was taken over. There is no evidence
                to indicate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 77</ENAMEX> as a hijacking until it crashed into
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> audio file, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herndon Command Center</ENAMEX>, line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5114</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:07:13</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> audio file,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herndon Command Center</ENAMEX>, position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:19</TIMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:07</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Air Traffic Control</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> recommended to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA Command Center</ENAMEX> that a cockpit warning be sent to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> of all commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to secure their cockpits. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Center</ENAMEX> sent
                out such warnings to the commercial flights in its sector, we could find no evidence
                that a nationwide warning was issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATC</ENAMEX> system.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen King</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 2004</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> air traffic control tapes indicate that
                at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:19</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA Air Traffic Control System Command Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herndon</ENAMEX> ordered
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> to send a cockpit warning to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1989</ENAMEX> because, like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX>, it was a transcontinental flight departing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan Airport</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">69</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>' response, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> briefing (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 2004</TIMEX>). For
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballinger's</ENAMEX> warnings, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed Ballinger</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 2004</TIMEX>). A companywide
                order for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX> to warn cockpits was not issued until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:21</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> report,
                "Timeline: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch/SMFDO Activities-Terrorist Crisis</ENAMEX>," undated. While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> assisted him, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ballinger</ENAMEX> remained responsible for multiple
                flights. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed Ballinger</ENAMEX> interview (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 2004</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>' policy
                called for the flight dispatcher to manage only the hijacked flight, relieving him
                of responsibilities for all other flights. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>' policy, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>
                Marquis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Parfitt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Bertapelle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Mulcahy</ENAMEX> interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19, 2003</TIMEX>).
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> had no such "isolation" policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL System Operations Control</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">briefing</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 20, 2003</TIMEX>).
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specialist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Factual Report of Investigation-Digital</ENAMEX>
                Flight Data Recorder" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">93, Feb. 15, 2002</TIMEX>; on CVR, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>,"CVR from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UA</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#93</NUMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aircraft</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communication and Reporting System</ENAMEX> (ACARS) messages sent to and from Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>
                (which indicate time of message transmission and receipt); see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballinger ACARS</ENAMEX> log, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:22</TIMEX>, after learning of the events at the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melody Homer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leroy Homer</ENAMEX>, had an ACARS
                message sent to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> in the cockpit asking if he was okay. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> record,
                ACARS message, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specialist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Factual Report of Investigation-Digital</ENAMEX>
                Flight Data Recorder" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">93, Feb. 15, 2002</TIMEX>; on CVR, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>,"CVR from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UA</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#93</NUMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> report,"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic</ENAMEX>
                Hijack Events: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Traffic Control</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recording-United Airlines</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> represented a load factor of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20.33 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s
                seating capacity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">182</NUMEX>, considerably below the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52.09 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX> on
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tuesdays</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three-month</TIMEX> period prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 11-September 4</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93 EWR-SFO</ENAMEX> load factors, undated. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>
                holding reservations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX> did not show for the flight. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> were
                interviewed and cleared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "Flight <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#93</NUMEX> 'No <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show' Passengers</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 9/11/01</TIMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Withdrawal of Application for Admission</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed al Kahtani</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">74</TIMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> regulations, Admission to flight deck, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R. </ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"> 121.547</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>, copies of boarding passes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">93, Sept. 11,2001</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> passenger
                reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> first-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were aboard the flight. If that number is
                accurate, it would include the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> hijackers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of investigation,
                interview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Jefferson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX> passenger
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manifest</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>. All but one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> seated in the
                first-class cabin communicated with the ground during the flight, and none mentioned
                anyone from their cabin having gone into the cockpit before the hijacking. Moreover,
                it is unlikely that the highly regarded and experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight</ENAMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">93</TIMEX> would have allowed an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> into the cockpit before or after takeoff who had
                not obtained the proper permission. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> records, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> files of Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>. For jumpseat information, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weight and Balance Information</ENAMEX> for
                Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 175</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAL</ENAMEX> records, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dispatch Environmental</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control/Weekly Flight Summary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 77</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75</TIMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atta</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 11</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarrah</ENAMEX> apparently did not know how to operate the
                communication radios; thus his attempts to communicate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> were
                broadcast on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "CVR from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UA</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#93</NUMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4, 2003</TIMEX>.
                Also, by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:32</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> notified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> that the flight was not responding
                to radio calls. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>, the flight's nonresponse and its turn to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">east</ENAMEX> led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> to believe by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:36</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was hijacked. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich Miles</ENAMEX>
                interview (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21, 2003</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> report, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> dispatch SMFDO activities-terrorist
                crisis," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">76</TIMEX>. In accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> regulations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 93</ENAMEX>'s cockpit voice recorder recorded
                the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last 31 minutes</TIMEX> of sounds from the cockpit via microphones in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>'
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headsets</ENAMEX>, as well as in the overhead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> of the flight deck. This is the only
                recorder from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> to survive the impact and ensuing fire.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVRs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDRs</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United 175</ENAMEX> were not found, and the CVR from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> Flight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX> was badly burned and not recoverable. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report, "CVR from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UA</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#93</NUMEX>,"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4, 2003</TIMEX>; see also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> regulations, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R. </ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"> 25.1457</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91.609</NUMEX>,
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91.1045</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121.359</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX> CVR data. A transcript of the CVR recording was prepared
                by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX>. All calls placed on airphones were from the rear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. There was one
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airphone</ENAMEX> installed in each row of seats on both sides of the aisle. The airphone
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> was capable of transmitting only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> calls at any one time. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report
                of investigation, airphone records for flights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> 175 on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18, 2001</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> audio file, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Center</ENAMEX>, position <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lorain Radar</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX> CVR data; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, "CVR from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UA</ENAMEX> Flight <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#93</NUMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4, 2003</TIMEX>.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">79</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation, interviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Beamer</ENAMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>, through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 11, 2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reports of investigation, interviews of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Bradshaw</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001, through Oct. 4, 2001</TIMEX>. Text
                messages warning the cockpit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 93</ENAMEX> were sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Ballinger</ENAMEX>
