
    
        
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FORESIGHT-</ENAMEX>AND HINDSIGHT
            In composing this narrative, we have tried to remember that we write with the benefit
                and the handicap of hindsight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindsight</ENAMEX> can sometimes see the past clearly-with
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> vision. But the path of what happened is so brightly lit that it places
                everything else more deeply into shadow. Commenting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>, Roberta
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wohlstetter</ENAMEX> found it "much easier after the event to sort the relevant from the
                irrelevant signals. After the event, of course, a signal is always crystal clear; we
                can now see what disaster it was signaling since the disaster has occurred. But
                before the event it is obscure and pregnant with conflicting meanings."
            
            As <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> passes, more documents become available, and the bare facts of what happened
                become still clearer. Yet the picture of how those things happened becomes harder to
                reimagine, as that past world, with its preoccupations and uncertainty, recedes and
                the remaining memories of it become colored by what happened and what was written
                about it later. With that caution in mind, we asked ourselves, before we judged
                others, whether the insights that seem apparent now would really have been
                meaningful at the time, given the limits of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> then could reasonably have
                known or done.
            We believe the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> attacks revealed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> kinds of failures: in imagination, policy,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capabilities</ENAMEX>, and management.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMAGINATION</ENAMEX> 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Perspective</ENAMEX>
            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> attack was an event of surpassing disproportion. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> had suffered
                surprise attacks before-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> well-known case, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> attack
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> another. But these were attacks by major powers. While by no means as
                threatening as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s act of war, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> attack was in some ways more
                devastating. It was carried out by a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, not enough to man a full
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">platoon</ENAMEX>. Measured on a governmental scale, the resources behind it were trivial. The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> itself was dispatched by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> based in one of the poorest, most
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remote</ENAMEX>, and least industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> on earth. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> recruited a
                mixture of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fanatics</ENAMEX> and highly educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealots</ENAMEX> who could not find suitable
                places in their home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> or were driven from them.
            To understand these events, we attempted to reconstruct some of the context of the
                1990s. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> celebrated the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> with a mixture of relief and
                satisfaction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> hoped to enjoy a peace dividend, as
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> spending on national security was cut following the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> military
                threat.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> emerged into the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War world</ENAMEX> as the globe's preeminent
                military power. But the vacuum created by the sudden demise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
                created fresh sources of instability and new challenges for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George H.W. Bush</ENAMEX> dealt with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of these in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 and 1991</TIMEX> when he
                led an international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> to reverse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>. Other examples
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>' handling new threats included the removal of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belarus</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kazakhstan</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nunn-Lugar</ENAMEX> threat reduction program to help
                contain new nuclear dangers; and international involvement in the wars in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> stood out as an object for admiration, envy, and blame. This created
                a kind of cultural asymmetry. To us, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> seemed very far away. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> seemed very close. In a sense, they were more globalized than we
                were.
            Understanding the Danger
            If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> understood the gravity of the threat they faced and
                understood at the same time that their policies to eliminate it were not likely to
                succeed any time soon, then history's judgment will be harsh. Did they understand
                the gravity of the threat?
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> responded vigorously when the attack was on our soil. Both Ramzi
                Yousef, who organized the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mir Amal</ENAMEX>
                Kansi, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> as they waited to go to work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Langley</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, were the objects of relentless, uncompromising, and successful efforts to
                bring them back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to stand trial for their crimes.
            Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX> had killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
                including the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Africa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> attack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government
                took the threat seriously, but not in the sense of mustering anything like the kind
                of effort that would be gathered to confront an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, or even
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> rank. The modest national effort exerted to contain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> and its
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">depredations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1995 and 1999</TIMEX>, for example, was orders of
                magnitude larger than that devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>.
            As best we can determine, neither in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> nor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first eight months of 2001</TIMEX> did
                any polling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> think the subject of terrorism
                sufficiently on the minds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to warrant asking a question about it in a
                major national survey. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, or even terrorism was not an important
                topic in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> called little
                attention to it.
            If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> wanted to rally the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to a warlike effort, he would need
                to publicize an assessment of the growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> danger. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could
                spark a full public discussion of who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was, what kind of organization
                he led, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> intended, what past attacks they had sponsored or
                encouraged, and what capabilities they were bringing together for future assaults.
                We believe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and international public opinion might have been different--and
                so might the range of options for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--had they been informed of these
                details. Recent examples of such debates include calls to arms against such threats
                as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> ethnic cleansing, biological attacks, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction,
                global climate change, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic.
            While we now know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> was formed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
                occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> did not describe this
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, at least in documents we have seen, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Estimate</ENAMEX> distributed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1995</TIMEX> predicted future terrorist attacks
                against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>-and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. It warned that this danger would
                increase over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next several years</TIMEX>. It specified as particular points of
                vulnerability the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>, symbols of capitalism such as Wall
                Street, critical infrastructure such as power grids, areas where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> congregate
                such as sports <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">arenas</ENAMEX>, and civil aviation generally. It warned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1993 World</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Center</ENAMEX> bombing had been intended to kill a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, not to achieve any
                more traditional political goal.
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This 1995</TIMEX> estimate described the greatest danger as "transient groupings of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>" that lacked "strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> but rather are loose affiliations."
                They operate "outside traditional circles but have access to a worldwide network of
                training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and safehavens." This was an excellent
                summary of the emerging danger, based on what was then known.
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-1997</TIMEX>, the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> received new information making clear that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> headed his own terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, with its own targeting agenda and
                operational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX>. Also revealed was the previously unknown involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> attack on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yemeni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> quartering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> shootdown of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army Black Hawk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, and
                quite possibly the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riyadh</ENAMEX> bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> training mission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> update of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> estimate did not discuss the new
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>. It did state that the terrorist danger depicted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> would persist.
                In the update's summary of key points, the only reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was this
                sentence:"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and its surrogates, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>, have stepped up their threats and surveillance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> facilities
                abroad in what also may be a portent of possible additional attacks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was mentioned in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> other
                sentences in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-page report. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> was not mentioned. The
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> update was the last national estimate on the terrorism danger completed before
                    9/11.
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1998 to 2001</TIMEX>, a number of very good analytical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> were distributed on
                specific topics. These included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s political philosophy, his command of a
                global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, analysis of information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> captured in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s operational style, and the evolving goals of the Islamist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extremist</ENAMEX> movement. Many classified articles for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> briefings were prepared for
                the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with titles such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Ladin Threatening</ENAMEX>
                to Attack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Aircraft</ENAMEX> [with antiaircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>]" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1998</TIMEX>),"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strains Surface</ENAMEX>
                Between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1999</TIMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Terrorist Threat to US Interests in</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasus</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1999</TIMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Ladin to Exploit Looser Security During</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holidays"</ENAMEX>(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>),"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Ladin Evading Sanctions"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX>),"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                Interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Biological, Radiological Weapons</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2001</TIMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban Holding Firm</ENAMEX>
                on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Ladin for Now</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2001</TIMEX>),"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Terrorist Groups Said Cooperating on US Hostage</ENAMEX>
                Plot" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Ladin Determined to Strike in the US"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>).
            
            Despite such reports and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> paper on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin's</ENAMEX> command <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>,
                there were no complete portraits of his strategy or of the extent of his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s involvement in past terrorist attacks. Nor had the intelligence
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> provided an authoritative depiction of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s relationships
                with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, or the scale of the threat his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> posed to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
            Though Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> said to us that the cumulative output of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> (CTC) "dramatically eclipsed" any analysis that could have
                appeared in a fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence Estimate</ENAMEX>, he conceded that most of the
                work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30- to 40</NUMEX>-person analytic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> dealt with collection
                    issues.
            
            In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI GeorgeTenet</ENAMEX> recognized the deficiency of strategic analysis against
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. To tackle the problem within the CTC he appointed a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, who
                briefed him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2001</TIMEX> on "creating a strategic assessment capability." The CTC
                established a new strategic assessments <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2001</TIMEX>. The decision to add
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> to this effort was seen as a major bureaucratic victory, but the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> labored to find them. The new chief of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> reported for duty on
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 10, 2001</TIMEX>.
            
            Whatever the weaknesses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s portraiture, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> and their top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> told us they got the picture-they understood Bin
                Ladin was a danger. But given the character and pace of their policy efforts, we do
                not believe they fully understood just how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> might kill, and how
                soon it might do it. At some level that is hard to define, we believe the threat had
                not yet become compelling.
            It is hard now to recapture the conventional wisdom before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>. For example, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> article in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1999</TIMEX> sought to debunk claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist leader</ENAMEX>, with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. Hard Put to Find Proof Bin Laden Directed</ENAMEX>
                    Attacks." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of analysis at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
                discounted the alarms about a catastrophic threat as relating only to the danger of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemical</ENAMEX>, biological, or nuclear attack-and he downplayed even that, writing several
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>:"It would be a mistake to redefine counterterrorism as a task of
                dealing with 'catastrophic,''grand,' or 'super' terrorism, when in fact these labels
                do not represent most of the terrorism that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is likely to face or
                most of the costs that terrorism imposes on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests."
            
            Beneath the acknowledgment that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> presented serious dangers,
                there was uncertainty among senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> about whether this was just a new and
                especially venomous version of the ordinary terrorist threat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> had lived with
                for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, or was radically new, posing a threat beyond any yet experienced. Such
                differences affect calculations about whether or how to go to war.
            Therefore, those government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> as an unprecedented new danger
                needed a way to win broad support for their views, or at least spotlight the areas
                of dispute, and perhaps prompt action across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The national estimate
                has often played this role, and is sometimes controversial for this very
                    reason.
            
            Such assessments, which provoke widespread thought and debate, have a major impact on
                their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, often in a wider circle of decisionmakers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Estimate</ENAMEX> is noticed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, for example. But, as we have said,
                none was produced on terrorism <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 1997 and 9/11</NUMEX>.
            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> still needed a decision at the highest level as to whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                Qaeda was or was not "a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> order threat," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX> wrote in his first memo
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Condoleezza Rice</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 25, 2001</TIMEX>. In his blistering protest about
                foot-dragging in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week before 9/11</TIMEX>,
                he repeated that the "real question" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> was "are we serious about
                dealing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qida</ENAMEX> threat? . . . Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qida</ENAMEX> a big deal?" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> school of
                thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this September 4</TIMEX> note, implicitly argued that the terrorist
                network was a nuisance that killed a score of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 18-24 months</TIMEX>. If that
                view was credited, then current policies might be proportionate. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> saw
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> as the "point of the spear of radical Islam." But no one forced the
                argument into the open by calling for a national estimate or a broader discussion of
                the threat. The issue was never joined as a collective debate by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                government, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, before 9/11.
            We return to the issue of proportion-and imagination. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s note challenging
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> to imagine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after an attack posits a strike that kills "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>" of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. He did not write "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>."
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Institutionalizing Imagination: The Case of Aircraft as Weapons</ENAMEX>
            Imagination is not a gift usually associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX>. For example, before
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had excellent intelligence that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> attack
                was coming, especially after peace talks stalemated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of November 1941</TIMEX>.
                These were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> notes, of "excruciating uncertainty." The most likely
                targets were judged to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>. An attack was coming,"but officials
                were at a loss to know where the blow would fall or what more might be done to
                prevent it." In retrospect, available intercepts pointed
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> as a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>. But, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observes</ENAMEX>,"in the face of a clear warning, alert measures bowed " to routine.
            It is therefore crucial to find a way of routinizing, even bureaucratizing, the
                exercise of imagination. Doing so requires more than finding an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> who can
                imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> could be used as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. Indeed, since <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> and other
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> had already used suicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, namely truck bombs, the leap to the use of
                other vehicles such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> attack) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> is not far-fetched. Yet
                these scenarios were slow to work their way into the thinking of aviation security
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, as a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800 crash, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> created
                a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> to report on shortcomings in aviation
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gore Commission</ENAMEX>'s report, having thoroughly
                canvassed available expertise in and outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, did not mention suicide
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hijackings</ENAMEX> or the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. It focused mainly on the danger of
                placing bombs onto aircraft-the approach of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> air plot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> Commission
                did call attention, however, to lax screening of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and what they carried
                onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, reports came in of a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> plan to hijack a
                plane. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 4</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Daily Briefing</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
                (reprinted in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 4</ENAMEX>), brought the focus back to more traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> taking;
                it reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s involvement in planning a hijack operation to free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>
                such as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Sheikh</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Abdel Rahman</ENAMEX>. Had the contents of this PDB been
                brought to the attention of a wider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, including key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, it
                might have brought much more attention to the need for permanent changes in domestic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX> and airline security procedures.
            
            Threat reports also mentioned the possibility of using an aircraft filled with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explosives</ENAMEX>. The most prominent of these mentioned a possible plot to fly an
                explosives-laden <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. This report, circulated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, originated from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> who had walked into an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consulate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August of the same year</TIMEX>, the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> had received
                information that a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyans</ENAMEX> hoped to crash a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>. In neither case could the information be corroborated. In addition, an
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> hijacked an airliner in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, most likely intending to blow it up
                over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, but possibly to crash it into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eiffel Tower</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, a private airplane had crashed onto the south lawn of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. In
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdul Hakim Murad-Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX> 's accomplice in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> airlines
                bombing plot-told <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yousef</ENAMEX> had discussed flying a
                plane into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> had been concerned about the danger posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least the 1996</TIMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Atlanta Olympics</ENAMEX>. There he had tried to create an air defense plan using assets from
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> declined to contribute
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> continued to work on the problem of airborne threats
                to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> region. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> chaired an exercise designed to highlight
                the inadequacy of the solution. This paper exercise involved a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX> in which a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> commandeered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learjet</ENAMEX> on the ground in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, loaded it with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explosives</ENAMEX>, and flew it toward a target in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.C. Clarke</ENAMEX> asked officials
                from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> what
                they could do about the situation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> said they could
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">scramble</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Langley Air Force Base</ENAMEX>, but they would need to go to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> for rules of engagement, and there was no mechanism to do so. There was no
                clear resolution of the problem at the exercise.
            
            In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, a great deal of discussion took place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> about the crash off
                the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts of EgyptAir</ENAMEX> Flight 990, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">767</ENAMEX>. The most plausible
                explanation that emerged was that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> had gone berserk, seized the
                controls, and flown the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> into the sea. After the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999-2000 millennium</TIMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alerts</ENAMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> had relaxed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> held a meeting of his Counterterrorism
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Group</ENAMEX> devoted largely to the possibility of a possible airplane hijacking
                by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>.
            
            In his testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> commented that he thought that warning about the possibility
                of a suicide hijacking would have been just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more speculative theory among many,
                hard to spot since the volume of warnings of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> threats and other terrorist
                threats, was in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX>-probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX>."18Yet the
                possibility was imaginable, and imagined. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early August 1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviation Security</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> summarized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> hijacking threat.
                After a solid recitation of all the information available on this topic, the paper
                identified a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> scenarios, one of which was a "suicide hijacking
                operation." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> judged such an operation unlikely, because "it does not
                offer an opportunity for dialogue to achieve the key goal of obtaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahman</ENAMEX> and
                other key captive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>. . . . A suicide hijacking is assessed to be an option
                of last resort."
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> could have shed some light on what kind of "opportunity for dialogue" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                Qaeda desired.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> did not write any analytical assessments of possible hijacking scenarios.
            One prescient pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> analysis of an aircraft plot was written by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
                Department trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> had taken an interest, apparently on his own
                initiative, in the legal issues that would be involved in shooting down a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX> in such a situation.
            
                weapons, too, and developed exercises to counter such a threat-from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> coming to
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from overseas, perhaps carrying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> of mass destruction. None
                of this speculation was based on actual intelligence of such a threat. One idea,
                intended to test command and control plans and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX>'s readiness, postulated a
                hijacked airliner coming from overseas and crashing into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>. The idea was
                put aside in the early planning of the exercise as too much of a distraction from
                the main focus (war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>), and as too unrealistic. As we pointed out in chapter
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> assumed that since such <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> would be coming from
                overseas; they would have time to identify the target and scramble
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interceptors</ENAMEX>.
            
            We can therefore establish that at least some government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> were concerned
                about the hijacking danger and had speculated about various scenarios. The challenge
                was to flesh out and test those scenarios, then figure out a way to turn a scenario
                into constructive action.
            Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> attack of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>, the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has devoted
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of effort to understanding the problem of forestalling a surprise
                attack. Rigorous analytic methods were developed, focused in particular on the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, and several leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> within the intelligence community
                discussed them with us. These methods have been articulated in many ways, but almost
                all seem to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in common: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) think about how surprise
                attacks might be launched; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) identify telltale indicators connected to the most
                dangerous possibilities; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) where feasible, collect intelligence on these
                indicators; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) adopt defenses to deflect the most dangerous possibilities or at
                least trigger an earlier warning.
            After the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, concerns about lack of warning led to a major study
                conducted for DCI <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gates</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> that proposed several recommendations, among
                them strengthening the national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> for warning. We were told that
                these measures languished under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>. Responsibility for warning
                related to a terrorist attack passed from the national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> for
                warning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Community Counterterrorism Board</ENAMEX> had the
                responsibility to issue threat advisories.
            
            With the important exception of analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> efforts in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX>, biological,
                radiological, and nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, we did not find evidence that the methods to
                avoid surprise attack that had been so laboriously developed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> were
                regularly applied.
            Considering what was not done suggests possible ways to institutionalize imagination.
                To return to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> elements of analysis just mentioned:
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> did not analyze how an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, hijacked or explosivesladen, might be
                used as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. It did not perform this kind of analysis from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> ("red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>" analysis), even though suicide terrorism had become a
                principal tactic of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. If it had done so, we believe such an
                analysis would soon have spotlighted a critical constraint for the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrorists</ENAMEX>-finding a suicide operative able to fly large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet aircraft</ENAMEX>. They had
                never done so before 9/11.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> did not develop a set of telltale indicators for this method of attack.
                For example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such indicator might be the discovery of possible terrorists
                pursuing flight training to fly large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet aircraft</ENAMEX>, or seeking to buy advanced
                flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulators</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> did not propose, and the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> collection management
                process did not set, requirements to monitor such telltale indicators. Therefore the
                warning system was not looking for information such as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> report of
                potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> interest in various kinds of aircraft training in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, or
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX> arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zacarias Moussaoui</ENAMEX> because of his suspicious behavior in a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> flight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moussaoui</ENAMEX> arrest was briefed to the DCI
                and other top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> under the heading "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Islamic Extremist Learns to</ENAMEX>
                    Fly." Because the system was not tuned to comprehend
                the potential significance of this information, the news had no effect on warning.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Neither the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> nor aviation security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> analyzed systemic
                defenses within an aircraft or against terroristcontrolled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, suicidal or
                otherwise. The many threat reports mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> were passed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>. While
                that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> continued to react to specific, credible threats, it did not try to
                perform the broader warning functions we describe here. No one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was
                taking on that role for domestic vulnerabilities.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX> told us that he was concerned about the danger posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> in
                the context of protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Atlanta Olympics of 1996</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> complex, and
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-8</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genoa</ENAMEX>.
            But he attributed his awareness more to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX> novels than to warnings from the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. He did not, or could not, press the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to work on
                the systemic issues of how to strengthen the layered security defenses to protect
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> against hijackings or put the adequacy of air defenses against suicide
                hijackers on the national policy agenda.
            The methods for detecting and then warning of surprise attack that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                government had so painstakingly developed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> did not
                fail; instead, they were not really tried. They were not employed to analyze the
                enemy that, as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX> closed, was most likely to launch a surprise
                attack directly against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            POLICY
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> again illustrates how the large, unwieldy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> tended to
                underestimate a threat that grew ever greater. The terrorism fostered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> was different from anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had faced before. The
                existing mechanisms for handling terrorist acts had been trial and punishment for
                acts committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>; sanction, reprisal, deterrence, or war for acts by
                hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. The actions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> fit neither category. Its crimes were
                on a scale approaching acts of war, but they were committed by a loose, far-flung,
                nebulous conspiracy with no territories or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> or assets that could be readily
                threatened, overwhelmed, or destroyed. Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI Tenet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Director</ENAMEX>
                for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations James Pavitt</ENAMEX> gave an intelligence briefing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President-elect Bush</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President-elect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX>; it included the topic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. Pavitt
                recalled conveying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was one of the gravest threats to the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> asked whether killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> would end the problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pavitt</ENAMEX> said he and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> had answered that killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> would have an impact, but would not stop the
                threat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> later provided more formal assessments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
                reiterating that conclusion. It added that in the long term, the only way to deal
                with the threat was to end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s ability to use <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> for
                its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.
            
            Perhaps the most incisive of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> on terrorism to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holdover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX>. Yet he admits that his policy advice, even if it had
                been accepted immediately and turned into action, would not have prevented
                    <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>. We must then ask when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had
                reasonable opportunities to mobilize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for major action against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>
                and its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX>. The main opportunities came after the new information the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> received in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-1997</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX>,
                after the discoveries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> plots in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1999</TIMEX>, and after the
                attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Cole</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX>.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy response to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> was essentially defined following
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX>. We described those decisions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 4</ENAMEX>. It
                is worth noting that they were made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> under extremely
                difficult domestic political circumstances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> were seeking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s
                impeachment. In addition, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998-99</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was preparing the government
                for possible war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>, and he had authorized major air strikes against
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.
            The tragedy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings provided an opportunity for a full examination,
                across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, of the national security threat that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> posed. Such an
                examination could have made clear to all that issues were at stake that were much
                larger than the domestic politics of the moment. But the major policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> did not meet the threat. The diplomatic efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
                State were largely ineffective. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX> and terrorism was just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more priority
                added to already-crowded agendas with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>.
                After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> that changed.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policymakers</ENAMEX> turned principally to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and covert action to implement policy.
                Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> had more responsibility-or did more-to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>,
                working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day and night</TIMEX>, than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. But there were limits to what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> was able
                to achieve in its energetic worldwide efforts to disrupt terrorist activities or use
                proxies to try to capture or kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX>. As early as
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1997</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> wrote to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>: "All we're doing is holding the
                ring until the cavalry gets here."
            
            Military measures failed or were not applied. Before 9/11 the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>
                was not given the mission of ending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> regarded a full <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> invasion
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> as practically inconceivable before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>. It was never the subject of
                formal interagency deliberation.
            Lesser forms of intervention could also have been considered. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would have been the
                deployment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military or intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, or special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">strike forces</ENAMEX>, to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> itself or nearby-openly, clandestinely (secretly), or covertly (with
                their connection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> hidden). Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would no
                longer have been dependent on proxies to gather actionable intelligence. However, it
                would have needed to secure basing and overflight support from neighboring
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. A significant political, military, and intelligence effort would have
                been required, extending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over months</TIMEX> and perhaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, with associated costs and
                risks. Given how hard it has proved to locate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> when there are
                substantial ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, its odds of sucess are hard to calculate.
                We have found no indication that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was offered such an intermediate
                choice, or that this option was given any more consideration than the idea of
                invasion. These policy challenges are linked to the problem of imagination we have
                already discussed. Since we believe that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
                were genuinely concerned about the danger posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, approaches involving
                more direct intervention against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> apparently must have
                seemed-if they were considered at all-to be disproportionate to the threat.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insight</ENAMEX> for the future is thus not easy to apply in practice. It is hardest to mount
                a major effort while a problem still seems minor. Once the danger has fully
                materialized, evident to all, mobilizing action is easier-but it then may be too
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late</TIMEX>.
            Another possibility, short of putting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> on the ground, was to issue a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blunt</ENAMEX> ultimatum to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>, backed by a readiness to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least</TIMEX> launch an
                indefinite air campaign to disable that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>'s limited military capabilities and
                tip the balance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s ongoing civil war. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had warned the
                Taliban that they would be held accountable for further attacks by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> against
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests. The warning had been given in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, again in late
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, once more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 2000</TIMEX>, and again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 2001</TIMEX>. Delivering it
                repeatedly did not make it more effective. As evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s responsibility
                for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> attack came in during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Advisor Samuel</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> to develop a plan for a sustained air campaign against the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> developed a paper laying out a formal, specific ultimatum. But
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s plan apparently did not advance to formal consideration by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Group</ENAMEX>
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>. We have found no indication that the idea was briefed to the new
                administration or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> passed his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> to them, although the same team of
                career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> spanned both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>.
            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> was responsible for the attack on
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Cole</ENAMEX>. Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> took any action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s inference
                may well have been that attacks, at least at the level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX>, were risk
                    free.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPABILITIES</ENAMEX>
            Earlier chapters describe in detail the actions decided on by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">administrations</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> considered or authorized covert actions, a process
                that consumed considerable time-especially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>- and
                achieved little success beyond the collection of intelligence. After the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX>
                missile strikes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> remained on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in or near the
                region, prepared to fire cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Shelton</ENAMEX> developed as many as
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> different strike options, and did not recommend any of them. The most extended
                debate on counterterrorism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> had to do with
                missions for the unmanned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Predator</ENAMEX>- whether to use it just to locate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> or to
                wait until it was armed with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>, so that it could find him and also attack
                him. Looking back, we are struck with the narrow and unimaginative menu of options
                for action offered to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.
            Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> tried to solve the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> problem with the same
                government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and capabilities it had used in the last stages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
                War and its immediate aftermath. These capabilities were insufficient, but little
                was done to expand or reform them.
            For covert action, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> depended on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX>
                and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directorate of Operations</ENAMEX>. Though some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, particularly in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, were eager for the mission, most were not. The higher management of
                the directorate was unenthusiastic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s capacity to conduct paramilitary
                operations with its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> was not large, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> did not seek a
                large-scale general expansion of these capabilities before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Pavitt</ENAMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of this directorate, remembered that covert action, promoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, had gotten the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clandestine Service</ENAMEX> into trouble in the past. He had no desire
                to see this happen again. He thought, not unreasonably, that a truly serious
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counterterrorism</ENAMEX> campaign against an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of this magnitude would be business
                primarily for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clandestine Service</ENAMEX>.
            
            As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Staff</ENAMEX> were keen to help.
                Some in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Operations Command</ENAMEX> have told us that they worked on plans for
                using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Operations Forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and that they hoped for action
                orders. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JCS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> General <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Zinni</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Command</ENAMEX>
                had a different view. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelton</ENAMEX> felt that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX> attacks had proved a waste
                of good ordnance and thereafter consistently opposed firing expensive Tomahawk
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> merely at "jungle gym" terrorist training infrastructure.
            
            In this view, he had complete support from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shelton</ENAMEX>
                was prepared to plan other options, but he was also prepared to make perfectly clear
                his own strong doubts about the wisdom of any military action that risked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> lives
                unless the intelligence was "actionable.
            
            The high price of keeping counterterrorism policy within the restricted circle of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Security Group</ENAMEX> and the highest-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> was nowhere more
                apparent than in the military establishment. After the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX> missile strike,
                other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JCS</ENAMEX> let the press know their unhappiness that, in conformity
                with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater-Nichols</ENAMEX> reforms, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelton</ENAMEX> had been the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JCS</ENAMEX> to
                be consulted. Although follow-on military options were briefed more widely, the vice
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of operations on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX> Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commented</ENAMEX> to us that intelligence and
                planning documents relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> arrived in a ziplock red package and that
                many flag and general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> never had the clearances to see its contents.
            
            At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX> point before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> fully engaged in the mission of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">countering al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, though this was perhaps the most dangerous foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> then
                threatening the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> effectively relied on the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to take the lead in preparing long-term offensive plans against an enemy
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sanctuary</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> adopted this approach, although its emerging new
                strategy envisioned some yet undefined further role for the military in addressing
                the problem. Within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Rumsfeld</ENAMEX> gave
                their principal attention to other challenges.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeland defenders</ENAMEX> faced outward. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> itself was barely able to retain
                any alert bases. Its planning scenarios occasionally considered the danger of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hijacked</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> being guided to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, but only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> that were
                coming from overseas. We recognize that a costly change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX>'s defense posture
                to deal with the danger of suicide hijackers, before such a threat had ever actually
                been realized, would have been a tough sell. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX> did not canvass available
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> and try to make the case. The most serious weaknesses in agency
                capabilities were in the domestic arena. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 3</ENAMEX> we discussed these
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>-the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization Service</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>, and
                others. The major pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> effort to strengthen domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> capabilities came in
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, as part of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX> after-action review. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal advisers</ENAMEX> paid considerable attention then to border security problems, but
                were not able to bring about significant improvements before leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>-led interagency process did not effectively bring along the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice and Transportation</ENAMEX> departments in an agenda for institutional change.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> did not have the capability to link the collective knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in the
                field to national priorities. The acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> did not learn of his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s hunt for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or about his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s arrest of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> taking flight training until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of central intelligence knew about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moussaoui</ENAMEX> investigation
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> before word of it made its way even to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant director</ENAMEX> for
                counterterrorism.
            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> deferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDB</ENAMEX> reporting to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
                of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> full-field investigations related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, news the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> said he
                found heartening, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had simply restated what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had said. No one looked
                behind the curtain.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>'s capabilities to take aggressive, anticipatory security measures were
                especially weak. Any serious policy examination of a suicide hijacking scenario,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">critiquing</ENAMEX> each of the layers of the security system, could have suggested changes
                to fix glaring vulnerabilities-expanding no-fly lists, searching passengers
                identified by the CAPPS screening system, deploying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Air</ENAMEX> Marshals
                domestically, hardening cockpit doors, alerting air <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> to a different kind of
                hijacking than what they had been trained to expect, or adjusting the training of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">controllers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NORAD</ENAMEX>.
            Government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> also sometimes display a tendency to match capabilities to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> by defining away the hardest part of their job. They are often passive,
                accepting what are viewed as givens, including that efforts to identify and fix
                glaring vulnerabilities to dangerous threats would be too costly, too controversial,
                or too disruptive.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANAGEMENT</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operational Management</ENAMEX>
            Earlier in this report we detailed various missed opportunities to thwart the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>
                plot. Information was not shared, sometimes inadvertently or because of legal
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misunderstandings</ENAMEX>. Analysis was not pooled. Effective operations were not launched.
                Often the handoffs of information were lost across the divide separating the foreign
                and domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
            However the specific problems are labeled, we believe they are symptoms of the
                government's broader inability to adapt how it manages problems to the new
                challenges of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-first century</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are like a set of specialists
                in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, each ordering tests, looking for symptoms, and prescribing
                <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>. What is missing is the attending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> who makes sure they work as
                a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.
            One missing element was effective management of transnational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. Action
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> should have drawn on all available knowledge in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. This
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> should have ensured that information was shared and duties were clearly
                assigned across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and across the foreign-domestic divide.
            Consider, for example, the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar, Hazmi</ENAMEX>, and their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX> trip to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>, detailed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 6</ENAMEX>. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>) analyzed communications associated with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf</ENAMEX>,
                and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem</ENAMEX>. Working-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> knew
                little more than this. But they correctly concluded that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nawaf</ENAMEX> " and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Khalid</ENAMEX>"might
                be part of "an operational cadre" and that "something nefarious might be afoot." The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> did not think its job was to research these identities. It saw itself as an
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> to support intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> tried to respond
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">energetically</ENAMEX> to any request made. But it waited to be asked. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> had been asked
                to try to identify these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> would have started by checking its own
                database of earlier information from these same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Some of this information
                had been reported; some had not. But it was all readily accessible in the database.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> would promptly have discovered who Nawaf was, that his full name
                might be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>, and that he was an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khalid</ENAMEX>.
            With this information and more that was available, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> could have more
                effectively tracked the movement of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> in southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. With the
                name "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> could then have asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> also to
                check that name. State would promptly have found its own record on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>,
                showing that he too had been issued a visa to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX>
                would have learned that the visa had been issued at the same place-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jeddah</ENAMEX>-and on
                almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> as the one given to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX>.
            When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>, local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were able to
                identify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX>. After the flight left, they
                learned that one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX> had the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alhazmi</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> did not
                know what that name meant.
            The information arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangkok</ENAMEX> too late to track these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> as they came in.
                Had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> there already been keeping an eye out for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX> as
                part of a general regional or worldwide alert, they might have tracked him coming
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">in.</ENAMEX> Had they been alerted to look for a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>,
                they might have noticed him too. Instead, they were notified only after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>
                sounded the alarm. By that time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> had already disappeared into the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 12</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> told his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> that surveillance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> was continuing. He may not have known that
                in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX> had dispersed and the tracking was falling apart.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> regretfully reported the bad news on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 13</TIMEX>. The names
                they had were put on a watchlist in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> might notice
                if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 14</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> unit
                again updated his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>, telling them that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were continuing to track the
                suspicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who had now dispersed to various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
            Unfortunately, there is no evidence of any tracking efforts actually being undertaken
                by anyone after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> disappeared into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>. No other effort was made to
                create other opportunities to spot these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> in case the screen in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> failed. Just from the evidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s passport, one of the logical
                possible destinations and interdiction points would have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Yet
                no one alerted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> to look for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. They arrived,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unnoticed</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 15</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early March 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> reported that
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>, now identified for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time with his full name, had departed
                on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 15</TIMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> did not
                appreciate the significance of that name or notice the cable, we have found no
                evidence that this information was sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>.
            Even if watchlisting had prevented or at least alerted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to the entry of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, we do not think it is likely that watchlisting, by itself, have
                prevented the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> attacks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX> adapted to the failure of some of its
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> to gain entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. None of these future hijackers was
                a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>. Alternatively, had they been permitted entry and surveilled, some larger
                results might have been possible had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. These are difficult
                what-ifs. The intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> might have judged that the risks of conducting
                such a prolonged intelligence operation were too high-potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> might
                have been lost track of, for example. The pre- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> might not have been judged
                capable of conducting such an operation. But surely the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> would
                have preferred to have the chance to make these choices.
            From the details of this case, or from the other opportunities we catalogue in the
                text box, one can see how hard it is for the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to assemble
                enough of the puzzle pieces gathered by different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to make some sense of
                them and then develop a fully informed joint plan. Accomplishing all this is
                especially difficult in a transnational case. We sympathize with the working-level
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, drowning in information and trying to decide what is important or what
                needs to be done when no particular action has been requested of them.
            Who had the job of managing the case to make sure these things were done? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> answer
                is that everyone had the job. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
                Pavitt, stressed to us that the responsibility resided with all involved. Above all
                he emphasized the primacy of the field. The field had the lead in managing
                operations. The job of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, he stressed, was to support the field, and do
                so without delay. If the field asked for information or other support, the job of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> was to get it-right away.
            
            This is a traditional perspective on operations and, traditionally, it has had great
                merit. It reminded us of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> emphasis on the primacy of its field
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. When asked about how this traditional structure would adapt to the
                challenge of managing a transnational case, one that hopped from place to place as
                this one did, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy director</ENAMEX> argued that all involved were responsible for
                making it work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavitt</ENAMEX> underscored the responsibility of the particular field
                location where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> were being tracked at any given time. On the other hand,
                he also said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> was supposed to manage all the moving
                parts, while what happened on the ground was the responsibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> in the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Headquarters</ENAMEX> tended to support and facilitate, trying to make sure everyone was in
                the loop. From time to time a particular post would push one way, or headquarters
                would urge someone to do something. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> never really took
                responsibility for the successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of this case. Hence the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> did not realize that omissions in planning had occurred, and they
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scarcely</ENAMEX> knew that the case had fallen apart. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the Counterterrorist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> at the time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cofer Black</ENAMEX>, recalled to us that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> was one among
                many and that, at the time, it was "considered interesting, but not heavy water
                yet." He recalled the failure to get the word to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> fast enough, but has no
                evident recollection of why the case then dissolved, unnoticed.
            
            The next level down, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> at the time recalled
                that he did not think it was his job to direct what should or should not be done. He
                did not pay attention when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> dispersed and things fell apart. There
                was no conscious decision to stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> was temporarily lost
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>. He acknowledged, however, that perhaps there had been a letdown for his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overworked</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> after the extreme tension and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long hours</TIMEX> in the period of the
                millennium alert.
            
            The details of this case illuminate real management challenges, past and future. The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must find a way of pooling intelligence and using it to guide the
                planning of and assignment of responsibilities for joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> involving
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> as disparate as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>,
                and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security.
            Institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management</ENAMEX>
            Beyond those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> tasks of bridging the foreign-domestic divide and matching
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> with plans, the challenges include broader <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> issues pertaining
                to how the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> set priorities and allocate resources. Once
                again it is useful to illustrate the problem by examining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, since before 9/11
                this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s role was so central in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s counterterrorism efforts.
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 4, 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI Tenet</ENAMEX> issued a directive to several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX> for community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, stating:"We are at war. I want no resources or
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spared in this effort, either inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX>."
            
            The memorandum had little overall effect on mobilizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> or the intelligence
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
            
            The memo was addressed only to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX> for community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Dempsey</ENAMEX>. She faxed the memo to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of the major intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
                after removing covert action sections. Only a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> received it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> at the time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lieutenant General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Minihan</ENAMEX>, believed the memo applied
                only to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>, because no one had informed him of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>
                shortcomings. For their part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> thought the memorandum was intended for
                the rest of the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, given that they were already doing all they
                could and believed that the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> needed to pull its weight.
            
            The episode indicates some of the limitations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX>'s authority over the
