
    
        
            HOW TO DO IT? A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DIFFERENT WAY OF ORGANIZING THE GOVERNMENT</ENAMEX>
            As presently configured, the national security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government
                are still the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> constructed to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
                confronts a very different world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Instead of facing a few very dangerous
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adversaries</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> confronts a number of less visible challenges that
                surpass the boundaries of traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and call for quick, imaginative,
                and agile responses.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> generation rose to the challenges of the 1940s
                and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950s</TIMEX>. They restructured the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> so that it could protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
                That is now the job of the generation that experienced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>. Those attacks showed,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emphatically</ENAMEX>, that ways of doing business rooted in a different era are just not
                good enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> should not settle for incremental, ad hoc adjustments to a
                system designed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generations ago</TIMEX> for a world that no longer exists.
            We recommend significant changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. We know that
                the quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is more important than the quality of the wiring diagrams.
                Some of the saddest aspects of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> story are the outstanding efforts of so many
                individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> straining, often without success, against the boundaries of the
                possible. Good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can overcome bad structures. They should not have to.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has the resources and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should combine
                them more effectively, achieving unity of effort. We offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major
                recommendations to do that:
            
                unifying strategic intelligence and operational planning against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islamist</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> across the foreign-domestic divide with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Counterterrorism</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>;
                unifying the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> with a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>;
                unifying the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the counterterrorism effort and their
                    knowledge in a network-based information-sharing system that transcends
                    traditional governmental boundaries;
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unifying</ENAMEX> and strengthening congressional oversight to improve quality and
                    accountability; and
                strengthening the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeland defenders</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITY OF EFFORT ACROSS THE FOREIGN-DOMESTIC DIVIDE</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Action</ENAMEX>
            Much of the public commentary about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> attacks has dealt with "lost
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunities</ENAMEX>,"some of which we reviewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 11</ENAMEX>. These are often
                characterized as problems of "watchlisting," of "information sharing," or of
                "connecting the dots." In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 11</ENAMEX> we explained that these labels are too narrow.
                They describe the symptoms, not the disease.
            In each of our examples, no one was firmly in charge of managing the case and able to
                draw relevant intelligence from anywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, assign responsibilities
                across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> (foreign or domestic), track progress, and quickly bring
                obstacles up to the level where they could be resolved. Responsibility and
                accountability were diffuse.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> cooperated, some of the time. But even such cooperation as there was is
                not the same thing as joint action. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> cooperate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> defines the problem
                and seeks help with it. When they act jointly, the problem and options for action
                are defined differently from the start. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> from different backgrounds come
                together in analyzing a case and planning how to manage it.
            In our hearings we regularly asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>: Who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX>? The other
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are in their positions, doing their jobs. But who is calling the play that
                assigns roles to help them execute as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>?
            Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, those issues have not been resolved. In some ways joint work has gotten
                better, and in some ways worse. The effort of fighting terrorism has flooded over
                many of the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> boundaries because of its sheer quantity and energy.
                Attitudes have changed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> are keenly conscious of trying to avoid the
                mistakes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>. They try to share information. They circulate-even to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>-practically every reported threat, however dubious.
            Partly because of all this effort, the challenge of coordinating it has multiplied.
                Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> was plainly the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> confronting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                played a very secondary role. The engagement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense and State</ENAMEX>
                was more episodic.
            
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> is still central. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> is much more active, along with
                    other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> effort is now enormous. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of its unified commands,
                    each headed by a four-star general, have counterterrorism as a primary mission:
                    Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations Command</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Command</ENAMEX> (both headquartered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>), and
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Command</ENAMEX> (headquartered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>).
                A new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Homeland Security</ENAMEX> combines formidable resources in border
                    and transportation security, along with analysis of domestic vulnerability and
                    other tasks.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> has the lead on many of the foreign policy tasks we
                    described in chapter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>.
                At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Council</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>) now is joined by a
                    parallel presidential advisory structure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security Council</ENAMEX>.
            
            So far we have mentioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons for joint action-the virtue of joint planning
                and the advantage of having someone in charge to ensure a unified effort. There is a
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>: the simple shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> with sufficient skills. The limited pool of
                critical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>-for example, skilled counterterrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and linguists-is
                being depleted. Expanding these capabilities will require not just money, but time.
            Primary responsibility for terrorism analysis has been assigned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorist</ENAMEX>
                Threat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Integration Center</ENAMEX> (TTIC), created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, based at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> but
                staffed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, reporting directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence</ENAMEX>. Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> houses another intelligence "fusion" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>: the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> that played such a key role before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> major
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analytic</ENAMEX> unit is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>,
                concentrating more on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> vulnerabilities, is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Homeland</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> is in the process of building the analytic capability it has long
                lacked, and it also has the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Terrorist Screening Center</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> cannot afford so much duplication of effort. There are not enough
                experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to go around. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">duplication</ENAMEX> also places extra demands on
                already hard-pressed single-source national technical intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> like
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combining Joint Intelligence and Joint Action</ENAMEX>
            A "smart" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would integrate all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of information to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> as a
                whole. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated</ENAMEX> all-source analysis should also inform and shape strategies to
                collect more intelligence. Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Terrorist Threat Integration Center</ENAMEX>, while it has
                primary responsibility for terrorism analysis, is formally proscribed from having
                any oversight or operational authority and is not part of any operational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>,
                other than reporting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of central intelligence.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> now tries to handle the problem of joint management, informed by
                analysis of intelligence from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways.
            
                First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with lead responsibility for certain problems have constructed
                    their own interagency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> and task <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in order to get cooperation. The
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, for example, recruits liaison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> from
                    throughout the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Command</ENAMEX> has its
                    own interagency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, recruiting liaison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> from all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> from
                    which it might need help. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Terrorism Task Forces</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84</TIMEX>
                    locations to coordinate the activities of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> when action may be
                    required.
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the problem of joint operational planning is often passed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> tries to play this role. The national security staff
                    at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> (both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> and new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>) has
                    already become <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> larger since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>. But our impression, after talking
                    to serving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, is that even this enlarged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is consumed by meetings
                    on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> issues, sifting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>'s threat information and trying to
                    coordinate everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.
            
            Even as it crowds into every square inch of available office space, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is
                still not sized or funded to be an executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 3</ENAMEX> we described some
                of the problems that arose in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, constitutionally
                insulated from the usual mechanisms of oversight, became involved in direct
                operations. During the 1990s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX> occasionally tried to exercise such
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>, sometimes successfully, but often causing friction.
            Yet a subtler and more serious danger is that as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is consumed by these
                day-to-day tasks, it has less capacity to find the time and detachment needed to
                advise a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on larger policy issues. That means less time to work on major
                new initiatives, help with legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to steer needed bills through
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and track the design and implementation of the strategic plans for
                regions, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and issues that we discuss in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 12</ENAMEX>. Much of the job of
                operational coordination remains with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. There DCI
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenet</ENAMEX> and his chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> ran interagency meetings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly every day</TIMEX> to coordinate
                much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> insisted he did not make policy
                and only oversaw its implementation. In the struggle against terrorism these
                distinctions seem increasingly artificial. Also, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DCI</ENAMEX> becomes a lead
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s operations, it becomes harder to play all the
                position's other roles, including that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> in chief.
            The problem is nearly intractable because of the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is currently
                structured. Lines of operational authority run to the expanding executive
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>, and they are guarded for understandable reasons: the DCI commands the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> overseas; the secretary of defense will not yield to others in
                conveying commands to military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> will not give up the
                responsibility of deciding whether to seek arrest warrants. But the result is that
                each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> needs its own intelligence apparatus to support the
                performance of its duties. It is hard to "break down stovepipes" when there are so
                many stoves that are legally and politically entitled to have cast-iron pipes of
                their own.
            Recalling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater-Nichols</ENAMEX> legislation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rumsfeld</ENAMEX> reminded us
                that to achieve better joint capability, each of the armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> had to "give up
                some of their turf and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and prerogatives." Today, he said, the executive
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branch</ENAMEX> is "stove-piped much like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> were nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>." He
                wondered if it might be appropriate to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to "give up some of their
                existing turf and authority in exchange for a stronger, faster, more efficient
                government wide joint effort." Privately, other key
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have made the same point to us.
            We therefore propose a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX>-led unified joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> for
                counterterrorism. It should combine strategic intelligence and joint operational
                planning.
            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Staff</ENAMEX>, which serves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of</ENAMEX>
                Staff, intelligence is handled by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the J-2 directorate</TIMEX>, operational planning by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J-3</ENAMEX>,
                and overall policy by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J-5</ENAMEX>. Our concept combines the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">J-2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J-3</ENAMEX> functions
                (intelligence and operational planning) in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, keeping overall policy
                coordination where it belongs, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Council</ENAMEX>.
            
                Recommendation: We recommend the establishment of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Center</ENAMEX> (NCTC), built on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of the existing
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Terrorist Threat Integration Center</ENAMEX> (TTIC). Breaking the older mold of national
                    government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should be a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for joint operational
                    planning and joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">intelligence</ENAMEX>, staffed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> from the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
                    The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should have authority to evaluate the performance of the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> assigned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>.
            
            
                Such a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> should be developed in the same spirit that guided the
                    military's creation of unified joint commands, or the shaping of earlier
                    national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Reconnaissance Office</ENAMEX>, which was formed to
                    organize the work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and several defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in space.
                
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC-Intelligence</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should lead strategic
                    analysis, pooling all-source intelligence, foreign and domestic, about
                    transnational terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> with global reach. It should develop net
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assessments</ENAMEX> (comparing enemy capabilities and intentions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> defenses
                    and countermeasures). It should also provide warning. It should do this work by
                    drawing on the efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>, and other departments
                    and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. It should task collection requirements both inside and outside the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
                The intelligence function (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">J-2</NUMEX>) should build on the existing TTIC structure
                    and remain distinct, as a national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX>. As the
                    government's principal knowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamist</ENAMEX> terrorism, with the main
                    responsibility for strategic analysis and net assessment, it should absorb a
                    significant portion of the analytical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> now residing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Intelligence Task Force-Combatting</ENAMEX>
                    Terrorism (JITF-CT).
                
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC-Operations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should perform joint planning.
                    The plans would assign operational responsibilities to lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, such as
                    State, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> and its combatant commands, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>,
                    and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should not direct the actual execution of these
                    operations, leaving that job to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> would then track
                    implementation; it would look across the foreign-domestic divide and across
                    agency boundaries, updating plans to follow through on cases.
                
                The joint operational planning function (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J-3</ENAMEX>) will be new to theTTIC
                    structure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> can draw on analogous work now being done in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and
                    every other involved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, as well as reaching out to
                    knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should not be a policymaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and planning should
                    follow the policy direction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
            
            
                Consider this hypothetical case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> discovers that a suspected terrorist is
                    traveling to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should draw on joint
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence resources</ENAMEX>, including its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> counterterrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, to
                    analyze the identities and possible destinations of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. Informed
                    by this analysis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> would then organize and plan the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the
                    case, drawing on the talents and differing kinds of experience among the several
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> assigned to it-assigning tasks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> overseas, to
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX> watching entry points into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>.
                    If military assistance might be needed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Operations Command</ENAMEX> could be
                    asked to develop an appropriate concept for such an operation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> would be
                    accountable for tracking the progress of the case, ensuring that the plan
                    evolved with it, and integrating the information into a warning. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> would
                    be responsible for being sure that intelligence gathered from the activities in
                    the field became part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s institutional memory about Islamist
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist personalities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and possible means of attack.
                In each case the involved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> would make its own senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> aware of what
                    it was being asked to do. If those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> heads objected, and the issue could
                    not easily be resolved, then the disagreement about roles and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> could be
                    brought before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Council</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">NCTC-Authorities</ENAMEX>.
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should be appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and should be equivalent
                in rank to a deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet department</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> would report
                to the national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> whose creation we recommend below,
                placed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> would thus
                also report indirectly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>'s nomination should be
                confirmed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and he or she should testify to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, as is the case
                now with other statutory presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>.
            
                To avoid the fate of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> with great nominal authority and little
                    real power, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> must have the right to concur in the choices of
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to lead the operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> focused
                    on counterterrorism, specifically including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the Counterterrorist
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Division</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> of the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>'s Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations Command</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Command</ENAMEX>, and the
                    The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should also work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> in developing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s counterterrorism budget.
                There are precedents for surrendering authority for joint planning while
                    preserving an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s operational control. In the international context, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> may get line authority over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> assigned by other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                    unified commands, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> plan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that may involve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> belonging to
                    <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the services. In each case, procedures are worked out, formal and
                    informal, to define the limits of the joint <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>'s authority.
            
            The most serious disadvantage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> is the reverse of its greatest virtue. The
                struggle against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamist</ENAMEX> terrorism is so important that any clear-cut
                centralization of authority to manage and be accountable for it may concentrate too
                much power in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place. The proposed NCTC would be given the authority of planning
                the activities of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Law or executive order must define the scope of
                such line authority.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> would not eliminate interagency policy disputes. These would still go to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Council</ENAMEX>. To improve coordination at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, we believe
                the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security Council</ENAMEX> should soon be merged into a single National
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX>. The creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> should help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> concentrate on
                its core duties of assisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and supporting interdepartmental
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">policymaking</ENAMEX>.
            We recognize that this is a new and difficult idea precisely because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
                we recommend for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX> really would, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rumsfeld</ENAMEX> foresaw, ask strong
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to "give up some of their turf and authority in exchange for a stronger,
                faster, more efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wide joint effort." Countering transnational
                Islamist terrorism will test whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can fashion more flexible
                models of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> needed to deal with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-first-century</TIMEX> world.
            An argument against change is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is at war, and cannot afford to
                reorganize in midstream. But some of the main innovations of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s and 1950s</TIMEX>,
                including the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of Staff</ENAMEX> and even the construction of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> itself, were undertaken in the midst of war. Surely the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> cannot wait
                until the struggle against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamist</ENAMEX> terrorism is over.
            "Surprise, when it happens to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, is likely to be a complicated, diffuse,
                bureaucratic thing. It includes neglect of responsibility, but also responsibility
                so poorly defined or so ambiguously delegated that action gets lost." That comment was made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 40 years ago</TIMEX>, about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbor</ENAMEX>. We hope another commission, writing in the future about another attack, does
                not again find this quotation to be so apt.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITY OF EFFORT</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTELLIGENCE COMMUNITY</ENAMEX>
            In our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> section, we concentrated on counterterrorism, discussing how to combine
                the analysis of information from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of intelligence with the joint planning
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that draw on that analysis. In this section, we step back from looking
                just at the counterterrorism problem. We reflect on whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
                organized adequately to direct resources and build the intelligence capabilities it
                will need not just for countering terrorism, but for the broader range of national
                security challenges in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> ahead.
            The Need for a Change
            During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> did not depend on seamless integration to
                track and count the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>-such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>-fielded
                by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and other adversary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> concentrated on its
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specialized</ENAMEX> mission, acquiring its own information and then sharing it via formal,
                finished reports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> had given birth to and dominated the
                main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> for technical collection of intelligence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources</ENAMEX> were shifted at an
                incremental pace, coping with challenges that arose over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>.
            We summarized the resulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in chapter 3.
                It is outlined below.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Intelligence Community</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence</ENAMEX>, which includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the</ENAMEX>
                Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence for Community Management</ENAMEX>, the Community
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Staff</ENAMEX>, theTerrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Threat Integration Center</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community offices</ENAMEX>.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>), which performs human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> collection,
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-source analysis, and advanced science and technology.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>:
            
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>), which performs signals collection and analysis
                    collection and analysis
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Reconnaissance Office</ENAMEX> (NRO), which develops, acquires, and launches
                    space systems for intelligence collection Other national reconnaissance
                    programs
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departmental</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>:
            
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX> (DIA) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Intelligence and Research</ENAMEX> (INR) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of State</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism and Finance Intelligence of the Department of Treasury</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence and the Counterterrorism</ENAMEX> and Counterintelligence
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence of the Department of Energy</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directorate of Information Analysis and Infrastructure Protection</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IAIP</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directorate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard Intelligence of the Department of</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>
            
            The need to restructure the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> grows out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> problems that
                have become apparent before and after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>:
            
                Structural barriers to performing joint intelligence work. National
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> is still organized around the collection disciplines of the home
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, not the joint mission. The importance of integrated, allsource
                    analysis cannot be overstated. Without it, it is not possible to "connect the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dots</ENAMEX>." No one component holds all the relevant information.
                By contrast, in organizing national defense, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater- Nichols</ENAMEX>
                    legislation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> created joint commands for operations in the field, the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unified Command Plan</ENAMEX>. The services-the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps</ENAMEX>-organize, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, and equip their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> to perform their
                    missions. Then they assign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> to the joint combatant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>,
                    like the commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Command</ENAMEX> (CENTCOM). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX>-
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> Act required <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to serve tours outside their service in order to
                    win promotion. The culture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> was transformed, its
                    collective mind-set moved from service-specific to "joint," and its operations
                    became more integrated.
                
                
                    Lack of common standards and practices across the
                        foreign-domestic divide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the intelligence community
                    should be able to pool information gathered overseas with information gathered
                    in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, holding the work-wherever it is done-to a common standard
                    of quality in how it is collected, processed (e.g., translated), reported,
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX>, and analyzed. A common set of personnel standards for intelligence can
                    create a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> better able to operate in joint activities,
                    transcending their own service-specific mind-sets.
                
                    Divided management of national intelligence capabilities.
                    While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> was once "central" to our national intelligence capabilities,
                    following the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> it has been less able to influence the use of
                    the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s imagery and signals intelligence capabilities in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> national
                    agencies housed within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX>,
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the lessons learned from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> was the value of
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> (satellites in particular) in precision warfare.
                    Since that war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> has appropriately drawn these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> into its
                    transformation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. Helping to orchestrate this transformation is
                    the under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense for intelligence, a position established by
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>. An unintended consequence of these developments has been
                    the far greater demand made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> on technical systems, leaving the DCI
                    less able to influence how these technical resources are allocated and used.
                
                    Weak capacity to set priorities and move resources. The
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are mainly organized around what they collect or the way they collect
                    it. But the priorities for collection are national. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> makes hard
                    choices about moving resources, he or she must have the power to reach across
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> and reallocate effort.
                
                    Too many jobs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> now has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> jobs. He is
                    expected to run a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. He is expected to manage the loose
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confederation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that is the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. He is expected to
                    be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> in chief for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, sifting evidence and directly
                    briefing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> as his principal intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>. No recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> has
                    been able to do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> effectively. Usually what loses out is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of
                    the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, a difficult task even in the best case because the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX>'s current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are weak. With so much to do, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> often has not
                    used even the authority he has.
                
                    Too complex and secret. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
                    and the rules surrounding the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> have accumulated to a depth
                    that practically defies public comprehension. There are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or parts
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have become arcane matters, understood only by initiates after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long</TIMEX>
                    study. Even the most basic information about how much money is actually
                    allocated to or within the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and most of its key components
                    is shrouded from public view.
            
            The current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> is responsible for community performance but lacks the three
                authorities critical for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> head or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive officer</ENAMEX>: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) control
                over purse strings, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the ability to hire or fire senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the
                ability to set standards for the information infrastructure and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>.
            
            The only budget power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> lies in
                coordinating the budget requests of the various intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> into a single
                program for submission to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The overall funding request of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in this program is then presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> separate volumes.
            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passes an appropriations bill to allocate money to intelligence
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, most of their funding is hidden in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> in order to keep
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> spending secret. Therefore, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> are the authorizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> for funding of the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,
                the final budget review is handled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Subcommittee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appropriations</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX>. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> have no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittees</ENAMEX> just for intelligence, and only a
                few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> review the requests.
            The appropriations for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and the national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGA</ENAMEX>, and
                NRO-are then given to the secretary of defense. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> transfers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s
                money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> but disburses the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' money directly. Money for the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s national security components falls within the appropriations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>.
            
            In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> lacks hire-and-fire authority over most of the intelligence
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>'s senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. For the national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> housed in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>, the secretary of defense must seek the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX>'s concurrence
                regarding the nomination of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, who are presidentially appointed. But
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> may submit recommendations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> without receiving this
                concurrence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> cannot fire these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX> has even less influence
                over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s national security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component</ENAMEX>, who is appointed by the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> in consultation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combining Joint Work</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stronger Management</ENAMEX>
            We have received recommendations on the topic of intelligence reform from many
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commissions</ENAMEX> have been over this same ground. Thoughtful bills have
                been introduced, most recently a bill by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Intelligence</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Committee Porter Goss</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>), and another by the ranking minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Graham</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>) have introduced reform proposals as well. Past efforts have foundered,
                because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> did not support them; because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX>, the secretary of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>, or both opposed them; and because some proposals lacked merit. We have
                tried to take stock of these experiences, and borrow from strong elements in many of
                the ideas that have already been developed by others.
            
                Recommendation: The current position of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> should be replaced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
                    main areas of responsibility: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) to oversee national intelligence centers on
                    specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of interest across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) to manage the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> and oversee the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that contribute to
                    it.
            
            First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> should oversee national intelligence
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX> to provide all-source analysis and plan intelligence operations for the
                whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> on major problems.
            
                One such problem is counterterrorism. In this case, we believe that the center
                    should be the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> (formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTIC</ENAMEX>) inside the National
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Center</ENAMEX> we have proposed. It would sit there alongside the
                    operations management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> we described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, with both making up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX>,
                    in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. Other national intelligence
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>-for instance, on counterproliferation, crime and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX>, and
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-would be housed in whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is best suited for them.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> would retain the present <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI</ENAMEX>'s role as the
                    principal intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. We hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will come
                    to look directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of the national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> to
                    provide all-source analysis in their areas of responsibility, balancing the
                    advice of these intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> against the contrasting viewpoints that may
                    be offered by department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>,
                    and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> should manage the national intelligence
                program and oversee the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component agencies</ENAMEX> of the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. (See
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagram</ENAMEX>.)
            
            
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> would submit a unified budget for national
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> that reflects priorities chosen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Council</ENAMEX>,
                    an appropriate balance among the varieties of technical and human intelligence
                    collection, and analysis. He or she would receive an appropriation for national
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> and apportion the funds to the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, in line with
                    that budget, and with authority to reprogram funds among the national
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to meet any new priority (as counterterrorism was in the
                    1990s). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> should approve and submit nominations
                    to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who would lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NGA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Analysis</ENAMEX> and Infrastructure
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> intelligence capabilities.
                
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> would manage this national effort with the
                    help of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX>, each of whom would also hold a key position in one of
                    the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component agencies</ENAMEX>.
                
                foreign intelligence (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>)
                defense intelligence (the under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense for intelligence)
                
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homeland</ENAMEX> intelligence (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant director</ENAMEX> for intelligence
                    or the under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security for information analysis and
                    coordinate their work within each of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> areas, largely staying housed
                    in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that support them now.
            
            Returning to the analogy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, these three
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deputies</ENAMEX>-like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX>-would have the
                job of acquiring the systems, training the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and executing the operations
                planned by the national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>.
            And, just as the combatant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> also report to the secretary of defense, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of the national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers-e</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">g.</ENAMEX>, for counterproliferation, crime
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX>, and the rest-also would report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>.
            
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>'s military intelligence programs-the joint military
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> (JMIP) and the tactical intelligence and related activities
                    program (TIARA)-would remain part of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s responsibility.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> would set personnel policies to establish
                    standards for education and training and facilitate assignments at the national
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> lines. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
                    also would set information sharing and information technology policies to
                    maximize data sharing, as well as policies to protect the security of
                    information.
                Too many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> now have an opportunity to say no to change. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> should participate in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that can
                    resolve differences in priorities among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and bring the major
                    disputes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for decision.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> should be located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Office of the</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, who would be confirmed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and would testify
                before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, would have a relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
                taking the place of the existing community management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> housed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>.
            In managing the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> is still
                providing a service function. With the partial exception of his or her
                responsibilities for overseeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCTC</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> should
                support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> of national intelligence-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and policymaking
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, defense, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>.
            We are wary of too easily equating government management problems with those of the
                private sector. But we have noticed that some very large private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> rely on a
                powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> who has significant control over how money is spent and can hire or
                fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>, assisted by a relatively modest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, while
                leaving responsibility for execution in the operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>. There are
                disadvantages to separating the position of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> from the
                job of heading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> will not
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> of his or her own and may have a weaker base of support. But we
                believe that these disadvantages are outweighed by several other considerations:
            
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> must be able to directly oversee
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> collection inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Yet law and custom has
                    counseled against giving such a plain domestic role to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> will be one among several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX> for funds in setting national
                    priorities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> should not be both one of the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> of them all.
                Covert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> tend to be highly tactical, requiring close attention. The
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> should rely on the relevant joint mission center
                    to oversee these details, helping to coordinate closely with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
                    The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> will be able to concentrate on building the capabilities to carry out
                    such operations and on providing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who will be directing and
                    executing such operations in the field.
                Rebuilding the analytic and human intelligence collection capabilities of the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> should be a full-time effort, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> should focus on
                    extending its comparative advantages.
            
            
                Recommendation: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> should emphasize (a) rebuilding the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s analytic capabilities; (b) transforming the clandestine service by
                    building its human intelligence capabilities; (c) developing a stronger language
                    program, with high standards and sufficient financial incentives; (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) renewing
                    emphasis on recruiting diversity among operations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> so they can blend
                    more easily in foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>; (e) ensuring a seamless relationship between
                    human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> collection and signals collection at the operational level; and (f)
                    stressing a better balance between unilateral and liaison operations.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> should retain responsibility for the direction and execution of clandestine
                and covert operations, as assigned by the relevant national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and
                authorized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. This would
                include propaganda, renditions, and nonmilitary disruption. We believe, however,
                that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> important area of responsibility should change.
            
                Recommendation: Lead responsibility for directing and executing
                    paramilitary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, whether clandestine or covert, should shift to the
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>. There it should be consolidated with the capabilities for
                    training, direction, and execution of such operations already being developed in
                    the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Operations Command</ENAMEX>.
            
            
                Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> did not invest in developing a robust capability to
                    conduct paramilitary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. It relied on proxies
                    instead, organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> without the requisite military training.
                    The results were unsatisfactory.
                Whether the price is measured in either money or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
                    cannot afford to build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate capabilities for carrying out secret
                    military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, secretly operating standoff <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, and secretly training
                    foreign military or paramilitary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should concentrate
                    responsibility and necessary legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>.
                The post-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> precedent of using joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>-military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> for
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">covert</ENAMEX> and clandestine operations was a good one. We believe this proposal to be
                    consistent with it. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> would concentrate on its comparative advantages
                    in building capabilities for joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> itself would be
                    planned in common.
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> has a reputation for agility in operations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> has a
                    reputation for being methodical and cumbersome. We do not know if these
                    stereotypes match current reality; they may also be one more symptom of the
                    civil-military misunderstandings we described in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 4</ENAMEX>. It is a problem to
                    be resolved in policy guidance and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, not in the creation of
                    redundant, overlapping capabilities and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in such sensitive work. The
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> should be integrated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s training, exercises, and
                    planning. To quote a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> now serving in the field:"One fight, one
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>."
            
            
                Recommendation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finally</ENAMEX>, to combat the secrecy and complexity we
                    have described, the overall amounts of money being appropriated for national
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> and to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component agencies</ENAMEX> should no longer be kept secret.
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should pass a separate appropriations act for intelligence, defending
                    the broad allocation of how these <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of billions of dollars</NUMEX> have been assigned
                    among the varieties of intelligence work.
            
            The specifics of the intelligence appropriation would remain classified, as they are
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">declassification</ENAMEX> argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> could learn about
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> capabilities by tracking the top-line appropriations figure. Yet the
                top-line figure by itself provides little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insight</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and
                methods. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> readily provides copious information about spending on
                its military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, including military intelligence. The intelligence community
                should not be subject to that much disclosure. But when even aggregate categorical
                numbers remain hidden, it is hard to judge priorities and foster accountability.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITY OF EFFORT IN SHARING INFORMATION</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Sharing</ENAMEX>
            We have already stressed the importance of intelligence analysis that can draw on all
                relevant sources of information. The biggest impediment to all-source analysis-to a
                greater likelihood of connecting the dots-is the human or systemic resistance to
                sharing information.
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has access to a vast amount of information. When databases not
                usually thought of as "intelligence," such as customs or immigration information,
                are included, the storehouse is immense. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has a weak system
                for processing and using what it has. In interviews around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, official
                after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> urged us to call attention to frustrations with the unglamorous "back
                office" side of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9/11</TIMEX> story, for example, we sometimes
                see examples of information that could be accessed-like the undistributed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>
                someone had to ask for it. In that case, no one did. Or, as in the episodes we
                describe in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 8</ENAMEX>, the information is distributed, but in a compartmented
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX>. Or the information is available, and someone does ask, but it cannot be
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX>.
            What all these stories have in common is a system that requires a demonstrated "need
                to know" before sharing. This approach assumes it is possible to know, in advance,
                who will need to use the information. Such a system implicitly assumes that the risk
                of inadvertent disclosure outweighs the benefits of wider sharing. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
                assumptions are no longer appropriate. The culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> feeling they own the
                information they gathered at taxpayer expense must be replaced by a culture in which
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> instead feel they have a duty to the information-to repay the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' investment by making that information available.
            Each intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has its own security practices, outgrowths of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.
                We certainly understand the reason for these practices. Counterintelligence concerns
                are still real, even if the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> has been replaced by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX>.
            But the security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> need to be weighed against the costs. Current security
                requirements nurture overclassification and excessive compartmentation of
                information among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s incentive structure opposes sharing, with
                risks (criminal, civil, and internal administrative sanctions) but few rewards for
                sharing information. No one has to pay the long-term costs of overclassifying
                information, though these costs-even in literal financial terms- are substantial.
                There are no punishments for not sharing information. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> uphold a
                "need-to-know" culture of information protection rather than promoting a
                "need-to-share" culture of integration.
            
            
                Recommendation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX> procedures should provide incentives for
                    sharing, to restore a better balance between security and shared knowledge.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> gathered about transnational terrorism should be processed, turned into
                reports, and distributed according to the same quality standards, whether it is
                collected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.
            The logical objection is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and methods may vary greatly in different
                locations. We therefore propose that when a report is first created, its data be
                separated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> and methods by which they are obtained. The report should
                begin with the information in its most shareable, but still meaningful, form.
                Therefore the maximum number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> can access some form of that information.
                If knowledge of further details becomes important, any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> can query further, with
                access granted or denied according to the rules set for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>-and with queries
                leaving an audit trail in order to determine who accessed the information. But the
                questions may not come at all unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> at the "edge" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> can
                readily discover the clues that prompt to them.
            
            We propose that information be shared horizontally, across new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> that
                transcend individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
            
                The current system is structured on an old mainframe, or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hub</ENAMEX>-andspoke,
                    concept. In this older approach, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has its own database. Agency users
                    send information to the database and then can retrieve it from the database.
                A decentralized network model, the concept behind much of the information
                    revolution, shares data horizontally too. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies</ENAMEX> would still have their own
                    databases, but those databases would be searchable across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> lines. In this
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, secrets are protected through the design of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and an
                    "information rights management" approach that controls access to the data, not
                    access to the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>. An outstanding conceptual framework for this kind
                    of "trusted information network" has been developed by a task force of leading
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> in national security, information technology, and law assembled by
                    the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Markle Foundation</ENAMEX>. Its report has been widely discussed throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                    government, but has not yet been converted into action.
                
            
            
                Recommendation: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>-wide effort
                    to bring the major national security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> into the information
                    revolution. He should coordinate the resolution of the legal, policy, and
                    technical issues across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to create a "trusted information network."
            
            
                No one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> can do it alone. Well-meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are under
                    tremendous pressure to update their systems. Alone, they may only be able to
                    modernize the stovepipes, not replace them.
                Only presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> can develop government-wide concepts and
                    standards. Currently, no one is doing this job. Backed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX>, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> empowered to set
                    common standards for information use throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and a secretary
                    of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security who helps extend the system to public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and relevant
                    private-sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">databases</ENAMEX>, a government-wide initiative can succeed.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is also needed because the policy and legal issues are
                    harder than the technical ones. The necessary technology already exists. What
                    does not are the rules for acquiring, accessing, sharing, and using the vast
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> of public and private data that may be available. When information
                    sharing works, it is a powerful tool. Therefore the sharing and uses of
                    information must be guided by a set of practical policy guidelines that
                    simultaneously empower and constrain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, telling them clearly what is and
                    is not permitted.
            
            "This is government acting in new ways, to face new threats," the most recent Markle
                report explains." And while such change is necessary, it must be accomplished while
                engendering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> that privacy and other civil liberties are being
                protected, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are not being unduly burdened with requests for
                extraneous or useless information, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> money is being well spent, and
                that, ultimately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> will be effective in protecting our security." The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> add: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leadership</ENAMEX> is emerging from all levels of government and from many
                places in the private sector. What is needed now is a plan to accelerate these
                efforts, and public debate and consensus on the goals."
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITY OF EFFORT</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONGRESS</ENAMEX>
            Strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Oversight of Intelligence and Homeland Security</ENAMEX>
            Of all our recommendations, strengthening congressional oversight may be among the
                most difficult and important. So long as oversight is governed by current
                congressional rules and resolutions, we believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will not get the
                security they want and need. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> needs a strong, stable, and capable
                congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> structure to give <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s national intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oversight</ENAMEX>, support, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. Few things are more difficult to change in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> than congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> jurisdiction and prerogatives. To a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>,
                these assignments are almost as important as the map of his or her congressional
                district. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may have to insist that these changes occur, or they
                may well not happen. Having interviewed numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> from both
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, as well as congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff members</ENAMEX>, we found that dissatisfaction with
                congressional oversight remains widespread.
            The future challenges of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are daunting. They include
                the need to develop leading-edge technologies that give our policymakers and
                warfighters a decisive edge in any conflict where the interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
                are vital. Not only does good intelligence win wars, but the best intelligence
                enables us to prevent them from happening altogether. Under the terms of existing
                rules and resolutions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> lack the power,
                influence, and sustained capability to meet this challenge. While few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> have the broad knowledge of intelligence activities or the know-how about
                the technologies employed, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> need to feel assured that good oversight is
                happening. When their unfamiliarity with the subject is combined with the need to
                preserve security, a mandate emerges for substantial change.
            Tinkering with the existing structure is not sufficient. Either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should
                create a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> for intelligence, using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Atomic Energy Committee</ENAMEX>
                as its model, or it should create <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> with combined
                authorizing and appropriations powers.
            Whichever of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forms are chosen, the goal should be a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>- codified by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> with powers expressly granted and carefully limited- allowing a
                relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, given time and reason to master the
                subject and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, to conduct oversight of the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> and
                be clearly accountable for their work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> should be
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonpartisan</ENAMEX> and work for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> and not for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
            The other reforms we have suggested-for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Counterterrorism Center</ENAMEX> and a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>-will not work if congressional oversight does not
                change too. Unity of effort in executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> can be lost if it is fractured
                by divided congressional oversight.
            
                Recommendation: Congressional oversight for intelligence-and
                    counterterrorism-is now dysfunctional. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should address this problem. We
                    have considered various alternatives: A joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX> model of the
