
    
        
            FROM THREAT TO THREAT
            In chapters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 and 4</TIMEX> we described how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> adjusted its existing
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> and capacities to address the emerging threat from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and his
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>. After the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX> bombings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and his chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> explored ways of getting Bin
                Ladin expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> or possibly capturing or even killing him. Although
                disruption efforts around the world had achieved some successes, the core of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> remained intact. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was deeply concerned about
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. He and his national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel "Sandy" Berger</ENAMEX>, ensured they
                had a special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> pipeline of reports feeding them the latest updates on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin's</ENAMEX> reported location.
            
            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spoke repeatedly about the threat of terrorism,
                referring to terrorist training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> but saying little about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and nothing
                about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. He explained to us that this was deliberate-intended to avoid
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enhancing Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s stature by giving him unnecessary publicity. His speeches
                focused especially on the danger of nonstate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and of chemical and biological
                    weapons.
            
            As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> approached, the most publicized worries were not about terrorism
                but about computer breakdowns-the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Y2K</ENAMEX> scare. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were
                concerned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> would take advantage of such breakdowns.
            
            THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MILLENNIUM CRISIS</ENAMEX>
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bodies Will Pile Up in Sacks</ENAMEX>"
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 30, 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> intelligence intercepted a telephone call between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu</ENAMEX>
                Zubaydah, a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khadr Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> said, "The time for training is over." Suspecting that this
                was a signal for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> to commence a terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> police
                arrested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> others and informed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raed Hijazi</ENAMEX>, had been born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>; after
                spending his childhood in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, he had returned to northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
                taken refuge in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islamist</ENAMEX> beliefs, and then made his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khaldan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, where he learned the fundamentals of guerrilla warfare.
                He and his younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had been recruited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> into a loosely knit plot
                to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>.
            
            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1996</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> was arrested and jailed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijazi</ENAMEX> moved back to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, worked as a cabdriver in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, and sent money back to his fellow
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plotters</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX>'s release, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijazi</ENAMEX> shuttled between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
                gathering money and supplies. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX>, he recruited inTurkey and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> as
                well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>; with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah's</ENAMEX> assistance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> sent these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> for training.
            
            In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijazi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> had settled on a plan. They would <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> attack
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS Radisson Hotel</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX>, the border crossings from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> holy sites, at a time when all these locations
                were likely to be thronged with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. Next, they would target
                a local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> and other religious and cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijazi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> cased
                the intended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> and sent reports to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX>, who approved their plan.
                Finally, back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijazi</ENAMEX> gradually accumulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-making
                materials, including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfuric acid</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5,200 pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nitric acid</ENAMEX>, which were then
                stored in an enormous subbasement dug by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plotters</ENAMEX> over a period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>
                underneath a rented <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijazi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalil Deek</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and
                an associate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> who lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peshawar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, and who, with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>, had created an electronic version of a terrorist
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manual</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Encyclopedia of Jihad</ENAMEX>. They obtained a CD-ROM of this encyclopedia from
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deek</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, with help from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> arranged with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijazi</ENAMEX> and
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> others to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> for added training in handling explosives. In late
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hijazi</ENAMEX> reportedly swore before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Zubaydah the bayat to Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">committing</ENAMEX> himself to do anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> ordered. He then departed for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> and
                was at a waypoint in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> the message that
                prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to roll up the whole cell.
            
            After the arrests of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Hoshar</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> others, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordanians</ENAMEX> tracked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deek</ENAMEX> to
                Peshawar, persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to extradite him, and added him to their catch.
                Searches in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX> found the rented <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and, among other things, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX> drums of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>,
                several forged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> passports, detonators, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deek's Encyclopedia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> of the
                accomplices were sentenced to death. In custody, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijazi</ENAMEX>'s younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> said that
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s motto had been "The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> is coming, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> will pile up in
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sacks</ENAMEX>."
            
            Diplomacy and Disruption
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 4</TIMEX>, as news came in about the discoveries in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Counterterrorism Coordinator Richard Clarke</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX>, "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>'s
                [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenet</ENAMEX>'s] story about a planned series of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">UBL attacks</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX> is true, we
                will need to make some decisions NOW." He told us he held several conversations with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> during the crisis. He suggested threatening reprisals against the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in the event of any attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests, anywhere, by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. He further proposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> that a strike be made during the last week
                of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>-a proposal not adopted.
            
            Warned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> that the disrupted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> plot was probably part of a larger
                series of attacks intended for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, some possibly involving chemical
                weapons, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Principals Committee</ENAMEX> met on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 8</TIMEX> and decided to task
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Security Group</ENAMEX> (CSG) to develop plans to deter and disrupt
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> plots.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sheehan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX>, communicated warnings to the
                Taliban that they would be held responsible for future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> attacks." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> was
                not diplomatic," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX>. With virtually no evidence of a Taliban
                response, a new approach was made to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Zinni</ENAMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Command</ENAMEX> (CENTCOM), was designated as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s special
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> and sent to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Musharraf</ENAMEX> to "take whatever action you deem necessary
                to resolve the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> problem at the earliest possible time." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zinni</ENAMEX> came back
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emptyhanded</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Milam</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musharraf</ENAMEX> was
                "unwilling to take the political heat at home."
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> worked hard with foreign security services to detain or at least keep an eye
                on suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenet</ENAMEX> spoke to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> of his foreign counterparts.
                Disruption and arrest operations were mounted against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight</TIMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-December</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Memorandum of Notification</ENAMEX> (MON) giving
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> broader authority to use foreign proxies to detain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX>,
                without having to transfer them to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> custody. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> was to capture, not
                kill, though lethal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> might be used if necessary<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenet</ENAMEX> would later send a
                message to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> overseas, saying, "The threat could not be more real. .
                . . Do whatever is necessary to disrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UBL</ENAMEX>'s plans. . . . The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
                counting on you and me to take every appropriate step to protect them during this
                period." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> issued a worldwide threat advisory to its posts
                    overseas.
            
            Then, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 14</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jihadist</ENAMEX> was caught bringing a load of explosives
                into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s Arrest
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Ressam</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>, had illegally immigrated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. Using a falsified
                passport and a bogus story about persecution in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX> entered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> and
                claimed political asylum. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX> he supported himself with petty
                crime. Recruited by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumnus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Zubaydah's Khaldan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> trained in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, learning, among other things, how to place cyanide near the air
                intake of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to achieve maximum lethality at minimum personal risk. Having
                joined other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algerians</ENAMEX> in planning a possible attack on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> or consulate,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1999</TIMEX> carrying precursor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> for explosives
                disguised in toiletry bottles, a notebook containing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> assembly instructions, and
                <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX>. Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, he went about procuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, and false
                    papers.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early summer 1999</TIMEX>, having learned that not all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> could get the
                travel documents to enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> decided to carry out the plan alone. By the
                end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> he had chosen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles-area</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> as potential
                targets, ultimately fixing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles International</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAX</ENAMEX>) as the largest and
                easiest to operate in surreptitiously. He bought or stole chemicals and equipment
                for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, obtaining advice from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, all of whom were wanted
                by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for their roles in past terrorist attacks there. Ressam
                also acquired new confederates. He promised to help a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdelghani Meskini</ENAMEX>, get training in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meskini</ENAMEX> would help him maneuver
                in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> began his final preparations. He called an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>-based
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilitator</ENAMEX> to inquire into whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> wanted to take credit for the attack,
                but he did not get a reply. He spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX> preparing the explosive
                components with a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> were so caustic that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> kept
                their windows open, despite the freezing temperatures outside, and sucked on cough
                drops to soothe their irritated throats.
            
            While in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> also rented a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX> for his travel into the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, and packed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> in the trunk's spare tire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX>.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 14, 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX> drove his rental car onto the ferry from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> planned to drive to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> and meet
                Meskini, with whom he would travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and case
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Case Study in Terrorist Travel</ENAMEX>
            Following a familiar terrorist pattern, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> used fraudulent
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passports</ENAMEX> and immigration fraud to travel. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s case, this involved flying
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> using a photo-substituted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> passport under a false
                name. Under questioning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX> admitted the passport was fraudulent and claimed
                political asylum. He was released pending a hearing, which he failed to attend. His
                political asylum claim was denied. He was arrested again, released again, and given
                another hearing date. Again, he did not show. He was arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times for
                thievery, usually from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, but was neither jailed nor deported. He also
                supported himself by selling stolen documents to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was a document broker
                for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> eventually obtained a genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> passport through a document <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> who
                stole a blank baptismal certificate from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. With this document he
                was able to obtain a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> passport under the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benni Antoine Noris</ENAMEX>. This
                enabled him to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, and from there to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> for his training,
                and then return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. Impressed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Zubaydah</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> to get more genuine
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> passports and to send them to him for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> to use.
            
            Another conspirator, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdelghani Meskini</ENAMEX>, used a stolen identity to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
                on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 11, 1999</TIMEX>, at the request of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mokhtar Haouari</ENAMEX>, another conspirator.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haouari</ENAMEX> provided fraudulent passports and visas to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ressam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meskini</ENAMEX>'s
                planned getaway from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meskini</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdel HakimTizegha</ENAMEX>, also filed a claim for political
                asylum. He was released pending a hearing, which was adjourned and rescheduled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
                times. His claim was finally denied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> after his initial filing. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
                appealed the decision, andTizegha was allowed to remain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> pending the
                appeal. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine months later</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> notified the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that he could not locate
                his client. A warrant of deportation was issued.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAX</ENAMEX>. They planned to detonate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> on or around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2000</TIMEX>. At the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>) preinspection <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX> presented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> with his genuine but fraudulently obtained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
                passport, from which he had torn the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> entry and exit stamps. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> on duty ran the passport through a variety of databases but, since it was not
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s name, he did not pick up the pending <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> arrest warrants. After a
                cursory examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> to board the
                    ferry.
            
            Late in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 14</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Angeles</ENAMEX>. He waited for
                all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to depart the ferry, assuming (incorrectly) that the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> off
                would draw less scrutiny. Customs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> assigned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, noticing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s
                nervousness, referred him to secondary inspection. When asked for additional
                identification, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> handed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Price Costco</ENAMEX> membership card in
                the same false name as his passport. As that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> began an initial pat-down, Ressam
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">panicked</ENAMEX> and tried to run away.
            
            Inspectors examining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s rental car found the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives concealed</ENAMEX> in the spare
                tire well, but at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they assumed the white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder</ENAMEX> and viscous liquid were
                drug-related-until an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> pried apart and identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> timing
                devices concealed within black boxes. Ressam was placed under arrest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX>
                guessed his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. They did not learn about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> airport
                planning until they reexamined evidence seized in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>; they obtained
                further details when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX> began cooperating in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>.
            
            Emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooperation</ENAMEX>
            After the disruption of the plot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX>, it had not escaped notice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
                that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijazi</ENAMEX> had lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and driven a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deek</ENAMEX> was a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">naturalized U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> who, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, had been in
                touch with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as well as abroad.
            
            Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s arrest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> saw no need to raise a public alarm at home- although
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> put all field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> on alert.
            
            Now, following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s arrest, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> asked for an unprecedented number of special
                wiretaps. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> andTenet told us that their impression was that more Foreign
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Surveillance Act</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX>) wiretap requests were processed during the
                millennium alert than ever before.
            
            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, writing about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s arrest and links to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berger</ENAMEX>
                informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> would advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to step
                up activities but would still try to avoid undue public alarm by stressing that the
                government had no specific information about planned attacks.
            
            At a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 22</TIMEX> meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX>
                briefed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> on wiretaps and
                investigations inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> tied to the
                Ressam arrest, a seemingly unreliable foreign report of possible attacks on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerians</ENAMEX> detained on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> border, and searches in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>
                related to a jihadist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> released a statement on the alert
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same day</TIMEX>.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> warned, "Foreign terrorist sleeper cells are present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and
                attacks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> are likely." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> to try
                to make sure that the domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> remained alert." Is there a threat to
                civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>?"he wrote. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> also asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> in late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> to
                discuss a foreign security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> report about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> plan to put bombs on
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transatlantic</ENAMEX> flights.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> met constantly.
            
            Later, when asked what made her decide to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX> to step out of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Dean</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> who referred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> to secondary inspection,
                testified that it was her "training and experience." It
                appears that the heightened sense of alert at the national level played no role in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s detention.
            There was a mounting sense of public alarm. The earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> arrests had been
                covered in the press, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s arrest was featured on network <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> news
                broadcasts throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas season</TIMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> was more communicative during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> crisis than it had ever been.
                The senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> for counterterrorism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Watson</ENAMEX>, was a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> had good relations both with him and with some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handling al Qaeda</ENAMEX>-related investigations, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John O'Neill</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. As a
                rule, however, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX> nor these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> brought much information to the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> simply did not produce the kind of intelligence reports that other
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> routinely wrote and disseminated. As law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> tended to write up only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> interviews. Written case analysis usually
                occurred only in memoranda to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> requesting authority to initiate or expand
                an investigation.
            
            But during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> alert, with its direct links into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from
                Hijazi, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deek</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ressam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were briefing in person about ongoing
                investigations, not relying on the dissemination of written reports. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> told us
                that it was hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to hold back information in front of a
                cabinet-rank <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. After the alert, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>
                staff, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> returned to its normal practice of withholding written reports and
                saying little about investigations or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> interviews, taking the position that
                any information related to pending investigations might be presented to a grand jury
                and hence could not be disclosed under thenprevailing federal law.
            
            The terrorist plots that were broken up at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1999</TIMEX> display the variety of
                operations that might be attributed, however indirectly, to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX>
                cell was a loose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX>; we now know that it sought approval and training from
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> swore loyalty to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. But the cell's
                plans and preparations were autonomous. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> were even looser.
                Though he had been recruited, trained, and prepared in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> affiliated with the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s own plans were, nonetheless, essentially
                independent.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> himself, did have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> of their very own in
                mind for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> period. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 5</ENAMEX> we introduced an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> operative
                named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nashiri</ENAMEX>. Working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, he was developing a plan to attack a ship
                near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3</TIMEX>, an attempt was made to attack a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>warship in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Aden</ENAMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS The Sullivans</ENAMEX>. The attempt failed when the small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, overloaded with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explosives</ENAMEX>, sank. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> salvaged their equipment without the attempt
                becoming known, and they put off their plans for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX>.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>" was also coming along. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> caught a glimpse of its preparations.
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lost Trail</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>
            In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX>) analyzed communications associated
                with a suspected terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, indicating that several
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of "an operational cadre" were planning to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> in early
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>. Initially, only the first names of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> were
                known-"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf</ENAMEX>,""<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem</ENAMEX>,"and"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> surmised correctly that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX> was
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nawaf</ENAMEX> 's younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. Seeing links not only with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> but specifically with
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> embassy bombings, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> desk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> guessed that "something more nefarious
                [was] afoot."
            
            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 5</ENAMEX>, we discussed the dispatch of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for
                their part in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> operation-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX>. Two more,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khallad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abu Bara</ENAMEX>, went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> to case flights for the part of the
                operation that was supposed to unfold there.
            
            All made their way to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, except for
                Mihdhar, who traveled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>.
            
            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nawaf</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> was temporarily lost, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> soon identified"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Khalid</ENAMEX>" as Khalid
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Mihdhar</ENAMEX>.
            
            He was located leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> and tracked until he arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2000.45</NUMEX> Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>, unidentified at the time, were watched as they gathered with
                him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>.
            
            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 8</TIMEX>, the surveillance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> had suddenly
                left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> on a short flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>.
            
            They identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>. They later learned that one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX> was
                named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alhazmi</ENAMEX>, although it was not yet known that he was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf</ENAMEX>." The only
                identifier available for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was part of a name-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salahsae</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> received the information too late to track the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as
                they came in, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> disappeared into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> (CTC) had briefed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> on the gathering in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>, and the information had been passed on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
                to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> and others at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> (though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had the
                lead and would let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> know if a domestic angle arose). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> kept providing updates, unaware at first even that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> had left
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>, let alone that their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> had been lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>.
            
            When this bad news arrived, the names were put on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> watchlist so that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> could inform the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> if any of them departed from
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>.
            
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several weeks later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX> prodded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> for
                additional information regarding the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early March 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaf al Hazmi</ENAMEX>, now identified for the
                <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time with his full name, had departed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 15</TIMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX>
                flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid al Mihdhar</ENAMEX>, there was no report of his
                departure even though he had accompanied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazmi</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>.
            
            No one outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX> was told any of this. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> did not
                try to register <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mihdhar</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIPOFF</ENAMEX> watchlist-either
                in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, when word arrived of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s visa, or in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, when word came that
                Hazmi, too, had had a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa and a ticket to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>.
            
            None of this information-about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mihdhar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> visa or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazmi</ENAMEX>'s travel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>-went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, and nothing more was done to track any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> until
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>, when the investigation of another bombing, that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Cole</ENAMEX>,
                reignited interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khallad</ENAMEX>. We will return to that story in chapter 8.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POST-CRISIS REFLECTION</ENAMEX>: AGENDA FOR <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> alert, elements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> reviewed their
                performance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> was told that while a number of plots had been
                disrupted, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> might be only the "kick-off " for a period of extended
                    attacks.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 11, 2000</TIMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>
                staff had come to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main conclusions. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> disruption efforts thus far had
                "not put too much of a dent" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s network. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> wanted to
                "roll back" the threat, disruption would have to proceed at "a markedly different
                tempo." <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,"sleeper cells" and "a variety of terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>" had turned up at
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
            
            As one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> noted, only a "chance discovery" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Customs</ENAMEX> had
                prevented a possible attack.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> gave his approval for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to commence an "afteraction review,"
                anticipating new budget requests. He also asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI Tenet</ENAMEX> to review the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s
                counterterrorism strategy and come up with a plan for"where we go from here."
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had only been "nibbling at the
                edges" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and that more terror attacks were a question not of
                "if "but rather of "when"and "where."59The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Principals Committee</ENAMEX> met on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>,
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, to review possible new moves. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> ended up agreeing that the
                government should take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major steps. First, more money should go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to
                accelerate its efforts to "seriously attrit" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, there should be a
                crackdown on foreign terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>,
                immigration law enforcement should be strengthened, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> should tighten
                controls on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> border (including stepping up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> cooperation). The
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">principals</ENAMEX> endorsed the proposed programs; some, like expanding the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism Task Forces</ENAMEX>, moved forward, and others, like creating a centralized
                translation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> for domestic intelligence intercepts in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> and other languages,
                did not.
            
            Pressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
            While this process moved along, diplomacy continued its rounds. Direct pressure on
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> had proved unsuccessful. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> note put it,
            "Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> is not so much a state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of terrorism as it is
                a state sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2000</TIMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> began a high-level effort to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to use its influence
                over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Inderfurth</ENAMEX> and
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s counterterrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sheehan</ENAMEX>, met with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Musharraf</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX>, dangling before him the possibility of a
                presidential visit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> as a reward for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> cooperation. Such a visit was
                coveted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musharraf</ENAMEX>, partly as a sign of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s legitimacy. He told the
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoys</ENAMEX> that he would meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mullah Omar</ENAMEX> and press him on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. They
                left, however, reporting to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> was unlikely in fact to do
                anything," given what it sees as the benefits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> control of
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>."
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was scheduled to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> felt that he
                should not visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> without also visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> and the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, however, warned in the strongest terms that visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> would risk the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s life. Counterterrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> also argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> had not done
                enough to merit a presidential visit. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> insisted on including
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> in the itinerary for his trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX>.
            
            His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> stopover on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25, 2000</TIMEX>, was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had been
                there since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. At his meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musharraf</ENAMEX> and others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
                concentrated on tensions between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and the dangers of nuclear
                proliferation, but also discussed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told us that when he
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pulled Musharraf</ENAMEX> aside for a brief, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> meeting, he pleaded with the general
                for help regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>." I offered him the moon when I went to see him, in
                terms of better relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, if he'd help us get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and
                deal with another issue or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>."
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> effort continued. Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musharraf</ENAMEX> to carry
                through on his promise to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mullah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar</ENAMEX> to expel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladin</ENAMEX>.
            
            At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX>, Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pickering</ENAMEX> followed up with a
                trip to the region.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCI Tenet</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> with the same general message.
            
            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was becoming openly critical of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> for
                supporting a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taliban</ENAMEX> military offensive aimed at completing the conquest of
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, taking a step proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some months earlier</TIMEX>, the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> led a campaign for new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> sanctions, which resulted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN Security</ENAMEX>
                Council Resolution <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1333</TIMEX>, again calling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s expulsion and forbidding any
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> or military assistance.
            
            This, too, had little if any effect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> did not expel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pakistani</ENAMEX>
                arms continued to flow across the border.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> told us, "We did not have a strong hand to play
                with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistanis</ENAMEX>. Because of the sanctions required by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law, we had few
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carrots</ENAMEX> to offer." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> had blocked most economic and
                military aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> because of that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> program and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musharraf</ENAMEX> 's coup. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehan</ENAMEX> was critical of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musharraf</ENAMEX>, telling us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> "blew a chance to remake <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>."
            
            Building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Capabilities</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
            The after-action review had treated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> as the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for any offensive
                against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>, at their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX> meeting, had endorsed
                strengthening the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s capability for that role. To the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX>, that meant proceeding
                with "the Plan," which it had put forward <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</TIMEX>-hiring and training
                more case <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and building up the capabilities of foreign security services
                that provided intelligence via liaison. On occasion, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>,
                these liaison services took direct action against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> cells.
            
            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> and higher up, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> believed that they desperately needed
                funds just to continue their current counterterrorism effort, for they reckoned that
                the millennium alert had already used up all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>'s funds for the current
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> had spent <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">140 percent</NUMEX> of its allocation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenet</ENAMEX> told
                us he met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> to discuss funding for counterterrorism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two days</TIMEX> after
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>' meeting.
            
            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> strongly favored giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> more money for counterterrorism, he
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differed</ENAMEX> sharply with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> about where it should come from. They
                insisted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had been shortchanged ever since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.
                Their ability to perform any mission, counterterrorism included, they argued,
                depended on preserving what they had, restoring what they had lost since the
                beginning of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, and building from there-with across-the-board recruitment
                and training of new case <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, and the reopening of closed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. To finance
                the counterterrorism effort, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenet</ENAMEX> had gone to congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings and persuaded them to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> a special supplemental
                appropriation. Now, in the aftermath of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> alert, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenet</ENAMEX> wanted a boost
                in overall funds for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and another supplemental appropriation specifically for
                    counterterrorism.
            
            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>, this seemed evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> did not give sufficient
                priority to the battle against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. He told us that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Pavitt</ENAMEX>,
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directorate of Operations</ENAMEX>, "said if there's going to be money
                spent on going after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, it should be given to him. . . . My view was that he
                had had a lot of money to do it and a long time to do it, and I didn't want to put
                more good money after bad."
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had a very different attitude: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavitt</ENAMEX> told us that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                unit did"extraordinary and commendable work," his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of station in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> "was
                just as much part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> struggle as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> sitting in [the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>
                    unit]."
            
            The dispute had large managerial implications, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> had found <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>). They had supplied him with the figures he
                used to argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> spending on counterterrorism from its baseline budget had
                shown almost no increase.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> met twice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenet</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> to try to resolve the dispute. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deputies</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later in the month</TIMEX> to review <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000 and 2001</TIMEX> budget
                priorities and offsets for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>,
            Tenet obtained a modest supplemental appropriation, which funded counterterrorism
                without requiring much reprogramming of baseline funds. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> still believed
                that it remained underfunded for counterterrorism.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorist Financing</ENAMEX>
            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> major point on which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> had agreed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX> was the need to
                crack down on terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and curtail their fund-raising. The embassy
                bombings of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> had focused attention on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s finances. One result had been
                the creation of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>-led interagency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> on terrorist financing. On its
                recommendation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> had designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> as subject to
                search for and freeze any <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> assets that reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                financial system. But since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OFAC</ENAMEX> had little information to go on, few funds were
                    frozen.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> applied the same designation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> for harboring
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>. Here, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OFAC</ENAMEX> had more success. It blocked <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $34 million</NUMEX> in Taliban
                assets held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. Another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$215 million</NUMEX> in gold and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in demand
                deposits, all belonging to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> central bank and held by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>, were also frozen.
            
            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1999</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> formally designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> a "foreign
                terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>," it became the duty of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to block its transactions
                and seize its funds.
            
            Neither this designation nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> sanctions had much additional practical effect; the
                sanctions were easily circumvented, and there were no multilateral mechanisms to
                ensure that other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> were not used as conduits for
                terrorist funding.
            
            Attacking the funds of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>, was easier than finding and
                seizing the funds of a clandestine worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. Although
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> had originally been inspired by the idea of studying
                terrorist financial links, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> assigned to it had any experience in
                financial investigations. Any terrorist-financing intelligence appeared to have been
                collected collaterally, as a consequence of gathering other intelligence. This
                attitude may have stemmed in large part from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, who did not
                believe that simply following the money from point A to point B revealed much about
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>' plans and intentions. As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> placed little emphasis on
                terrorist financing.
            
            Nevertheless, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> obtained a general understanding of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> raised money.
                It knew relatively early, for example, about the loose affiliation of financial
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, and wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
                    activities.
            
            Much of the early reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s financial situation and its structure came
                from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamal Ahmed al Fadl</ENAMEX>, whom we have mentioned earlier in the report.
            
            After the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> embassy bombings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> tried to develop a clearer
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">picture of Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s finances. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interagency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>
                twice, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999 and 2000</TIMEX>, to get information from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudis</ENAMEX> about their
                understanding of those finances. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> eventually concluded that the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oft-</ENAMEX>repeated assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> from his personal fortune
                was in fact not true. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> developed a new theory: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> was getting its
                money elsewhere, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> needed to focus on other sources of funding,
                such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>, wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, and financial facilitators. Ultimately, although
                the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> devoted more resources to the issue and produced somewhat
                more intelligence, it remained difficult to distinguish
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s financial transactions among the vast sums moving in the international
                financial system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> was not able to find or disrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>'s money
                    flows.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> thought that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> possible solution to these weaknesses in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> was to create an all-source terrorist-financing intelligence
                analysis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> pushed for the funding of such a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>, but
                neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> was willing to commit the resources.
            
            Within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> gathered intelligence on
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">organizations</ENAMEX> suspected of raising funds for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> or other terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. By
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> understood that there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist organizations</ENAMEX> operating within
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> supporting a global jihadist movement and with substantial
                connections to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> operated a web of informants, conducted electronic
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surveillance</ENAMEX>, and had opened significant investigations in a number of field
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>. On a
                national level, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> never used the information to gain a systematic or
                strategic understanding of the nature and extent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> fundraising.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">financial institutions</ENAMEX>, were generally focused
                on finding and deterring or disrupting the vast flows of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> currency generated by
                drug trafficking and high-level international fraud. Large-scale scandals, such as
                the use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">money launderers</ENAMEX> to move <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
                dollars out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, captured the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of the Treasury</ENAMEX> and
                of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
            
            Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> did not consider terrorist financing important enough to
                mention in its national strategy for money laundering.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Security</ENAMEX>
            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> point on which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> had agreed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX> was the need for
                attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s porous borders and the weak enforcement of immigration laws.
                Drawing on ideas from government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> developed a menu
                of proposals to bolster border security. Some reworked or reiterated previous
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presidential</ENAMEX> directives.
            
            They included 
            
                creating an interagency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> to target illegal entry and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human traffickers</ENAMEX>;
                imposing tighter controls on student visas;
                
                taking legal action to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> from coming into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
                    and to remove those already here, detaining them while awaiting removal
                        proceedings;
                
                further increasing the number of immigration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI JointTerrorism Task</ENAMEX>
                    <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Forces</ENAMEX> to help investigate immigration charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> suspected of
                        terrorism;
                
                activating a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to enable the use of classified evidence in
                    immigration-related national security cases; and
                both implementing new security measures for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> passports and working with
                    the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to raise global security standards
                    for travel documents.
                
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> compiled new proposals as well, such as 
            
                undertaking a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Perimeter Defense</ENAMEX> program with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> to establish
                    cooperative intelligence and law enforcement programs, leading to joint
                    operations based on shared visa and immigration data and joint border <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrols</ENAMEX>;
                staffing land border <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">crossings 24/7</NUMEX> and equipping them with video cameras,
                    physical barriers, and means to detect <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction (WMD); and
                addressing the problem of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">migrants</ENAMEX>-possibly including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>- who destroy
                    their travel documents so they cannot be returned to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of
                        origin.
                
            
            These proposals were praiseworthy in principle. In practice, however, they required
                action by weak, chronically underfunded executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and powerful
                congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, which were more responsive to well-organized interest
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> than to executive branch interagency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>. The changes sought by the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX> were only beginning to occur before 9/11.
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Afghan Eyes</ENAMEX>"
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early March 2000</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> received an update on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>covert action
                efforts against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, he wrote in the memo's margin that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
                could surely do better. Military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Staff</ENAMEX> told us that they
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> this sense of frustration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> used the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s comment to push the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> to brainstorm new ideas, including aid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Alliance</ENAMEX>.
            
            Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Alliance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Shah Massoud</ENAMEX> had offered to
                stage a rocket attack against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Derunta</ENAMEX> training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX> at the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had worried that giving him a green light might cross the line into violation of
                the assassination ban. Hence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massoud</ENAMEX> was told not to take any such action without
                explicit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> authorization.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 2000</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had sent out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to explore possible closer
                relationships with both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uzbeks</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Alliance</ENAMEX>, discussions took place
                in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massoud</ENAMEX>.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massoud</ENAMEX> should get some modest technical help so he could
                work on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> priorities-collecting intelligence on and possibly acting against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qaeda</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massoud</ENAMEX> wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> both to become his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> in trying to
                overthrow theTaliban and to recognize that they were fighting common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Clarke</ENAMEX>
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cofer Black</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Counterterrorist Center</ENAMEX>, wanted to take this next
                step. Proposals to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Alliance</ENAMEX> had been debated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
                government since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> and, as we mentioned in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 4</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as a
                whole had been wary of endorsing them, largely because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Alliance</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">checkered</ENAMEX> history, its limited base of popular support in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s objections.
            
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> also began pressing proposals to use their ties with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance</ENAMEX> to get <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> on the ground in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> for an extended period,
                setting up their own base for covert intelligence collection and activity in the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panjshir Valley</ENAMEX> and lessening reliance on foreign proxies." There's no substitute
                for face-to-face," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> told us.
            
            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s institutional capacity for such direct action was weak, especially if
                it was not working jointly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. The idea was turned down as too
                    risky.
            
            In the meantime, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> continued to work with its tribal assets in southern
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early August</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribals</ENAMEX> reported an attempt to ambush <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">convoy</ENAMEX> as he traveled on the road between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kabul</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kandahar city</ENAMEX>- their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such
                reported interdiction attempt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year and a half</TIMEX>. But it was not a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribals</ENAMEX>' own account, when they approached one of the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vehicles</ENAMEX>, they quickly determined that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were inside and called off
                the ambush. Conveying this information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> noted that they had
                no independent corroboration for this incident, but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribals</ENAMEX> had acted
                within the terms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, plans continued to be developed for potential military operations in
                <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> that could launch <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> were still on
                call in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north Arabian Sea</ENAMEX>.
            
            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, the military refined its list of strikes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Operations</ENAMEX>
                possibilities to a set of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> options within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Infinite Resolve</ENAMEX>
                    plan.
            
            Yet planning efforts continued to be limited by the same operational and policy
                concerns encountered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 and 1999</TIMEX>. Although the intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> sometimes
                knew where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> was, it had been unable to provide intelligence considered
                sufficiently reliable to launch a strike. Above all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> did not have
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> eyes on the target. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> put it, we had our hand on the
                door, but we couldn't open the door and walk in.
            
            At some point during this period, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> expressed his frustration with
                the lack of military options to take out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al Qaeda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>,
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">remarking</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Shelton</ENAMEX>, "You know, it would scare the shit out of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Qaeda</ENAMEX> if suddenly a bunch of black ninjas rappelled out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> into the
                middle of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>."<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">109</NUMEX> Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelton</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> he did not remember
                the statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> recalled this remark as "one of the many things I
                said." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> added, however, that he realized nothing would be accomplished
                if he lashed out in anger. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> thought that the
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> might have been making a hypothetical statement. Regardless, he said, the
                question remained how to get the "ninjas" into and out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> of
                    operations.
            
            As discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter 4</ENAMEX>, plans of this kind were never carried out before 9/11.
            In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Staff</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of operations, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vice Admiral</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Fry</ENAMEX>, directed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief information operations officer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigadier General</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Gration</ENAMEX>, to develop innovative ways to get better intelligence on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s
                whereabouts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gration</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> worked on a number of different ideas aimed at
                getting reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> eyes on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> in a way that would reduce the lag time
                between sighting and striking.
            
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> option was to use a small, unmanned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">drone</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Predator</ENAMEX>,
                which could survey the territory below and send back video footage. Another
                option-eventually dismissed as impractical-was to place a powerful long-range
                telescope on a mountain within range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>'s training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. Both
                proposals were discussed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Shelton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs of</ENAMEX>
                Staff, and then briefed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSG</ENAMEX> was
                searching for new ideas. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> brought in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s
                assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for collection, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Allen</ENAMEX>, to work together with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fry</ENAMEX> on a
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">joint CIA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> effort that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> dubbed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Afghan Eyes</ENAMEX>." After much argument between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> about
                who should pay for the program, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> eventually imposed a cost-sharing
                agreement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> agreed to pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Predator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-day</TIMEX> "proof of
                concept" trial run.
            
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Group</ENAMEX> backed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Eyes</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of June 2000</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-July</TIMEX>, testing was
                completed and the equipment was ready, but legal issues were still being ironed
                    out.
            
