
    
        
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PREFACE</ENAMEX>
            We present the narrative of this report and the recommendations that flow from it to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for their consideration. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Commissioners</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> chosen by elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> from our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital at a time of great
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partisan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>-have come together to present this report without dissent.
            We have come together with a unity of purpose because our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> demands it.
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>, was a day of unprecedented shock and suffering in the history of
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was unprepared. How did this happen, and how can we
                avoid such tragedy again?
            To answer these questions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> created the National
                Commission on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Terrorist Attacks Upon</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">107-306</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 2002</TIMEX>).
            Our mandate was sweeping. The law directed us to investigate "facts and circumstances
                relating to the terrorist attacks of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>," including those relating
                to intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, diplomacy, immigration issues
                and border control, the flow of assets to terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, commercial
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aviation</ENAMEX>, the role of congressional oversight and resource allocation, and other
                areas determined relevant by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>. In pursuing our mandate, we have
                reviewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2.5 million</NUMEX> pages of documents and interviewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,200</NUMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. This included nearly every senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> from the
                current and previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> who had responsibility for topics covered in
                our mandate. We have sought to be independent, impartial, thorough, and nonpartisan.
                From the outset, we have been committed to share as much of our investigation as we
                can with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. To that end, we held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 days</TIMEX> of hearings and took
                public testimony from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.
            Our aim has not been to assign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> blame. Our aim has been to provide the
                fullest possible account of the events surrounding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> and to identify lessons
                learned.
            We learned about an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> who is sophisticated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, disciplined, and lethal. The
                enemy rallies broad support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world by demanding redress of
                political grievances, but its hostility toward us and our values is limitless. Its
                purpose is to rid the world of religious and political pluralism, the plebiscite,
                and equal rights for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. It makes no distinction between military and civilian
                targets. Collateral damage is not in its lexicon.
            We learned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> charged with protecting our borders, civil aviation,
                and national security did not understand how grave this threat could be, and did not
                adjust their policies, plans, and practices to deter or defeat it. We learned of
                fault lines within our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>-between foreign and domestic intelligence, and
                between and within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. We learned of the pervasive problems of managing and
                sharing information across a large and unwieldy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that had been built in a
                different era to confront different dangers.
            At the outset of our work, we said we were looking backward in order to look forward.
                We hope that the terrible losses chronicled in this report can create something
                positive-an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that is safer, stronger, and wiser. That <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September day</TIMEX>, we came
                together as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. The test before us is to sustain that unity of purpose and
                meet the challenges now confronting us. We need to design a balanced strategy for
                the long haul, to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and prevent their ranks from swelling while at
                the same time protecting our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> against future attacks. We have been forced to
                think about the way our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is organized. The massive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that prevailed in the great struggles of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX> must work
                together in new ways, so that all the instruments of national power can be combined.
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> needs dramatic change as well to strengthen oversight and focus
                accountability.
            As we complete our final report, we want to begin by thanking our fellow
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Commissioners</ENAMEX>, whose dedication to this task has been profound. We have reasoned
                together over every page, and the report has benefited from this remarkable
                dialogue. We want to express our considerable respect for the intellect and judgment
                of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, as well as our great affection for them.
            We want to thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> staff. The dedicated professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, headed by
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Zelikow</ENAMEX>, has contributed innumerable <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to the completion of this report,
                setting aside other important endeavors to take on this all-consuming assignment.
                They have conducted the exacting investigative work upon which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has
                built. They have given good advice, and faithfully carried out our guidance. They
                have been superb. We thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. Executive branch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
                have searched records and produced a multitude of documents for us. We thank
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, past and present, who were generous with their time and provided us with
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PENTTBOM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Group</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, and
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspectors General</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> provided great
                assistance. We owe a huge debt to their investigative labors, painstaking attention
                to detail, and readiness to share what they have learned. We have built on the work
                of several previous Commissions, and we thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Joint Inquiry</ENAMEX>, whose
                fine work helped us get started. We thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX> for assistance with
                documents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Printing Office</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.W. Norton</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Company</ENAMEX> for helping to get this report to the broad public.
            We conclude this list of thanks by coming full circle: We thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>,
                whose persistence and dedication helped create the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>. They have been with
                us each step of the way, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. They know better than any of us
                the importance of the work we have undertaken.
            We want to note what we have done, and not done. We have endeavored to provide the
                most complete account we can of the events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11</TIMEX>, what happened and why.
                This final report is only a summary of what we have done, citing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a fraction of</TIMEX>
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> we have consulted. But in an event of this scale, touching so many
                issues and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, we are conscious of our limits. We have not interviewed
                every knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or found every relevant piece of paper. New information
                inevitably will come to light. We present this report as a foundation for a better
                understanding of a landmark in the history of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
            We have listened to scores of overwhelming personal tragedies and astounding acts of
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heroism</ENAMEX> and bravery. We have examined the staggering impact of the events of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> on
                the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their amazing resilience and courage as they fought back. We
                have admired their determination to do their best to prevent another tragedy while
                preparing to respond if it becomes necessary. We emerge from this investigation with
                enormous sympathy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> and their loved ones, and with enhanced respect
                for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. We recognize the formidable challenges that lie ahead.
            We also approach the task of recommendations with humility. We have made a limited
                number of them. We decided consciously to focus on recommendations we believe to be
                most important, whose implementation can make the greatest difference. We came into
                this process with strong opinions about what would work. All of us have had to
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pause</ENAMEX>, reflect, and sometimes change our minds as we studied these problems and
                considered the views of others. We hope our report will encourage our fellow
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to study, reflect-and act.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas H. Kean</ENAMEX>, chair
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee H. Hamilton</ENAMEX>, vice chair
        
    
