
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Evening</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yo</ENAMEX>-yos
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>:

            You are too generous about my Prudie credentials, but judging from the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> debate (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s being <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> away) I thought they were all
displaying manners up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ying-yang</ENAMEX>, to the point of ... well, being mannered.
Do manners matter in politics? I'm afraid not, though if one were to cross the
line in an extremely obvious way, negative reaction might bubble up--but not
necessarily because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> appeared to be rude but because he would appear to
be desperate. When it comes to the authenticity quotient, I--being older, if
not wiser--have pretty much written that off. All of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, are so cautious about image that whatever "real" characteristics
seep out they serve as kind of personality <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> leaves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is probably the
most "authentic," and even he's had a little coaching.

            Since I know you have a little time to kill before you go to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>,
I've rustled up the news equivalent of junk food to give you sustenance for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upcoming Evening of the Yo</ENAMEX>-yos. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuever</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> has a
dishy piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center Honors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX>, if you will. This
interested me because a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> (not one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>) was on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, and I always enjoyed the event. En passant I read
that the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz Carlton</ENAMEX> (nee the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax</ENAMEX>) has been rechristened the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fairfax</ENAMEX>. This interested me because a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> (one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>) used to
own it. Also of interest was our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> recalling his visit to the Parthenon
(owned by no one I was married to) wondering what our civilization's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monument</ENAMEX> would be. I'm guessing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>-story black beret.

            There are big doings in the divorce arena. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith Whittlesley</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> chum and twice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>) is divorcing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relly</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Neill</ENAMEX>. Putting aside that the once happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> might do well to
reside with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX> from whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> escaped, the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">frou-fra</ENAMEX> is
that heretofore secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Trust</ENAMEX> details may wind up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
court! And speaking of money, another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> has bought the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>
millennium package at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Ritz Carlton</ENAMEX>. (Nope, never married to him.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> said, looking forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, "I'll be drinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>." Well, I'm crossing my fingers that the dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is awake
when it's time for dinner. She has also requested "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>
entertainment." Wouldn't you think for that kind of money they could get
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>? In any case, I am not mentioning the name of this couple
so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't waylay them on their way to dinner.

            And here's a great nugget: A "supermodel" was tear-gassed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>
driven crazy by the constant ringing of her cell phone. I'm with the mad macer
on the phone deal, but the real question is what was a supermodel doing in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cab</ENAMEX>? I mean, I'm only a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Oil of Olay</ENAMEX> model, and I wouldn't be caught
dead in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. But onward. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucianne</ENAMEX> and her dot-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">com</ENAMEX> are all het up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> people
dissing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Jesus</ENAMEX>. She says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> called him homeless, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX>
said he was unemployed. Which makes for a nice segue to my thought that you and
I should perhaps cool our ethnic references. It is conceivable that we could
incite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in sheets to march on 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, which, while
not actually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> are close enough ... and I know for a fact that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riot squads</ENAMEX> there are pooped. Well, maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> more latke. And do check
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoes</ENAMEX> for scorpions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xxM</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
