
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cosmic Jokester</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Prudie</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> can win over the hearts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
sitting in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Square</ENAMEX>, then I suppose he has a prayer.

            What you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> rings true. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, I trailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>-hall meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. If he had a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and a chubby
sidekick, you would have mistaken his speech for the opening monologue of a
late-night talk show. Here's an excerpt from my notebook:

            

               I'd like to introduce some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we have with us here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. ...
Yes, there's Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX>. Could you stand up? If any of you have
any problems with socialist, pinko commie bias of his news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, you
know where to take up your complaints. ... Is there anyone here from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>?
We won't hold that against you.

            

            Every line is a wisecrack. And it's delivered in a deadpan style that seems
clearly borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Carson</ENAMEX>. Much of it is a gallows sense of humor. He
is somebody who has seen the worst of life and knows that much of the garbage
he deals with in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is a part of a cosmic joke. All of which leads me
to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> have been asking the wrong question about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. We
have had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> with tempers before, but have we ever had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who
is this glib? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> certainly considered his campaign a joke, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
had an ability to laugh off problems. But at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> was a
somber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> was a horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is a serious
business, and I wonder if it's wise to install a jokester as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the free
world. ("Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, tear down this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> and remove that splotch!") Perhaps
the answer is yes. I am undecided on the matter.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> online is reporting that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anecdote</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has been telling in debates is wrong. (Someone's
research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> must have been working overtime on that one.) "Candor" and
"accuracy" are apparently not synonymous.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, give us a book report and tell us, who's smarter: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. or Esther</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Honey</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
