
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nattering Nabob</ENAMEX> of Solipsism
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmmph</ENAMEX>. And I feared the whole subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books was a little
lowbrow for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>. Maybe better for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Herbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX> on whether the felonious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monkeys in Caps for Sale</ENAMEX> should be put to death."). One final word on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, courtesy of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Marshall</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the
series, lived for a while in far <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West Texas</ENAMEX>, and he's buried in the tiny town
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marathon</ENAMEX>. So we're not all bad.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Didja</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? Another one of his sommelier numbers, in which he
removes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s cork and sniffs it in full view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>. Who
died and made him the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX>'s worthiness? (For that matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>,
who died and made us judge?) I don't mind his taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s foreign policy
speech apart: I appreciate his listening to it and analyzing it so I don't have
to (I would have had to find toothpicks to keep my eyes open), but the whole
"oracle of wisdom" aspect to his approach is beginning to tick me off. When you
read one of his columns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, or at least when I do, you get the sense
that it's more about him than it is about it or them; the phrase "nattering
nabob of solipsism" suddenly springs to mind. There's a great story about his
self-importance circulating down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>. Do you remember a couple of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> wrote in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> consecutive columns about coming to see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>? As I understand it, he called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s communications
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, on, like, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, and said, "I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming Tuesday</TIMEX>." Not "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can I</ENAMEX>
come?" but "I'm coming." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> supposedly said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s going to
be out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>," to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> responded, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, you don't understand, I'm
coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>." P.S., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> changed his schedule. Can you imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX>
pulling that crap? If the story's true, it lends credence to a theory I have
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about Safire</TIMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and I were watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX> over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">holidays</ENAMEX> (which I'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Team Carlson</ENAMEX> wasn't, since it was on TV), and it
occurred to me that there's a bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oz</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Safire</ENAMEX>: He seems all-powerful and
scary, someone you have to bow before to curry favor, but when you pull the
curtain back he's just a nebbishy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who used to write speeches for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>. If
things had gone differently, he could be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> frontrunner and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> could be doing a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice-weekly</TIMEX> column called--what? "Heil
Everybody"?

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oz</ENAMEX>, what would he give the various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> candidates
before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s debate? A brain for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>, couldn't resist.) A
heart for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>. A chill <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, since he obviously doesn't need
courage. And how's about self-awareness for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, who's at least
pretending that he has a chance in hell of breaking the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> threshold in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> other than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>? I thought, actually, we might spend some time today
talking about the debate, which I fear is going to be unnatural and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unrevealing</ENAMEX>. It's not like we're going to learn anything about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> other
than who prepped well and who's prone to flop sweat under the klieg lights. I
know I sound like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Lemann</ENAMEX>, but it's about as accurate a measure of true
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> make the Ivy League, so why not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>? In a real crisis--say, a nuclear conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>--no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will
have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> debating a stand-in for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yelstin</ENAMEX>. Rather than test the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in such a formal setting, we ought to catch them off-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>. Life is
off-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>, right? But then we're getting dangerously close to the realm of the
pop quiz, and we all know where that got us last time.

            Before I go, I want to revise and extend my remarks about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>: This
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> he has not one but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> links to stories about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' personal
lives. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s going to use her maiden name in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bid, and
the other says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> are going to divorce <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX> he's out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Drudge teases each by saying they come from a "paper," but when you
click on the link, you learn they come from a supermarket tab <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> , respectively. Next he'll be linking us to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World News</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartford Courant</ENAMEX> was right: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> is
toast.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Evan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
