
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX> Class
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>:

            Don't get me started on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. You know that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 45 years</TIMEX>
(until recently) we have spent considerable portions of every other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> or so
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. I was a fellow at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Antony's College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, a
visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London School of Economics</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976-77</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> you
went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster</ENAMEX>), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-88</TIMEX>, one of
the happiest years of our life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> can be so deft. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> we had a
flat on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Regent's Park Road</ENAMEX>, facing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Primrose Hill</ENAMEX>, and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> was one
of the familiar blue-and-white plaques that said: "From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1873 to 1895</TIMEX>, here
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lived Frederick Engels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Philosopher</ENAMEX>." Not stalwart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> for the
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. Or enemy of the capitalist class. Just political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">philosopher</ENAMEX>.

            Yet there has also been an ugly strain of anti-Semitism that has run through
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> life, associated with the identification of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> with money.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aristocrats</ENAMEX> have land, even penniless, not money.) It is there in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX>'s pre-WWII novel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stamboul Train</ENAMEX> , with its picture of the greasy
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">currant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>. It is there in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. S. Eliot</ENAMEX>'s poems (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Burbank With a Baedeker:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bleistein With a Cigar"</ENAMEX>), the subject of a disputed book by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony Julius</ENAMEX> just
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. (Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>, interestingly enough, had at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in
her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Joseph</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Rifkind</ENAMEX>, etc.--and her intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer</ENAMEX> was our late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Letwin</ENAMEX>.)

            So many of these contradictions come to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Spectator</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that is full of sparkling writing. Yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auberon Waugh</ENAMEX> (familiarly called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bron</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> are wont to do with
public figures), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Waugh</ENAMEX>, had a column in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Spectator</ENAMEX>
in which he remarked: "We are all familiar with being in strange places and not
knowing exactly where we are. I woke up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> and was served a filthy
kosher breakfast, and I realized that I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>." I wrote a note to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Chancellor</ENAMEX>, who was then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> (and who now writes
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">International Papers</ENAMEX>" for 
                  Slate
               ), and asked how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Waugh</ENAMEX> knew that
it was a "filthy kosher breakfast," unless it was filth recognizing filth. Not
the best of repartee; but one loses wit in anger.

            And then there is the unspeakable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taki</ENAMEX>, who still writes a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> column for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> , called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"High Life</ENAMEX>," about the party-going and boozing and
womanizing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gstaad</ENAMEX>. There is often that globule of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> spit that he drops into his column. Yet in his writings for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, he is careful to refrain. I remarked on this once at a
party in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and was overheard by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel Malcolm</ENAMEX>, who said: Do you want him to
double his anti-Semitism? Sir, I replied, you are too clever by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repartee</ENAMEX>.

            You know that I began a book on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> that I never
finished. What prompted it was the realization that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> had lived in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 30 years</TIMEX>, and that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX> he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> mirrored their fate, his writings on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> society are so thin.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curiously</ENAMEX>, he never tried to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mazzini</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Herzen</ENAMEX>, fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exiles</ENAMEX>,
let alone <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stuart Mill or Matthew Arnold</ENAMEX>. He remained within the closed
circle of his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX>.)

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> was preoccupied with economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, he never understood
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> society, which has been ruled by social class. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> has been
a fairly rigid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> society--made "visible" by accent--but with relatively
open access for talented grammar-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lads</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Bullock</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Asa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Briggs</ENAMEX>, who become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX> and occupy the major positions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> cultural and
educational life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaiah Berlin</ENAMEX> first made his mark by conversation.

            Status ruled. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> bought status by buying land--in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gentleman</ENAMEX>--or entering a profession. (In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trollope</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palliser</ENAMEX> novels, the vade
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mecum</ENAMEX>; of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> society, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> says: I am not in trade; I have a
profession.) Or they renewed the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, and money, by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> heiresses. I
don't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> would have liked the novels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX>; he loved the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and gore of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Shue</ENAMEX>.

            And now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> has finally achieved what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Crosland</ENAMEX> wrote
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 40 years ago</TIMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> could not be a class party (after all, the
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> was shrinking in a post-industrial world); he has made it a
"middle-class" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> is a brilliant, ruthless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> (albeit with an
authoritarian streak) but vacuous in his rhetoric and ideas. His house
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intellectual</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Giddens</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London School of Economics</ENAMEX>, has
told him (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years late</TIMEX> ) that left and right have no meaning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on the
ideological spectrum. So, they have formulated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>. What is it? No
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> seems to know. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. G.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Runciman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity</ENAMEX> (quite a combination), calls it "recycled platitudes."
Les mots justes . Is that not the definition of political life <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as well as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dad</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
