
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pornographer</ENAMEX> Who Didn't Bark

            So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> has been having an affair with congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callista</ENAMEX>
Bisek for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>--since before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Revolution of 1994</ENAMEX>. Why didn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> tell us about it when it mattered? You remember: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>, the
pornographer, and his crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of snoops were going to blast the lid off the
hypocritical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that was trying to impeach a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> over
sex, etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $1 million</NUMEX> in reward money. Yet here one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s juiciest potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> was cheating, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> didn't blow his
cover.

            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> fail to find out about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bisek</ENAMEX>? No, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan</ENAMEX>
MacDonell, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonell</ENAMEX> told
kausfiles that "we had some information" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>--indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> had compiled a "good dossier" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> before he resigned
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1998</TIMEX> elections. Did that dossier include the Bisek
matter? "Yes." So why didn't Flynt expose the affair? "We were holding back."
Why hold back? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacDonell</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bisek</ENAMEX> was a "private" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, which caused
some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, but also that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> "wanted to see what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> was
going to do next as far as his career was concerned."

            Hmmm. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1999</TIMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> impeachment was pending before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> charged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> was blackmailing anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX>. This came after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Moldea</ENAMEX>, told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX>, "We have a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, dead bang, and the
evidence is clear. But they haven't been going on TV, or on the floor of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, shooting their mouths off, trying to take the moral high ground
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. And as a consequence, we're throwing it back in the river." If
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "hasn't been shooting his mouth off," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moldea</ENAMEX> said, "we let him
go."

            And, come to think of it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> was kind of uncharacteristically
quiet during the impeachment mess, wasn't he? ...

            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> had the goods on him? "We never contacted him," says
MacDonell, though he concedes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> "could have known." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonell</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> was getting maximum publicity and sales for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> , not necessarily making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> behave. "We were going to wait
until the disclosure would do us the most benefit." If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> had come out in
a high-profile way and denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sexual immorality, would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> have
dropped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> then? "That was kind of our idea." What if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> hadn't
resigned after his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election losses, and instead had resolved to seek
another term as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>--would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> then have tried to bring him down?
"Not necessarily," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonell</ENAMEX>. "We weren't that concerned with bringing
down anybody. We wanted to do the most for [ourselves]."

            So was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> effectively (if not illegally) blackmailed? You, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>,
be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>! I tend to believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacDonell</ENAMEX>'s claim of pure, publicity-seeking
self-interest. But that doesn't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s behavior wasn't affected by
knowledge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>, or someone like him, knew about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bisek</ENAMEX> and might blow the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whistle</ENAMEX>. Intentionally or not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> served <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> well.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> would probably agree. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last spring</TIMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment trial
was over<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">--and months</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> resigned--he finally published his
long-awaited (and disappointing) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flynt Report</ENAMEX>. It did allude to the
Bisek matter, saying: "Rumors of an ongoing affair between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remarried</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff member</ENAMEX> of then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Gunderson</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>)* reached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUSTLER</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. Maybe this
whiff of fresh scandal was the deciding factor in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s abrupt withdrawal from
the mud fight." And, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> might have added, in determining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s fighting
style during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous months</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Shields</ENAMEX>, declined to comment on this
story when contacted by kausfiles .

            
               * In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, when her romance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> apparently began, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bisek</ENAMEX> was
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gunderson</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
