
   
   
      
         
            When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Will the Seagram Building Fall Down</ENAMEX>?

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Scully</ENAMEX>, the eminent (now retired) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>
architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, whether public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-to-late</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> were less durable than public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that predate
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. Of course they
are, he said. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX> has penned a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> Magazine piece on this topic. In the
last of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Magazine</ENAMEX> 's special issues on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX>
writes,

            

               
                  Our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>-frame and curtain-wall skyscrapers are major symbols of our
age, but there is every reason to surmise they won't be here for long. Their
life expectancy is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years or so</TIMEX>, and that assumes assiduous
maintenance.
               

            

            Reading this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was chilled to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX> is right,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> realized, that means <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX>
Building has only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to go before it falls over. Thinking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> very blue. Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mies van der Rohe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s landmark <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> has inspired a host of ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">imitations</ENAMEX> (including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>--also designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mies</ENAMEX>--which
essentially is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Building</ENAMEX> knocked on its side), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has a
strong attachment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Building</ENAMEX>. It was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> Chatterbox
was, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s maternal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> worked for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that supplied
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bronze</ENAMEX> used in its handsome spandrels, mullions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>beams. And when
Chatterbox was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a wee cube</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pappy Chatterbox</ENAMEX> had an office in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX>
Building. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is far from the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with a strong attachment to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX>; in an essay in an earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX> issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Muschamp</ENAMEX> proclaimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Building</ENAMEX> "my choice as
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>'s most important building."

            Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> got sufficiently worked up thinking about the
possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Building</ENAMEX> might fall down that he phoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX>,
who reassured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that when he wrote those words in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
piece he wasn't thinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. "They take good care of
that," he said. (Among other things, the bronze is oiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.) "If you
take good care of them, they can last for quite awhile." This seemed somewhat
at odds with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX>'s written remark about assuming "assiduous maintenance,"
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> decided to let that go. Instead, he asked precisely when one
could expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Building</ENAMEX> to fall down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX> answered that he
didn't know.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America-College Retirement Equities Fund</ENAMEX> (TIAA-CREF),
which bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Building</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram's</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. Chatterbox read the
troubling passage from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> Magazine piece to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
DiGennaro, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managing director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIAA-CREF</ENAMEX>'s mortgage and real estate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>.
"You can tell [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX>] I am offering, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> are accepting, leases in
excess of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiGennaro</ENAMEX> answered. "That building represents the finest
current construction, not construction for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its day</TIMEX> and age." He added
(without my asking) that the computers that now run the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> and the
heating systems and whatnot are all fully Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compliant</ENAMEX>. Yes, but how long
will the building keep standing there? "This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was constructed of
materials that should last more than a lifetime if you and I are going to live
to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years old</TIMEX>." More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thought. That
doesn't seem especially long. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> asked: Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX>
Building make it to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX>? "We're scheduling the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> millennium
party right now," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiGennaro</ENAMEX> assured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, with a chuckle. But by then, of
course, he wasn't taking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> very seriously.

         
      
   
