
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Crash of 2002</ENAMEX>? What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Would George W. Do</ENAMEX>?
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>,

            Many thanks for the thoughts on technological change. As for identities, I
suppose I could continue on the subject with a lengthy disquisition on the
construction of national identities in early modern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, drawn from my new
book. But somehow, I think this would be getting a little too specialized for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>. So I hope you don't mind if I change the subject and
pontificate a little about the presidential campaign. Living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
it's hard to resist the temptation.

            I must say, though, that since I spend much of my time immersed in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX>, the crazily ritualistic aspects of the campaign strike
me very forcefully. The weirdest thing, to my mind, is the way the candidates
and the media all seem to pretend that we are electing a benevolent dictator
who, once elected, will snap his fingers, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of pages of
position papers drawn up by his campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> will automatically become the
law of the land. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elect Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> and abortion will be abolished. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elect George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> and we will get a tax cut. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elect Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> will be welcomed into the
military. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elect Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> and everyone will be required to wear underwear on
the outside (to continue my homage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bananas</ENAMEX> ).

            At the very least, it seems to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> could make more of a
distinction <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between three</NUMEX> very different types of campaign promises: those it
would take a constitutional amendment to fulfill (e.g. abortion, maybe campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> reform, because of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> amendment concerns); those that would require
congressional action (health care, tax cuts, etc.); and those that could be
done with a presidential order. Why even waste much time on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> category?
Let's pretend, as a thought experiment, that a conspiracy of vintners
contaminates the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> supply with powerful psychedelic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushrooms</ENAMEX> just
before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>, and that as a result, the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> goes on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-long</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hallucinatory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> trip and elects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, only sobering up after
his inauguration. Will abortion still be legal in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>? Of course it will.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> was strongly against abortion, too. We can be pretty cautious
about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> category as well, especially when it comes to the details of
health-care plans that will be rewritten and amended time and again before
(possible) passage. In fact, one of the few big issues where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>'
specific promises really matter is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, since that can be done
by executive order. That's why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s promise to end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policy and let
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in is probably the most important campaign news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            This general problem is why I get steamed when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> moan about how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are ignoring "the issues." Get real. What matters is not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s position papers, but their basic principles, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX>
things they care most about; their experience; their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>; their political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">savvy</ENAMEX> (as our shared favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy novelist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles McCarry</ENAMEX>, emphasized in the
Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>), and yes, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. And this is all the more the
case during a time when there are no big national disasters to be faced, at
least not the sort that require urgent responses. If peace and prosperity
continue, and there are no major wars, pretty much any of the serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> now running could probably muddle through all right (not counting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> as serious, that is). But what about the stock-market collapse of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estonia</ENAMEX>? The terrorist bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>? All
those things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> don't have position papers on? What really
matters is to choose a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who can deal best with a real crisis, rather
than worry about what's going to happen to ethanol subsidies (anyone care to
bet the subsidies will be gone in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> is elected?--of
course, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> remarks in "Ballot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX>," the issue itself is still a good test of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>). Thinking in
these terms, do we really want to elect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George W</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
