
   
   
      
         
            Ghosts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trotsky</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo</ENAMEX>,

            It makes me happy that you feel comfortable calling me <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Massa Honey</ENAMEX> and I
like the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> dolls. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Evangelical children</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will
want one for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. When you rub <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>'s belly, he says, "Welcome the unborn
into the world" and then emits a cute little giggle. I am contrarian on the
subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>. Let's set aside any of our quibbles with his positions.
I actually think he's a smart, ideologically consistent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who makes his case
in a reasonable way. But far more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> is hobbled by race, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> is
hobbled by looks. No profile can resist mentioning that he's short and looks
like a lizard. Last night, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>'s questioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was especially shrewd. He
asked whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> bad behavior would ever deserve sanctions: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Would Bush</ENAMEX>
want to punish them if they doubled the number of slave-labor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>? Increased
tenfold the number of forced abortions? It made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> squirm. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> really has
played a big role in helping put the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> issue on the table, and he deserves
credit for this.

            Let me bore you with a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> tidbits: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> is a nitwit
and has never had patience for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> looked physically pained being
questioned by him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are afraid that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> will be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> to survive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary. Their fear: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>
will tag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to beat up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> isn't pro-life
enough. This is what I love about watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the religious
right. They are the closest living things to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trotskyites</ENAMEX>. (I should know. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX>
disclosure: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotsky</ENAMEX> was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> never forgave him for changing
his name from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronstein.</ENAMEX>) They think about politics and power in a way far more
calculating than we can imagine. They will enter into popular-front alliances
to force their issues onto the agenda. And they bicker among themselves
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endlessly</ENAMEX>. Last night a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> tried to describe to me the differences between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Coast Straussians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> ones--apparently this is an important
split among social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> over the teachings of philosopher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo Strauss</ENAMEX>.
The debate revolves around the importance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. I'll try to figure out more by my next dispatch.

            The hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> is not nearly so glamorous as you would think. For starters, I
never seem to know any of the truly good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX>. Besides, the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late night</TIMEX> at the
hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> is used to lay the groundwork to get good dish later. Political
reporting is like selling insurance--it's about relationships. I am hoping that
my cultivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spinmeisters</ENAMEX> tonight will score me scoops down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. Does
that make me as calculating as the religious right and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trotskyites</ENAMEX>? I think
so.

            Your sectarian friend,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
