
   
   
      
         
            Go, <i>Times</i>, Go!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo</ENAMEX>,

            I am in no mood to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>boycott the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. (Perhaps I will have a change of heart
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.) In fact, as I write this I am turning toward <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">43rd Street</ENAMEX> and
saluting in the direction of culture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Darton</ENAMEX> and the family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sulzberger</ENAMEX>. I am ecstatic about their appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Mitchell</ENAMEX> and A.O.
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tony"</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> as tag-team replacements for outgoing film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>.
(See this morning's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> .) Allow me to
write the press release: This may be the best--and certainly the most
interesting--lineup of film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
has ever fronted. Daily film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are generally a sorry lot. They have to
contend with so much <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> hokum that they're driven to overuse of
overwrought literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pyrotechnics</ENAMEX> and banal humor. (There are exceptions, such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenstern</ENAMEX>.) But I am guessing the new-look New York
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> will be the bright shining lights in their dim profession.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, currently with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star-Telegram</ENAMEX> , has the perfect sensibility for writing about a steady
profusion of disaster movies and romantic comedies. He's a hipster with a canny
understanding of the popular culture. It's hard to imagine him praising every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> flick that comes his way, but it's hard to imagine him
dismissing them outright either. Plus, he can write wonderfully scathing pans.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, brings intellectual heft. As far as I know, he hasn't
done much in the way of film reviewing. But this is a plus. It will be fun to
watch him get his legs.

            There are other reasons for a rosy cultural outlook
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. (Be cheery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo</ENAMEX>!) A piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> notes the demise of rap impresario <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Puff Daddy</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skip Gates</ENAMEX> of hip-hop. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> have backlashed against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puffy</ENAMEX>, accusing him of
exploiting the death of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and collaborator, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notorious B.I.G.</ENAMEX>
Recently, record sales have been disappointing. It's a deserved fate. This is
not to diminish his career. His work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.I.G.</ENAMEX> was slick yet irresistible.
(If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notorious</ENAMEX> had lived, perhaps their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> would have flourished into
the rap equivalent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Evans</ENAMEX> relationship.) And his rap
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">empire</ENAMEX> is a great success story of capitalism. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puffy</ENAMEX>'s career has been,
well, puffy. His music does dwell on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s death in a way that feels
disgustingly hollow. And the rest of oeuvre consists of forgettable, not very
catchy ditties. In other words, he's commercial without being listenable. And
that makes him merely crass. Finally, I think that the existence of the Boring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maplewood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, is a reason for optimism. I am not sure what they
do, and I don't agree with their choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> as most boring celeb. For
that category, I nominate <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Puff Daddy</ENAMEX>. I have an idea, dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>. With your
expertise in etiquette, I propose that we put out a special millennial edition
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table--Best-Mannered Celebrity of All Time</ENAMEX>. We're now accepting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>. (I have begun creating a set of criteria and my own list of choices,
which I will submit later.)

            Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> with the pompoms,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
