
   
   
      
         
            Life on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>? And Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Essays</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times leads with an assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> talks in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that ended on Friday</TIMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> front similar analyses. The former leads
with the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> news. The latter leads with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> will allow
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> of rival Internet services to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lines</ENAMEX>," a story
not on any other fronts.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> controls <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s cable lines and had declared
it would only let its own Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> (ISP) use them for at least
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> doesn't say when this declaration was made or if the two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> are up. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> plans to send a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kennard</ENAMEX> in which it will outline its deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s second
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MindSpring Enterprises Inc.</ENAMEX>, and its concurrent commitment to an
"open access" policy. The piece says "open access has become a pivotal debate
within the telecommunications world." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Competitors</ENAMEX> and consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> feel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> hasn't gone far enough and worry that this is a proactive attempt by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to avoid stricter industry regulation. There's also worry that the
telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> still has the power and potential to "undermine the
free-flowing ethic if the Internet," which it could do by funneling traffic
away from non-AT&T ISPs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT WTO</ENAMEX>
story's angle: The lack of a trade deal is a major setback for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. It's
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> major foreign policy defeat since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
rejection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> issued an optimistic
statement on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, but anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> called the
talks a "fiasco" and "circus."

            The WP touches on the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> situation was a blow
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, but focuses on why the negotiations bombed--labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> and human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> credited their protests; trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> said it was the sheer complexity of issues coupled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>'
unwillingness to compromise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s refusal to talk about
"eliminating its generous subsidies for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and their exports" the biggest
obstacle. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sweeney</ENAMEX> feels no deal
is better than a bad one; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> defines this as "one that failed to set up a study
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> ... to make recommendations on labor rights."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has a different emphasis, exemplified by its Sweeney
quote: The talks represented "a stunning breakthrough in the public debate over
globalization." It (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost giddily</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> "the unruly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of democracy
collided with the elite world of trade policy"; "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elitists</ENAMEX> ... lost and
debate was changed forever." The anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> barely existed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>,
it notes, and has been "abetted by global communication ... and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>." An LAT piece reefered on its front cites a rebellion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX> from Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> "that helped bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> summit to an
abrupt and embarrassing halt."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Polar Lander</ENAMEX> mission <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>' mantra
is that the communication failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLP</ENAMEX> "was not unexpected." (Do those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> will be comforted by the idea that they thought a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$165 million</NUMEX> mission might flop?) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on its front that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> haven't given up
hope but conceded that "chances of success would be diminishingly slim if they
are unable to hear from the robotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> in a test on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reefers a story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPL</ENAMEX> news which has a
more pessimistic tone than the others about the likelihood of establishing
contact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> space probe.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
off-leads an exclusive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> reports prepared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooperation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> on human rights abuses in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The first
details the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> abuse of power after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> air war started. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Albanians</ENAMEX>' efforts, often spearheaded by the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation Army</ENAMEX> and often evidenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX>, to drive
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> since the conflict's end. The reports will be
released on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX>.

            Inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries news that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Commission</ENAMEX> on the Causes
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention of Violence</ENAMEX> found that violent crime in major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> reported to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has risen by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>." The findings provide a
counterpoint to reports of crime decline based on comparisons between
contemporary rates and those of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1980s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX>, when "unusually
high levels of violence" prevailed.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front piece on the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopefuls</ENAMEX>
discusses the sniping between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> but also talks about the
"remarkably civil ... in comparison" relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story focuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' relationship.

            The WP fronts a piece on wacky, esoteric college application
essay questions that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> are
using for a variety of reasons. How important are these essays compared to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>
scores as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> determines acceptances, and are the essays fair assessments
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' abilities? The piece might be weightier if it addressed such
issues.

         
      
   
