
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Global Warming Is Good for Gore</ENAMEX>

            If you are an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> supporter, pray for a mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>. This is the message
Chatterbox gleans from a "to be sure" paragraph in a Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liesman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Schlesinger</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> explains why the doubling of oil prices <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> has failed to disrupt
the economy. The reasons cited include: the shift to natural gas and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX>; the
growing relative importance of the service sector; more efficient futures
markets that allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to lock in low prices for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>; more
energy-efficient technology in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>; cost-cutting associated with
(what else) the Internet; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
piece, the main reason oil prices have spiked to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> a barrel--the highest in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 10 years</TIMEX>--is that there's been more compliance than usual with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s
current effort to cut production. Even so, when you factor out inflation and
taxes, a gallon of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 cents</NUMEX> less than it did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>.

            But let's take a look at that "to be sure" paragraph. A "to be sure"
paragraph is exactly what it sounds like--a paragraph that carefully lays out
significant caveats to the story's main hypothesis. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nowadays</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , it's considered somewhat hackneyed actually to include the
phrase "to be sure" in your "to be sure" paragraph.) In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liesman</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlesinger</ENAMEX>'s story, which is appropriately judicious, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
"to be sure" paragraphs, but here's the one that interests Chatterbox:

            
               The real test may be yet to come. If industries stock up on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> ahead of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX> or a lengthy cold snap grips the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> think
oil prices could creep above <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> a barrel--a level seen only briefly during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. That scenario worries some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>. If prices reach that height
and stay there, "economic activity slows, and the trade deficit worsens," says
oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Verleger</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brattle Group</ENAMEX>, a consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> based in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX> "It can be a prescription for a fairly serious and sharp
recession."
            

            Remember recessions? These were economic downturns, once thought to be
cyclical in nature, that caused unemployment and general unhappiness. They
frequently ejected sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>)
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. Assuming that recessions haven't been rendered
permanently extinct by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long Boom</ENAMEX>, the reappearance of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election would
be extremely inconvenient for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> essentially boils down
to: "I don't like what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> did with his wanker, but I sure do like
what he did with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy."

            That's where the necessity for a mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> kicks in. If a frigid winter
pushed oil prices high enough to trigger a recession, it would be very bad for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.* His chances of winning the general election--and maybe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nomination**</ENAMEX>--would be greatly diminished. On the other hand, if the
temperature stayed warm, there would be no oil price spike, hence probably no
recession. This is the sense in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is an ironic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> of
global warming , the ongoing natural catastrophe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s been issuing
jeremiads about for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. (There is a complex argument that also
blames cold snaps and other forms of extreme weather on global warming, but for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simplicity</ENAMEX>'s sake <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will ignore it.) An added benefit of a warm
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">winter</ENAMEX>, of course, would be that it would make it clearer than ever that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
concern about global warming is well-founded.

            If you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> supporter, however, please do not interpret this to
mean that you should climb into your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUV</ENAMEX> and drive around the block <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> times in
order to dump more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> into the atmosphere. Most obviously, reducing
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide emissions</ENAMEX> is more important than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
Secondarily, it probably wouldn't cause the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> to warm up quickly enough to
make a difference in weather patterns for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX>.
And, finally, if lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> suddenly increased the number of miles they
drove in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, oil prices would of course shoot up and create the very
risk of recession that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> want to avoid.

            
               *To-be-sure footnote: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s ties to the petroleum industry
wouldn't be looked on favorably during a recession triggered by high oil
prices. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> would still probably reap a net benefit from not being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> . If by some chance the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> were instead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, he would reap a larger benefit, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
isn't associated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' minds with the oil industry.
            

            
               **A cold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> might conceivably help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> win the nomination,
but as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> in the general election he'd have to contend with accusations
that his party caused the recession.
            

         
      
   
