
   
   
      
         
            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Winner for Best Entrance Is ...</ENAMEX>
            

            Hey y'all:

            I'd have to agree with you about this being the year for ensemble work,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best performances of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> came in a movie with an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ensemble</ENAMEX> cast not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saw. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best Man</ENAMEX> featured
a turn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Howard</ENAMEX> that should've propelled him into movie-star orbit.
He had the best entrance I saw in a movie <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX>--strumming a flamenco guitar
solo while clocking the honeys in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. Then, as he strolled off
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>, he strummed the neck of the guitar. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sassy</ENAMEX> and charismatic, as was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa DeSouza</ENAMEX>, as the spoiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buppie</ENAMEX> who played her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ma</ENAMEX> like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-inch</NUMEX>. There
it is, as they used to say back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. Given all the trends that have
been tagged and tracked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, and all the excitement that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX> mentioned
about films in general, it's still a troubling time for black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>. Had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard or DeSouza</ENAMEX> been in a movie officially sanctioned by the hip media--a
contradiction in terms if ever there was one, they'd have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> picture deals
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>. Or at least Dimension. Instead, there's still a
separate-but-equal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> of color for the most part. I cringe
when I think of the hunger there must've been among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> for
what will end up being the highest profile part for a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coffey</ENAMEX> role in The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Duncan Clarke</ENAMEX> handles the
role with all the dignity he can muster, and it's undeniably a well-meaning
movie. But to have a gentle black giant hang his head and say "Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>,"
while almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> prison circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> is portrayed as a
forward-thinking, tolerant humanist is the biggest backhanded slap I've seen in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> movie in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.

            Which is why I was so impressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> . It spins the race
issue from all angles--all the stuff about what derogatory term is proper for
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>, co-signed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ice</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cube</ENAMEX>, until he glimpses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX> beating on a
TV inside the bunker. And the self-hatred speech about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> may have
been, if you'll pardon the expression, too on-the-nose, but so what? The movie
whipped along so quickly, I'm happy it took a moment for a breather at that
point. Sure, the atrocities heaped on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> throw you out of the movie
the same way the hospital scene in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Third Man</ENAMEX> does--but if the point
of the movie is that war isn't fun and games, then it should be equally
assaultive on all points.

            And that will be all I have to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> . Unless until
this check from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Russell</ENAMEX> clears my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. Incidentally, did
anybody see a remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> movie about an intense, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed</ENAMEX>, love
affair called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Praise</ENAMEX> ? Because its frankness and heat bring to mind
another suffering genre--the adult-relationship film. Most of the best stuff of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> was playful but missed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">y'know</ENAMEX>, human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interaction</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
