
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">strangest day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, because that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> actually went down. Watching the expressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on TV, and
hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the office talk about a "sell-off," you would have thought
that we were on the verge of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1997</TIMEX> again instead of dealing with a
slight decline in an index that is up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 20 percent</NUMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just past two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. Since everyone's so surprised when the market actually drops, that must
mean that they expect it to keep going up. But then you'd think everyone would
pile in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>, since it's better to buy stocks when they're cheaper rather
than more expensive. Of course, that logic is both impeccable and almost
blissfully irrelevant to this market. We have a dream: Buy low, sell high, wait
till the stocks tumble, then buy low again, sell high again. And so we creep on
...

            Anyway, on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chat</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same day</TIMEX> that the merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>, the largest
industrial merger in history , was approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX> moved to block the merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP Amoco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arco</ENAMEX> . Apparently,
that deal will result in higher gas prices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and the West, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> deal will merely result in the creation of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in the world."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Free-PC, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> once boasted would be bigger than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> some day, agreed to be acquired by low-cost PC <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> eMachines,
and announced that it was ending its program of giving away free PCs .
Potential new names for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> include: 'Not-so-expensive-PC';
'Cheaper-than-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>-PC'; 'Not-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-big-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>-YET-PC'; and 'Harold.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redback Networks</ENAMEX> announced that it was acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siara Systems</ENAMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.3 billion</NUMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siara</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, some potentially cool technology,
and literally <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0</NUMEX> in revenue . What a great negotiation that must have
been: 'Having made no money yet, we think we're worth, oh, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX>.' 'How
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $4.3 billion</NUMEX>?' 'We'll take it!'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wrestling Federation</ENAMEX> announced that it would be toning
down the content and language on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its most popular shows,
Smackdown , after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> pulled their
ads from the show. I guess sending a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestlers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and teaching him a lesson he'd never forget wasn't considered a
realistic option."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Wants To Be a Millionaire</ENAMEX> will now become
a three-times-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a-week</TIMEX> regular series , starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>,
there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Wants To Be a Millionaire in the</ENAMEX>
ratings top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> . Presumably, if there were a show called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Wants To Be</ENAMEX>
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Billionaire</ENAMEX> , no one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> would ever watch anything else."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Winebaum</ENAMEX>, who left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> to start the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX>
eCompanies with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earthlink</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky Dayton</ENAMEX>, paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.5 million</NUMEX> for the
business.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com URL</ENAMEX>. He was immediately mocked as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naif</ENAMEX> who was out of
his element in the Net world. But come on. With that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>, you could put up a
Web page designed by your precocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>, sell closeout merchandise from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dress Barn</ENAMEX>, and the IPO would still price the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion</NUMEX>. Sounds like
a good investment to me."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Plains</ENAMEX> All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Pipelines</ENAMEX> said it had lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$160</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> on 'unauthorized' transactions by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Either
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> bet wrong on oil futures, or he floundered trying to corner the
market for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red Pokémon</ENAMEX>, when everyone knows Yellow is where you have to
be."

         
      
   
