
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long Live Celluloid</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Friends</ENAMEX>,

            No quarrel from me about the excitement of being a film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. This
was one of those miraculous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> when new talents, and revitalized
old talents, came bursting forth. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The year</TIMEX> was a slow starter, despite such
early exceptions as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cookie's Fortune and Kore-Eda's After</ENAMEX>
Life , but starting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telluride</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> festivals there was an
unveiling of riches that went on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week after week after week</TIMEX>.

            I agree with the praise for Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> and Three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kings</ENAMEX> --movies that were free . Watching them, we had absolutely no
idea what would happen next, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last half hour</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> was as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inventive</ENAMEX> and unexpected as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Having been pounded through the '90s
with predictable, upbeat film endings dictated by test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> ("Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>
really have to burn at the stake?"), I was so exhilarated to see films that
gave themselves the liberty to surprise and amaze me.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">At year's end</TIMEX>, there was another film like that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Thomas Anderson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> . I would not dream of revealing what happens at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
that movie, but I wanted to cheer when it did happen, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson</ENAMEX>
was demonstrating in a way both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic</ENAMEX> and bizarre that all narrative is
arbitrary--that no matter what happens next, it need not, and that no director
need feel shackled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> or studio expectations.

            I imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Magnolia</ENAMEX> will get widely divergent reviews (I know of one
national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> who has put it on his "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> worst" list), but I thought it struck
the right note to close <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX> of invention. Yes, some will argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s surprise is cheating, or arbitrary, or a trick--but the way for it
is prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Jay</ENAMEX>'s witty narration at the beginning of the film, which
all but tells us to expect learned <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>.

            I was disappointed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, having applauded so much innovation, put
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julien</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Donkey-Boy</ENAMEX> on his worst list. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harmony Korine</ENAMEX> demonstrates
here that he has the soul of a real filmmaker. Yes, the movie is frustrating
and aggressive, but after it is over it has revealed a shape and purpose, one
suited to its style (the whole story is seen through the eyes of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">schizophrenic</ENAMEX>).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julien</ENAMEX> serves another symbolic function <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>: It was shot on a
video camera, and (if we can judge by the outtakes on the Web site) its style
was created mostly in post-production on a computer much like the one I am now
using. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julien</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project are the foot in the
door of digital production; these days anyone can make a movie, and if
it is good enough, can find an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassavetes</ENAMEX> would rejoice (maybe
not at those two movies--but think how he would have welcomed the freedom of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> video camera).

            I was told <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundance</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> would be the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in
which more of the movies had been shot on film than video. We shall see. I am
as firmly in support of video production as I am opposed to the alarming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specter</ENAMEX> of digital video projection in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>--a subject that most movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have ignored.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the industry believe the hype that digital projection is
destined for the near future. The fact is that digital projection is nowhere
near being practical or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">affordable</NUMEX>, and even if it were--are video and film the
same thing? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perceptual scientists</ENAMEX> believe video creates a hypnotic mind
state, and film creates a reverie <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Why is it that we sense, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vaguely</ENAMEX>, a different mental <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in a movie than while watching television?
How ironic if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> threw out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of film to adopt a technology that
did not evoke the mind-state that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> buy movie tickets in order to
obtain?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> knows this is an obsession of mine; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times I</ENAMEX> published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long</TIMEX> article that questions
widespread beliefs about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> digital projection system and
extols a much cheaper film projection system called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MaxiVision48</ENAMEX>, which uses
existing, proven technology, and produces a picture its patent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> claim is
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">500 percent</NUMEX> better (not a misprint) than existing film or digital projection,
take your choice.

            As we bow gratefully to this wonderful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">final year of the first century</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>, let us hope it is not one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final years</TIMEX> of celluloid itself.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
