
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Resumption of History</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>:

            In re <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>: A camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> was here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
to interview me for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> news hour. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> has a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven-minute</TIMEX> segment called "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Century</ENAMEX>." The segment
focuses on a single topic. The one I saw <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> was called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Feminism</ENAMEX>." The
theme was carried principally by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX>' narration and documentary footage,
and this was interspersed briefly with some comments by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel Allende</ENAMEX> and the cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Douglas</ENAMEX>. It is hard to recall
what each of them said, for they were literally sound bites (or is it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bytes</ENAMEX>?).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> have scheduled a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Prediction</ENAMEX>," and I
was called because in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> I had initiated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> on the Year <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX>," had been reprinted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.I.T. Press</ENAMEX>; as was this year
my book The Coming of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Industrial Society</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Books</ENAMEX>, with a
new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX>-word foreword.

            I spoke with one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 40 minutes</TIMEX> on camera. What they
will make of it I do not know, for I began by saying that one could not
predict the future, if by the future one meant point events such as: Who will
become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>? Who will succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> does not create a ruse to succeed
himself? What will happen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>? Or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>? No one knows. There are too many imponderables.

            I think of an episode of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zbigniew Brzezinski</ENAMEX>, who had been a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Commission of the Year 2000</ENAMEX>. He was being baited on television by
a hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX>, who began: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brzezinski</ENAMEX>, you are a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlinologist</ENAMEX>." "Yes," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zbig</ENAMEX>, "if you like that clumsy word." "You tell
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> what goes on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> continued.
"When they listen," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zbig</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> then sprang his trap: "How come you
failed to predict the ouster of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Khrushchev?</ENAMEX>" And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zbig</ENAMEX>, who is quick on his
feet, replied: "Tell me, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khrushchev</ENAMEX> couldn't predict his own ouster, how do
you expect me to do so?"

            The simple point is that one can "predict" only if you have an algorithm, a
decision rule that tells you how to sort things out. Or where there is a firm
set of rules for institutional succession. When I initiated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission on</ENAMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX>, I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gardner</ENAMEX>, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>, for funding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> said: "You have written an interesting
memorandum, but give me a prediction." "It is very difficult to predict," I
said. "Well, if you don't give me a prediction, you don't get the money."

            To paraphrase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, there is nothing like the loss of money to
concentrate the mind. So, without much forethought, I said: "This is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> there will be an election for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>; equally, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968, 1972, 1976</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> ... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>." "You call that a prediction<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX> asked incredulously.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>," I replied, "there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> in the world; about how
many can you make such a prediction<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" (This was shortly after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Army</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> had been preparing to send in the paras to overthrow the government
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Mollet</ENAMEX>, until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Gaulle</ENAMEX> stepped in to assert authority.) "Oh," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX>
replied. We got the money.

            This is running on, but to anticipate you, or any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>: Can I return to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gardner</ENAMEX>'s question and give one prediction about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>? No, not
a prediction (for that is not the way to think about it) but a relevant social
framework to identify issues and problems. What we are witnessing is a change
in the "axis" of world socio-political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>; namely, one of widening
economic integration (crossing national boundaries) and increasing political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragmentation</ENAMEX> (within national boundaries).

            The economic dimension is a "change of scale," as all national economies are
absorbed into a global framework. The fragmentation is occurring because (as I
remarked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>) the national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is becoming too small for the big
problems of life, and too big for the small problems. The national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> innovation in response to the breakdown of local
economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. Now the national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> becomes defensive against the
international onrush of capital, currency, commodity, and even demographic
flows. And in imposing social programs from a national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, it becomes
unresponsive to the varieties and needs of different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">localities</ENAMEX>.

            More than that, we are witnessing not the end of history but the resumption
of history. Communism was a large smothering blanket thrown across societies
and suppressing primordial identities. With the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tito</ENAMEX>
regimes, those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> have broken open. But it is not only those ideological
empires; the re-assertion of defensive primordial identities is taking place in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> there is an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish parliament</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Welsh</ENAMEX> assembly, and a self-governing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>.
All this is called devolution, to rhyme with "evolution" (and not to rhyme with
"revolution").

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think you have it easier. You are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> specializing in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. They think that "the past" is now over. You
know better. It is not. The past is itself ever subject to revision and new
interpretation. As we said when we adopted an epigraph for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission on</ENAMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX>: "The past is never finished, for the future is yet to come."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dad</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
