
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reformulated</ENAMEX>
            

            I don't totally agree with you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>--there are some formulas in
sight. What diminished <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> for me was that at heart it was a
"conversion" melodrama in which a cynical, amoral, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogartish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> finally can't
live with himself in the face of injustice and opts to "do the right thing" at
considerable personal cost. That's one of the great movie plots, but it doesn't
feel as fresh as the rest of what's on screen. Elsewhere, however, it's the way
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> bend and twist formulas that accounts for the
"anything goes" quality that we've all been responding to. The beauty of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limey</ENAMEX> is that it takes a pretty standard pulp formula--wronged gangster
turned vigilante avenger--and creates what amounts to an essay on the idea of
"distance": from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, from the effects of our own actions in the past,
and from ourselves. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villain</ENAMEX> turns out not to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but a concept. You
see that not just at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> but in the middle, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Fonda</ENAMEX>--a superb,
non-star performance that supports your thesis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>, about the subordination
of ego in many of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s most interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>--registers terror at the
thought that it's all "getting too close" to him. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s willful
blindness to the fact that his behavior in the past had rippling consequences
that has brought about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s death.

            Meanwhile, there are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a zillion formulas</NUMEX> in the wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dogma</ENAMEX> , but
they're all rearranged--and then held in place--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX>'s passion.
Election is a reworking of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Makes Sammy Run</ENAMEX>? --the replacement
of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Glick</ENAMEX>" with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Flick"</ENAMEX> gives the game away--but told in a way that
makes more (or more modern) sense: Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>--unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budd Schulberg's</ENAMEX>--doesn't
remain the voice of moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>; his envy, self-hatred, and displaced lust
makes him self-destruct in spectacular fashion. My larger point is that it's
doubtful we'll escape formulas--especially with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and would-be
screenwriters flocking to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert McKee</ENAMEX> and others. The more
realistic hope is that filmmakers will use the technology to deconstruct those
formulas before our eyes--in ways that remind us what was vital about them to
begin with.

            I'd like to follow up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>, on your question about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>'s big
themes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menaker</ENAMEX> wrote a fascinating article here in 
                  Slate
                on what has
shaped up as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> trend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. Using <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Truman Show</ENAMEX> ,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrix</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Notting Hill</ENAMEX> , and a score of other films, he cited
scenarios in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>--whose lives are swamped by technology and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>--must "break through into the real." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> must leave the studio/world,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX> must escape the cameras (ditto <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTV</ENAMEX> ), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in
Pleasantville are stuck in a "TV artifice of life and must break through
it in order to get back to their real existences." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menaker</ENAMEX> goes on: "What may
be new ... is the role that technology and the media play in these productions
as existential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>, depriving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of their 'real lives.' " (Consider
The Insider --mysteriously named <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best movie by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Film</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>--in this light.)

            I don't think that theme is going to go away. As our culture becomes more
and more private--as video replaces movies the way movies replaced theater, as
e-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> replace phone calls the way phone calls replaced talking over the
back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX>--we might find that our most powerful relationships are with figures
in movies and television and our own fantasy lives. "Breaking through into the
real" might not be so simple.

            P.S.: Oh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other thing, I strongly dispute the comparison to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. I
don't have a video guide handy but wasn't that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Godfather II</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mean Streets</ENAMEX> , and one or another great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> picture ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Long</ENAMEX>
Goodbye ?). I don't see the same kind of ambitions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s films, and
I don't see any outright "masterpieces." Let's just say that this has been a
great year, a reversal of so much that happened in movies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. But
we're not back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> yet.

         
      
   
