
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> Wants <I>You</I> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ended the welfare program called Aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dependent Children</ENAMEX> (AFDC) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Since then, caseloads in the main federal
welfare program, now known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</ENAMEX> (TANF),
have fallen to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> their previous levels. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> reminds us of this
at every opportunity, as well he should. His major political achievement has
been cleansing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> of their previous, not-unjustified image as the
pro-dole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            So could <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> now really be pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> back onto the dole? In a small
but significant way, the answer is yes. The announcement was buried in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> radio address of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4</TIMEX>. After boasting, "We've changed the
culture of welfare from one that fostered dependence to one that honors and
rewards work," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> unveiled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> new "high-performance bonuses"--extra
money that will be used as a carrot to induce <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to do certain things. One
will reward states that get more poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> into two-parent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. (No
problem there.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> will reward states that enroll more poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>. (Good idea!) But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> will reward states that show the biggest
"improvement in the percentage of low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Stamps</ENAMEX>
who get them."*

            That one seems like a really bad idea.

            Why? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>), which proposed
the regulations implementing the new food-stamp bonuses, says
they will promote the goal of "ending the dependence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy parents</ENAMEX> on
government benefits." But wait a minute. The proposed bonus tries to get states
to go out and sign more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up for government benefits--namely food
stamps.

            And food stamps are a peculiar benefit, in that, if you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, you
can get them whether or not you work. Indeed, you can make no attempt to even
find a job or support your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and you'll still qualify for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$230</NUMEX> a month in
food stamps (for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-person <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$329</NUMEX> (for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-person <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>) or
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$419</NUMEX> (for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>). In southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, this food-stamp benefit typically exceeds
the regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX> benefit. Food stamps are also fungible--although the
stamps can be used only to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, they work just like cash. You buy food
with them as if they were cash; they are traded informally as if they were
cash.

            There is a word for cashlike benefits you can get whether you work or not.
The word is welfare. Pushing food stamps on poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is unlikely to move
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off of welfare because food stamps are welfare. As a veteran
liberal welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> told me, upon hearing of the new bonus, it's "perverse
to say we want you to move <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to self-sufficiency and then say we want you
to sign them up for more welfare."

            Because food stamps are a form of welfare, they--like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> and TANF
benefits--have traditionally been stigmatized, even among those who are
eligible to get them. This stigma is the natural flip side of the work ethic:
If you "honor and support work," in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s phrase, then you are at least
slightly dishonored and ashamed to get a handout that goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't
work a lick. Low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, especially, have been reluctant to sign up for
the benefits to which they are legally entitled. As noted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX>, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 39</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with earnings who are eligible for food stamps benefits
participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Stamp Program</ENAMEX>, compared to a participation rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX>
percent overall." Some of those who don't claim their benefits may be less-poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> whose small food-stamp allotment isn't worth the hassle of applying.
But many are undoubtedly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are simply proud that they don't depend on
a handout. It's hard to deny that this pride is, in some sense, a good
thing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s new plan in effect dismisses the food-stamp stigma as an archaic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relic</ENAMEX>. This represents a small but telling victory for those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>--I call
them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Money Liberals</ENAMEX>--for whom getting cash to the poor, not upholding the work
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ethic</ENAMEX>, is the most important thing. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> reform, their central
strategy--promoted, most importantly, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendell Primus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Greenstein</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Priorities</ENAMEX>--has been to destigmatize old
welfare programs such as food stamps by repackaging them as "work supports"
that can boost the incomes of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> leaving welfare for low-paying
jobs.

            Sure enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> declared food stamps "critical supports," and vowed to
"hold states accountable and make sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> get the benefits they need." To
qualify for a bonus under his new regulations, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would be required not
just to make it easy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who leave welfare (TANF) to keep getting food
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stamps</ENAMEX>, but to actively "encourage food stamp applications even if the TANF
application halts." In effect, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would be saying, "Sign up! It's good to
get food stamps." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stigma</ENAMEX>, schmigma!

            Maybe I'm overreacting, but I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is courting disaster here. While
food stamps might help support some welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> during a transitional
period between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX> and pure self-sufficiency, removing the food-stamp stigma
risks encouraging a far greater number to become dependent in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.
Suppose you're a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>. You're proud not to be on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX>. You don't even know where the welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is. Then you hear a
"public-service announcement" of the sort the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> regulations encourage. It
tells you that food stamps are respectable, that you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> not to go down
and claim what you're entitled to. So you find out where the welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is,
and there you also learn that if you quit your job you can qualify for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX> welfare. If you go on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX>, and then later go back to work at the
Gap, you get to keep not only food stamps but a bit of your welfare check too.
Hmmm. Sounds appealing.

            Or worse, you're a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who's just graduated from high school. You've
never had a job. Why not have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> out of wedlock, collect your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$230</NUMEX> a month
in stamps, live with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and worry about going to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>? Food stamps
are OK! They're good! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> says so.

            True, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is trying to say that food stamps
are really good only if you're also working at least part-time, but that's kind
of a complicated message to get across. One deterrent to food-stamp use,
remember, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Checkout-Line Factor</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to look at you funny when
you whip out your food-stamp card to buy your groceries. If food stamps are
destigmatized, though, nobody will look at you funny--even if you really aren't
working at all. The sales pitch designed to "support" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> will also protect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shirkers</ENAMEX>. In practice, how could the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> hope to destigmatize food
stamps for the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> but not for the latter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (who are, under law,
also entitled to them)?

            How did the welfare culture grow in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? It happened in the late
1960s, when state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> embarked on a campaign to encourage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX> and food-stamp use--to remove stigma and boost "participation rates."
The result? A tripling of the welfare rolls. This "welfare explosion" wasn't
undone until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> reform sent the opposite message. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> risks
reversing, at least partially, the actual, practical process that brought him
the caseload declines he's crowing about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Will he be happy when the rolls
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> stamps and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX> start to rise again?

            The arguments the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> now makes about food stamps, of course, can
easily be made about basic welfare--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX>--too. Can't it, too, provide a
"critical support" for those who've just gone to work but don't earn enough to
make it all the way out of poverty? Shouldn't we encourage those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to stay
on welfare, albeit at a lower benefit level, rather than make a harsh, clean
break? Don't they "need" an ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX> check to "complete the transition to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-sufficiency</ENAMEX>," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> puts it? You say food stamps are different because
they are "nutritional"? Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> need clothes as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>?

            In fact, these arguments are already being made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Money Liberals</ENAMEX> around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The next campaign, once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX> and food stamps have been redefined as
respectable "work supports," will be to make those benefits more generous. But
in a welfare program, the same benefit levels apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and non-workers
alike. If benefits are raised, it will be increasingly possible for at least
some part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to piece together enough "work supports" to live on
the supports without the work. Not to live well, of course, but the
problem of dependency has never been about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seems to be ignoring one of the hard-won lessons of liberalism's
collapse, which is that programs to help poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> should actually be
restricted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. These "work-tested" programs make society's values
(i.e., the work ethic) unmistakably clear. Not coincidentally, these
programs--including unemployment compensation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned</ENAMEX>
Income <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Credit</ENAMEX> (EITC), all of which you have to work to get--have been
politically unassailable, while welfare programs are either unpopular or
actively despised. And when a benefit is restricted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can
make it more generous without the risk of creating a culture of dependency.

            If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> wants to get more money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX>--as it
should--why not do it through measures restricted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX>, like an
expanded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX> and a higher minimum wage, rather than through food stamps? Until
then, if working-poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think they need food stamps and want to claim
them, fine--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> shouldn't make that difficult (as some, allegedly, have
done). But if a working-poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sees food stamps as an undignified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handout</ENAMEX>, that judgment, too, deserves respect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shouldn't make it
a goal to push benefits onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think food stamps are welfare by
another name. They're right, after all.

            
               * If you read the fine print, the "bonus," which amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX>,
is to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that show the greatest "improvement" in the percent of
low-income working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> receiving food stamps. That
restriction doesn't save the plan, however. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> who are most likely to stigmatize the receipt of welfare.
They are a key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> we don't want to slip into dependence. And removing the
stigma for them is likely to remove it for everyone, including the non-workers
who remain eligible for food stamps.
            

            To read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> regulations on the new food stamp bonus, click here
               .
            

         
      
   
