
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Pains</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> continues to dominate, leading at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
off-leads the story, going instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s new home-rule, power-sharing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, a story nobody else fronts.
The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> met in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time and the
Times quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendee</ENAMEX> as enthused about the personal relationships
he saw there between former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>. The only discordant
note was sounded by the two hard-line <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, who boycotted
the meeting and held a press conference ominously urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not to "get
carried away about new dawns and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">new days</TIMEX> having arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead details much local ferment about the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> handled the
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> inside has an excellent up-close on
some of the self-proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anarchists</ENAMEX> thought to have been responsible for
much of the violence and destruction on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. But the general
thrust of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> reporting is that with the discord outside the trade meeting
pretty much subsiding, there was a chance to focus finally on the discord
inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> refers to the meeting as a potential "fiasco." The most
divisive policy point is centered on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s suggestion earlier in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> failing to meet basic labor standards might be subject
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> sanctions. The coverage reports that this was rejected by business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> and developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>,
who view such standards as thinly veiled protectionism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> as threatening to "explode the meeting" if the
proposal goes forward. To further confuse things, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quote Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> as saying that the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. WTO</ENAMEX>
negotiation position does not include the sanction idea.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that just prior to leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
signed a bill banning extreme conditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor, citing as he did so
the examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't explain
how any bill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could sign could affect conditions overseas. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does: What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-sanctioned international
treaty. This too, the paper adds, was a cause of upset, with developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> pointing out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has been generally laggard in endorsing
other international labor codes.

            Everybody fronts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' debate (not the
right word, since, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> point out, there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>-to-candidate
questioning), the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. The coverage views the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> as focusing most of its energy on testing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, especially on taxes and
foreign policy. Verdict: No major gaffes. But both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
seem most charmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>--they get a kick out of reporting on his
answer to the question, "Would you reappoint <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>?" If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> were to die, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> said, "I would do like they did in the movie
Weekend at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie</ENAMEX>'s . I would prop him up and put a pair of dark
glasses on him."

            A difference of style is on display for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s recent
characterizations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> platform. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story is slugged,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY REBUTS GORE ON HEALTH CARE AND SOCIAL SECURITY</ENAMEX>," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
opts for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GORE</ENAMEX> LIES REPEATEDLY, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY SAYS</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> flags high in its front-page business
news box word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> has hired a Wall Street investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> as a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> protestations
otherwise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> sees this as a signal that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> might be
contemplating a sweeping restructuring of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. At the very least, the
paper suggests, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is viewing the move as opening round saber-rattling
going into the settlement talks.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Michael Lerner</ENAMEX>, briefly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> early in the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration, is featured on the LAT op-ed page making the stretchiest
pitch yet for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>. They are, explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lerner</ENAMEX>, fighting the "same
battle that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> will celebrate by lighting candles for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX>, starting
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>." Another ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintonite</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, explains to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source</ENAMEX>" that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s 'I'm sorry'
gift. This is his marital comeback strategy. If she runs for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, she'll
need him to raise money. If she runs, she'll lose. If she loses, she'll need
him. But if she wins, she'll divorce him."

         
      
   
