
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smile</ENAMEX>, You're on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>:

            I had an interesting focus group moment before and during the debate that
told me all I needed to know about it (or so I thought). I couldn't watch it in
real-time because I was co-hosting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> or so welcoming the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and not a single person
here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> lives and governs, seemed even to know or
care that he and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were having at it while we made
polite conversation and munched <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushroom rugalach</ENAMEX>. Not a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>--and trust me, this was an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ink-Stained-Wretchathon</ENAMEX>--seemed even remotely
interested to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was sparring with yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England TV</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. Not a single highly paid political spinner or slick <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster</ENAMEX> (as we
privately refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>) seemed even a little bit curious to learn about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s positions on abortion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, or welfare recipientarians. The
reason is that the damn thing didn't matter and wouldn't unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> or maybe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> began speaking in tongues (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> stopped). They aren't debates,
no matter how many times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> stiffly turn to address each other.
There's nothing being debated here. They don't really answer the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">questioner</ENAMEX>'s
questions, and they don't bother to rebuff each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame parries</ENAMEX>. They
regurgitate their pre-packaged sound bites (which are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> food of
political discourse; add <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and serve), stand up straight, smile wide, and
get the hell off stage.

            That said, when I flipped on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Channel</ENAMEX> rerun at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> my time, there
was plenty to see. You're right about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>--he didn't look right. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point,
I thought I saw him rocking back and forth on the balls of his feet. I couldn't
tell if he was nervous or excited, but he wasn't comfortable; he wasn't in his
element. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is all about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX>. He's an absolutely fabulous retail
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. Put him in a social setting, where he gets to grab shoulders and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kiss</ENAMEX> cheeks and twinkle, and he could be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>. But in front of a big
audience he's off his game. I haven't seen every one of his speeches this
campaign, obviously, but the ones I've seen have been really mediocre--not in
the writing but the delivery. In this way he isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, and he isn't his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dad</ENAMEX>, and he isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. They could all get up, do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TelePrompTer</ENAMEX> fandango,
and say "God bless" in one fluid motion (in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> the elder's case, too fluid).
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>'s not cut out for dramatic pauses, laugh lines, etc. He rushes, slurs,
put the right emphasis on the wrong words, and twists his face up into a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-smirk that distracts you from the message. I bet he's distracted too: He'd
rather be anywhere else. There was a lot of this in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s performance last
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Did you notice him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weirdly</ENAMEX> laughing when other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, particularly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, were speaking? I realize it was hard not to laugh, but like I said, it
didn't look right. I keep having to remind myself that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has a mixed history
of debating. He did OK against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX>, a tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'94</TIMEX>, but a
much weaker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'98</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Mauro</ENAMEX>, cleaned the floor with him in their
one debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>. Fortunately for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> it was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> during
high-school football <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, so <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saw it. Judging by my focus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> last night, it's possible that not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> saw this one either. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> shouldn't worry. Stylistic quibbles aside, he was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>'s big winner.
How could he not be, given who he's running against?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files analogy</ENAMEX> is right on; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> has to stop smiling or
else <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Mulder</ENAMEX> is going to put one of those sharp stainless-steel thingies in
the back of his neck. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is sooooooo strange. As far as I'm concerned, he
lost any shred of a chance he had when he refused to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to consider a
change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> age. By doing so, he gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> his best shot of
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>. Prepped for an assault, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> whipped out an editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> had
written in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> consider
such a change. (Of course, the joke's on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>: I'd bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>
didn't write that himself. Somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Canaan</ENAMEX>, a former editorial
assistant is getting his hand wickedly slapped in retrospect.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> smiled a lot, too. Was this a deliberate attempt to mute the
criticism of his temper, or was he going after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> alien vote? Like
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, I find myself oddly compelled to want to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, whose
honesty and openness is appealing, but he creeped me out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. Every one
of his answers went in one of my ears and out the other because they were
delivered from behind an enormous, unnatural smile. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, lose the happy
pills--or change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharmacists</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>. Do I really want to waste my breath? No. But let me
say just one thing: It ain't racism that's causing the media to ignore his
campaign; it's no-chance-in-hellism.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, to my surprise, was the least nutty of the nuts. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> didn't
do a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">360</NUMEX> on his neck; no need to call a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> or an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>. But his
positions on the sanctity of life on down are simply too extreme for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> and, therefore, way too extreme for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, which is
momentarily moderate. Otherwise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> would be running.

            Instead, we get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borrin' Hatch</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>, it's going to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long year</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Evan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
