
   
   
      
         
            Sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Cars</ENAMEX>, and Carville

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>-acto <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knife Award</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creative Editing</ENAMEX> goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of
the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleepy Hollow</ENAMEX> . Their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ads feature this
quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> :

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Sleepy Hollow</ENAMEX>' has got to be the most gorgeous, sumptuous, painterly movie
ever made ..."

            

            The full sentence, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Giles</ENAMEX>' review, reads:

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Sleepy Hollow</ENAMEX>' has got to be the most gorgeous, sumptuous painterly movie
ever made about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple decapitations</ENAMEX>."

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Carville Hitches a Ride</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>--last seen
pathetically weaseling out of his ill-considered offer to pay
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> "to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who can show me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> linked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sexual misconduct with his childhood" in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Franks</ENAMEX>'
Talk article--is now "volunteering" to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to campaign
against Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>. "I'm
going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. I'm setting up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carville</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . Has it occurred to anyone on Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s campaign
staff that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> might not be entirely congruent with the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lady</ENAMEX>'s? Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants to get elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>. Carville no doubt wants her
to get elected, too, but above all he needs to draw attention to himself to
pump up his book sales and lecture fees. It's in his interest to make a fuss in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> even if it doesn't help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> a bit in the polls--even if he hurts
her. How could he hurt? Because he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-era <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who reminds
undecided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of everything about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past eight years</TIMEX> they'd like to be rid
of. ...

            
               Mandatory Automotive Items: The news in the latest Consumer
Reports "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Car Preview</ENAMEX>" is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9-5</ENAMEX>'s terrific reliability score. Who
would have thought a car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> half-owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> would build a
car--even a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> car--as trouble-free in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first year</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>? Maybe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX> won't be ruined if, as expected, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> buys <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of it. ... A
previous, highly scientific kausfiles item proclaimed the victory, in the marketplace,
of "high-butt" over "low-butt" auto designs. Further confirming evidence now
comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> raised the rear end of its mass-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> four
inches--and raised sales <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX> (compared with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</TIMEX>), according
to figures released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. Indeed, the new, non-drooping <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> outsold the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camry</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> to become the best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX> time raise the rear <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five inches</NUMEX>! The sky's the limit! ...

            
               Yent-a-Matic No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: 
               An occasional feature in which kausfiles
suggests romantic possibilities between public figures who may or may not
know each other . This is one of our classier matchups:
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Williams</ENAMEX> , slightly neurotic,
obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of the long-awaited, critically acclaimed country-rock album
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Car Wheels</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gravel Road</ENAMEX>,

and


               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> , slightly neurotic, obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the long-awaited,
critically acclaimed book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explaining Hitler</ENAMEX> .

            Bonus rationale: He's a sometime literary and
music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>; she's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of a respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>.

            Notes: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>-- Don't read her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-inaugural poem. It stank! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda</ENAMEX>-- Write a song about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pale</ENAMEX>
Fire and he's yours!

         
      
   
