
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper Chase</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>,

            It has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> since you left home, and we have been talking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intermittently</ENAMEX> since then by telephone. You have gone far geographically, and,
I was going to say, careerwise, but as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is a strict grammarian I
knew she would wince at that "wise" ending. (We used to say that when you were
an undergraduate at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, you were one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who knew that one
should not begin a sentence with "Hopefully," and more, why one should not do
so.) In any event, meander as I am wont to do, you have gone far in your chosen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>. (I used to say that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and yourself, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ph.D.s</ENAMEX> in early
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> history, would go to any lengths to find a subject for which
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> could not give you a bibliography.)

            Now we are talking by e-mail, an unfamiliar venue for me. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has a
computer; I don't, though I use hers fitfully. This is in spite of the fact
that I taught <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> on technology for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 10 years</TIMEX> before I retired and
have even written books on the new technology. But as you know, I always
consider myself in the position of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> drafted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> navy
who, when asked if he knew how to swim, replied: I know the theory of it. My
interest is in theory because I am interested in the logic of technology and
how that unfolds. And as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX>, I have long argued for the priority of
theory, since theory allows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to take a finding or a proposition out of one
context and apply these to different, and even unfamiliar ones. I stand by the
old saw: If something works in practice, does it also work in theory?

            As you can see, I am seeking to avoid getting started over this unfamiliar
route and talking, as we are supposed to do, about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s events as they
unfold in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. But the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, for me, is
something I read at a distance, so to speak. Though we have now lived in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 30 years</TIMEX>, I do not see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> , our local
paper. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Each morning</TIMEX>, before we get up, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> are delivered to our door. I have always found the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> to be somewhat dull and parochial, and I would know what was
playing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> nabes, rather than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. But now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
has a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> edition, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> weather and television schedule, and the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tab</ENAMEX>," a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>" paper with special town editions, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, tells
me what is playing at the local movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.

            We get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> because it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and has all the news
that it sees fit to print. And having recently been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, we
appreciate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> all the more for its detailed news coverage, as
against all the nattering about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alistair Campbell</ENAMEX> that
fills to overflowing the quality <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. And the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , for its intriguing front-page news stories and the succinct
presentation of business and political news in two columns, even though the
editorial page makes me gnash my teeth. I would prefer the London Financial
Times , which is the only decent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> (and I mean decent in
many senses, since they do not show tits and bums or print gossip about the
marital adventures of cabinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>), but it is too expensive to get here
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>. Besides, we read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> regularly, such a prize for its
fine and lucid prose and its comprehensive worldwide coverage that fills the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gaps</ENAMEX> left by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> .

            All right, to the news. ... But I have gone on nattering for the asked-for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half</TIMEX>, so why don't you begin?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dad</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
