
   
   
      
         
            Mixed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messages for African-American Actors</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Elvis</ENAMEX>,

            Your message arrived in my inbox and I couldn't open it with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UULite</ENAMEX>, StuffIt
Expander, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeBabelizer</ENAMEX>. E-mail is still not quite a universal medium when a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> who has been online for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> and writes a column for a Web magazine
can't open a binary attachment. Eventually a small, dim light bulb illuminated
above my head, and I simply went to the 
                  Slate
                Web site--where, of
course, your posting was waiting.

            I had a real problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best Man</ENAMEX> , and maybe this is the best
place to talk about it. I went to see it at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>, and found it static and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">talky</ENAMEX>. I left after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, because I had another screening next door I
had to attend, and because I thought perhaps on a fresh day, freed from
the back-to-back festival screening routine, it might look different. On a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> viewing back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, it did not, and I passed it to another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, just to give it another shot.

            I thought <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best Man</ENAMEX> was similar to, and inferior to, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX> , which came out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and was also a movie about high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
having a reunion at a wedding. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX> had many of the same qualities
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best Man</ENAMEX> , but more life and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, and it knew a lot more about
how to use a camera instead of lining up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> for prolonged
heart-to-hearts.

            I know what you mean about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Clarke Duncan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in The
Green <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mile</ENAMEX> . His function is essentially to absorb and process white pain,
suffering, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, and guilt, which he does visibly--which is a novel change
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the decades</TIMEX> of films in which black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have done the same thing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">invisibly</ENAMEX> (is there much difference between what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duncan</ENAMEX> does for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> here and
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poitier</ENAMEX> did for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Steiger in In the Heat of the Night</ENAMEX> ?). I also
wondered whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> death row would have been integrated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>, and
whether all but one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> would have been so decent and humane.

            On the other hand, I wonder whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>)
should be subjected to the kind of unspoken test that no white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> or
character ever has to face. No one ever asks whether a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, as a white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, should have played a given role. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coffey</ENAMEX> had been played by a
white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perlman</ENAMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and race would have gone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unremarked</ENAMEX>.

            I remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morgan Freeman</ENAMEX>'s regret as he told me that the recent role he
most wanted was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannibal Lecter</ENAMEX>--"but of course they couldn't let a black man
play a villain like that." Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeman</ENAMEX> is one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> I can think
of who might have equaled or improved on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX>' performance, I share
his regret that for no-doubt pious liberal reasons a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> could not be
considered.

            This just in: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry J. Lennix</ENAMEX> does a superb job
of playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch-villain</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titus</ENAMEX> , although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX>,
of course, gets to bake <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamora</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat pies</ENAMEX>.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
