
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO Protesters</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chastise Cuba</ENAMEX>, Not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NikeTown</ENAMEX> may make irresistible targets for the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> who have been tying up, and tearing up, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. But the real
engines behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>'s hesitancy to take up environmental and labor standards
are not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>. They're the developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to which those
standards would be applied.

            This point seems either incredibly naive (since we all know that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">multinational U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> really rule the world) or incredibly banal
(since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> can't really do anything if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of its
membership--the developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--disapproves). Perhaps the point is both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">naive</ENAMEX> and banal. But it's still true, and imagining that low wages and poor
working conditions are realities imposed upon developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> is a delusion that makes understanding the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> impossible.

            It was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, after all, who said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that
developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> needed to stick together, because "we produce goods and
services with comparative advantages that they [that is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>] are trying to take away under the pretext of so-called labor
standards." And it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> who are insisting that
those standards stay off the table, precisely because they fear that their
inclusion in trade talks will eliminate any incentives for foreign (or even
domestic) investment.

            Now, just because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is against higher labor
standards doesn't mean either that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are against them
or that we in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should simply defer to the wishes of
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. There are powerful indigenous movements in almost every
developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in favor of better working conditions and higher wages, and
in any case the fear of engaging in cultural imperialism is a poor guide to
making policy. But there is still something in the absence of developing-nation
support for new standards that should give us pause.

            From a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buchananite</ENAMEX> perspective, of course, developing-nation hostility to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> intervention is irrelevant, because in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s ideal world, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> wouldn't be trading with those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> at all. From what you might call
the internationalist anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> perspective, though, there's a real paradox here,
since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is simultaneously excoriated for being a kind of supranational
government smashing down local regulations and excoriated for not being enough
of a supranational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to create global living and working
standards.

            The paradox exists, though, because opposition to free trade depends upon
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> antithetical ideas, both of which, interestingly enough, are wrong. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that free trade is lowering the standard of living in developed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> by encouraging the migration of jobs and the creation of trade
deficits. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is that free trade is widening the economic gap between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> and poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. (A common corollary to this is that trade is widening
the gap between rich and poor in all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.) For both these to be true,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> would have to be losing jobs and productive capacity and
getting richer at the same time, even as developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> would be taking
away jobs, growing faster, and yet getting poorer.

            That's not happening, of course. It's almost certainly true that certain
sectors of developed economies (textiles, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>) are hurt by free trade, but
it's equally true that other sectors (computer software and hardware, financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>) are helped. More to the point, the fundamental truth of free trade is
that when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> produce those goods in which they have a comparative
advantage, both sides benefit, because capital ends up being allocated to its
most productive uses, which is the only way real wealth can be created.

            I don't know whether that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> has suddenly started reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricardo</ENAMEX>, but his invocation of "comparative advantage" was right on target. For
developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the one meaningful road to economic development, which is
to say the only way they can narrow the gap between themselves and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, is via free trade. It's a mistake for these
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to argue that having minimum-wage laws or regulations keeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> from running toxic dumps will wreck their chances of competing in
the world market, just like it's a mistake for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to argue that
having a minimum-wage law in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> does irreparable harm to them.
But it's not a mistake for these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to believe that the fewer barriers
to trade--of whatever sort--there are, the better. The really interesting
thing, of course, is that it's not a mistake for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to believe
that, either.

         
      
   
