
   
   
      
         
            Mind Their Manners
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> could have used the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several decades ago</TIMEX>. Though I am
confident a good plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> could help now. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Insert</ENAMEX> jokes about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality surgeons</ENAMEX> here.)

            Looks ... I'm more interested in manners. And it's here that you, dear
Prudie, could provide some real insight into the campaign. Which of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> has the best manners? And does it matter? We are, after all,
obsessed with authenticity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>--the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. At least, that's what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> and the newsmagazines blare. But it's the fake stuff that interests
me more, and here I am talking about such things as etiquette and decency. I
want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who is true to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more than he is true to himself.
I'll let you weigh in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> on this one, because of your expertise on the
subject.

            As far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> malapropisms go--or as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> calls them,
"Bushisms"--I have a dandy from an interview that I had with the good governor
of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> (which if it were a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, would be the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11 th</NUMEX> largest economy in the world). I asked him about the efforts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptists</ENAMEX> to convert <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and he responded: "I mean, that's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptists</ENAMEX>. But I don't think that this is a government function." And
on that note--where my questions to presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> really do make me
look like an obsessive on the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yidden</ENAMEX>--I leave it to you. I'll try to
file my next entry from the debate.

            Catching rays for you,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
