
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twitchy Bush</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Extraterrestrial Forbes</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>:

            I was happy to see you refer to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> where "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> smoke freely at
their tables" as "unsullied," just as I was discouraged but not surprised to
learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marfa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, are dreaming about easy IPO riches. At
least they're smoking as they do it. Someday even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> will be smoke-free
and doing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tae-Bo</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will have lost something.

            Pardon me, but I'm in a nostalgic mood. Must be the effect of watching last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">night</ENAMEX>'s debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did a decent job, I thought, but he just didn't come
across the way he did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months ago</TIMEX>. He seemed far stiffer and more programmed
than I remember. His physical restlessness, which always stuck me as
appealingly energetic and vital, all of a sudden seemed twitchy and nervous.
Part of it is context. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is so much better in person than he is behind a
microphone that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've experienced him only through television must be
baffled by his endorsements and fund-raising success. But it's more than that.
I think he's changed.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This spring</TIMEX>, for instance, I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> about his reading habits. He was
pretty straightforward about preferring page-long briefing memos from his staff
and sports on TV. He didn't pull a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> and brag about reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX> in
the original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> asked him what he was
reading, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> boldly claimed to be immersed in "a book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX>."

            There's nothing wrong with not reading books about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX>. There is
something awful about pretending you do. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX>'s a pretty nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, so he didn't
hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> with the obvious and tempting follow-up questions: A book about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>
Acheson, huh? Quick: What's the title of the book? Who wrote it? How many terms
did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX> serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>? That's a trick question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gotcha</ENAMEX>.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX> phoniness wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s real problem last night. He did
himself the greatest damage when he agreed to appear with the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. Yes, I know he had no choice, that the political
costs of ditching another debate were too high. Still, it's hard to maintain a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-runner</ENAMEX>'s dignity and mystique if you're sharing a stage with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>.

            Not to beat up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>. I like him. He seems sincere. He's a totally
compelling orator, one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I've ever heard who speaks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extemporaneously</ENAMEX> in flawless, perfectly delineated, ready-to-print paragraphs.
And I agree with him on more things than you probably care to know about. In
fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> doesn't really fall apart until you administer what I think of as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Despot Test</ENAMEX>. It's simple: If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> had absolute power, how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would he kill? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> doesn't do well on this part of the exam. At all.
There's something about his eyes.

            Speaking of, I had a pretty disturbing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-Files moment toward the end
of the debate when I looked too long at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>. Mesmerized by his
unblinking stare, I suddenly had the feeling he was going to steal my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>. I
choked back panic and turned away, probably just in time. Spooky.

            I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has had the same experience, which may explain why he was
comparatively tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, who poses no real threat to him, while he went
out of his way to stroke <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> (literally at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, on the cheek), who has
a shot at beating him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> one gets the sense that a lot
of politics is personal. Doesn't bother me. At least he knows an alien when he
sees <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
