
   
   
      
         
            It's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smart To Be Dumb</ENAMEX>

            Massa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>:

            You know, of course, that the free-floating envy we regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> have for
you political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> is all about the post-event kickback session in the
hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. We imagine that the lubricated and informed nature of your skewering
is just better than ours. What political junkie wouldn't give anything to hear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News and World Report</ENAMEX> , say, tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> that for
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who's been marinated in money, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dubya</ENAMEX> seems particularly beset by plural
articles and singular verbs. I really am waiting--maybe the next debate?--for
someone to ask him what caused <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, and for him to tell us it was
Lust, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avarice, Sloth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX> book or no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX>
book, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> clearly doesn't know from history.

            To show solidarity with you, I watched the whole encounter, larded up as it
was with odd rules. Even if they all meant what they said--or even wrote it--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> simply cannot do everything he wants, and can't do anything by
himself, so who really cares what gets said there? It's all just
blah-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">blah</NUMEX>-blah. The only useful byproduct, perhaps, is that we get to see who's
uncomfortable with concepts, or who oughta' be given a pulpit.

            After a while, I couldn't even make myself listen. Do you think I have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.D.D.</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was the only one who came across as smart, informed, and
seemingly unscripted, though even he, in the wrap-up, seemed a little bit on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autopilot</ENAMEX>. Maybe all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--both parties--could just stipulate that they
plan to be good, fair, more, better. The impressions I came away with were that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> works the plantation metaphors for reasons unclear to me. I already know
he's black. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> looks like a toy ... a doll whose name I cannot for the life
of me remember. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ... well, he just seems like some lucky sum' bitch who
was whisked out onto center stage, no rehearsal necessary. (This is assuming,
of course, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> imagines it lucky to wind up in the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>.) Not to
be fixated or anything, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> finessed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX> book challenge. The
problem is that I haven't read that book, so I don't know if they caught
him out or not. And I want to know. Do you know? Maybe they could put a truth
squad up there when these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> go at it.

            Since I was invited into no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> after the "debate," I read the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , which, strangely, gave me an overview of some of what I had just
seen: In this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election year</TIMEX>, it's smart to be dumb. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anti-intellectualism</ENAMEX> plays
well and equates with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>." Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. Anyway, come on out of that
desert. And don't forget orrinhatch.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xxM</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
