
   
   
      
         
            How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Bout That Yahoo</ENAMEX>!?
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> reached yet another all-time high, the most
astounding move was made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahoo</ENAMEX>, which leapt <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX>, adding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $17</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> to its market capitalization. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> is joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">S&P 500</ENAMEX> tomorrow
(making it only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, to do so), and in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> since its addition to the index was announced its share price has risen
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 150</NUMEX> points.

            The situation, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least today</TIMEX>, boiled down to too much demand chasing too
little supply. Index funds, which track the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> directly, had to buy shares
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> in proportion to its market cap, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> is market-cap
weighted. And since there are plenty of mutual fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> out there who try
to mimic the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX>--while charging significantly more in fees than an index
fund--there was other institutional money chasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahoo</ENAMEX> as well. And as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s shares became more expensive, funds had to buy more of them (because
of the market-cap weighting). The result was a virtuous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> and
a truly vicious one for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>.

            Still, the picture seems a bit more complicated than this, because the
average trade in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yahoo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">503</NUMEX> shares. Needless to say, most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> are not buying stock in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>-share lots, so that means that a great
deal of the action <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was driven by individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and, most likely,
day <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> hoping to ride the stock's momentum and to get out before the
eventual fall. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> was, in that sense, a moment when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>'s crucial
stock-market trends--indexing, momentum investing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> investing, and
the Internet--converged to make <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yahoo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> very happy indeed.

            It's almost certain that the stock will fall in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to come, but its ride
up has been so furious, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is such a good one, that it would be
surprising if the tumble were too precipitous. In any case, the most important
thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX>'s addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> is not the effect on its stock
price. Instead, it's the way that addition drives home an often-overlooked but
nonetheless crucial fact about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">S&P 500</ENAMEX>, that it is as actively managed
as any mutual fund.

            This point was first made, as far as I can tell, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Miller</ENAMEX>, the
brilliant fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legg Mason Value Trust</ENAMEX>, in a letter to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>. Index funds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> pointed out, are passively managed,
which is to say that they simply duplicate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">S&P 500</ENAMEX> in order to
replicate the performance of the "market." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">S&P 500</ENAMEX> itself is added
to and subtracted from in an attempt to make the index look as much like the
stock market, and the economy as a whole, as possible.

            If this is the case, why is it so difficult for fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to beat index
funds based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX>? There seem to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, and most
obvious, is that index funds have minuscule fees and very low transaction
costs. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, though, is that the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> is weighted by
market capitalization means that it manages money--and therefore
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">investments</ENAMEX>--in almost a textbook fashion. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> grow more successful,
and more expensive, they take up a larger percentage of the index, and as they
grow less successful, and cheaper, they take up a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">smaller percentage</NUMEX>. In other
words, the index effectively allows its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> to run and its losers to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dwindle</ENAMEX>.

            You'll often hear fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> say it's unfair to benchmark them against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> because it does things like add <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> and take out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laidlaw</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that will be booted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>). Assuming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahoo</ENAMEX>, even with its
recent run-up, will do better over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laidlaw</ENAMEX>, then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> will do better than it would otherwise have done. (Significantly
better, in fact, given the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX>'s market capitalization.) But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX>'s approach to investing--add dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> the market has already
rewarded--and to money management is easily replicable. It's a measure of how
addicted to trading fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> have become that instead of replicating that
approach, they prefer to complain about it.

         
      
   
