
   
   
      
         
            Trust in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
            

            That new scrolling investment ticker at the top of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moneybox</ENAMEX> has not been a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> hit. Personally, I like it (although I can't figure out why it runs
on my desktop but not my laptop--presumably that has something to do with the
browsers I'm using on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> machines). But some of you find it intrusive, and
others are bothered by the perpetual pop-up box asking whether you want to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">install Microsoft Investor Ticker</ENAMEX>.*

            I can understand why you'd like that box to go away once and for all--our
crack techies are working on a solution to the problem, but as they say, it's
not trivial--but before you do, recognize that the copy in that pop-up <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">box</ENAMEX> is
absolutely remarkable. Here's how it read when I installed the ticker:

            "Do you want to install and run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Investor Ticker</ENAMEX> signed on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/4/99</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:23 PM</TIMEX> and distributed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corporation</ENAMEX>?

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX> authenticity verified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VeriSign Commercial Software Publishers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CA.</ENAMEX>"

            "Caution: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corporation</ENAMEX> asserts that this content is safe. You
should install/view this content if you trust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corporation</ENAMEX> to make
that assertion."

            Then comes the kicker at the bottom, with a little box you can check to
assent to the following statement:

            "Always trust content from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corporation</ENAMEX>."

            Always? God only knows what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> will make of this.

            * The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Investor Ticker</ENAMEX> is available only for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX>.
            

         
      
   
