
   
   
      
         
            Remember <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead with the arrest of
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> is being held without bail
on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> counts of mishandling nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> design, construction, and testing
information. The indictment alleges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> downloaded data onto <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> portable
tapes and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> tapes are missing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> is not specifically accused of
leaking secrets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. Yet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes, to convict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> on
all counts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must prove that he intended to injure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and benefit a foreign power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> explains that the
indictment might be an attempt to squeeze new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>. The charges
carry life sentences. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> claim he is innocent of wrongdoing. A
LAT front-pager underscores that the indictment does not clarify how
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> acquired nuclear secrets.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s acceptance of an offer to apply for
membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> was reluctant to accede because of
fears that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> would pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> to relinquish its claim to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX>. To
join, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> must improve its human rights record by abolishing the use of
torture and loosening free speech strictures. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager mentions
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> angered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and embarrassed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> by
voting not to extend an offer of accession to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> has been seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> membership since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front-pager stresses that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> expanded its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> pool
by extending offers to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulgaria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Latvia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lithuania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovakia</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malta</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estonia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovenia</ENAMEX> are
already negotiating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> entry. If all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> are approved, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> will
become a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>-nation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> that encompasses nearly all of central and eastern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> also endorsed a plan to create a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> rapid-reaction force
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franjo Tudjman</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">independent Croatia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> provides plenty of biographical detail:
Tudjman rose to power as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s and 1980s</TIMEX> he was
imprisoned for nationalist activities, and he died of cancer-related
complications. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reefer their obits.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> highlights <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tudjman</ENAMEX> low points--he forced the exodus of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200,000</NUMEX> according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ), hindered the search for
suspected war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, and neglected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX>'s economy.
(
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tudjman</ENAMEX> was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>' lesser evil.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tudjman</ENAMEX>'s reign
he enriched his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $700 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian Constitution</ENAMEX>
dictates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vlatko Pavletic</ENAMEX> will serve as interim
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> until a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is selected.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s timeout. After suffering a bout of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart palpitations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> cancelled a campaign appearance and three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raisers</ENAMEX>. He went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> but did not require treatment. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was diagnosed with atrial fibrillation--a heart rhythm problem that
afflicts former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2 million</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reefers the story but notes that health questions dogged the late
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> presidential campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
received mild electrical shocks to treat his arrhythmia on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> occasions
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior to 1998</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> underwent the
"cardioversion" treatment twice.) In a reefer, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> downplays
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health problem.

            Wilderness programs for wayward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are the latest frontier of the therapy
industry, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of programs aim to
rehabilitate troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> by forcing them to brave the rigors of the great
outdoors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redcliff Ascent Outdoor Therapy Program</ENAMEX> provides group counseling
and forbids sarcasm. Although the concept is as old as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> pay as
much as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350</NUMEX> a day.

         
      
   
