
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Debates</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANNCHESTER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teflon</ENAMEX> is back. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who appears to
have inherited this invisible armor from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, who
finally entered the fray <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Forum</ENAMEX> sponsored
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WMUR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> television. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> press questioners, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Brown</ENAMEX> and Brit
Hume, planted various <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> in his path. None detonated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> lobbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">grenades</ENAMEX> at him. They all bounced harmlessly off.


            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s effectiveness didn't have much to do with the quality of his answers.
These were merely adequate, giving off in some cases a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaylean</ENAMEX> whiff of heavy
pre-programming, especially on foreign policy topics. Rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s appeal
derived from his demeanor. He seemed not only at ease in the confrontational
setting but to be enjoying himself--savoring the pleasure of being shot at and
missed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wore a jaunty grin through most of the debate, grasping the podium
as if it were the steering wheel of a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. When one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pygmies</ENAMEX> attacked him, his grin would turn into a smirk. The smirk turned into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cackle</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> went after him for considering the possibility of raising
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> retirement age. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was armed with the perfect comeback: a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">column Forbes</ENAMEX> once wrote advocating exactly the same thing. He read it aloud,
with gusto. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> demanded that he commit to choosing a pro-life running
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> felt no compulsion to respond to him at all. 

            Nor was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> set off balance by questions designed to expose him as a
lightweight. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hume</ENAMEX> asked him what sort of thing he liked to read, he didn't
come back with an insecure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s list of big books (the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> once
responded to this question by saying he was reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato's Republic</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> answered, "I read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>." He subsequently mentioned "a book about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX>." It would have been interesting to quiz him further about the
contents of this work, but the format didn't permit it.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> seemed Teflon-coated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>--the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aggressor</ENAMEX> against him
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>--was pure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Velcro</ENAMEX>. Whenever someone criticized him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> looked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sheepish</ENAMEX> and guilty, like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> caught stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> was mainly a
target for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>, who is running against him in a separate, unofficial campaign
for headman of the religious right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bauer</ENAMEX> landed blows against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> for
wanting to privatize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and for proposing tax cuts that would
mainly benefit the rich and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> grimaced at every blow and
didn't defend his positions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, who came across as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did, spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most of the evening</TIMEX>
doing stand-up comedy. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> shouldn't be
reappointed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> if he persists in raising interest rates,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> volunteered that he thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> is doing a great job. "Not only
would I reappoint Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>, if Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> should happen to die, I would
do like they did in the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weekend at Bernie's</ENAMEX> ," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> said. "I'd
prop him up and put a pair of dark glasses on him." If you were watching at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, you saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> laughing hysterically at this, perhaps recalling his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fraternity days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> also kept up a running gag about his supposedly fierce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temper</ENAMEX>, which robbed the charge of any possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> took a dig
at him on the issue anyhow. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hume</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s behavior in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> responded: "He does have a temper and sometimes it's terrible
to be on the other side of it." This prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, sincerely
but somewhat patronizingly, as "a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> did not disappoint those who missed his antics last time. Asked about
his allegation that the media treat him in a racist fashion, he stuck to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, saying he wasn't covered by the press, despite his obvious appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, because "blackout means black out ." At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point Keyes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attacked Bush</ENAMEX>'s proposed tax cuts as insufficient by saying that we shouldn't
"get down on our knees and thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massa Bush</ENAMEX> for letting us keep more of our own
money," describing that as "thinking like slaves." After the debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> once
again came into the media filing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and repeated his nutty
performance from the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> debate virtually word for word.
"You ignore my successes, just as you ignored my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ancestors</ENAMEX>' successes," he
exploded at a harmless question. "And then you want to tell me you're not a
racist! You better think about it, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>! You better think about what
you're doing!"

            Nobody called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Keyes</ENAMEX> on the most outrageous thing he said in the debate, that
atrocities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> were mostly "propaganda" devised by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration in order to manipulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> into supporting a
war. It was something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noam Chomsky</ENAMEX> might have said--or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>.  

         
      
   
