
   
   
      
         
            Are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain Really Neck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neck</ENAMEX>?
            

            A recent poll found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> among New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> percentage points, with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> margin of error.
Does this mean they are really in a dead heat?

            Possibly. You actually need <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> numbers to understand a poll. One is the
margin of error --an estimate of how large a discrepancy might exist
between a survey's results and the true value. (It's unlikely, for instance,
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> polled in some national survey will speak accurately for all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The margin of error measures just how wrong those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could be.) The margin of error is typically <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 to 5 percent</NUMEX> and is almost
always cited alongside the results. The other important number is the degree
of confidence , which is the likelihood that the real value falls within the
margin of error. Most polls use a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> degree of confidence, so it's
usually omitted from news reports.

            Here's an example of how the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> numbers work together. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters/WHDH-TV</ENAMEX> poll showed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent to 32 percent</NUMEX> with a
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> margin of error. This means that there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> chance
(there's the degree of confidence) that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 30 and 40 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population supports</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> (that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> plus or minus the margin
of error), and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> chance that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 27 and 37 percent</NUMEX> supports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            So, based on this poll, how sure can we be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is truly ahead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>? The answer is, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 95 percent</NUMEX> sure. The reported margin of error
relates to each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s individual score. But the margin of error on
the spread (i.e., the difference between their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX>) is much larger, since it
incorporates the potential variations in both scores. As a rule of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thumb</ENAMEX>, you can multiply the reported margin of error by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX> to get the margin
of error for the spread. Since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX> times <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.5</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters/WHDH-TV</ENAMEX> survey
would need to show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least an 8.5 percent</NUMEX> advantage over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for
his lead to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> certain. Since his lead is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> percentage
points, it's being called a dead heat. But the small lead is not meaningless;
although it is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 95 percent</NUMEX> certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, it is still
more likely than not that he is really ahead.

            (Visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Statistical Association</ENAMEX>'s Web site
for extensive information on common methods--and errors--in measuring public
opinion.)

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks many 
               Slate 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> for suggesting this
topic.
            

            Next question?

         
      
   
