
   
   
      
         
            Who's Afraid of an Internet Tax?

            Judging from the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential debates, the new big issue
in this campaign is taxation of Internet commerce. Or rather, since none of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> wants to tax Internet commerce right now, the issue is who is
most committed to extending the current congressional moratorium on taxing
Internet commerce, which runs out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. Writing in the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 6</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Harwood</ENAMEX> identified Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taxation</ENAMEX> as a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX> wedge issue" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, who
says he wants to extend the moratorium but won't rule out Internet taxes in the
future. In the zany context of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> nomination race, this makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
a tax-and-spend liberal. Here's how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harwood</ENAMEX> explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
political dilemma:

            

               
                  The issue pits traditionally <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Republican Main Street</ENAMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietors</ENAMEX>
against the highflying <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> who have contributed more
to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign than any other. It also pits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of
antitax economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> against many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> whom
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is relying upon to support his primary campaign. ... The reason that
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and his gubernatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backers</ENAMEX> are loath to support a permanent ban is
they tend to rely heavily on sales taxes to fund their state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>, of course, have it exactly right. It's totally
unfair that Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> can sell their wares without making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
pay state sales taxes, given that bricks-and-mortar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are obliged to make
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> pay state sales taxes. A reasonable alternative to
taxing Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commerce</ENAMEX> would be for all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to eliminate sales taxes
altogether and make up the lost revenue with increased or new state income
taxes. But don't hold your breath for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> (or even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>) to
embrace that redistributionist solution anytime soon. (Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> are headed in the opposite direction: They propose
eliminating the federal income tax and replacing it with a national sales
tax.)

            In pressing for a tax-free Internet until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of time</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>
are ignoring or minimizing whatever costs that would impose on traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. Check out this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> (from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 6</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> debate on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>) between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justly</ENAMEX> praised for being stirringly responsible on many
other issues in this campaign, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>, you and I have worked on ... the Internet tax moratorium
act. As you know, this was stoutly resisted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> governors
as well. Don't you think we ought to make the Internet tax moratorium
permanent?
               

            

            
               Chatterbox translates: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>, don't you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> in general,
especially <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> of big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> bordering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, are tax-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jerks</ENAMEX> who would make
bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> ? I would never say such a thing, of course, but perhaps
you'll do it for me .

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>: Yes, I really do. I really think that we ought to do it, because I
think it's far overblown to think that the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> buy over the
Internet is going to reduce mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USA</ENAMEX>. I think mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USA</ENAMEX> can compete
very, very well.
               

               I mentioned [in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> debate] <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, I asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that, I said: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX>, what would you do if you could order everything
right over the Internet and have it delivered right to your home? She said: I
still want to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, I want to test things, I want to look at them,
I want to enjoy it. I think she's not alone.
               

            

            
               Chatterbox translates: "Even though usually I'm a big Internet
booster, I am going to pretend now that Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commerce</ENAMEX> will never amount to
much. And I'm going to flatter bricks-and-mortar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> by telling them
they're so powerful that they can subject their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to my new national
sales tax and still trounce the tax-free Internet! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopee</ENAMEX>! It's a good
thing I have no chance of getting elected!"

         
      
   
