
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>?

            Everybody leads with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> to resume peace
talks--probably starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>--after a lapse of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly four years</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times fronts feature a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at his press
conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, where he announced the development.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls the talks a "major foreign policy victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>." The coverage makes it clear that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major issue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>
have to sort out is what to do about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> occupied
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1967 Six Day War</ENAMEX> and which has served as a key security buffer for
it ever since. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is the clearest about another: what to do about
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Syria</ENAMEX> maintains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> and about its support for
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> there conducted by the militant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hezbollah</ENAMEX>.

            The coverage is largely upbeat, with only the LAT including the
following: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> publicly supports the talks, privately the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> were stunned by them and fear that they will have an adverse
affect on their own dealings with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the political opposition in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is not pleased, with one right-wing party viewing the talks as a
complete surrender to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) there is much bitterness too from Golan
Heights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> who fear losing their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.

            Everybody runs stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s press conference yesterday
and all of these mention a question near the end that seemed to have caught him
somewhat flat-footed, a question about why most top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> jobs in his
administration have gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. But all of these stories run inside and
none dwell at length on the issue the question raises. With the exception, that
is, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , which serves up a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,900</NUMEX> word pass
at the topic on its front page. The story highlights the basic fact raised (and
not denied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>) at the press conference: While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has presided over
a historically diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>, all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've held the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> jobs under him have been white, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> of them have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. The story
garners <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> that are sure to give the topic some media
life: Current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Press Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying that when it
comes to crucial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> decisions, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> still have to
fight for a seat at the table." And former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Press Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee Dee Myers</ENAMEX> says,
"The rule is still that when the big decisions get made, it's not as diverse a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> as the overall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. And I'm putting it nicely." The story
tries to suggest important examples where this alleged ethnic skew hurt. The
most convincing: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' slow response to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> civil war and
genocide in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts an exclusive from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> campaign trenches: At a private
fund-raiser organized by gay and lesbian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> said that
the "Don't Ask, Don't Tell" policy crafted by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to govern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the
military was a failure, and that if elected she would work to overturn it. The
Times points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX>'s likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, also opposes
the policy. The paper further reports that at the event the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> also
supported full rights for "same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>," even though, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> she supported, along with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, a bill passed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that
effectively banned gay marriages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> runs the story next to
pictures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> and the killed in the case of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> private convicted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of murdering a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> he'd harassed for being gay.

            An LAT front-pager reveals that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
shooting of rap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notorious B.I.G.</ENAMEX> is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> now in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> on
unrelated bank robbery charges. A theory being pursued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> conspired with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row Records</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion</ENAMEX>
"Suge" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX> to arrange a contract killing of the rapper. On this theory, the
actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> was a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>.

            Everybody reports inside that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> decided, in a lawsuit
brought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>, that a retired local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafe owner</ENAMEX>
was part of a conspiracy involving "governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>" in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> King
murder. This means, explains the coverage, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> does not believe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> convicted of the crime, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX>, was the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a story inside about an execution conducted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>
with possible political ramifications. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> scheduled to be
executed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> was found unconscious from a drug overdose. Nevertheless, the
state decided not to issue a stay of execution for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and instead put him
to death on time. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> was out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> during all this
and so technically not in on the decision, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> confirms he agreed with it. Wackiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">detail</ENAMEX> reported by the
Times : "Because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> deemed such a move 'risky,' state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> used an airplane staffed by medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to ensure that he
arrived in good health after the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25-minute</TIMEX> trip."

            Some quality control problems noted at the WP : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) A story about
trials of an experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-autism</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is slugged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> "Treatment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Counters Autism</ENAMEX>" even though the story goes on to explain that the drug worked
no better in the studies than placebos given to the control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>
story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> runs about a credit card scam targeting senior military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> fails to mention that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> broke the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) over a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heart-wrenching</ENAMEX> story about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 9-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who concealed the accidental death
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>, leaving her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> in their home because he was afraid
of being sent to an orphanage, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes with the bad taste headline
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOTHER</ENAMEX> DIED, BUT <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">BOY, 9, KEPT MUM</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
