
   
   
      
         
            In Praise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s Brain

            In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX> press conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, perhaps inadvertently,
stimulated some thoughts about his presidential legacy. Asked who he would name
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> (reportedly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> has made the same choice). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told the famous story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>,
on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> being elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>, visiting the nonagenarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Wendell Holmes</ENAMEX>, prompting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> to observe that while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> didn't have a first-class mind, he had a first-class temperament.

            By now it's well understood that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lacks a first-class, or even a
second-class, temperament. He can't control his impulses, especially the
libidinal ones; he has an unattractive tendency to blame other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for his
problems; he has a terrifyingly effective gift for misleading and,
occasionally, telling outright lies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who work for him rarely come away
from the experience with a high opinion of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> continues to
believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> (and, without question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>) would have been
better off had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> chosen to resign the presidency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.

            But though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lacks a first-class temperament, he possesses a
first-class mind. By this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't mean only that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
knowledgeable and smart; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> were knowledgeable and
smart, too, but they weren't particularly good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>. As the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speechwriter James Fallows</ENAMEX>* famously observed in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Passionless Presidency</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> had a habit of deploying his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> toward pathetically small matters like deciding who could use the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, was someone whose brilliance
blended <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seamlessly</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>, doing serious damage to his judgment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, by contrast, is
someone whose brain (unlike other parts of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>) seems always to be
deployed in just the right places, shining light on an astonishing variety of
important matters. (Check out his comments at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s press
conference on trade, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, and health care, among others.) The many
accomplishments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, most especially his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of
the economy, resulted much more from the sharpness and discipline of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
mind than from the shiftiness and dithering of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s temperament (which
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have mistaken for brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>).

            There are many smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, but none of
them will likely match <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s ability to wear his intelligence so lightly
and so well. Anyone who's ever read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> in the Balance knows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s formidable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> is a clunky suit of armor. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortunately</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> isn't in his
tortured-intellectual mode, his judgment is much better.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s intelligence has a narcissistic quality, too often focused on
demonstrating its exquisite sensitivity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s intelligence, like his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">temperament</ENAMEX>, is impulsive in the best and worst senses. (For an example of the
latter, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's Afraid</ENAMEX>
of an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax?</ENAMEX>") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' is monomaniacal and deluded. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>' are completely devoted to articulating
(magnificently well) their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> ideologies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
... well, let's just say both are emphasizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and quantity of
experience above all else.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will not miss many things about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> when he's gone. But he
will miss his brain, and that will be missing a lot.

            * subsequently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
