
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheehy Treatment</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choice</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s latest study of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>,
confirms her status as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> explainer--which, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> once pointed out, "is fine if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. If not, not." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> turned self-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> who transformed the
scary-sounding "crises" of academic adult-development theory (such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mid</ENAMEX>-life crisis) into the user-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passages</ENAMEX> , the name of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">megabestseller</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s diagnosis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>-slash-senatorial candidate
has the compelling obviousness of good local gossip, though with the upbeat
ending you'd expect from an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> whose message has consistently been, The
more intense the suffering, the better the chance to grow .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>, became the brilliant and driven <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> she is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> out of a desire to avoid becoming her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, a withdrawn and frustrated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s emotional life was stunted by an unloving, unavailable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who didn't even attend his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s college graduation. His lack
of supportiveness left her susceptible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>, seductive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>,
which led her to abandon her political dreams and take up his, which made her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resentful</ENAMEX>, which caused her to push him even harder than his own considerable
ambitions were already doing, whereupon he self-destructed, which left them
both in a horrible mess, from which she has emerged in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 50s</TIMEX> a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, ready to break out of her chrysalis and fly.

            This is a very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> story, much more so than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Buchanan</ENAMEX>, to
whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> has also been compared. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s faith in change and redemption
reflects an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>-esque optimism about human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">malleability</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F. Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>'s portrait of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">egotist</ENAMEX> whose selfishness wrecks her life and the
lives of everyone around her reeks of dourness. That the newly hatched
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterfly</ENAMEX> that is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s psyche seems to be fluttering straight into the
flames of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX> politics and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s popularity does not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conform to Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s triumphalist narrative, so although she discusses what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s candidacy means to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> doesn't give us a single outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> on it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> is a therapist to the stars, not a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. She tells us how our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> feel , not what they stand for or
what might become of them or even what we should think about the things they
do.

            The way we talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> has come a long way since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolstoy</ENAMEX> railed against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlyle</ENAMEX>'s great-man theory of history <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">130 years ago</TIMEX> in
War and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> : "To study the laws of history, we must entirely change
the subject of our observation, must leave aside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">generals</ENAMEX>, and study the common, infinitesimally small elements that influence
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>." Since then, history has been through a host of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">determinisms</ENAMEX>--economic, demographic, biological, geographic, even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meteorological</ENAMEX>--each meant to relegate the individual psychology of great men
to the realm of the contingent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s innovation is to boldly cast all of
that aside and bring us back to the pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolstoy</ENAMEX> era. For her, the national
stage exists as nothing more nor less than a setting for grand
personalities.

            Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> outdoes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlyle</ENAMEX>, because the only thing that matters to her
is personality; she doesn't give a damn about the national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>. Reading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> is like listening to a botany <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> describe the inner life of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>. What she extracts from the public figures in whose private selves she
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traffics</ENAMEX> is how well they adhere to the rules of growth--preferably the ones
she has sketched out. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s key works in this regard are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passages</ENAMEX> ,
which deals with life up until one's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50s</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Silent Passage</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>),
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about menopause</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Passages</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> adulthood that
begins in one's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50s</TIMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Understanding Men's Passages</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), about male
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">menopause</ENAMEX>.) When she writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Character</ENAMEX> , her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> study of the
political temperament, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX> learned from his defeat for
re-election as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachussetts</ENAMEX> to demonstrate some warmth, that's
good. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> has never transcended the patterns of denial common to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX>, and that, she pronounces, is bad. Never mind how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s psychological idiosyncracies may have changed the nature
of presidential campaigning, the presidency, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> are case studies, just like the ones laid out in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passages</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosalyn</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who had to flee
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> to find herself; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia</ENAMEX>, who enslaved herself to a saintly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">philosopher</ENAMEX> and had to divorce him to find herself; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Babcock</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotchkiss</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> who unconsciously emulated his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in everything
he did, and who, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> implied, had damn well better go through a crisis in
order to find himself, and soon. Each story she tells is a cautionary tale with
the exact same moral: You have to pass through the stages of adult development
or wither and die.

            What are these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stages</ENAMEX> to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> claims we are all subject, regardless
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, race, or creed? Each has its own clever nickname--the Trying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twenties</ENAMEX>, the Catch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirties</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forlorn Forties</ENAMEX>--and archetypal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Transient</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wunderkind, the Caregiver, the Nurturer Who Defers Caregiving</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Caregiver Who Defers Nurturing</ENAMEX>. The important thing, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>, is not to
skip a step: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> cannot jump from A to C, and the only path to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> is through
engaging the tasks of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX>; there are no alternative routes." It's not as if these
steps are unusual or bizarre; on the contrary, they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soothingly</ENAMEX> familiar. At
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, you're supposed to break away from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and find your own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>. At another, you have to commit to a "lifework" or risk drifting into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stasis</ENAMEX>.

            All this is so anodyne as to be completely unobjectionable. If you believe
that personality trumps everything else, you might as well have an idea about
how it works, no matter how banal. The disturbing part is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> uses her
theories not just to explain decisions that have proved historically momentous,
but to explain them away . In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passages</ENAMEX> , for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Panther co-founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eldridge Cleaver</ENAMEX>'s role in the black nationalist movement is
perceived as nothing more than an example of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s difficulty making a
necessary passage: "Taken to the extreme," she writes, "the unwillingness to
commit leaves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">no quarter</TIMEX> for expression of the merger self. If no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, or love match can be trusted (or if, as in the case of Eldridge
Cleaver, the only way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> sees fit to redress the wrongs of society
is to smash it or choose exile from it), the path leads to isolation."

            Banished in those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sentences is the entire world outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleaver</ENAMEX>'s
pushing, expanding, developing self--any racism and poverty he may have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endured</ENAMEX>, the ideas that inflamed him, the time in which he lived. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> claims
he became a revolutionary because he failed to grow properly, like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX> that
has unhealthily abandoned its stick. That's the strangest thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s
model of development: The self comes off as organic, context-less, and amoral,
judged only in reference to the imperative to grow. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s decision to
run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> while still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> good for anyone but her? Is it an
opportunity to expand the oppressive limits of political wifery, or is it an
abuse of her power? Should <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> be glad or sad that she might become its
next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>? About all this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> has nothing to say.

            It's tempting to get up on one's high <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and declare this a wrongheaded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to approach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, whose actions have an impact on the rest of us
too. But that would be like denouncing the weather, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s view is
now the journalistic norm. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, any effort to arrive at a deeper
understanding of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is referred to as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX> treatment.") The
question of whether and how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> has grown in his or her adult years
has become the master narrative of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, who
is more or less running on a record of turning his life around after having
done nothing until he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>. Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, who never stops rediscovering yet
another inner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. Has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> changed in a way that makes him better suited to
govern? Do we really like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s latest reincarnation? Who knows? Who
cares? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheehy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> longs to be given the same free pass--to have hers be
yet another uplifting tale of growth in the face of personal suffering. Will
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> buy it? Culturebox sure hopes not.

            
               Photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Table of</ENAMEX>
Contents by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter Morgan/Reuters</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
