
   
   
      
         
            Let <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Us Now Praise Famous Women</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> , a collection of photographs by celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> Annie
Leibovitz with an introductory essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sontag</ENAMEX>, has already been soundly spanked by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. So why talk about it now? Because while its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> have rightly
noted that the book's organizing principle--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in all their diversity--is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">banal</ENAMEX>, they have not responded to an implicit and probably unintended message
of the book. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> sees it, the real topic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> is
Celebrity--specifically, how the world looks to a celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX>.

             Let's start with the
pictures--portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, most of them well-known, a few of them not.
Leibovitz photographed the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on assignment for high-end magazines
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). She probably took the pictures of
the unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on her own. (There are no notes to tell us where the
photographs were originally published, so it's hard to say which pictures were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assignments</ENAMEX> and which ones <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibovitz</ENAMEX> was simply moved to take.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> are
depicted in ways designed to reinforce our warmest feelings about them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> looks youthfully studious as she pores over papers on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s
sunny balcony. A bold and cheerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>,
hefts a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> on a hunting expedition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Performer Anna Deavere Smith</ENAMEX> holds up
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand and testifies, seemingly lost inside one of her many magnificent
evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigourney Weaver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Barrymore</ENAMEX> are
each sexy in their own glamorous ways. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> are each tough in their own
heroic ways. As the image of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> follows another, we seem to
understand why they've made such names for themselves: They are so singular, so
attractive, so powerful, the world just had to take notice of them.

             It's
harder to describe the nonfamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, since their portraits lend themselves
less well to personal characterization. Unlike the celebrity portraits, these
were mostly taken without benefit of makeup, props, and lighting design; as a
result, faces tend to disappear into contexts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> are grimy. The sewing
machine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> sews. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> farm. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> is ripely innocent. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of domestic abuse looks battered. They are icons, in short, either of
their pioneering professions or else of their stereotypically feminine
situation. The path-breaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> tend to stare defiantly into the
camera: Imagine telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy A. Richman</ENAMEX>, a rabbinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> wrapped in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phylacteries</ENAMEX> and holding a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>, that she can't serve God! The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> trapped
in servile roles, on the other hand, withdraw from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leibovitz</ENAMEX>. Their faces are
blank or frankly hostile. You can't look for long at the picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX>
Eugenia <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ponce</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diner</ENAMEX>, so raw are the shame and
distrust in her eyes. We still feel a certain warmth toward these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-but-anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibovitz</ENAMEX> specializes in warm--but it's a much more
abstract emotion. We feel proud of, or sad for, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in general, not for any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in particular.

            In short, individuality here becomes a function of fame. The better known
you are, the more appealing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibovitz</ENAMEX> will grant you. This is not
to accuse her of lacking sympathy for the nonfamous. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibovitz</ENAMEX> is a
commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX>. When she's told to shoot a celebrity, she shows up
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>, an expansive amount of time, and the driving idea that this person
is important and must be allowed to get her identity across. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Non-celebrities</ENAMEX>
have less claim on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leibovitz</ENAMEX>, on her time, money, and curiosity, and therefore
a reduced impact on us--although it must also be said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leibovitz</ENAMEX> makes
distinctions between non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>, according an empathy and humanity to
inspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> that she can't seem to extend to the abjectly
downtrodden.

            To be fair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leibovitz</ENAMEX>, she's working under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other constraints. One is
formal: It's hard to communicate roundness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in a single photograph,
which is perforce a limited slice of space and time. How much easier it must be
to photograph <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> whose identities are already publicly disseminated! All you
have to do is gather up the strands of commonly told tales and give them visual
representation--a gesture, the color of the light, a costume, a chance
expression--in order to produce an image that feels both knowing and right. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> constraint may be the more important one. Leibovitz, after all, works
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at glossy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> who spend their days wrangling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> onto
their pages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrities</ENAMEX> demand flattering representation as the price of their
cooperation, and no one is better at flattering in a sophisticated yet intimate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way than Leibovitz</ENAMEX>. Should she ever stop making her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity subjects</ENAMEX> look
good, her career would quickly come to an end.

            Nonetheless, this troubling collusion of photography and social hierarchy
(for fame is well on its way to replacing class as the determining factor of
status in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>) is exactly the sort of thing you'd expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sontag</ENAMEX> to
hold forth about with brilliance and insight. And she does, too, just not in
her introduction, a disconnected series of meditations on what a collection of
photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> might tell us in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age. (Very little, she is
finally forced to admit.) Only in one clause does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sontag</ENAMEX> hint at the conditions
underlying the book--"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s hugely complex fashion-and-photography system,"
she calls it--but the topic at hand is something else, and she veers away.
Leibovitz, after all, is her very dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, and this is a coffee-table book,
not a work of criticism. But consider what a younger, sharper-tongued Sontag
might have written. This is her from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">On Photography</ENAMEX> , a collection of
essays published during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. The subject was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Sander</ENAMEX>, a 1920s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> who also set out to catalogue a large category of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, in his
case <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, but you could substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Leibovitz</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sander</ENAMEX> and come out with
an apt reading:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sander</ENAMEX>'s social sample is unusually, conscientiously broad. He includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society ladies</ENAMEX>, factory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">industrialists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and gypsies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>. But such variety does
not rule out class condescension. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sander</ENAMEX>'s eclectic style gives him away. Some
photographs are casual, fluent, naturalistic; others are naïve and awkward. ...
Unself-consciously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sander</ENAMEX> adjusted his style to the social rank of the person
he was photographing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professionals</ENAMEX> and the rich tend to be photographed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indoors</ENAMEX>, without props. They speak for themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Laborers</ENAMEX> and derelicts are
usually photographed in a setting (often outdoors) which locates them, which
speaks for them--as if they could not be assumed to have the kinds of separate
identities normally achieved in the middle and upper classes. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sander</ENAMEX>'s
complicity with everybody also means a distance from everybody. His complicity
with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> is not naïve ... but nihilistic.

            

            Indeed.

            
               
Photographs are from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Leibovitz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sontag</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.C. Shen Chu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sewing</ENAMEX> machine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Maples Ladies' Blouse Company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chinatown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
