
   
   
      
         
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kyle's Mom Is a Bitch</ENAMEX>": An Exegesis
            

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, all:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger: Doubtless Elvis</ENAMEX> will be responding to you about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Clarke Duncan</ENAMEX>
in The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> , but I've got to say I flinched when I read that "his
function is essentially to absorb and process white pain, suffering, disease
and guilt, which he does visibly--which is a novel change from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> of
films in which black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have done the same thing invisibly." That's
exactly what drives some of us crazy about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--that he has no
autonomous existence, that he's there solely to help "process" white pain.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poitier</ENAMEX> might have humanized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steiger</ENAMEX>, but Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tibbs</ENAMEX> is nominally flesh and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a full range of emotions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coffey</ENAMEX> is another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s mystical black martyrs with extra-sensory perception. In the scene in
which he heals <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Clarkson</ENAMEX>, he hovers over her bedridden form in a way
that's meant to summon up rape fantasies of fragile white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>
menaced by darkies--and to miraculously invert them. But to me a miraculous
inversion of a rape fantasy is almost as cheap and false as the thing
itself--the black saint as much of an unhealthy projection as the black
demon.

            Before I drop the film-vs.-video, reverie-vs.-hypnosis issue, let me say
that a) I'm salivating over your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home theater</ENAMEX> setup and b) I'm slightly wary of
anecdotal evidence. Your fears about the medium might be warranted (and let's
find out before all those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> get converted!), but the tendency to trance
out in front of a boob tube (even a mega-mega-boob tube) has a lot to do with
the setting and the quality of your attention. You can stretch out, glance
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, go to the toilet, read a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>--and even if you don't, you
know you have the option. I've had most of my really intense aesthetic
experiences at live theater (and a few at the opera), and I've always figured
that's because I'd been forced to make more of an investment in what I was
watching--to commit to it in a way I don't when I watch TV.

            I want to apologize, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>, if I gave the impression <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX> were making fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> at a showing of that
film. They were each discussing it--not discreetly but not "publicly"--at a
screening for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Talented Mr. Ripley</ENAMEX> , and I'm certain that
they didn't think some smartass like me would report the gist of their
conversations to the world. (I gather, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Siegal</ENAMEX> has lambasted
the picture on an upcoming program of yours. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX> has never been
ashamed to have his opinions widely broadcast.) I suppose I invoked them
because they represent such wildly divergent sensibilities--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX>, the
other defiantly highbrow--and both were united in a kind of ebullient loathing
of this poor picture. I'm glad you're putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magnolia</ENAMEX> on your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-best
list, because it needs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX>; it seems to me so poignantly vulnerable to
ridicule.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>: In your final post <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> you asked: "Can it really be that
difficult to write a song called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Kyle's Mom Is a Bitch</ENAMEX>?' I bet any number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> reading this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> could do as well or better."

            I don't wish to discourage anyone from doing as well or better--my mailbox
is open (as, I'm sure, is yours, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>). But I'd like to speak up for that
number, which is emblematic of many of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> 's strengths. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mom Is a Bitch</ENAMEX>" is an infantile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> chant raised to the level of comic
art by a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cartman</ENAMEX>'s speed-freak/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squalling-baby</ENAMEX> vocal, b) the sophisticated
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway-style orchestration</ENAMEX>, and c) the happy notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cultures</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>) would come out in full
national <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">regalia to sing</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> being a bitch. In form, it's a
showbizzy patter song, but because of its lightning tempo (which makes the
words barely intelligible) and the steady repetition of "bitch" on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downbeat</ENAMEX>, it has the primal force of an incantation:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle'sMomisaBITCHshe</ENAMEX>'sabigfatBITCH
she'sthebiggestBITCHinthewholewideworld ...
OnMondayshe'saBITCHonTuesdaysshe'saBITCH ...

            

            OK, it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel Coward</ENAMEX>, but it makes me as blissful as anything has since
I was toilet-trained.

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
