
   
   
      
         
            May the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best-Looking Man Win</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>--ohmyGod, I had no idea I was thought to be obsessive about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chosen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>. Who started that base canard? Believe me, having married <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and
being now entangled with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> hardly makes up for my almost total lack of
information re the history of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I absolutely thought, until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> celebrated the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">loaves</ENAMEX> and fishes being miraculously lit by
an oil lamp. Perhaps I have managed to fool a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because I know some
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>. As for the latkes, I went to a divine <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 th</NUMEX> -birthday party
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> where the menu was latkes and birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>. Of course I
realize that such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> could only happen here, in egghead heaven ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, home of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>. And if you're really serious about a home remedy
for grease-induced skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">eruptions</ENAMEX>, try <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX>. As for sympathy, I have
oodles for you--probably from guilt, because my skin is probably the feature I
am most known for.

            Well, now that I have managed to touch on a bit of my marital history, my
religious ignorance, announcing where I live, and a zit treatment, let's push
away that plate of latkes and get serious. Now comes the part where I reveal
what I believe to be a sin: envy. How I wish I, too, could be winging to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX> to see those rummies go at it again. (I trust you are e'ing me from the
little phone in the seat, making each minute cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Kinsley</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2.80</NUMEX>,
making your words, indeed, golden.)

            I am probably skirting another sin, here, but I can't get away from
evaluating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' looks. Keyes, I guess, is classically
attractive, but he looks like he just managed to run away from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> perhaps could be considered good-looking, but you can see the ongoing war
of his muscles trying to rein in the smirk. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> looks like the polymer clay
model for an animated cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> ... well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> could use
some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX>. It is surely a coincidence that I like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> best.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> (a predictable situation, seeing as how we control
the media), I am most concerned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safra</ENAMEX> murder. That is my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>! Between a
mysterious murder and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> coming up, I could wind up with my checking account
erased, and then I would be reduced to ... well, modeling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Oil of Olay</ENAMEX>. As
for television, I think you're misspelling "dreck." My choice would be "drek."
Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Weiseltier</ENAMEX> will check in and set us straight.

            While you are gauging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , I
started with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. Am very concerned about
whether we'll go to war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> over the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in the inner tube. Señor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> is saying return the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> or else. Or else what? Also, I am fascinated by
the blue-green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">algae</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> (in a capsule) that takes away aches and pains
and migraines. Its name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spirulina</ENAMEX>. (Anything to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thumbelina</ENAMEX>, do you
think?)

            But returning to what's important: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>. I am most interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubya</ENAMEX>'s
next bon mot. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>, to date, was his announcement that he knew the name
of "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. But it doesn't matter that he's not articulate (except
maybe to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is, after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that, if it were a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>, would be the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11 th</NUMEX> largest economy in the world.

            Talk to you later. (And skip the sour <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX>, go with the applesauce.)

         
      
   
