
   
   
      
         
            Heard of Any <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Scandals Lately</ENAMEX>?
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>,

            I agree with you entirely about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> versus local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. As
you know, when we moved down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, we thought we would save
a little money and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few pounds</NUMEX> of trash per week by getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
only on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>. But right from the start, we went into serious Times
withdrawal. Sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is a good enough paper, and we
like its local reporting, but its foreign coverage doesn't compare to the
Times , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Op-Ed</ENAMEX> page tends to counteract the effects of my morning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coffee</ENAMEX> (with the exception of the divinely cranky <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wednesdays</ENAMEX>--long may he rant), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> often seem clueless about how to
put together an attractive and readable paper. They still haven't figured out
that it's a good idea to put all the high-technology features in a single
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> section, the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> does. However, thanks to the Internet,
I have been indulging my Times addiction for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> now without
any additional cost or trash (it makes me wonder how many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
doing the same, and just how much money the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has lost as a
result).

            As you say, we're supposed to be talking about the news. But what has been
most interesting to me about the news in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX> is what has
not been there, namely, scandal. It's as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> business was
such a big, greasy, nauseating chunk of scandal to swallow that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">chattering</NUMEX> classes subsequently lost their appetite for the stuff, at least
temporarily. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, it seemed as if we had entered the age of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Permanent Floating Scandal</ENAMEX>. There always seemed to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three or four</NUMEX>
stacked up over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at any one time, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> waiting to land at
National <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater, Travelgate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files, the campaign-finance
scandals, not to mention the extra, auxiliary scandals around half the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>.
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>, it's seemed as if there's been scarcely a week in which some
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> scandal didn't hit the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> dropping hopeful hints about there being Much
More to Come, and how this might all ultimately Bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> Down.

            But since the Much More came, and several additional, large, indigestible
helpings on top of it (and still the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> didn't fall!), it's as if the
press and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have gone on a scandal diet, sneaking in only an
occasionally guilty snack like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>. Ironically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX> in office seem certain to be more free of scandal than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s. And along with the demise of the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, the tone of the
coverage has changed. I certainly haven't seen much recently of the prestige
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>'s dreadfully sententious hand-wringing along the lines of "Should we be
dignifying with our attention these allegations about presidential fondling, as
detailed in the following <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>-page special report (and make sure not to miss the
amazing revelations from the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> about her
attitudes toward oral sex!)." Instead, the tone has been pretty
straightforwardly condemnatory in regard to excess prosecutorial zeal and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prurient</ENAMEX> exposures of private life. Still, this is an eminently self-correcting
situation. The longer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> remains without its traditional appetite for
scandal, the more careless powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will get, and eventually one of them
will get blown up in a big, juicy affair which will have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits joyfully</ENAMEX> going off the diet and gorging on all the sordid details.

            Of course, as our sainted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> here at 
                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley, has often said, the real scandal is not what's illegal, but what's
legal and going on all the time. Do you think there's any chance that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>'s temporary diet will encourage more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to look at this other kind
of scandal, instead of dreaming about being the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>?

            Well, I see I've gotten to the end of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half</TIMEX>, and haven't
gotten to the news, either (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>?). So why don't you
begin? Any thoughts on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
