
   
   
      
         
            For <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Cooks With Commitment</ENAMEX> Issues

            This may be hard to believe, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> has discovered a "best-of" list
with solid, practical value. It's a brand extension of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best American</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">literary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>--you know, The 
               Best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Essays</ENAMEX> ,
The 
               Best <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Short Stories</ENAMEX> , etc. This iteration of the idea
is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best American Recipes 1999: The Year's Top 100 From Books</ENAMEX>,
Magazines, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspapers</ENAMEX> & the Internet , edited by book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fran</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCullough</ENAMEX> and food <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne Hamlin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton-Mifflin</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26</NUMEX>).

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best American Recipes</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> wishes to warn you in advance,
is not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illustrated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> or anyone
else pledged to uphold gastronomical values. On the other hand, it's not for
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummies</ENAMEX>" either, as the other leading introductory series likes to put it.
This cookbook's brow-level is all over the place. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One minute</TIMEX> you're cooking the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-prize-winning recipe in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillsbury BAKE-OFF®</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> thighs with a
sweet-and-sour <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old El Paso®</ENAMEX> salsa, currants, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey sauce</ENAMEX>, served on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">couscous</ENAMEX>), and the next you're composing the sternly <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> endive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fennel</ENAMEX>, and orange <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> from the latest cookbook by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Wolfert</ENAMEX>, the most rigorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cookbook
writing. The recipes are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> and French
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesotan</ENAMEX>. They're culled from
regional cookbooks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sophia Loren</ENAMEX>'s memoirs, and
the kinds of sample recipes you find inside the box when you open your new
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Kitchen</ENAMEX> Aid. The introduction lists emerging food trends of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, albeit a
bit cursorily, and without really specifying how the trends are certified as
such. There are marginal notes explaining how to secure obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX> or
perform difficult procedures, and menu recommendations that allow you to
assemble an impressive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-course meal using this book alone. In short, it's
the perfect purchase or gift for those among us with bare <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> bookshelves
and larger culinary ambitions that dwell in latency, stymied by a grave--though
common--psychological flaw: being unable to commit to a single technique or
ethnic cuisine at a time.

            Which brings us to the question raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best American Recipes</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> : Why, in a world besotted with mindless applications of the "best-of"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conceit</ENAMEX>, did it take so long to come up with this one? The answer surely has
something to do with the sociology of cooking right now--you're supposed to
crave purity, or at least authenticity. If you're going to cook <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>, you'd
best get the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcella Hazan</ENAMEX>, or else a food <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropologist</ENAMEX> who has
interviewed all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and discovered the best
liver-and<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">-grappa</ENAMEX> pasta <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> to be found north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arno</ENAMEX>. Ditto with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penelope Casas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Sahni</ENAMEX>, and on it goes around the globe. If
your tastes are downmarket, you can be a purist in that department too--just
buy the works of white-trash aficionados <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Stern</ENAMEX>, all of whose
dishes must be presented with the requisite ironic appurtenances, such as trays
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swizzle</ENAMEX> sticks. Reference-style cookbooks, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fannie Farmer</ENAMEX>, range
fairly broadly over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> basics, but if you want to get higher-end than
that, you're hard-pressed to find anything but books devoted to individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cuisines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foodies</ENAMEX> don't believe in mixing and matching--it's the culinary
equivalent of putting an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eames</ENAMEX> chair in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> full of frilly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">antiques</ENAMEX>.
Look at the harsh waves of criticism that greeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Guarnaschelli</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who asked food <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity chefs</ENAMEX> of all stripes and
preferences to contribute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> update of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Joy of</ENAMEX>
Cooking .

            But cooking is one of the few areas in which anthologizing actually makes
sense. A best-of collection of recipes is a much more satisfying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> than
most other genres of best-ofs. When it comes to poetry, for instance, such
compilations always lack context: Who can grasp the greatness of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> on the
basis of a single poem? Anthologies of essays, on the other hand, just make you
feel oppressed. No one wants to read that much of the same thing--that much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">folksy</ENAMEX>, digressive argument--in a single sitting. But <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best American</ENAMEX>
Recipes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> reflects life as it is lived. This is how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> eat--at an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> restaurant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> one the next. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> the melting pot
has become <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best American Recipes</ENAMEX> makes
a virtue of that fact.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCullough</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamlin</ENAMEX> say they plan to repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best American</ENAMEX>
Recipes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, which is good, because there's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for improvement here.
Some things are strangely delicious, such as the salsa-and-couscous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lemon-Almond Pound Cake</ENAMEX>, which is essentially baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marzipan dough</ENAMEX>. Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dishes</ENAMEX>, such as the cloyingly sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX> with olives and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX> from celebrity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Batali</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Simple Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX> , just don't measure up. The
times given for cooking are not to be relied on. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> tested everything
in or on a gas range viewed favorably by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> , and found
that some things were done in the time recommended, but the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownies</ENAMEX>--a dry, crumbly, tasteless contribution from a book presumptuously
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Perfect Recipe</ENAMEX> --would have been overbaked, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batali</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish understewed</ENAMEX>, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> had followed the recipes strictly. The fault
may lie with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of the original cookbook or recipe, but since Hamlin
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCullough</ENAMEX> allege that they tried everything out, they share the blame.

            There are other faults. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eclecticness</ENAMEX> guarantees waste and inefficiency.
Should you shell out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> for a bottle of Italian lemon liqueur you will use
once, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in your liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>? Or should you make your own, which
would take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four days</TIMEX>? The writing can be breathless and schmaltzy--it was
not necessary to say of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> poached <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> with garlic yogurt from a
cookbook written by a couple that "this is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning meal</TIMEX> from two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose love for garlic is as intense as it is for each other." The
emphasis on trends leads to a knee-jerk over-reliance on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX> that
happen to be fashionable right now, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cumin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coconut milk</ENAMEX>. But these
are quibbles, which could well be obviated by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s anthology. And
besides, they're in keeping with the basic idea. This is a cookbook that's
pleasingly shallow and imperfect, just like those of us who are drawn to
it.

         
      
   
