
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            By the time most of you read this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Producer Price Index</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
will have been released, and if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s other economic statistics are any
indication, the PPI will show only very mild inflationary pressure back up the
producer pipeline. With the exception of energy prices, in fact, inflation
remains about as quiescent as it can be, despite the fact that the economy
continues to grow at a better-than<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-4 percent</NUMEX> clip and that the unemployment
rate has reached levels no one thought were possible anymore. If you take
energy and food prices out of the Consumer Price Index--giving you the
so-called core rate--prices in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> will have risen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 1.75 percent</NUMEX>, which
is the lowest annual inflation rate we've had during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this entire business</TIMEX>
cycle. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX> "cycle" even the right word anymore?)

            No one, of course, really knows why this is happening. But there is one
remarkable statistic (which itself is difficult to explain): Since the middle
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the falling unemployment rate has become decoupled from wage
increases. In other words, even though it's getting harder and harder to find
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the tight labor markets are not yet translating into wage increases in
excess of productivity. This may be evidence of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>-take-all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, or of continued anxiety among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, or it may be that the wage
gains due to productivity are enough to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> happy. Or perhaps it's
just evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> really is God. In any case, on to the
Chat.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasbro</ENAMEX> announced it was cutting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> and
taking a restructuring charge of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$97 million</NUMEX>, even though it owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
license for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pokémon</ENAMEX> trading cards . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> blamed sluggish sales of
Star Wars merchandise. For instance, reportedly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar-Jar Binks</ENAMEX>
action figures have ever been bought in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Ivester</ENAMEX> unexpectedly announced he was retiring
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a couple of years</TIMEX> as head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Ivester, who will be
stepping down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, gave no real reason for his retirement , though
he must be tempted to scream, 'It was those damn Belgians!' as he walks out the
door."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Explaining why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pixar</ENAMEX> decided to release <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toy Story 2</ENAMEX> in movie
theaters rather than making it a straight-to-video production, Pixar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX> said, 'We looked at films like Godfather 2
               
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Terminator 2</ENAMEX> and said, "We can do that."' Ah yes: 'I know it was
you, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potato Head</ENAMEX>! You broke my heart.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "The putative recovery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy appears to have stalled
yet again , since the latest economic data show that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> fell back
into recession <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last quarter</TIMEX> without the artificial pump-priming of extravagant
public-works spending. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> yen, though, continues to be the world's
strongest currency , raising the question: 'Are Internet-stock day traders
speculating in currencies in their spare time?'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>'s latest beige-book regional economic survey
declares the impact of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> to be uneven across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, although
one lumber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> worries had prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to hold off
buying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX>. Apparently there wasn't enough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> rings to include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'2000</NUMEX>,' so no one knows what'll happen when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'00</NUMEX> rolls
over."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> reiterated that he planned no new tax
increases if he's elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, but did allow that if the economy went
sour, it might be necessary to raise taxes. Hmmm. Let's get the logic
here : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economy</ENAMEX> in recession, demand weak, increase taxes so demand will be
even weaker. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy booming</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spending freely, keep taxes same so demand
will keep going up. Oh right. That's straight of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Econ 101</NUMEX>. On the planet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Venus</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "Linux maker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Linux</ENAMEX> went public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at an offering price of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>, but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trade was at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$299</NUMEX> . Don't you have to believe the guy
who bought that first block of stock was doing it just so he could say, 'Yes, I
was that dumb'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
