
   
   
      
         
            Proposal: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candidate Quality Control Board</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Honey</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, you are right that there are negatives to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, his humor and
honesty aside. Your imaginary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> line, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, tear down this wall,
and remove that splotch!" was wicked. Go to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. I am cranky, as you can
tell, becoming more and more distressed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who put themselves
forward to run. And I have lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. We need a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candidate Quality Control</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX>. But then, who would decide on them ? There is a collective longing
for someone clearly first-rate, capable, and untainted. That kind of person
somehow seems to be unattainable and in our past. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> quipped, "If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> were alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ..."

            As for my outing with a book and a latte in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Square</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (and
here I know I am kissing goodbye a few dinner invitations from some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nightline friends</ENAMEX>), I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Williams</ENAMEX> memoir is great fun. And
let's put it this way: She is easily as smart as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubya</ENAMEX>.

            Rising earlier than usual <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, I have fished out a small nugget
about the previously mentioned (by you, let the record show) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puff Daddy</ENAMEX>, or
Puffy for short. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> asked someone, "Why does he call himself
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fluffy?</ENAMEX>" I admit to feeling sympathetic to his mishearing the name. When I was
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> (when ice covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>), I unfortunately became known as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who thought she was working for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Nuclear</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">His Policy</ENAMEX> and bragged
that she was tackling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Useless</ENAMEX>." I think that was probably my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX> book.

            In an ecumenical spirit, I want to agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> founder
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>. He told an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "has
the morals of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">alley cat</ENAMEX>" but is one of the most brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> ever.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, an absolute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. He's managed to stymie the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>."
Not to mention Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            ever thine,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
