
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Toon-Town</ENAMEX>
            

            It's fitting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> ends with the best year for movies of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade, 1999</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>, thank God, nobody got around to slipping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX>'s "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>"
into a movie. Not even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of Days</ENAMEX> , which was so low that such a cliché
would've looked like a classy move.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> animated movies
alone that deserve to be on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">top-10</NUMEX> list-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Iron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toy Story 2</ENAMEX> . (And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mononoke</ENAMEX> ,
that has moments of epic grandeur and images so primal they could be lifted
from a nightmare, or cause one.) Even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 20 minutes</TIMEX> or so of
Tarzan , before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Collins</ENAMEX> started to resurrect songs that weren't good
enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michelob</ENAMEX> commercials, were impressive.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> is so good that the apparent problem, bringing the show's
limited stylization to the big screen--it's like animation by Colorforms
(which, I know, is the point)--was immediately solved. Some of its sequences
bounce around in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> forever. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>'s big number, a malicious piece of
parody that's one of the funniest movie moments of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, is a power ballad
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> crowd--imagine an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Lloyd Webber</ENAMEX> number written for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loaf</ENAMEX> or, worse, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bolton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> is a reminder of the great
moments from the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Beard/Doug Kenny National Lampoon</ENAMEX> , where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">audacity</ENAMEX> and smarts still leave you tearing up helplessly when you try to
explain what you love about the work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX>. And your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> roll their
eyes at your lack of descriptive skills.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX> have been a struggle to put together a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-best list, so
when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cartoons make enough of an impact to each deserve a slot, you know
things are looking up. Toy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story 2</ENAMEX> , like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Park</ENAMEX> , is thick
with small jokes bordering the bigger jokes. It seems perfect for that genre
that flowered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, the movie made for repeated home viewing so you can
study it frame by frame, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zapruder</ENAMEX> film. (Or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s surly
video apology, where you try to analyze the squint as he says, "I did not have
sex with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> ... Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.") The end of the picture, a breather
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz</ENAMEX> take a moment to go over what has happened to them, feels
like the end of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ford</ENAMEX> movie, and has a wonderful ease.

            I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> in the sub-basement of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those I-don't-wanna-be-here
multiplexes, and watched the place light up with happy chatter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> trying to explain their version of the movie to the other.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>, which started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> so out of touch I
thought it was stuck in the triangle section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurassic Park Orchestra</ENAMEX>,
bounce back. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kings and The Matrix</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s most
propulsive pictures, were also part of the revivified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> slate. Both movies
have brains and velocity. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> feels like it was fired from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gun</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Matrix</ENAMEX> generates so much excitement that it's like being
caught in the crosshairs of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            The only disappointment is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> wasn't able to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> to mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, it probably does take an
outfit like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> to put out animation. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> did release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pokémon</ENAMEX> ,
though taking credit for its success is, to use an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorne Michaels</ENAMEX> line,
like standing next to someone who got shot and getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Purple Heart</ENAMEX> anyway.)
Though a bigger disappointment is that they were able to put <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild, Wild</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> over, which is a bigger insult than the lazy samples <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Smith</ENAMEX> has
turned into a pop career. (You can almost hear him going through his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>'
collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vinyl</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Record Club</ENAMEX>.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kings</ENAMEX> uses the
mechanism of the action picture for its visceral power, and to make a point
about the callousness of action movies, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> with a bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Third</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> slipped in to make a point. It's gotta be a great year for movies when
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Jonze</ENAMEX>, who gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the best
supporting performances of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, also directs one of the best pictures:
Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> . It's all about riches just for domestic
movies.

         
      
   
