
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Overblown B2B Hype</ENAMEX>
            

            Even by the standards of this hyperactive stock market, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s initial
public offering for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FreeMarkets</ENAMEX> was staggering. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had originally
planned to go public at a price of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 to $18</NUMEX> a share, but by the time it came
to market, the offering price had tripled to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48</NUMEX> a share. That was still too
low (though still impressive). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trade was at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$248</NUMEX> a share, and unlike
the way most IPOs trade, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FreeMarkets</ENAMEX>' shares kept rising during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>,
closing at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$280</NUMEX> a share. (The shares were down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I'll take a guess and
say that was profit-taking.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FreeMarkets</ENAMEX>' performance came as no surprise to anyone. (When investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> triple the offering price on a stock, it's a good sign that the IPO isn't
going to crash and burn.) That's not so much because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> itself,
which essentially runs online business-to-business auctions for corporations
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>. Rather, it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> appetite for Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">business-to-business</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">B2B</NUMEX>) stocks has suddenly become voracious. B2B is, we're
being told, the true wave of the future on the Web, and so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> ranging
from professional services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to infrastructure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> to database
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are now the darlings of the Street. Most--in fact, nearly all--of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> remain unknown to just about everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. But over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few months</TIMEX> you could have made a huge amount of money in stocks like
Akamai, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ariba, Sapient</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viant</ENAMEX>.

            There are, as usual, a host of studies by various research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to justify
the swing in sentiment toward B2B stocks. There have to be, because many of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are currently so tiny that estimating their present value on
the basis of their internal numbers alone would be futile. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FreeMarkets</ENAMEX>, for
instance, did <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.8 million</NUMEX> in revenue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> but now has a market
capitalization of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.1 billion</NUMEX>.) In any case, these studies all show that the
B2B market for goods and services on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> will soon dwarf the B2C
(<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">business-to-consumer</TIMEX>) market. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> recent estimate, cited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FreeMarkets</ENAMEX> in its
prospectus, has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B2B</TIMEX> market growing from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$109 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trillion</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. If you can get even a tiny slice of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 trillion</NUMEX>, then
you're in great shape.

            The idea, then, is that within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B2C</TIMEX> e-commerce--that is, what all
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> piling into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and eToys are hoping to capitalize
on--will be only a small part of the overall e-commerce market, perhaps as
small <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as 10 percent</NUMEX>. This doesn't necessarily mean that e-tailers like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>
are doomed (as stocks, that is). But it does suggest that you'd be better off
looking at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">B2B</NUMEX> stocks for the next true Internet titan.

            But there is one problem with this whole theory, which is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
that are going to be doing all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B2B</TIMEX> buying on the Web have to make the
money with which they pay for all their purchases somewhere. And it can't just
be from selling to other businesses. In other words, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the B2B</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">daisy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> there have to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> hyped
B2B by saying (I paraphrase): "Think of all the parts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> has to buy every
day just to keep its business going, and multiply that by all the giant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> out there that have to buy parts." But let's remember this: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> spends
less on parts in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> spend on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. That's by definition.
Otherwise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> would go out of business. In fact, if you add up all the money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> spend on parts and databases and infrastructure, it's less
than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> spend on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, again by definition.

            In other words, the hype surrounding B2B has depended on the idea that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that sell to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are going to migrate to the Web while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that sell to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are going to stay offline. But while B2B
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> will probably migrate more quickly, and while obviously there's a
lot of business that will always be offline (unless we figure out a way to get
a virtual haircut), it's illogical that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B2B</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> will explode while B2C
will remain stagnant. Especially when the former ultimately depends on the
latter. The real message of the whole B2B craze, in fact, may be that we should
take another look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>. How much longer can it be
before <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are actually being sold online (instead of through the archaic
dealer structure)? And when that happens, imagine how much better <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s business
will be.

         
      
   
