
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planet Better</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
announcement that it plans to play a role in the numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> lawsuits against
the gun industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , will begin pressing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to make concessions to settle the various city lawsuits and if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> don't, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> will bring a class action suit of its own against them on
behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s public housing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. The story is fronted at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official bureaucratic
reaction to the almost certain loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Polar Lander</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s vow to
completely reassess its interplanetary exploration program, a story everybody
else fronts but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with a story everybody else stuffs:
the decision by a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to block a web news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>'s attempt to post
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> financial disclosure forms submitted by all federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>. Paper
versions of the forms are already available to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with a local story: The claim of public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
that dozens of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> supplied answers to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for the standardized tests that determine how city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are ranked
and also whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are promoted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s top non-local story,
which nobody else fronts, is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">P.M.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>'s call for a moratorium on
further <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">settlement</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>, an apparent reversal of the policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> had been following since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> came into power <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead observes that the new federal gun strategy could realize through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> gun control measures that have failed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Measures like
controlling sales at gun shows, limiting the volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> purchases at any one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, and cutting off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> whose sold <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are disproportionately involved
in crimes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story adds a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>-supplied stat that fleshes
out the public housing angle: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Typically</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 70 percent</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>
murders occurring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> largest housing projects are
committed with a handgun. The papers point out that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
move is patterned after its lawsuit against the cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes an important difference: the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have many
times the size and staying power of the gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT NASA</ENAMEX> story goes high with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> saying,
"Clearly something is wrong, and we have to understand it." The coverage makes
it clear that understanding might require postponement or even scrapping of
already-scheduled space missions. A main object of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s reassessment, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , will be the "faster, better, cheaper," mandate the unmanned
missions have been operating under, including the entire <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$356.8 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-mission package that failed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead breaks a
baffling silence that has marked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> coverage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>: it
finally identifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> program's prime contractor--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>
(although not until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">10th</NUMEX> paragraph). In this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s hand was somewhat
forced, since it's now apparent that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s performance will be a focus
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> re-look. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> story also mentions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story doesn't, nor does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's, nor does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's
front-pager, (although an inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post NASA</ENAMEX> effort does).

            The central issue of the federal bench financial data case--whether
dissemination via the Web poses some sort of extra danger not posed by
paper--is also raised in a front-page WSJ feature about a recently
discovered scam in which someone applied for and got and used credit cards in
the names of the top <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">admirals</ENAMEX>. This was possible because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>' service numbers, which are
just their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> numbers, were made available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> as part of
the promotion process, and have since appeared on a Web site maintained to
protest the use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSN</ENAMEX> as a national <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ID</ENAMEX>. But, the story points out, nobody
can prove that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSNs</ENAMEX> weren't gotten directly from the
Congressional Record . None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> are on the hook for the money
cadged but the story points out a more serious angle: Since service numbers are
now just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSNs</ENAMEX>, if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> is captured, as things stand now, he is required to
provide his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSN</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captors</ENAMEX>, which they could use to find out all about his
family, finances and personal background. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> is therefore, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , seriously considering going back to its old practice of issuing
separate service numbers unrelated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSNs</ENAMEX>.

            An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story reports that the tense situation between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> over custody of that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was compounded when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>
demanded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> return the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of a fishing boat it says was hijacked
out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, and is now in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> custody.

            
               About <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face</ENAMEX>! On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 12.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>
joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>. In fact, he joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force Reserve</ENAMEX>. TP regrets the error and has fixed it in the online text.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> can
now be used to pay income tax bills. But not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't explain
why. You'd think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would want its piece of what's sure to be a record
volume of tax payments, no?

         
      
   
