
   
   
      
         
            Nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like a Dane</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the resumption in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>
peace talks. Both papers emphasize that prospects for an end to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51-year</TIMEX>
state of war between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are excellent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon general</ENAMEX>'s report, to be released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, stating that although in any
given year one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> experiences a mental disorder and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do so at least once in the course of their lives, most never seek
treatment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX>'s release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of a
special edition of its annual statistical abstract of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> that offers a
snapshot of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has changed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. Some examples: In
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century's first decade</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, and in its last, the numbers were approximately the
reverse; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s air is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times as polluted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>; the population
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> is almost exactly the same as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, while that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> is about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> times larger. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> inside story on the abstract notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
the most popular girls' names in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha</ENAMEX>, while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
neither is in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>.

            The reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> makes it clear that the most sensitive issues
to be hashed out are whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will keep an intelligence-gathering post in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX> and its access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX>. The WP account
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that in the run-up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s announcement of the talks, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
engaged in much secret diplomacy, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> phone calls between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez Assad</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reported
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> was not pleased by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> thaw, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> doesn't follow up on this.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon general</ENAMEX>'s report finds that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with mental
disorders don't get help because they don't think effective treatments exist,
or they fear being stigmatized, or because they lack applicable insurance. The
report endorses, says the paper, equality between mental health insurance
coverage and that for physical illnesses and claims that such a coverage
increase needn't be costly.

weekend reaction to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year's 2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter Games</ENAMEX> bribery scandal: voting
in a reform package designed to restore the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>'s reputation. The package's
most prominent measure is a ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' visits to bidding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. The story
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quotes IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Antonio Samaranch</ENAMEX> as saying the vote means the problem
is solved, but it also notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> will be
questioning him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> at hearings looking into <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> corruption. In
addition, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> investigation continues.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-page in-depther on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, second in a series, portrays him as driven
and insecure as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar-athlete</ENAMEX>. The story says that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knick</ENAMEX>, he
routinely held on to an opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX>'s shorts and even garners a quote from
the man <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 years later</TIMEX>: "He was one of the dirtiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> I ever played
against." (And the story also relates that at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> dated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX>, seriously enough that she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> visited his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas one year</TIMEX>. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX> would comment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
about the romance.) Meanwhile, on the USAT front <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Bush</ENAMEX> mounts a
defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s gravitas: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> don't know that he is a very smart
history buff and that's what he reads." (For 
                  Slate
               's
take on another aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GWB</ENAMEX>'s persona click
here.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" confuses with a graphic about "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Specials</ENAMEX>." The text says they are a favorite among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, but the
stats go the other way: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNSs</ENAMEX> only account for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 15</NUMEX>
percent of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> traced to crimes, and another shows that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
models with the shortest time-in-existence-before-use-in-a-crime are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNSs</ENAMEX>. In other words, it's clear from all this that "good" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are more of a
problem.

            
               We remember when "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gilded Age</ENAMEX>" was just an expression: The
Wall Street Journal front reports a "microtrend" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s fashion: weaving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> into suits.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> happiest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the
world. No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, and No. 1 is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
