
   
   
      
         
            How To Do an IPO
            

            In purely financial terms, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s initial public offering from Linux
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">networker Andover</ENAMEX>.net will go down as just another in a series of remarkable
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-day</TIMEX> debuts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s shares priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18</NUMEX>, opened at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to $50</NUMEX>,
and closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$63 3/8</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>.net's shares jumped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 14 1/8</NUMEX>
points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.) In other words, it looked just like a typical tech IPO in this
frothiest of markets. But in fact there was nothing typical about the success
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>.net IPO. This was a deal the ramifications of which we're going
to be feeling for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come.

            That's because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>.net was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to be taken public by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambrecht</ENAMEX>, the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that is attempting to transform the IPO process
by replacing the traditional method of allocating shares and setting opening
prices with what's called a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> auction. (See 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer</ENAMEX>"
for more on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> auctions.) In a typical IPO, the lead underwriter sets an
initial filing price, then takes provisional orders from institutional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> that it uses to gauge demand. The filing price can be adjusted upward
if demand is strong enough, but in general the offering price for a company
going public is considerably below the market-clearing price. As a result,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who are able to get in on an IPO have a very good chance of reaping
some easy gains.

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> auction, by contrast, the price is essentially determined by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, who submit the highest price they're willing to pay and the number
of shares they want at that price. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who bid the highest (and, if they
bid the same price, the earliest) get first dibs on the shares, which are then
allocated in order from highest to lowest bid, until they're all gone. No
matter what you bid, though, the price you pay is the lowest price that any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> who got shares bid.

            This is a superior way of pricing an IPO because no one gets shares on the
basis of who they know, and because it ensures that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> going public
isn't going to leave too much money on the table by going public at a lower
price than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the market was willing to pay. It's also superior because it
eliminates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">middleman</ENAMEX> (the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>) and lets the market set the
price.

            Given the more general move in business toward disintermediation, it seems
inevitable that eventually this will be the way most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> go public. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambrecht</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>-auction strategy has gotten off to a slow start because its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> IPOs, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravenswood Winery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, were relative busts, at
least in the sense that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has seen a significant gain over its
offering price. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> feel they can't make money investing in IPOs
underwritten by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambrecht</ENAMEX>, they'll pay less for them then they would if the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were being underwritten by more established investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>,
thereby defeating the whole purpose of going public with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambrecht</ENAMEX>.

            That's why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>.net's awesome debut, with its price soaring <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">252 percent</NUMEX>
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the opening day</TIMEX>, is so important. It suggests, as I argued at
the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>'s IPO, that the problem with the earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambrecht</ENAMEX>
offerings was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>-auction idea, but rather the quality of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that were going public. Take a real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in a hot sector, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>.net, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> can make a lot of money, even as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> itself
raises more cash in the IPO than it would have done otherwise.

            There is, to be sure, something of a paradox here, since if the point of
having a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> auction is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> not to leave any money on the table,
the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">252 percent</NUMEX> jump in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>.net's stock price might seem to suggest that
the auction didn't work all that well. But there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things to keep in mind
here. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, and more mundane, point is that you have to have a brokerage
account with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambrecht</ENAMEX> to participate in its IPOs, so the number of potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambrecht</ENAMEX> offering is significantly smaller than the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who might be interested in that offering. (Of course, the more IPOs
like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hambrecht</ENAMEX> has, the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> it'll get, since anyone who
has <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> can open an account.) The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, and related, point is that no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can control the retail market for its stock. The market-clearing price
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>, in other words, will not be the market-clearing price at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> or at
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX>, and that's true for all stocks, not just IPOs. Now, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> become
more comfortable with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> auctions, and as more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> take part in these
kinds of IPOs, the spread between the offering price and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX>'s
closing price will narrow, and that will be a good thing. But for now, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">252</NUMEX>
percent leap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>.net took is very good news, the first significant blow
against Wall Street's old-school IPO process.

         
      
   
