
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX>'s Follies
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>,

            Yes, sad to say, I have indeed read most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Archer</ENAMEX>'s novels. If you
excuse the analogy, they're something like sordid one-night <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX>. You stay up
late in bed with them, breathless and excited, but when you wake up in the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning next</TIMEX> to them you feel ashamed and disgusted with yourself.

            Still, it's nice to know you're not bothered by the fact that I've read
them. The thing about growing up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> is that
reading trashy fiction somehow seems worse--more of a "transgressive act," as
some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic colleagues</ENAMEX> would put it--than many other minor crimes and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misdemeanors</ENAMEX> (even more than using the word "hopefully" incorrectly). The
nightmare scenario runs as follows. I'm sitting in a quiet corner somewhere,
devouring the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Crichton</ENAMEX>, the cover carefully hidden from sight.
Suddenly, from nowhere, in walks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Trilling</ENAMEX>. "Ah, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Kazin</ENAMEX>," she says, her great eyes shining sternly. "What are you
reading? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proust</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dostoyevsky</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Liberal Imagination ?</ENAMEX>" I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tremble</ENAMEX> so hard the book falls out of my hands, and she sees the cover. The
shame! The humiliation! Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> captured this idea perfectly in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bananas</ENAMEX> , in the scene where he buys a pile of intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, and
tries to slip a copy of a pornographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in with them, only to have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> holler, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey Harry</ENAMEX>, how much for a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Orgasm ?</ENAMEX>" Later,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> sits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, gazing at the offending item, which he has neatly
tucked into the latest edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary</ENAMEX> , with an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> on the cover (another favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> line, of course, comes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie Hall</ENAMEX> , when he quips that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissent</ENAMEX> and Commentary have
merged to form a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dysentery</ENAMEX>-- I was probably one of
the few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-olds</TIMEX> to laugh at that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>).

            But getting back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Archer</ENAMEX>. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> read his books, they
don't know much about him, and in any case, the current scandal is much too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">convoluted</ENAMEX>, with all its references to a previous scandal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years ago</TIMEX>,
to generate much coverage here. Besides, when it comes to illicit goings-on by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, I'm afraid the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> responses are, in order: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Who? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Do we care? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Aren't they always getting up to that sort of stuff
anyway? I mean, take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> of scandals which, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, would have blown the
top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> into low earth orbit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is revealed to have,
not just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>, but an entire <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> family, whom he has been housing, for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, in a government-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is revealed to have been
essentially a youthful Fascist fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> who later helped shield <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX> from the law. And just to make things really juicy, he covered up
the fact that he suffered from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> throughout much of his presidency. That
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fran√ßois Mitterrand</ENAMEX>. But I would guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times as many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> know the
details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX>'s bulimia as have ever heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fran√</ENAMEX>ßois
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitterrand</ENAMEX>. As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy prime minister</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> deputy prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>??!!), he could set off a small nuclear device while simultaneously
engaged in an unnatural act with a hippopotamus in the middle of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX>-Place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>, and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> would probably give it three
column inches on Page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A13</TIMEX>. Is this too cynical?

            But enough about this. We're just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half weeks</TIMEX> away from the year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Any thoughts on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>?

         
      
   
