
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weimar Russia</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>,

            Well, I'll accept "recycled platitudes" as covering most political life in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, and I certainly don't want to devote
any more of this space to the dreadful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taki</ENAMEX>. So let me turn from the ridiculous
to the sublimely horrible, and from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to a place where they can only
dream of a politics of contented, recycled platitudes: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.

            Has ever a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> been a better metaphor for the society he governs than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>? He stands there, an awesome wreck: drunk, corrupted, angry, in pain,
delusionary, his vital organs putrifying, but still possessing surprising
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reservoirs</ENAMEX> of strength, and still capable of delivering vicious and
unpredictable blows. In his shambling gait and glassy, uncertain stare he
reminds me all too closely of another awesome wreck of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who led another
awesome wreck of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall von Hindenburg</ENAMEX> at the end of his life. And
that scares me, because the similarities between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindenburg's Weimar Germany</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> seem all too exact. In both cases there is the society in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of collapse, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> tottering dizzily from crisis to crisis,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> increasingly gripped by resentment and rage against a West they
blame for abandoning, betraying, and exploiting them. Does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
in waiting? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukashenko</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebed</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zyuganov</ENAMEX>? It's hard to take any of them
seriously. But then, again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> wasn't taken very seriously at the start,
either, with his preposterous rhetoric and silly little moustache.

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> easily get carried away by historical comparisons.
But, if you forgive me for tooting my horn a little, you may remember a little
piece I wrote for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paristroika</ENAMEX>," laying
out the uncanny similarities between the situation of the then-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and
the situation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> on the eve of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1789</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">revolution</ENAMEX> (the pompous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sovietologist Jerry Hough</ENAMEX> wrote a condescending letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, scolding
me for my ignorance in failing to realize that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> would never let
things get to the point where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuania</ENAMEX> might secede. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oops</ENAMEX>). I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">devoutly</ENAMEX> hope I am wrong this time.

            But assuming things do continue to get worse in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, what should the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> do? We can always sit around and flagellate ourselves for letting
it happen through our "antagonizing" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war (and look! Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
running up with a selection of nice, dry, leather bullwhips). Personally, I
doubt that there was anything we could have done, given the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>
thrown up into leadership positions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> collapse, and the
disintegration of anything that might have evolved into civil society. Check
out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>'s excellent column in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> for more
on this, and on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s willful blindness to the corruption of his good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>.

            But regardless of how we interpret our own actions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, it seems to
me that there is one critical historical lesson we can't afford to forget. In
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1930s</NUMEX>, the road to appeasement was paved by Western guilt over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">post-World</TIMEX>
War I policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>--over the harshness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles Treaty</ENAMEX> and
reparations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> have a point, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX> said. We were too hard on
them. Give them a little slack now, and everything will even out and get back
to normal. Well, we know how well that policy worked. So by all means,
flagellate away. Lay in with a strong will and a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. Howl to the
heavens that our earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> policy was a failure. But don't let it stop us
from having a strong will and a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> when it comes to what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> are doing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, or it will encourage them to do it again
somewhere else.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
