
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Manners</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>,

            I quite agree that filmmakers are enthusiastic about the considerable
freedom given them by digital production. But then you write, "Most filmmakers
don't care if digital projection looks better than celluloid; they'd be
thrilled if it looked as good." And I wonder.

            I think most filmmakers do care about the picture quality of their films, as
evidenced by the fact that those who broke through with video (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>)
turned to real film the moment they had the money. And besides--sod the
filmmakers! I care! While I am perfectly able to enjoy films shot on video,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Mariachi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Movie</ENAMEX> , I also
enjoy the voluptuous pleasures of great celluloid cinematography in a film like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Double Life of Veronique</ENAMEX> .

            You write of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> : "At a screening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> I had the
pleasure of listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Siegel</ENAMEX> make fun of the movie behind me and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> (in a separate conversation) make fun of the movie in front of me. That
clinches it--it's one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best movies!"

            It's also on my best-movie list (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 2</ENAMEX>). I also heard there was a lot of
derision at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> screening. ("If you can keep your head when all about
you," etc.) That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> screenings and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screenings</ENAMEX>: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, unless a movie is really bad and everyone senses
that everyone else thinks so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> the courtesy of not
distracting from his work by vocalizing their own opinions. I have been to a
lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> screenings over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, and have been surprised a) at how
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> feel the right to laugh scornfully or even talk back to the
screen, and b) how so many of them loudly share their opinions of a film as
soon as it's over. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> we have a rule that we do not talk about
films with each other after the screening. I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> need to know what my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> think, and they have the same interest in my opinion.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> , it is so exciting to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> (and yes, you
are right, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>) swinging for the fences, not holding back, not playing it
cool, going for it. What a movie.

            I agree, too, about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chloë Sevigny</ENAMEX>'s work in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry . She
provides our entrance into the story, and her reactions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> let us know
who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> is and how he/she is perceived. It is a superb performance.

            I fully expect that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> snorted and hooted all the way through
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titus</ENAMEX> , too, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry J. Lennix</ENAMEX> was superb in the film's key role, as
the villain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX> was splendid, too, in a role that
provides the definition of thankless. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> have been
breaking free of timid generic expectations, why not an audacious film of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s least accomplished and most wretchedly excessive tragedy?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
