
   
   
      
         
            <i>Magnolia</i> Goes to "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyond</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>, I loved your piece on this new film technology--you write about the
subject with infectious excitement. And you got to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Obispo</ENAMEX>! But I
wondered why you didn't dwell in that piece on what, for me, is the most
salient fact of digital filmmaking--not so much the means of exhibition as the
means of production. As you've pointed out in your entry above, what thrills
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmakers</ENAMEX> is that shooting on digital video is, like, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> times cheaper
than shooting on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> mm. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">or even 16 mm.</NUMEX>). We all know that in low-budget films,
it's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> that are your greatest expense, it's the film stock. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O. Russell</ENAMEX> made his great <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spanking The Monkey</ENAMEX> on "short ends" snatched
up by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Grillo</ENAMEX>, then a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital</ENAMEX> will be the
great equalizer. You shoot as much footage as you like and you don't have to
convert it all to "telecines"--it's computer-ready. Any fancy effect you do in
the editing--wipes, dissolves, superimpositions--won't have to be transferred
to film (which is what costs a fortune). The kind of arduous catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-catch-can
process that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Borchardt</ENAMEX> goes through in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Movie</ENAMEX> will be a
thing of the past. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> don't care if digital projection looks
better than celluloid; they'd be thrilled if it looked as good.

            As to the question of perception, it's fascinating--mind-blowing. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almereyda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundance</ENAMEX> documentary of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atom Egoyan</ENAMEX> ruminates on
the distinctions between film and video--on the fact that film goes at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
frames a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and that a lot of what you're looking at is blank space and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flicker</ENAMEX>. There's a distinct difference in his films between the video state and
the film <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Can video approximate the effect of film? Maybe not--but if
there's a way to simulate a digital equivalent, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX> will finance it.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more question: What is the distinction is between "hypnosis" and "reverie"?
It sounds like mystical poetry to me.

            I think it's great that anyone will be able to do what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harmony Korine</ENAMEX>
does, since what he does he does so badly. We really disagree on Julien
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Donkey-Boy</ENAMEX> . It can be exciting when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are willing to put
themselves on the line like that, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korine</ENAMEX> just pummels you with the same
idea over and over. He isn't trying to capture reality, he's trying to rub your
nose in it. And underneath, he has the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">huckster</ENAMEX>'s mentality as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corman</ENAMEX> or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.G. Lewis</ENAMEX>: He throws in a bloody dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> to get your
attention. As for the idea that the movie mimics the perceptions of a
delusional schizophrenic, it's hardly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other the other the other</TIMEX> shut up
I say shut up. Not not not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> that's not a mountain--you
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX>!--that's a hill my screen my screen is flashes on and off and on and off
and yarrrggghhhhh!

            See? I can do it, too.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Actors in Search of an Oscar</ENAMEX>. Make that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actors</ENAMEX>. Any bit could be taken out of context and shown at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>.
The whole movie is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> with their backs against the wall emotionally--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
peaking. They start peaking at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of Hour 1</TIMEX>; I didn't see how they could
get any bigger. But it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spinal Tap amplifiers</ENAMEX>. They go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>.
They go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>. When it's time to go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> something very strange happens. That
strange thing isn't thematically unpredictable. It has the same logic as
the earthquake at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short Cuts</ENAMEX> , except there it was
short and brutal and here it's a full-scale, surreal black-comedy routine. I
thought it was terrific--I think the movie is terrific. I don't care what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Anderson</ENAMEX> is smoking--what matters is that he loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruise</ENAMEX> is (I can't believe I'm writing this) brilliant. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John C. Reilly</ENAMEX>
is brilliant. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX> is--well, sorry, gotta go to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">11</ENAMEX>"
here--whee!--our <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Redgrave</ENAMEX>. At a screening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>, I had the
pleasure of listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Siegel</ENAMEX> make fun of the movie behind me and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> (in a separate conversation) make fun of the movie in front of me. That
clinches it--it's one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best movies!

            Which might be a good segue for talking about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s great performances,
of which there are so many. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>, you're right--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are keeping pace
with the filmmakers, daring to leave dreary realism (and other misapplications
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Method</ENAMEX>) behind. I don't care if they'e rocket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> in life or
not--on screen they seem so smart. A performance like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese Witherspoon</ENAMEX>'s in
Election isn't realistic; it only seems that way, because she's making
imaginative leaps that are so psychologically credible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chloë Sevigny</ENAMEX> pulls off
some uncanny transitions in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry , and they're all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subterranean</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary Swank</ENAMEX> is, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sevigny</ENAMEX>'s performance that really
captures the mystery at that movie's core. (In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julien</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Donkey-Boy</ENAMEX> , she
looks like a dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> stuck in an improv that won't end.)

         
      
   
