
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duff Rebuffed; Yeltsin Struts</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>--but of course your role in life is to cheer me up. And
it has taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only four days</TIMEX> to convince you. Perhaps I should run for
something.

            Couldn't agree more that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> looking the strongest wouldn't be
disasters ... well, maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. Not sure about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> making his bones as the
education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, either. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> transmitted directly to the brain, if
you think that's a good idea, then you need reeducating. As for
considering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lasik</ENAMEX>, the laser eye surgery, I think it works only for one of the
-sighted difficulties: near- or far-. But it is effective. However ... I love
the way glasses look. If glasses are your trademark, you may want to think
twice before ditching them. I mean, without them, you might be just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more
nondescript handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            Just before I push away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>, you should know that the
latest, online, is that the old drunk, I mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, "reminded"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> has a nuclear potential. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is also cozying up to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>. They and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> met for a "family
dinner" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. Think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had a lot to say to each other? Think there
was alcohol served? Also on the wires--if you can believe it--is that Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duff</ENAMEX>
was rebuffed (shall we now call that being "reduffed"?) by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in her bid to be awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100,000</NUMEX> A MONTH in
child support from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX>. It seems that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caleigh</ENAMEX> (what kind
of name is that, anyway), will not get her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s requested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">playroom</ENAMEX>. The way I washed that taste out of my mouth was to follow some
coverage of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of mourners for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Worcester</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX>. It
makes the world seem a more admirable place when you consider that there are
good and selfless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with values and heart. And I found it enormously
touching that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> came from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It is, indeed, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brotherhood</ENAMEX> of bravery.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, I do not know of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Barkley</ENAMEX>. Alben I do remember. When it
comes to sports, I am, shall we say, not present. Some might say non compos. I
have asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Snead</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Cousy</ENAMEX> what they did for a living, and at my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first Blackhawks</ENAMEX> game it took me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 minutes</TIMEX> to realize they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> were on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skates</ENAMEX>. Which is why our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Kinsley</ENAMEX> by name, no doubt asked me to be
the advice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for 
                  Slate
               , as opposed to the sportswriter.
And it is to my more serious Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> persona that I now return. I shall
miss the opportunity to be flip about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s happenings, and I shall
particularly miss being joined at the modem to you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Massa Honey</ENAMEX>. I'll be
rooting for you in your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearlong</TIMEX> quest for the perfect political story.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xxM</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
