
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX>-Twelfths of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> invited
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to nominate events, significant deaths, good and bad movies, etc.,
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>--a year likely to get little attention in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming weeks</TIMEX>, as news
organizations choose instead to review <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire century</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>--the
response was overwhelming. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> had promised to publish his official
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1999 In Review</ENAMEX>" item before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>, but some distant memory of a scruple
persuaded him to wait till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> was over. Nothing ever happens in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>.

            OK, that's not quite true. Hordes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> are making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>'s meeting there a much more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exciting TV</ENAMEX> story than anyone expected it to be. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reader Dan Crist</ENAMEX> (who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">finds Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s habit of referring to himself in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> "rather
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">annoying</ENAMEX> and less than professional") points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1941</TIMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> (moonlighting as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>) observed not quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year ago</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
cast its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> presidential-impeachment vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19, 1998</TIMEX>.
(That same news-filled day, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ended an air war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> said he'd decided not to become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> after all.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two months</TIMEX>
after the impeachment vote, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> failed
to convict the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--a highly significant event of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> that, for some
bizarre reason, slipped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s mind until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several indignant</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> wrote
in to remind him of it.

            By now, it should be clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> isn't much good at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>-in-review
journalism. Fortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are very good at it. He will now
turn this survey over to them.

            ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> previously stated that he wouldn't
include opinions he disagreed with, that standard proved too confining. Where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has solid information or opinions to the contrary, he occasionally
interjects below. Obviously stupid or unnecessarily sour reader comments were
discarded, but if you don't find your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> below it doesn't necessarily mean
that it was obviously stupid or unnecessarily sour. )

            Here are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> important things that happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hated Celebrity--Ever</ENAMEX>?
            

            

               
                   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
reported on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1999</TIMEX>, that a new record had been set in the latest
Times /<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> poll: [Its] highest negative rating ever scored by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in
the news. The honor went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>, who managed to
make an unfavorable impression upon some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of those polled. The paper
noted that this achievement far eclipsed the last comparably negative
rating--the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX> score attained by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>. Presumably this came as
no surprise to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>, who, upon announcing the formation of a presidential exploratory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 7, 1999</TIMEX>, had cited polls with "amazing results"--a
remark that was widely misinterpreted at the time.
               

               -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Allen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> (and frequent

                     Slate
                   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contributor</ENAMEX>)

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Foolishly Ignored Parts of the World</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that did bark but no one noticed--the political turmoil in the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, which now
are well on the way to passing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> northern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in population (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> just passed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> will soon pass <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are still fixated
on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern Asia</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says he must deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, because "you can't
ignore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>," but his own policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
shows that you sure can!
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Chapin</ENAMEX>

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Worst/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best Films</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  Here's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> for worst movie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> (complete category should
be: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst Movie of the Year That Assumedly Adult Male Reviewers</ENAMEX> Slathered
Over"): 
                  There's
Something <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Mary</ENAMEX>
                  --a pathetically sophomoric, penis-obsessed mess
that wouldn't even appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>!
               

               -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Menlo Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cal</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            

               
                  You've got the wrong year. That was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> .
                  
               

            

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> didn't have the heart to add that he thought There's
Something About <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> was pretty funny, especially the joke about "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">franks</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>."]

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicia</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oops</ENAMEX> ... well then, the best of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'99</NUMEX> was 
                  The
Red <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Violin</ENAMEX>
                  --lyrical, magical, musical, wonderful!
               

            

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> hasn't seen it.]

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shameless</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unsuccessful) Attempt To Have It Both Ways in</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> :

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> law, finds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "not
proven" on the impeachment charges.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Solovay</ENAMEX>

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Rest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>:
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX> (multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>)

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> (multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>)

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Strasberg</ENAMEX> (anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tipster</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strasberg</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> in the original production of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> adaptation, which some people
think wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> enough)

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Torme</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Reiness</ENAMEX>)

               
                  Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whozit</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> interjects : her name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Sheafe Miller</ENAMEX>], the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> ever to be saved
by penicillin (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Bolles</ENAMEX>)

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road</ENAMEX> Not Taken
            

            

               
                   What an extraordinary year! A
right-wing conspiracy topples the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> reveals
himself in a series of debates to be a natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> with an innate gift for
connecting with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, a sure sign of his electoral success <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. A
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Harris</ENAMEX> book brilliantly takes us deeper into the
mind of a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>; a new Star Wars movie redefines the very nature of
entertainment; a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX> film changes the whole national dialogue about
sex and marriage; a new TV series from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsNight</ENAMEX> --oh, I
can't even bring myself to bash that piece of do-gooder twaddle. If only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> had come out with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more boldly adult-flavored <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX>, it
would have been a perfect year for dud megaevents--all leading up of course to
Y2K, the limpest milestone in human history.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Gebert</ENAMEX>

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behaving Badly</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  Don't forget <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Woodstock</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> --the concert of "peace and love" that
ended in a literal blaze of glory when in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hours-long</TIMEX> tribute to the original
Woodstock, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> started ripping down vendor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booths</ENAMEX> and anything else that
would burn and piling it onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bonfires</ENAMEX> scattered about the scene.
[ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> interjects: Didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get assaulted and raped, too?]
I'm getting all sentimental just thinking about it.
               

               You also left out all the shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rampages</ENAMEX> . Several were done in the name of God
or love supposedly. They were all committed by "quiet, shy" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who "mostly
kept to" themselves. I've started to hang around only loud, obnoxious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Hoechstetter</ENAMEX>

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lunatic Rhapsody</ENAMEX> for the 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Yankees</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> can actually
be referred to as the glue that held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> together. Of course, as the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">champions</ENAMEX>, they are a significant "story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>."
However, this one singular achievement must be considered in a broader
context.
               

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> represented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">25th</NUMEX> championship of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. This beats, by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, the most championships any one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> won during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montreal</ENAMEX>
Canadiens have won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Cups</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>,
playing in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City of the Century"</ENAMEX> (so called by me to reflect the amazing
growth and transformation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> during this period), who play the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Pastime</ENAMEX>," are truly an amazing story.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> championship occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX>; therefore, they have won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
of the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78 years</TIMEX>, nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. This level of sustained excellence
is not matched in sports or in any other aspect of society. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> win is
possibly the most unique. With free-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, expansion, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> levels of
playoffs, it is much harder to win <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past years</TIMEX>. In fact, by
winning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> championships, they are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to
accomplish this feat during the eras of free-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and of divisional play.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Swat, the Iron Man</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee Clipper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mick</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yogi</ENAMEX>--these strong, masculine names are synonymous with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, the sport,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. They went hand in hand with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> world wars, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Superman</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX> status. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1999</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> does not feature "a name." This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>, with its myriad of human-interest stories, its international roster, and
no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of '90s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, male sensitivity, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pax American</ENAMEX>
interests, and the new political paradigm.

            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Landau</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Potomac</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX> (formerly of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Shot Calls for Decriminalizing Drug Use</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Johnson</ENAMEX> came out for ending drug prohibition. Though this
by itself has no immediate effect, it makes it respectable, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time,
for political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to discuss the subject, and thereby brings closer the day
when the vast majority of crimes will no longer be committed, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of
dollars will be freed to help the inner city instead of to ruin black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
lives, and when we will stop, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Butler</ENAMEX>'s 
                  Erewhon
                  , imprisoning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for the crime of
being sick.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Cohen</ENAMEX>

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> interjects: Didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Schmoke</ENAMEX> do the same thing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years ago</TIMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Don't Worry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX> proclaimed that most important thing in the world is to be
happy.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Taylor</ENAMEX>

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Athletic Bra Seen 'Round the World</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  Public interest and media attention to the women's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Horton</ENAMEX>

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Overlooked Foreign-Policy Event</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               Presidential primary elections for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Horton</ENAMEX>

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Policing the World Is Shown To Work</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                   I nominate as the most
under-reported story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> (and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX>) the continuing
alarmist predictions by foreign-policy and military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> about peacekeeping
efforts, which are then proved wrong and immediately forgotten. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the
obvious one is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> is also ending with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aussies</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> successfully stopped the slaughter with no
casualties.
               

               These followed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> as places where the West delayed
sending in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> because of alarmist predictions.

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Skurnik</ENAMEX>

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> Did <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This One on Her Year-End Special</ENAMEX>, But It's Still
Good
            

            

               
                  Don't forget, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Lucci</ENAMEX> finally won an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy</ENAMEX> .

               
                  --anonymous tipster
               

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annals of Justice</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX>: the despicable defense .
               

               -- anonymous tipster
               

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. Get Me a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Century</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quick</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  A sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was accused of rape.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> interjects: Yes, but the evidence was shaky--something the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's editorial page, which broke the story, was
not
very forthcoming about. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>
wrote in this column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, after he left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, was also accused
of having once committed rape. The evidence there was shaky, too.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Important Thing of All That Happened</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> had a PC, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX> (i.e.,
home-PC penetration passed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>). Of course, most of these PCs crashed
all the time, but it's still a significant development. By the way, Internet
hookups in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are still well below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Mossberg</ENAMEX>, "Personal
Technology" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> (and occasional
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">rock</ENAMEX>-music
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> for this column)

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. All Dolled Up and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nowhere To Go</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  General
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pinochet</ENAMEX>
               

               
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Maurer</ENAMEX>
               

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Endorses Nuclear Proliferation</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> rejected the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test</ENAMEX>
Ban <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty</ENAMEX> , thereby decapitating nuclear-arms control and sending <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> the message that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> won't raise a big
stink if they try to join <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> woke up to this
possibility at about the moment it was realized, and started lobbying for
passage of the treaty a day after it became too late.
               

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Pollack</ENAMEX>

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unremarked Natural Disaster</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Supercyclone</ENAMEX> is the biggest, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> at
least.
               

               
                  --Samir Raiyani
               

               
                  Photographs of: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter Morgan/Reuters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Portman</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Hamshere</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucasfilm Ltd./Reuters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Yankees</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershorn/Reuters; KLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hazir Reka/Reuters</ENAMEX>.
               

            

         
      
   
