
   
   
      
         
            To Wit
            

            Thanks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>, for your skepticism--although I'm not sure we're in as much
disagreement as your crackly tone would imply. The level of invention this year
has been amazingly high, but few movies have maintained it consistently. My

                  Slate
                reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> , Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Limey</ENAMEX> are full of qualifications, but many of the most exciting
films in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given year</TIMEX> are messed up in one way or another. (The last film for
which I have unqualified admiration is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Duvall</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Apostle</ENAMEX> .) I
was enraged by the killing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> and
resented some of the jokiness and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formula machinations</ENAMEX> that followed in its
wake. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David O. Russell</ENAMEX> can't (yet) make his absurdist vision mesh
perfectly with his moral outrage, he deserves our awe for having pulled off the
mixture as well as anyone since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coppola in Apocalypse Now</ENAMEX> . (And Three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kings</ENAMEX> is a lot less messed-up than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Apocalypse Now</ENAMEX> .)

            I didn't spot microphones in Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> (depending
on how a film is masked, you can see microphones in movies by the greatest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and cinematographers), but there are flatfooted patches and a
distinct falling off in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last half hour</TIMEX> (despite some marvelous puppet
work). Fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is indeed one of the picture's sub-themes; it's a theme of
many great sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farces</ENAMEX> and not ipso facto a bad thing. The movie's too-casual
discarding of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX>) suggests more self-loathing than
unchecked misogyny--although the two impulses are clearly linked. It seems to
me that when you're braving as many weird psychosexual areas as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Kaufman</ENAMEX>
does in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> , you're going to lose control at some point; he does.
The larger point is that his work--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>'s--is an inspiration; it makes
you makes you realize that, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Anxiety of</ENAMEX> 
               Influence
notwithstanding, there are an infinite number of possibilities for framing our
experience.

            As for your <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Park</ENAMEX> rant--them's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fightin</ENAMEX>' words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr</ENAMEX>. I'm going
to cheat by pointing out that I know you didn't see the movie in a packed,
responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, or you would, I'm certain, have been thrilled by the screams
of glee that attended each fabulous number. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> boring? The whole
damn film is a scant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">80 minutes</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its second half</TIMEX> features, among other
things, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan's</ENAMEX> soulful "Up There" number (please oh please let them do this at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s pleas for sex, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kyle's Mom Is a Bitch</ENAMEX>" with a
multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenny</ENAMEX>'s trek through the underworld, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartman</ENAMEX>'s obscenity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chip</ENAMEX>, the blaspheming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> fighter, and the staggeringly brilliant
medley on the eve of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX>--not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winona Ryder</ENAMEX>'s best performance
ever (courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Driver</ENAMEX>). If this is witless then I might as well pack
it in because I wouldn't know wit if it bit me on the ass.

            More later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">alligators</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
