
   
   
      
         
            To the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Unread</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> <i>This</i>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>:

            Who died and made us the final arbiters of political virtue? Great question,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that I'm asked frequently (usually by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who write in crayon on the
outside of the envelope). The short answer is, nobody. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> get to travel
around on expense account asking total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> invasive questions and passing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">swift</ENAMEX> and nasty judgment on their responses because ... well, just because
they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. Pretty unfair, isn't it?

            Sure it is, but I'm not complaining. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, I enjoy doing it. For
another, somebody's got to ask the questions. I won't give you the whole "we're
the guardians of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>" speech here--though I do recommend it for
getting past the rope line at political events--but I do think that without the
purifying influence of the press, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would devolve into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">totalitarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police state</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 20 minutes</TIMEX>. Shut down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> and internal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passports</ENAMEX> will follow.

            OK, I admit I may be exaggerating a bit. (The sound you hear in the
background is my emergency hyperbole alarm going off.) But if I tend to get
overwrought on the subject, it's only because there's so much noise coming from
the other side. I couldn't be sicker of hearing how Ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folks</ENAMEX>
Outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>, Average Working <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> [insert your favorite euphemism
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Unread</ENAMEX> here] have contempt for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. (My gut response,
seldom voiced, is: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX>, now we're even.) The problem is particularly acute in
some conservative circles, where belief in the liberal media conspiracy is part
of the catechism. Polls I keep reading about claim to indicate that most people
consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> inaccurate and arrogant, if not simply evil.

            This bugs me, and not just because it's me they're talking about. I don't
like the perception mainly because it isn't true. Inaccurate? Ever read a
newspaper from another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, say? How about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>? I have a copy of
a relatively highbrow English-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> that has a story
about witchcraft--played straight, like witchcraft is real--on the front
page.

            But the charge that irritates me most is arrogance. It's almost always made
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, and that's the really galling part. It's true that the national
press is a bit taken with itself. On the other hand, I don't know a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who's as dictatorial and self-involved as any one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>. Not even close, actually. How many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> do you know who
routinely refer to themselves in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>? Point made.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>, I've really worked myself into a frenzy here. Just in time for the
debate tonight.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
