
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Conspiracy</ENAMEX>

            This afternoon I attended a top-secret meeting of the media conspiracy's
central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. Being there was very exciting for me, because I've heard
about this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> without ever being invited into its inner
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sanctum</ENAMEX>. It was also an honor for 
                  Slate
               , because we are
apparently the first online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to be included in one of these
sessions.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> gathered in a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> at the Savery
Hotel in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. Present were all the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> in political
journalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>--though he's
known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dean</ENAMEX>" to all and sundry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> takes his journalistic
responsibilities very seriously. He has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX> living on a
hog <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cedar Rapids</ENAMEX> in preparation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s caucuses. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX> is also apparently working on another very big book--and this is very
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hush-hush</ENAMEX>--on the role of certified public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
policy-making.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyhow</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> called the meeting to order and explained that the
conspiracy had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few hours</TIMEX> to choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of the debate. He said he
thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> had made the right decision in handing the previous two
debates to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and in portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> as the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>.
He added that he thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> was making healthy progress toward its
medium-range goal--apparently established in meetings on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>--of creating a tight, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-person race in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> primaries.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>--I get to call him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill"</ENAMEX> now--responded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX> by
saying that he was getting bored with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> line and wanted to say
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had improved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> didn't go so far as to propose that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> win
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s debate, but he wondered whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> might be criticized for
something other than being a lightweight.

            "Such as what?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Greenfield</ENAMEX> asked.

            Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> explained, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> blows up whenever he reads anything negative
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> himself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. Why not order up a question designed to provoke
him--and then raise the issue of whether he has a thick enough skin to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> didn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX>'s idea. She reminded him of the rule of
pre-existing conditions (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> leaned over and explained this rule to me.
It's the one that says all new evidence has to confirm established personality
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traits</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stupidity</ENAMEX> is already <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s liability, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie</ENAMEX> said, and while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> might decide that this was not a serious problem later in the
campaign, it couldn't suddenly give him a new drawback without any advance
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX>.

            Besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> added, casting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as a hothead would tread on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s pre-existing condition, namely his temper. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> running
against each other in the primaries couldn't very well have the same character
flaw.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> agreed with all of this but wondered whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> couldn't at least
show some improvement in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s debate. He said that some groundwork needed
to be laid for a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CWR</ENAMEX>" (this stands for conventional wisdom reversal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunt</ENAMEX>
explained to me) once it became clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was going to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
nomination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Apple</ENAMEX> bristled at that comment, accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> of "eating
my lunch." This was not a literal reference to the capon carcass resting on the
platter in front of him but a metaphor for "invading his journalistic turf."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> sees it as his sole responsibility to establish the conventional wisdom
and rejects any attempt by the rest of the media conspiracy to assist him.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Woodruff</ENAMEX> had a compromise. She proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> simply be
"underwhelming," making one moderately serious gaffe to fuel concerns about his
preparedness for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> while also "exceeding expectations." She said members
could have a quick caucus during the period set aside for closing statements at
the end of the debate to decide what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gaffe</ENAMEX> had been.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX> objected again. He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> surge needed to be held back,
lest it crest too early--which could have the effect of making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late February</TIMEX>. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s performance should be
judged merely adequate.

            So who should win, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenfield</ENAMEX> asked? <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The hour</TIMEX> for decision was drawing
near.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liz Drew</ENAMEX> had a surprising idea--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>. While she said that this
violated the unwritten code against taking more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in the race
seriously at the same time, she noted that since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> wasn't running in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> would be his surrogate as "not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Touting Forbes</ENAMEX> would hold back the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> wave. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX> said there would then be an entire week to write off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Iowa caucus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>.

            This proposal initially drew some jeers from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> whose contempt for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> is pretty obvious. It especially upset <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Fineman</ENAMEX>,
who said they had already filed their columns declaring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. But
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX>'s point proved persuasive. Declaring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> the surprise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">victor</ENAMEX> would aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> without showing excessive "media bias" against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenfield</ENAMEX> then asked about the danger that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> might actually defeat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for the nomination. Everyone agreed that this was not a serious risk,
though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenfield</ENAMEX> was right to raise it. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>" then adjourned the
meeting.

         
      
   
