
   
   
      
         
            Internet: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lots of Balls</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>'
decision to reopen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> homicide cases and their pledge to revamp the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supervision</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> group <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> for the mentally disabled, all in response to a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story revealing that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital, officials
routinely don't investigate the suspicious deaths of retarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> went with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: the decision by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> to give competing Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> access to its high-speed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
runs this inside, leading instead with the trend in many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to aggressively
enforce truancy laws that threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> with fines and jail time. The story
stuns early with this statistic: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s
public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a month</TIMEX> of classes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
which also runs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> inside, leads with the claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election</ENAMEX>
Commission will have increasing trouble doing its job of enforcing federal
election laws because of the upsurge of work brought about by the most
expensive election cycle ever.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead points out the limits of good journalism when it
reminds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, still hasn't implemented the reforms
it promised in response to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> series done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> on abuse
in those group <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. Obviously, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> needs to bring in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with more
investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and a better sense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> than those calling
the shots now. How about hiring (in jobs with real power) some of the
Post <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who keep nailing these stories?

            The USAT FEC lead raises more questions than it answers: Why exactly
is this election cycle producing more work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>? The story mentions
the rise of complaints about "issue ads," but is that the sole cause? And what
do independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> think? The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> quoted by name in the story are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, which is less than convincing since it's in the interest of
every government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to cry being underbudgeted and understaffed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers, word that at
the moment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Polar Lander</ENAMEX> is still MIA. The papers report that there is
growing concern among project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> will not complete its
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$165 million</NUMEX> mission. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> question: Why don't the stories mention the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>? When an airliner crashes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> quickly
announce that it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> or an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX>--why should this be different?

            For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'
performance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is brutally frank, appearing under the headline "HEALTH
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">INDUSTRY SEES WISH LIST MADE INTO LAW</ENAMEX>."

            A pair of WP front-pagers emphasize that taxes are looming large in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> battle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, says the paper, is charging that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
will have to raise taxes in order to finance his health-care plan, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
has chosen not to rule out an increase. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> story serves up a memorable
line from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Nicholson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>, who
calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley "Dukakis</ENAMEX> with a jump shot."

            In its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heard on the Street"</ENAMEX> column, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> makes a great observation about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s likely announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of an IPO of a tracking stock tied to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wireless</ENAMEX> business: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underwriters</ENAMEX> of such deals tend to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that have in the
past given good ratings to the issuing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Which of course means those
ratings aren't exactly reliable for the rest of us.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" details a corollary of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s constitutional
provision that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> can be prosecuted for a crime while
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One hundred and five</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are convicts and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
others are wanted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. It would have been nice if the story had mentioned
what sort of immunity is enjoyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> and indeed how
many, if any, are convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT business front reports that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> Internet executive
who was arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> on charges of using the Internet
to solicit sex from a minor has a defense ready to go for his trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.
He will claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is a massive masquerade ball and that he never
expected that anybody portraying themselves as a minor there would actually be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> was more than a little fascinated with the topic of
whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">20th Century</ENAMEX>" in their names would change with
the times. So fascinated that it ran not one, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories on the apparently
bottomless topic, one in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money and Business</ENAMEX>" section and one in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
