
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.'s Smirk</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox Investigation</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s smirk has become a hot political story. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-Span</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "funny little grin, almost a smirk, that comes
across his face occasionally at inappropriate times" had occasioned perplexed
discussion among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> at the cutting-edge-conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> edits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Williams</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Nyhan</ENAMEX> also noted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smirk Problem on MSNBC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, respectively,
prompting a superbly detailed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3</TIMEX> article by the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Calmes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calmes</ENAMEX> described the following eerie scene:

            

               
                  At a campaign stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubuque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> toured a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
pregnancy-counseling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> to promote his antiabortion views and support for
faith-based social services. As he sat at a table with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> female workers
there, he continuously wore a sort of smile as he listened to each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. One
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> for "post-abortion trauma," told how she had become
pregnant at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>, helplessly felt she had no alternative but abortion, "and for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> ... suffered in silence." Still, the right side of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s mouth
seemed frozen in a half smile.
               

            

            The smirk resurfaced at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> debate, according to
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX>, who in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 13</TIMEX> issue writes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  will squinny his eyes, raise his chin, lift an eyebrow, and curl his lip
slightly--his face seems to be involved in a somewhat painful,
quasi-involuntary struggle to prevent itself from erupting into a broad,
self-satisfied smile. This facial skirmish is often accompanied by a slight
forward bend at the waist and a what-me-worry? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shrug</ENAMEX>, and they often occur
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> has delivered a line particularly well, or thinks he
has.
               

            

            The smirk is causing much justifiable worry in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> circles. "I hear
some saying that his friendly outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> on TV is mistaken for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smirk</ENAMEX> and smugness," a "senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>" was quoted as saying in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dec. 8 Boston Globe</ENAMEX> . "A few have said to me, 'He has to
make sure that charm is not mistaken for arrogance.'" Presumably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> himself
got the message; his smirk was not much in evidence at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
debate. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see for yourself.)

            Clearly, though, the smirk will return, and when it does, political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spinmeisters</ENAMEX> will try to define it away as an "image problem," a mere matter of
faulty subjective analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. A far more interesting
question than how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s smirk is interpreted , however, is: What does it
mean ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calmes</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-Span</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Lamb</ENAMEX> as saying, in effect, that it's
just a cruel trick of genetic physiognomy: "His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has the same thing; it's
just not as pronounced as it is with 'W.'" But since personality is also
to some extent genetically based and, moreover, can be passed environmentally
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> to the next--particularly when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> share not
only the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but also a few institutional influences (e.g.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>)--it is conceivable that the shared smirk signifies a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> ... arrogance.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>, quite rightly, warns us not to be too hasty in reaching this
conclusion:

            

               
                  It would be easy to mistake such elaborate body language for arrogance,
as more than a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> have, whereas the true meaning of the tic may be
the exact opposite. It may just signify relief--that he has successfully
managed to jump another public hurdle without embarrassing himself. Or it may
mean nothing at all.
               

            

            Concluding that the matter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s smirk was too weighty to be left in the
hands of nonscientists, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> e-mailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Ekman</ENAMEX>,
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> Sentinel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
"leading smile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>." His academic writings on how to interpret facial
expressions have been used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to figure out which potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eject</ENAMEX> during voir dire and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX> to figure out the giveaway signs
of a card <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">bluff</ENAMEX>. If anyone could explain the meaning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s
troubling smirk, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ekman</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ekman</ENAMEX> made clear in a response to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s note that he wouldn't play:

            

               
                  I watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> and have many thoughts about it. But I have a policy
about never talking about anyone who is in office or running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, or is
in litigation. So I can't help you. I don't know anyone responsible and
knowledgeable who can.
               

            

            Undaunted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> marched off to a nearby bookstore and purchased
What the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face Reveals: Basic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Studies</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spontaneous Expression Using the Facial Action Coding System</ENAMEX> (FACS) ,
edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erika Rosenberg</ENAMEX>. He then burrowed in for a long read.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> learned that the science of studying facial expressions is
relatively new: Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, apparently, "it was deemed a useless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX>." This consensus changed as a result of work done by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvan Tomkins</ENAMEX>,
Ekman, and a few others. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.V. Friesen</ENAMEX> examined
the facial expressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> as they watched
"stressful films." When they watched these films alone, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had similar, distressed expressions on their faces. When they watched
these films in the presence of an "authority figure," however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>'
facial expressions were essentially the same as when they watched the films
alone, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> "showed much less negative affect, smiled
sometimes, and actually masked negative emotion with smiling behavior."
Conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are less guarded in letting facial expressions show what
they're feeling. A reassuring finding in light of the question before us.

            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman</ENAMEX> developed a method called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facial Action</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coding System</ENAMEX> (FACS) to measure "all visually discernible facial movement."
The building blocks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> "action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUs</ENAMEX>) such as a
wrinkling of the nose, a puffing of the cheeks, dilation of the nostrils,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squinting</ENAMEX>, and so on. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUs</ENAMEX>, usually identified by the facial muscles that
perform these various tasks, are the tools used in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What the Face</ENAMEX>
Reveals . (To look at a few examples, click here and
here.)

            Sadly, there is no chapter on smirking per se in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ekman</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX>'s book. (In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman</ENAMEX> and several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-authors</ENAMEX> reject the term "smirk" on the grounds that it's too coarse and
imprecise, "ignoring differences between a variety of different muscular
actions to which [it] may refer, and mixing description with inferences about
meaning or the message which [it] may convey.") But there are three
chapters in the book that may nonetheless be relevant to the smirking
question:

            

               Let's start with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph G. Hager</ENAMEX>) titled "The
Asymmetry of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Facial Actions</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s smirk is asymmetrical, is it not? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX> describes an experiment in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> right-handed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caucasian</ENAMEX> women ages
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 to 53</TIMEX> were exposed to various mildly unpleasant experiences and asked to
smile. Then they were asked, "Now that this is done, aren't you glad it's
over<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" This inspired spontaneous smiles. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hager</ENAMEX> found that the
smiles-on-demand were less symmetrical than the spontaneous smiles. This might
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mean George W.</ENAMEX>'s apparent smirk is merely a forced smile, not a smug or
mean or even dishonest one.

               Another interpretation is suggested in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman</ENAMEX> and several
others) titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Type A Behavior Pattern</ENAMEX>." Here, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> argue that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> most likely to suffer <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX> are more apt than others to
glare and show facial signs of disgust. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> doesn't glare much, as far as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can tell, but his smirk may be an expression of disgust. If
that's true, he would seem to face a heightened risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>.

               The most provocative chapter in the book (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ekman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace V. Friesen</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>) is titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Smiles When Lying</ENAMEX>." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman, Friesen</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>, there is a clear distinction between "felt happy" smiles and
"masking" smiles intended to hide some other emotion. (The subject doesn't
actually have to be telling a lie; rather, the facial expression
itself is the lie.) Felt happy smiles "are defined as the action
of the zygomatic major [lip] and orbicularis oculi, pars
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lateralis</ENAMEX> [eye] muscles." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masking</ENAMEX> smiles use a whole bunch of other
facial muscles associated with fear, disgust, contempt, sadness, and anger. One
such muscle is the triangularis , which (judging from an illustrative
photograph on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">208</NUMEX>) pulls the corner of the lip down in an
expression that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would call ... a smirk.

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will refrain from endorsing any of these three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypotheses</ENAMEX>-- forced smile , susceptibility to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">falsity</ENAMEX> --to explain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s smirk. Rather, he calls on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ekman</ENAMEX> or some
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> to tell us which, if any, is correct.

         
      
   
