
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Complex Bouquet</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>,

            What a fun honor it is to swap opinions with you both,
not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. I liked your entries and agree about a
lot--I'll have more feedback <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, but first I should explain why I didn't
really find it useful to rank <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX>. Many of the really ambitious
efforts of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the ones we will look back on as turning points, also suffer
from some real limitations, and in a few cases some serious, stinkeroo flaws. I
want to salute those films that were onto something new, while recognizing that
in places they were kind of dodgy, and not necessarily the best-made of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. I quite liked Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> (inspired
metaphysical conceit, unforgettable crazy dance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX>, another
go-for-broke performance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Diaz</ENAMEX>). But did you notice the long
stretches of tin-ear dialogue for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay</ENAMEX> Place; the amateurish quality of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">setups</ENAMEX> (often you can see a microphone dipping and swaying at the top of the
screen); and, last but not least, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">10th</NUMEX>-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">misogyny</ENAMEX>? Another instance:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limey</ENAMEX> was a delicate, stylish piece of work,
saturated with love of movies past; but once a year there is a similar and--not
quite as good, but nearly as good--imported <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> mystery on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. Compared
with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Limey</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX> Lola
Run was clumsy, a chunk of bratwurst. Yet of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, it seems fresher to
me.

            I agree with you both that we're at a turning point,
although except in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David O. Russell</ENAMEX>, I'm not sure how much Godard
has to do with it. The easiest place to look for this new creativity is
technology: the special effects in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Matrix</ENAMEX> and
Toy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story 2</ENAMEX> , the hypertext plot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run Lola Run</ENAMEX> . But you could also see it in the style of acting. This
was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> since practically forever that I didn't long for more
genuine movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. This was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> when the indie ensemble
aesthetic--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors humbly</ENAMEX> serving a specific function, rather than being their
charismatic selves--really came into its own. Witness the number of big names
turning in shrewd, non-hammy, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> performances in animated
films; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> reviving his career by ceasing to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX>;
witness the reigning stardom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>, who is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audrey Hepburn</ENAMEX>
supernova she's cracked up to be, but, to her credit, a chameleon character
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> who happens to lovely. Witness the death throes of the once-great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>'s career. (Or was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>, he of the simmering stare and pained,
narrow grin, ever really that great? Probably, but that's the kind of
assumption <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s films have started to call into question.)

            My list of movies that felt fresh and creative but were
far from perfect, and sometimes not even so likable, is: the ensemble gem
Election , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sixth Sense</ENAMEX> ,
Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys</ENAMEX>
Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cry , Toy Story 2</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run Lola Run</ENAMEX> , and
Dogma . And, maybe, you've both convinced me,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron Giant</ENAMEX> .

            Now let the exchange begin. Potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disagreements</ENAMEX>: I
like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> , but not as much as either of
you--it drags, and at times operates in bad faith. I'll make a case for
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sixth Sense</ENAMEX> , which I think was seriously
underrated by most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Park</ENAMEX> ? I did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laugh</ENAMEX> (hard, I admit) at the shocking parts--<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first few</TIMEX> musical numbers and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence & Philip</ENAMEX> farting/violent death routines are hilarious and
creatively drawn. But the rest of it is hateful, and witless in a very
predictable way. There's no grace in the construction of the film, and though
there may be echoes of the early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Lampoon</ENAMEX>
(which hasn't always dated well, I might add), unlike in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lampoon</ENAMEX> there's not much news about the culture that you don't
already know. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marx Brothers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swift</ENAMEX>? It struck me, pardon the language, as
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>-f-----' con game, and boring to boot.

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
