
   
   
      
         
            Smells <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like Team Spirit</ENAMEX>
            

            It isn't often that you actually get a look at corporate life as it's
actually lived from the inside. That's part of what makes The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target Shoots</ENAMEX>
First , a new video documentary by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Wilcha</ENAMEX>, so memorable
(click here to buy a copy of the video). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, upon graduating college
with an ever-marketable degree in philosophy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilcha</ENAMEX> took a job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> (which was co-owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>) as a marketing
assistant, mostly so he could buy time until he figured out what he was really
going to do with his life. He brought with him a devotion to punk and indie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX> and a video camera that, somewhat improbably, he used to tape marketing
meetings, design discussions, conversations with his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, and a
visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia House</ENAMEX> actually manufactures and distributes
its product.

            The result is a movie that's a remarkable document of the time when it was
made. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilcha</ENAMEX> arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia House</ENAMEX> in the middle of the alternative-rock
explosion, which at the time looked like it was going to reshape the music
industry but would instead quickly fade away. In the wake of the huge success
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nirvana's Nevermind</ENAMEX> , which was released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September of 1991</TIMEX> and
stayed on the charts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>, major record labels went on a
band-signing spree, adding to their rosters any act that seemed to offer even
the faintest possibility of being the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nirvana</ENAMEX>. Of course, since this was a
lot like signing a host of bands hoping to find the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>, the strategy
didn't work.

            Still, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> no one knew this. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia House</ENAMEX> knew was
that something important was happening and that they had no clue either what it
really was or, more important, how to make money off it. In some sense,
alternative rock really did shake the industry, because it came, if not from
nowhere, then nowhere that the major labels had previously cared about. The
magnitude of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nirvana</ENAMEX>'s success--and the success of its lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX>,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Jam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundgarden</ENAMEX>--was such that it couldn't be ignored.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parallels</ENAMEX> could be drawn between the record industry's reaction to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nevermind</ENAMEX> and the film industry's reaction to sex, lies, and
videotape .)

            What all this meant was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilcha</ENAMEX>, which is to say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
had been listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nirvana and the Replacements and Minor Threat and HÃ</ENAMEX>¼sker
DÃ¼ long before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nevermind</ENAMEX> broke, suddenly seemed incredibly valuable. On
a smaller scale, what happened to them was like what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
Internet experience in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Doors that would normally have been sealed tightly
shut were opened, and they were given far more freedom in the workplace than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-olds</TIMEX> typically enjoy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target Shoots First</ENAMEX> begins with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilcha</ENAMEX>'s adjusting to the vaguely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dilbertesque</ENAMEX> world of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia House</ENAMEX> and
delineates the sharp division between the suits on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> floor
(home of marketing) and the creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> floor, and
then shows what happened when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilcha</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> were given a mandate to
create a separate alternative-rock catalog that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia House</ENAMEX> could send its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>.

            They essentially turned the catalog into the kind of self-aware,
inside-reference-laced music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that they would want to read themselves.
And it was a huge hit. Except, of course, that no matter how clever it was, it
was in the end still a catalog. And its success mostly meant that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> would get to sell more CDs.

            In his voice-over narration, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilcha</ENAMEX> is open about his dismay at this fact,
and the movie as a whole is embedded in a critique of consumerism that seems
ultimately naive. But naive or not, that dismay certainly feels true to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, as does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilcha</ENAMEX>'s decision to stop filming after the suicide of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX>
Cobain, lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nirvana</ENAMEX>. It may seem odd to think of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> as a "different time," but in so many ways (pre-Internet, pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>,
pre-boom, still expecting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the recession of 1990-1991</TIMEX> to come back) it was. And
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that was most different was the feeling that music really
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mattered</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nirvana</ENAMEX>'s having a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX> record would make a real difference in
the culture as a whole. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target Shoots First</ENAMEX> is amazingly moving, at
least for me, precisely because it reminds me of what it was like to feel that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, and so of what it is like not to feel that way now.

            Having said all that, the most interesting thing about the film is the way
it shows how changing the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> work actually makes a material difference
to the kind of work they do. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilcha</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> were given the job
of starting the alt-rock catalog, they explicitly adopted a team structure,
breaking down the traditional hierarchical division between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">th floors</ENAMEX> and integrating the marketing, creative, and design
functions in a way that had never been done before at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia House</ENAMEX>. The
result, perhaps predictably, was a working environment that was both more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enjoyable</ENAMEX> and, by all accounts, more productive. It was, in other words,
exactly the kind of experience that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fast Company</ENAMEX> loves to write
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>.

            This matters because the critique of consumerism that animates The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoots First</ENAMEX> is often accompanied by a critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fast Company-</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Peters</ENAMEX>-style ideas about work that dismisses these ideas as covers for
corporate power. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilcha</ENAMEX>'s movie ends up showing that, at least at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really can be happier and more engaged if they're allowed to work
differently. This doesn't mean, of course, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> structures are the route
to paradise, especially if you think making profits for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> is immoral. But it
does serve as a nice reminder that not all fads are frauds.

         
      
   
