
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gets Its Locks Off</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s warning to the Taliban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will hold them responsible for any
terrorist acts attributable to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>. Nobody
else fronts this. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead is the ceremony in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX>
Zone marking the imminent transfer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">waterway</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panamanian</ENAMEX> control. The
event drew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>, who as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> pushed for the hand-change. The
Post quotes his reference to the "colonialism" and "state socialism" of
the original arrangement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX>, but
its top non-local story is the agreement of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and industry to
set up a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.1 billion</NUMEX> fund to compensate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">estimated 1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still
alive who were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>. The story runs inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , is flagged near the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box, and is fronted at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , which leads with the latest blockbuster in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
continuing coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> scandal: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.A.</ENAMEX>'s view that dirty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cops</ENAMEX> may have tainted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 3,000</NUMEX> criminal cases. He is quoted as saying that
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> will be released as a result, that criminal charges will be filed
against some cops, and that the whole thing will take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to resolve.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's lead reminds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> has been indicted in connection
with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two 1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> bombings in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">229</NUMEX>. The paper
explains that the warning about him comes after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> just
barely announced arrests <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> somewhere about to
do something someplace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> cites some intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for the idea that the intended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">target</ENAMEX> may have been in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have paid reparations in the past
in connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>' murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and others, the coverage states
that the latest sum is their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> significant settlement on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>. A hallmark of the agreement, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
is that it will include payments from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>,
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX>. Previously these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> had protested that they had no
liability on the grounds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had forcibly taken over
their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-leads, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> carry inside, the
decision by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> had no immunity agreement
protecting her from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> wiretapping charges. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s key finding is,
says the paper, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s federal immunity didn't take effect until it was
approved by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks</TIMEX> after it was first promised to her by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the ruling deals "a major blow" to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s
defense in her wiretapping trial scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager reports a surprising consequence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>'s reform
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, which had been prompted by congressional hearings portraying (a
largely discredited portrayal, the paper reminds) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s hounding of
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wealthier Americans</ENAMEX> are being subject to less tax scrutiny
while poorer ones are being subject to more. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> is backing off attempts at
auditing the complex returns of the better off, while putting more effort into
looking for abuse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>, a credit available only to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX>, and into catching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who file no returns at all,
traditionally a practice inordinately associated with modest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> is investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> for alleged
antitrust violations in its dealings with major music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The core issue
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s practice of demanding music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> give its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX>, and
VH1 channels exclusive air rights to music videos when they are released,
making it nearly impossible for rival music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> to enter the market. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes that under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>'s proposed buyout of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, this sort of
issue will take on even more importance, because the resulting new company
would own additional cable music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>.

            Everybody fronts an illustration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX>, in honor of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
announcement that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 77</TIMEX> and ailing with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>,
will retire right after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first of the year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's continuing front-page deconstruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> today
looks at his schoolboy days in the Fellowship of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Athletes</ENAMEX>. The story
quotes intimates as saying that as late as senior year at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
was considering becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> tells the paper he has no
recollection of this. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> column, says
that in his most recent debate performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> supported "the holy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trinity</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and soft money."

         
      
   
