
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and Race
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>,

            Re our discussion of the function of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Clarke Duncan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> : I agree with you about his presentation as an
embodiment of mistaken southern rape fantasies. My description of his function
in the film was just that, a description, not a defense. I intended to convey
more or less the same thing you conveyed, that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> was yet another
example of a movie's black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> functioning as the absolver of white pain
and guilt.

            I think movies work in mysterious ways, however, and if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Green</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mile</ENAMEX> reaches a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, not all of them, perhaps not most of them,
will share the sophistication of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this discussion. Most people
just go to a movie. They react to the story on levels they do not articulate to
themselves. It may be that for some of them, the scene where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coffey</ENAMEX> heals
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">warden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will play in a positive way. They will think (not in so many
words) that appearances are misleading, that you can't judge a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> by your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prejudices</ENAMEX>, that it is wrong to fear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffey</ENAMEX> just because of his
imposing physical presence.

            The fact is, of course, that the moment the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coffey</ENAMEX> character and his
story are established, we know without any question or additional exposition
that he did not assault and murder the two little white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, because no
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movie of this sort would ever present an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> character
in such a light. By and large, when black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are presented as guilty in
films, it is only so that their innocence can be established, as a
demonstration of racist assumptions.

            We know that, but many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> will not. The film may work
on them like a useful parable. I think that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s intention in writing the
story, and would possibly be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darabont</ENAMEX>'s justification for the character.

            Has race so sensitized us that no black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> can appear in any movie
without being analyzed as a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>? I do not argue that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> of The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> should be colorblind: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coffey</ENAMEX> is obviously
presented as an imposing black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and that is one of the points of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is developed. I just say that if every black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> must
be passed through a prism of political correctness, that is not fair to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
Melvin the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimp</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liberty Heights</ENAMEX> made me
uncomfortable, and yet doubtless such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> existed at that time, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orlando Jones</ENAMEX> does a lively job with the performance, and if I am watching a
movie about a (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who runs a numbers game, is it not possible one of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> might be like this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re Magnolia</ENAMEX> : I did get the idea you were discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>'
reactions at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX> screening, not their post-mortem at another
screening. I was told, however, that there was laughter and derision at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Magnolia</ENAMEX> screening. And also at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>.

            But let me ask you: Do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> should make their opinions known
publicly at a screening? My own feeling is that the film deserves its chance to
develop in the minds of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> before being defined in a tidal wave of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buzz</ENAMEX>. At film festivals, when I'm asked what I thought of a film I just saw, I
often reply, "I don't like to discuss them until I've written my review." I
have often violated that rule in private conversations, but try never to
publicly broadcast my opinion to my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> after a screening.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
