
   
   
      
         
            Swiss Miss

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s air-dropped leaflet warning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>'s
capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grozny: Leave</ENAMEX> or die. Everybody else except <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> fronts the ultimatum, and it
tops the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's front-page news box. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times goes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s announcement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> will
review its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda</ENAMEX> decision, the national requirement that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> inform criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> of their basic constitutional rights, including
the right to remain silent, before questioning them. The story is stuffed at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , off-leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and is fronted below the fold at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ,
which goes instead with an independent investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s findings that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 54,000</NUMEX> dormant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> bank accounts, in the aggregate worth as much as
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX>, contain funds linkable to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, many more accounts
worth much more money than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> ever previously acknowledged. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> found no clear evidence of a conspiracy by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to steal
money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>, but they also cite their "deceitful actions."
No one else fronts the story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> are canceling domestic flights at a pace that will likely lead to
the highest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> percentage of scratches in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX>. While the
story cites maintenance and labor strife as contributing causes, it quotes one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airline</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> as saying that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of cancellations can be blamed on
bad weather and air traffic control problems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> with the lowest
cancellation rate: at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1 percent</NUMEX>, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>
are giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> (the other papers give
slightly varying numbers) until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thereafter</ENAMEX>, those who remain
will be declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, subject to massive shelling and bombing. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says there's little doubt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> can
follow through on their threat. The papers report that in response, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> not to follow through, saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will
"pay a heavy price" otherwise, without really specifying further.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ably explains
what's at issue in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda</ENAMEX>
case: whether with the original ruling, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Court</ENAMEX> was establishing a
rule of constitutional law or merely expressing its own preference for a method
of enforcing the constitutional right against compelled self-incrimination. If
the latter, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could overrule the method, which would mean that a
little-noticed alternative interpretation of how to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> against
self-incrimination buried in a bill passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> is in fact the law of the
land. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs both an editorial and an op-ed
piece urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s validation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Miranda</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> both off-lead the guilty verdict returned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by a
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SabreTech Inc.</ENAMEX> for mishandling hazardous
materials linked to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> crash of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ValuJet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
Everglades that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all 110</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such finding
in connection with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> air accident. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">SabreTech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were acquitted
in the case already.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SabreTech</ENAMEX>'s parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> now faces fines and
restitution payouts. State murder and manslaughter charges are next.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> uses its later
close time to file a front-pager on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' debate last
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>. This was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> ramp-up that the aspirants
could question each other, but, the paper notes, the discussion remained
"mostly amicable and genteel." The paper highlights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>'s
observation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> that with only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, he needs
more experience before becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--such as first being the vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            The business <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> report that the newly created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon Mobil Corp.</ENAMEX> has revoked a
prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> policy and will no longer provide health-care coverage to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> of new gay hires or to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> of current gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.
Several gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are responding with outrage.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front-page "cover
story" makes the observation that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> continue to work on the Y2K
problem, they face considerable non <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-Y2K</ENAMEX> computer
glitches. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports these commonplace troubles cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 billion</NUMEX>
annually in lost productivity.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Corrections</ENAMEX> :
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX> erred in saying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> LAT story had no information about the legal immunity enjoyed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. It did in fact say they are shielded from libel or slander
lawsuits based on remarks made in congressional debate and in official
reports.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that at the
opening of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s first media briefing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, she told the assembled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that they keep her on her toes and that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> is
reflected best around this table." Then, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> proceeded to give a "no comment" answer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> times. You
need a spreadsheet to keep track of all the grotesqueries in another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> item. "Reliable Source" quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gridiron Club</ENAMEX> gala comment about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX>: "I'm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">praying</ENAMEX>, of course, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> will win. If she doesn't--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, I'll have to
call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX> again."

         
      
   
