
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Performances</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear Everyone,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>'s entry captured it perfectly: From <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute to minute</TIMEX> in the movies
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, you didn't know what was going to happen next; you couldn't spot the
formula, because there wasn't a formula in sight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>, I'd really like to
explore your comparison of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999 and 1974</TIMEX>. That fabled year has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mythologized</ENAMEX> so much. Did you feel, at the time, like the movies had more in
common than just sharing in a sudden outburst of creativity? I'm asking because
I wonder if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s highlights, wildly disparate as they are (from the
slickly commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toy Story 2 to the uncompromising Boys</ENAMEX> Don't
Cry ) don't have some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> in common--the way, looking back, we can see
that some of the great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early-'70s</TIMEX> films took messed-up, naive, hypocritical
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> as a theme.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, I agree with you about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chloë Sevigny</ENAMEX>, and thank you, too, for
singling out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese Witherspoon</ENAMEX>, playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pathological goody-goody</ENAMEX> in
Election , as one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best performances; your description of
her leaps and bounds brought back images that match any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> for
memorability: the scene where she's alone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>, bouncing higher than
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pogo</ENAMEX> stick, her feet kicked way back behind her in unison as she leapt. (I
know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have tried to imitate this upon leaving the theater.) Also the
freeze-frame on her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>, her hand waving in the air like a
tentacle, her eye-lid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> closed, her lips moving into position for that grin
that wants to ingratiate but looks like a grimace. It's hard to write about
this performance, because it's so natural that it looks tossed off, and
especially because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witherspoon</ENAMEX>, quite deliberately, doesn't put across much
presence --compared with an old-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, or a technical wizard like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>, she seems kind of small. But if you think of her as representing
a whole new style, a generous style, a kind of post-narcissism, she looks
pretty great. She's quite real but at the same time abstract, almost cartoony;
she's loose and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-associative</ENAMEX> but attentive, above all, to the needs of the
story.

            Also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, sorry for the slam on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Park</ENAMEX> . You could be right that
a packed, whooping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> would have helped. But you know, I reserve my right
to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Park</ENAMEX> phenomenon a little toxic; I can't cut it too
much slack because I don't sense <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as much going on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> as you do. I
mean, forget about art. Can it really be that difficult to write a song called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kyle's Mom Is a Bitch?</ENAMEX>" I bet any number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> reading this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> could
do as well or better.

            All best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
