
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Annual Joseph Heller Memorial Cliché Contest</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the great contributions of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Heller</ENAMEX> was his understanding of how ideas and
phrases get repeated with mindless reverence in bureaucratic cultures. This is
especially true in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX> lampooned in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good As Gold</ENAMEX> ,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his minor novels (let's face it, aside from Catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> , they were
all minor). Repetition of meaningful phrases (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX>'s own coinage,
"catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>") tends to drain them of meaning. But it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX>'s special insight
that the ideas and phrases that make the most attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for
Washingtonspeak start out by containing almost no meaning at all . From
Good as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX> , here is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce Gold</ENAMEX>, a middle-aged
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, being recruited by phone for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> job by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Newsome</ENAMEX>, a chipper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>, wait, for Chrissakes!" It was in self-defense that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold</ENAMEX>
protested. "You're boggling my mind."
               

               "What was that?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX> asked in surprise.

               "You're boggling my mind."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>, that's a good phrase," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX> cried crisply. "Damned good. I don't
think I've ever heard boggle used with an animate subject before. I'll bet all
of us down here can start getting mileage out of that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right away. That is,
of course, if you don't mind letting us have it."

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>--"

               "Excuse me a minute, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>. I want to get it down exactly the way you said
it. How did it go?"

            

            Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX> was published, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has become
more of a rhetorical echo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> than ever. Remember how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> loosed
"the devil is in the details" on political discourse? A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> cliché even
emerged to praise mindless conformity: "singing from the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">songsheet</ENAMEX>."

            To honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX>'s passing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to nominate the top
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> rhetorical cliché for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. All nominations should be sent to
chatterbox@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and not
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>. Nominations should contain specific citations, preferably with Web
links, showing when and where the cliché was uttered. Whoever can come up with
the most citations for a suitably inane phrase will win. Newly hatched clichés
that are not confined to public-affairs discourse (e.g., "the new new thing,"
widely borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> book) are
ineligible. So are folksy evergreens such as "That <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> won't hunt." Please
submit entries by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 25</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
