
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coffee</ENAMEX>, and the Obituaries
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>,

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, quite literally, the first thing I turn
to, after scanning the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , is the obituaries. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had a prurient interest in these, such as those who went to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> of the thuggish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Cohn</ENAMEX> to make sure that he
was dead. But nowadays, so many of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> are
going--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past months</TIMEX>--that I turn to those pages
with what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kierkegaard</ENAMEX> called "the concept of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dread</ENAMEX>."

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> I read in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> of the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niccolo Tucci</ENAMEX>, at
age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">91</TIMEX>. I had not thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucci</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. He had come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
just before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> cultural attaché, and a fascist. A
fascist? Yes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> forget, or most never knew, that in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fascism</ENAMEX> was a powerful intellectual movement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> had been a prominent
left-wing socialist and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. Marinetti, the founder
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">futurism</ENAMEX>, was a fascist. As were the modernist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luigi</ENAMEX>
Pirandello, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">d'Annunzio</ENAMEX>, and the major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gentile</ENAMEX>, who influenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collingwood</ENAMEX> and was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of education in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucci</ENAMEX> had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follower</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentile</ENAMEX>, but broke with
fascism during the war and became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Macdonald</ENAMEX>'s circle around
Politics , where I met him. He had a tart wit.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, when I was managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common</ENAMEX>
Sense (my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varian Fry</ENAMEX>, who had returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> after saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">countless</ENAMEX> lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> by arranging for their exit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vichy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> and then to safer havens), I had asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucci</ENAMEX> to
write a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> column. On what? He asked. Oh, I replied, on, say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Travels to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." Strange <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, he said. Why do they call this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>? It was the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amerigo Vespucci</ENAMEX>). Why not Vespuccia? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fine</ENAMEX>, I said, we
can call it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Travels in Vespuccia</ENAMEX>," and you can write about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Daughters</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vespuccian Revolution</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vespuccian Legion</ENAMEX> march down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. He
did not. It reminded him too much of fascism.

            There are, or have been, strong differences between obituaries in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> press. Those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> are usually dry
and thin and fail to catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Those in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> are often quite personal and written at times by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the
individual. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Massingberd</ENAMEX> published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth</ENAMEX>
Volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obituaries</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> ! Obituaries are history. Yet
the times are changing. Witness the long obituary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Heller</ENAMEX> in the
Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, beginning with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> columns on the front page and
continuing, after the jump, to almost a full page inside.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the older arts of homage has been poetry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Lord Tennyson</ENAMEX>
published "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Memoriam AHH</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a hundred</NUMEX> verses of elegy and sorrow for
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Henry Hallam</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.H. Auden</ENAMEX> published "In Memory of W.B.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>" (d. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan., 1939</TIMEX>):

            
               He disappeared in the dead of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>;
The brooks were frozen, the air-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> almost deserted,
And snow disfigured the public statues; ...
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> of his death was a dark cold day.
            

            Yeats, of course, wrote his own "death poem":

            

               Under bare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Bulben</ENAMEX>'s head
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Drumcliff</ENAMEX> churchyard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX> is laid ...
On limestone quarried near the spot
By his command these words are cut!

               

                  
                     Cast a cold eye
On life, or death.
Horseman, pass by!
                  

               

            

            For us, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, the eulogy is not literary but religious. In going each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX>, we place a stone on the monument, in commemoration of the
acts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel</ENAMEX> in giving praise to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>. But the most affecting
act is the kaddish , the statement of mourning that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> says on the
death of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. It is haunting its recurring refrain, and keeps pulsing
through my mind, now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. I think of my close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Hofstadter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel Trilling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Hook</ENAMEX> ... They are now part of history.

            But the breakfast is finished, and here is the rest of the cold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> ahead
...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dad</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
