
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drama</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gifted VP</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>'s vote of confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>'s peace
negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, set to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> flags the story at the top of its
world-wide news box. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with a study released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> showing that
the insurance costs of businesses are rising--at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly three</NUMEX> times the rate of
inflation--but because of the tight labor market, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are absorbing most
of the added costs. In fact, says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' contributions to their
insurance coverage dropped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. The top non-local story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times is one that led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Surgeon General</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> regarding the surprising prevalence of mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and
the alarmingly low rate of treatment.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead's headline emphasizes the closeness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> vote, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says is far from the strong victory <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>
expected, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's stresses that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> is making it clear to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> that he is willing to cede the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX> back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> in return for security guarantees. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that the
diplomatic development has provoked "shouting matches, shock and hope among
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>, as well as a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> rise in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX> stock market." The paper
explains that the next internal political hurdle is a referendum on territorial
withdrawal. This, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , will be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s history.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> may bring in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> for the campaign over that.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s pronouncement--prompted by the publicity
surrounding that conviction of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for murdering a gay fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s "don't ask, don't tell" policy
should be abandoned. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> calls this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s "sharpest public break" yet
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policies and says that it represents a change from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">position Gore</ENAMEX> had been taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as this past weekend</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> aides
differ, saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> is just now reiterating a stand he's taken inside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign noted that with
his shift, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has just arrived at the position <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has been espousing for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reminds that this controversy underscores the importance
of the gay vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> politics but could cause difficulties for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in the general election.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s statement comes as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> ordered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
investigation to determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> in uniform are being harassed.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts that investigation and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s stance as does USAT .
The investigation raises a question that is only lightly touched on by the
papers: How can it work without violating the current policy wholesale? After
all, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> can't ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> if they are being harassed for being
gay without in effect "asking" them if they're gay, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> can't tell an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> that he is being harassed for being gay without "telling" the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> that he is gay.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> inside story reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX> has decided to abandon
its proscription of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> in the service in favor of a policy that will
ban all on-duty sex but not care about sexual orientation.

            The fronts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> feature obits for
Catch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Heller</ENAMEX>, who died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 76</TIMEX> of a heart
attack. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> remember to get past the famous war book's humor to
also include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX>'s overwhelming depiction of the death of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snowden</ENAMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> note that later on in his career,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heller</ENAMEX> wrote for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McHale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> .

            An inside story at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that the outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms</ENAMEX> says he thinks the prime suspect in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Atlanta Olympics</ENAMEX> bombing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Rudolph</ENAMEX>, is dead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATF</ENAMEX>'s
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s Most Wanted lists, hasn't been sighted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes inside with word that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and some
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have collectively contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> to a private fund
for making improvements to the vice presidential official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. (The story is based on a
report coming out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Public Integrity</ENAMEX>.) Gifts include a
billiard table, a hot tub, and landscaping. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Donors</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> (not
subject to the usual <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> limit because the money at issue was spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>) such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, and a tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exec</ENAMEX>. Corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Richfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>
Worldcom, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The story doesn't mention it, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have issues of tremendous financial consequence currently being
considered by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> serves up the late-breaking bulletin that online chat
has bred a new cluster of acronyms such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMHO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOL</ENAMEX>. And the paper was
fortunately able to get a minute with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kraut</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Mellon</ENAMEX>
University to get his explanation that it's very natural for human beings to
shorten words. Kraut, by the way, or so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> informs, is "professor
of social psychology and human-computer interaction" there. Where's an acronym
when you really need one?

         
      
   
