
   
   
      
         
            Foreign Entanglements
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>:

            Nice point about the lack of scandals in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> press, at least the
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> we read. We were abroad for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month in September</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, but
I do not recall the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> press featuring the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorce</ENAMEX> case, and the revelation that he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> for almost as long--or
was it longer?--than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was succored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Could it be
that there are fewer scandals, or is it that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> feel that they have gone overboard in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>?

            By contrast, almost all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>--let alone <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>--are full of stories about scandal and
corruption, and some of these make the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> stories, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>,
pale by comparison. What is extraordinary is how scantily this is written about
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> press.

            Take the story in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> that has been running for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two weeks</TIMEX> and
more--the revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Archer</ENAMEX>, the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX>
parliamentary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX>, who had announced his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> candidacy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, was shown to have lied and covered up a liaison with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News of the World</ENAMEX> , a paper that specializes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sleaze</ENAMEX>, had paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Francis</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14,000 pounds</NUMEX> to reveal that he
had given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> a false alibi in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Star</ENAMEX> accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> of marital infidelity with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Couglan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
disclosed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> had persuaded him to write a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Archer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> falsely stating that they had had dinner that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> had
altered his diary to show a meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> had sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Star</ENAMEX> and
won <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a million pounds</NUMEX> in the libel case. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> is disgraced and faces the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> of even going to jail for perjury and conspiracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hague</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, has egg all over his face.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, it has now been charged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> had secret campaign
funding accounts. All this emerged from an investigation of a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>-deutsche-mark cash donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Democratic Party</ENAMEX> by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX> arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krakheinz Schreiber</ENAMEX>.

            The most vehement accusations have been surfacing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>. There is new
speculation that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Andre Cools</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy prime minister</ENAMEX> who was shot
dead in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> as he left his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>'s flat in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liege</ENAMEX>, was about to expose
corruption in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. A trial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> had convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy Claes</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
other ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walloon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flemish</ENAMEX> socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> of channeling
bribes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> funds into their own bank accounts.

            I suppose where these stories merge with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> scene--leaving out the
other sex scandals, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, being
forced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> to choose between his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, as he was at
an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> ready to fly off with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> (and he finally chose her,
leaving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, later, to write a bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> account of their life)--is
with the problem of campaign funding. We have had detailed exposés of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Lincoln</ENAMEX>-bedroom sales, but nothing as lurid as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> tales. But
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last note, the failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> press to give much play to these
stories. Is it that these names are unfamiliar to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>? Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX>'s novels, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Among Equals</ENAMEX> , and I think you have
probably read them all, for relaxation--have sold extremely well here. So why
has the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> press, or even 
                  Slate
                for that matter, neglected
this reportage?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dad</ENAMEX>

            P.S.. If we had "newsbreaks" in this correspondence, I would report the
headline in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bishop's Wife Runs Away</ENAMEX>
With a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vicar</ENAMEX>." The title, of course, would be, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trollope</ENAMEX> might say, "There
will always be an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
