
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curfew Legal</ENAMEX>?
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Schell</ENAMEX> imposed an overnight curfew on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the second night</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> threatened to arrest
anyone who ventured into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> without "legitimate business." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> plans
to contest the action in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Is this curfew legal?

            Like most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> has municipal laws that grant the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> broad
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> powers"--the authority to take the actions necessary to protect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and their property. (Similar powers are granted to other chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.) In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> may declare a state of emergency and/or impose a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">curfew</ENAMEX> whenever he believes that "extraordinary measures [are needed] to
prevent the death or injury of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> and to protect the public peace, safety,
and welfare, and alleviate damage, loss, hardship or suffering."

            Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schell</ENAMEX>'s curfew is found to be consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s
municipal laws (as most agree it will be), it could still be challenged in
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> on the grounds that it violates constitutional rights, such as
free speech. Typically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> defer to the judgment of the executive branch
during the event--that is, they would be unlikely to grant an injunction
preventing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> from enforcing its curfew while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is in town.
Instead, cases are brought after the fact that seek either monetary damages
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or a court order barring similar action in the future.

            These instances--when public safety and fundamental rights
conflict--comprise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the murkiest areas of constitutional law. There are
few cut-and-dry legal standards for determining which interest prevails. The
facts are weighed on a case-by-case basis. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">curfew</ENAMEX> is contested
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--which is all but inevitable--here are the major questions the judge
will have to decide:

            
               Were free speech rights violated? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> have deemed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sidewalks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> to be open forums for free speech--and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s action
clearly limited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX>' access to them. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have also
determined that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> can restrict expression to a reasonable time,
place, and manner. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> might argue that this is all its curfew did, since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> could simply go elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to hold their demonstrations
without interference. But since access to the desired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is part of free
speech, complainants could counter that restricting their location impinged on
their rights.

            
               Were continued protests likely to have led to unlawful conduct?
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have clearly held that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> activities cannot be
banned simply because prior similar activity led to violence--as they did in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. (For example, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX> verdict and
ensuing riots in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> concluded that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX> had acted improperly in ordering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to
disband all future protests.) However, if police have specific information
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about future lawbreaking</TIMEX> or reasonably believe that they would be been unable
to control an outbreak of violence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have sometimes allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Amendment rights to be temporarily curtailed.

            
               Was the prohibition content-based? Any law that prohibits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of
speech while allowing another is presumptively unconstitutional. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>,
the curfew banned from downtown everyone who said they intended to protest or
who lacked another reason for entering. Therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> might argue, it was
not content-based: Everyone was equally affected, regardless of his or her
cause. However, complainants could contend that in practice it was
discriminatory: It actually affected only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> who opposed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, and some reports suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> were barring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> based on
their style of dress.

            
               Could the same result have been accomplished by more limited means?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Governments</ENAMEX> are required to restrict speech and other rights as little as
possible. So, complainants would likely win a case if they could prove that the
city did not pursue another, less restrictive option. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> could contend
that nothing short of an outright ban on downtown demonstrations would have
both protected public safety and ensured that non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>) would be able go about their lawful business. And they could point
to their accommodation--which some have even suggested was too great--of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and the limited duration of the curfew. But other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have already publicly stated that the complete prohibition of
demonstrations and the large size of the area are both unconstitutionally
extreme.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prof.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart Jay</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington School</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prof.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eben Moglen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University School of Law</ENAMEX>.
            

            Next question?

         
      
   
