
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Polar Lander: Phone Home</ENAMEX>!

            The inauspicious landing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Polar Lander</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> to transmit a signal confirming that
it had touched down safely on the surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> has
flight-operation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> scurrying to make contact. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> story
but leads with good news from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">234,000</NUMEX> new jobs were
created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer hours</TIMEX>.

            The papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are disappointed but confident that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polar Lander</ENAMEX> will be re-established. Only the LAT
captures an appropriate nail-biting tone--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> are described as "anxious"
and "growing more glum by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX>." Assuming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lander</ENAMEX> didn't crash, the
radio silence could be due to a misalignment of the antenna or a malfunction
that caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> to go to sleep. If contact is re-established, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polar Lander</ENAMEX>, designed to search for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martian</ENAMEX> soil and collect
information about the planet's climate history, could help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> figure
out if life could have existed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>. The papers report that the
embarrassment factor of losing the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$165 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> is high. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> lost its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Climate Orbiter</ENAMEX>, which either crashed or skipped off into space
after a failure to convert navigational instructions from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> to metric
units sent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orbiter</ENAMEX> fatally close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Red Planet</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that the combination of job growth and the
relatively low rise in wage rate sent stocks soaring on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>: the Dow Jones
rose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">247.12</NUMEX> points and closed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,286.18</NUMEX>, not far below its all-time high of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,326.03</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , points out that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s
activity drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> to a new record. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> hailed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> report as a "milestone," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is quick to break down
the numbers for lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. In percentage terms the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 million</NUMEX> new jobs created
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January of 1993</TIMEX> represent a growth of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18 percent</NUMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s and 1980s</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> grew by greater percentage rates over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>--25 percent
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX>, respectively.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s increased shipments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and money to
terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in an apparent effort to interrupt the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-sponsored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> peace process. The news is particularly discouraging given the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration's overtures to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatemi</ENAMEX>, who is seen as
a "genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> with enormous popular support." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will continue to seek a dialogue with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khatemi</ENAMEX>, despite suspicions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> involvement in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> bombing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s order to stop the use of live-fire
ammunition in military-training exercises on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> island of
Vieques, dubbed the "crown jewel of live-fire, combined-arms training," by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of naval operations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which stuffs the story.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also promised to end exercises there within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
looks for a new training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports on its front, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
will exercise with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>-filled bombs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> has rejected the protracted pull-out plan as unacceptable: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rico</ENAMEX>, which has criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, reached its breaking point
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, when an errant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> killed a civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front stories about the wrap-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
meetings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stuffs the story. No longer just paying lip
service to the actual issues on the table, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
goal to eliminate export subsidies on farm products. It isn't clear, however,
exactly how much headway the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> made. According to the LAT the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>, our
main adversary in the debate, "agreed to consider eliminating export subsidies
... but apparently made no commitments on a timetable." According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> has agreed to talks that could "eventually eliminate
subsidies on farm goods." And according to the WP the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is still
holding out because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> "agrees only to talk about substantial reductions in
the subsidies." Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s emphasis on more open and less secretive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
proceedings would be of help the next time around?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the challenge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s new inspection methods by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> processing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that failed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> tests for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">salmonella</ENAMEX>
contamination in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX>. In its lawsuit the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> claims the government
doesn't have the authority to regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">salmonella</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">salmonella</ENAMEX> is
destroyed during "normal cooking" and is not a "public safety issue."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kudos</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Op-Ed</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX> warns that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>,
convinced that anyone could be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in the Internet age, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of
the consolidation of news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> into a handful of media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX>.
Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> questions some media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' "cheerleading" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>' This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> panelists touting the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Wants To Be a Millionaire</ENAMEX>? show
without mentioning it brings home the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX>), he singles out a certain Web
magazine for objectivity, suggesting it might gain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' loyalty with its
"not-in-the-tank coverage of its parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
