
   
   
      
         
            "Don't Ask" Don't Work

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s announcement (or admission) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s "don't ask,
don't tell" policy regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> isn't working. Rather
than implement a new policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is expected to push military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to
better enforce the current <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The statement was prompted by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s
remarks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> should be allowed to serve
openly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reefers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks and leads with
an expose on failings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s education system. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
special education maintains that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 250,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have been
incorrectly assessed as "learning disabled" and funneled into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s
special education programs simply because they were not taught to read. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s
warning that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> abroad should take extra security precautions in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> has "credible information" that terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are
planning attacks that target <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>, whose sources
are quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , reefers the announcement.

            Despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> headline, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> abroad needn't run for the hills
just yet. Such announcements are relatively common, although they usually
accompany military actions, economic sanctions, or other foreign policy
initiatives (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s warning was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>). The
Post suggests that the warnings are a reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s
terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, but the link is dubious: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> wouldn't name a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, they only "indicated that [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>] is the most important
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> seeking to undermine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also
points out that that attacks could occur any time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from now</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>,
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> holy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX> ends.
Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s announcement mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX>, or did the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> add it? Either way, someone seems to be equating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> and
terrorism without explaining why. And wouldn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> be less
likely, not more likely, to take terrorist action during a holy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the LAT front stories highlighting different
facets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> examines <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, where the
disease kills <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> and could kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 13,000</NUMEX> per day in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. The article stresses the economic ramifications of these statistics: In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>, projected GDP in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> may be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 20 percent</NUMEX> lower
than it would have been without the disease's effect on young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> article on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> emphasizes a more encouraging
trend--hospices once filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> dying from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> are emptying and
closing because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are getting better and leaving, a phenomenon
dubbed "the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Lazarus</ENAMEX> syndrome."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> points to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s too-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close</NUMEX>-to-call presidential race in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> as a sign that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s democratization has progressed since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> stepped down over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX>. The contest, which
includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>'s main right and left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, is expected to end in a run-off, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s history.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> special report examines <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fund-raiser <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry McAuliffe</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAuliffe</ENAMEX> is seen as a new breed of entrepreneurial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> who leverage
their services not to obtain cushy ambassadorial posts or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> clout but to
help fuel telecommunications, banking, and real-estate  business deals. They've
also helped fuel some lawsuits: "I've signed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of documents, but never
read them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McAuliffe</ENAMEX> remarks. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, who plans to relocate to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> steps down, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAuliffe</ENAMEX> plans
to stay active in politics and is already raising money for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bid.

            
               Now That's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synergy</ENAMEX>: Used to be that only movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> could use high-profile glossy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> to flog their product. Now, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports, tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are paying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Inc.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of dollars to generate magazines similar in look and feel to popular
twentysomething mags like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mademoiselle</ENAMEX>. The new
magazines, packed with tobacco ads, are an attempt to plug the "communication
gap" (as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX> memo puts it) created by independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, which
generally limit tobacco ads to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 2 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> of total ads. But
persistent rumors that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX> has signed on to star opposite Gwyneth Paltrow
in an upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Miramax</ENAMEX> police drama are just that.

         
      
   
