
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future Ain't What It Used To Be</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>,

            For as long as I can remember, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 25 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> have been
asking you to make predictions about the future. And you have always given an
answer along the lines of what you told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. It's
convincing, and sober, and intellectually responsible, and it frustrates them
to no end. Just once, perhaps, you should give them what they want. "Watch for
the invention of flying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>, which will drastically affect the course
of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War III</ENAMEX> when it breaks out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX>. There'll be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>.
And by the way, make sure to sell all your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> stock by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Wednesday</TIMEX>."

            More seriously, I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question for you about all of this, and one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">demurral</ENAMEX>. The question concerns patterns of technological change. As a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> have been noting recently, the future isn't what it used to be.
When I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, visions of the future were heavy on, yes, flying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mars colonies</ENAMEX> and the like. Everyone was confidently predicting that by the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2000</TIMEX> the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> would be well on its way to settling the solar system,
while at home we'd be casually buzzing from continent to continent in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>,
and the robot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> took care of cleaning the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.

            These seemed reasonable enough predictions, actually, given the pace of
change up till then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20 th century</TIMEX>. It's hard to believe that
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just 66 years</TIMEX>, less than a lifetime, we went from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilbur</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville Wright</ENAMEX>
on the beach at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kitty Hawk</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Armstrong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz Aldrin</ENAMEX> on the moon. 66
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>! If that pace of change had continued, I would probably have been sending
you this e-mail from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX> orbit. But it didn't continue. In fact, it's hard
not to think that in a lot of areas, technological change has slowed to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crawl</ENAMEX>, with incremental improvements around the edges, but no great leaps
forward. We are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>, and have gone from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moon</ENAMEX> landing to
... the space shuttle. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years ago</TIMEX> we were flying on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">747s</TIMEX>, and now we are
flying on ... literally the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, at least,
transport by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and train is mostly slower than it was then (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> are one
area in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> have beaten us hands down--if we had their high-speed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, you could come down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> to see your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> with a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> train ride, instead of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven-plus</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX>
currently takes). The same is true of other sectors: generation of energy
(where we've stepped back from nuclear power), and even, with the exception of
computer-guided bombs and the like, weaponry. Where are the stun <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistols</ENAMEX> and
blast rays we were supposed to be using by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>? (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> has missed
out on a great slogan here. "Personal blast rays don't destroy whole city
blocks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> destroy whole city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX>.")

            But on the other hand, obviously, some technological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> have been
holding to the same, incredible pace of change that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aeronautics</ENAMEX> went through
earlier: information technology and biotechnology, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost. Why is
this? And how does it relate to the broader structural changes in the economy
that you talked about in your message?

            Here's my demurral. Is there really such a thing as "primordial identities,"
in the way you suggest? This is certainly what the present-day nationalists
would like us to think. They would like us to imagine that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX>, every
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> put her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to bed whispering, "We must put up with this
regime for now. But someday, someday, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> will awake!" I'm sure some of them
were doing exactly that, but lots of others adjusted just fine to the communist
regime. It was only when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> collapsed that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saw an
advantage for themselves in highlighting ethnic and linguistic differences, and
in, not so much resurrecting eternal, unchanging, primordial identities so much
as creating new identities based on the old myths and loyalties. And I think
they would probably abandon these new identities easily enough if it suited
them. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> could vote freely and had the choice between
possession of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, which do you think
they would choose?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
