
   
   
      
         
            <I>Kausfiles</I> Drills Down!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Maybe</ENAMEX>: Remember <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 227</ENAMEX>, the initiative by which (in
theory) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> threw out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s disastrous bilingual education
program and replaced it with "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> immersion"? For an excellent, maddening
report on how anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227</NUMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> are
defying the law and continuing to teach "limited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>,
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Stewart</ENAMEX>'s recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Times Los Angeles</ENAMEX> account. ... The question
begged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>'s story is: Isn't it time for some pro-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to sue to
get that law enforced? As it is, the main lawsuit on the table in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
is being brought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Defense and Education Fund</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALDEF</ENAMEX>), which is trying to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to enter into a
semi-collusive "consent decree" that will effectively undermine English
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immersion</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> describes this possible sellout to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALDEF</ENAMEX> here. ... Those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> that really do try <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">immersion</ENAMEX>,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>, have seen rising test scores. They include <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>,
Inglewood, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oceanside</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> for some national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> to pay them a visit, no? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rene</ENAMEX>
Sanchez, this means you! ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader Nails</ENAMEX>: 
               Kausfiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael S. Nadel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, had this reponse to the previous
item, which concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>'s investigation of congressional sex
"served <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> well" by possibly helping to cow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
(who was at the time have a risky affair with a congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>):

            

               How did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s silence "serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> well"? Wouldn't having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> as his
main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">antagonist</ENAMEX> have helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? He would have had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> even better than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>--even without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bisek</ENAMEX> affair in the public eye.

            

            Good question! Here <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possible answers: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s low-turnout,
put-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">em</NUMEX>-to-sleep strategy for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election was a disaster, which in turn
encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to acquit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. A different, more
active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> election strategy might have worked better, but it might also
have required that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> take a higher profile (and, inevitably, attack
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bet</ENAMEX> if you'd asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 1998</TIMEX> whether
they'd rather have an unencumbered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> or a subdued <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, they would
have picked the latter--even if, in hindsight, that might have been a mistaken
calculation.

            
               A 
               plea to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>: Please, please stop calling the old
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fairfax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel</ENAMEX>, where the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> lived, a "luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>," as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few nights ago</TIMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> took a vacation to
see the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> sights, we stayed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax</ENAMEX>, because (we were told) it
was the cheapest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in town. I remember it as a decent, shabby old
thing--not a fleapit, but nothing that attempted to be in any way sybaritic. My
mother remembers that we got a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> for something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14</NUMEX> a day. ...
Only much later, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> long gone, was the building refurbished and
turned into an overpriced luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, once part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, now called
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Peters</ENAMEX> made this very point in his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tilting at Windmills"</ENAMEX> column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Monthly</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last May</TIMEX>, but to no avail. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX> even pointed out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax</ENAMEX> was
so affordable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Greenfield</ENAMEX> lived there as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. ...

            
               Yent-a-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matic</ENAMEX> update : A recent
edition of the authoritative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Yent-a-Matic</ENAMEX> paired up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Torricelli</ENAMEX>, the
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arianna Huffingon</ENAMEX>, the publicity-seeking bleeding-heart conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>. As far as I know, this high-potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">matchup</ENAMEX> has not yet been
realized. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX> is going out with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundette</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>
Ingraham, which is about as close as you can get to going out with Arianna
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffington</ENAMEX> without going out with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kausfiles</ENAMEX> still
contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli-Huffington</ENAMEX> is inevitable, sort of like globalization,
or the collapse of communism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. ... No point trying to fight history,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>! ...

         
      
   
