
   
   
      
         
            Sense and Inessentiality
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>,

            That was a lovely letter. A long time ago you talked to me about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
obituaries, and since then, when I've had time, I've tried to read the obituary
page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> . After getting your message, I went back to
it on the Web, and saw again what you mean about the differences from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obits</ENAMEX>. Here's something from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, from a short notice written by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poet P.J. Kavanagh</ENAMEX> about his late brother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milford</ENAMEX>: "He could not
help having a creative laugh: unfeigned, joyous, it made you feel much funnier
than you thought you were, which is among the kindest of social gifts." I can't
imagine an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> printing an obituary with a sentence like this,
which might certainly help get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> through a cold day. There's a certain
delight in the inessential things in life which is one of the most pleasant
things about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> (and also <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>) culture. I suppose it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poetry</ENAMEX> remains so much more of a vital force in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> than in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, for what is poetry if not inessential?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, of course, doesn't seem to have much time for the inessential.
His <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> has to be dynamic, forward-thrusting, fully charged. In this, he
resembles no one so much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>, whose attitude toward the
inessential was one of brusque, snarling contempt. Speaking as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>,
this trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> politics is something I deplore, and my opinion has only
been strengthened by reading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mortimer</ENAMEX> (of Rumpole
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> fame), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> , which have
made a fetish out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> attitude toward inessential things. Long live
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fox</ENAMEX>-hunting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">High Table</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Tea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guards</ENAMEX> and public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>! But as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, I can't
resist remarking that the cultivation of the inessential is a trademark of
aristocratic societies (aristocrats deliberately spend their time on trifles to
show that they can , and others can't), and that as charming as it
appears to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> are unlikely to be so
well disposed, since the burden of the aristocracy falls on their shoulders.
And having seen one of the famous public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> at rather too close quarters
back when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your sabbatical year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, I think that if I
were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, I'd be more likely to approach those charming and inessential
aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> society with a box of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX> than with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> 's pious reverence (and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speccie</ENAMEX> in particular,
you'll remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Buruma</ENAMEX>'s devastating account of the place in his book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglomania</ENAMEX> ).

            But back to the news. The most amusing thing I saw in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> yesterday
was that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> legally named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DotComGuy</ENAMEX> (formerly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitch Maddox</ENAMEX>), is going to
move into an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> carrying only a credit card on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1</TIMEX> and not leave
again for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire year</TIMEX>, relying exclusively on the Internet for furniture,
food, services and entertainment. His Web site claims that he will spend the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> "living inside the Internet," as if this were some great foray into new
and unexplored regions of cyberspace. Talk about being behind the curve! I
think the real challenge for a currently employed middle-class professional
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would be to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> living entirely outside the Internet: no
e-mail, no eToys or E*<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MP3s</ENAMEX> or game demos, no online banking
or selection of benefits through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> intranet, not to mention, of
course, no 
                  Slate
               . I don't think I'd survive for more than a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> (which is why your daughter-in-law, alas, once referred to herself as a
"wwww", for "world wide web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>"). You may have a different opinion, not
being anywhere near as much a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> of the Web as I am. But then again,
here you are, in 
                  Slate
               : the public intellectual as content
provider for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
