
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Wobbles</ENAMEX> but He <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doesn't Fall Down</ENAMEX>
            

            Prudie,

            Even if you're not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Oil of Olay</ENAMEX> model--and I find that hard to believe--I
would hope that you would never be caught farther than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 feet</NUMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Car</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX> I hope to return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of divorce and manners and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>.
But this installment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX> is more like a nightcap. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX>'s
post-debate spin session spilled over into the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, and that's where I am
just returning from. So forgive me if I am sparing in my recounting of the
action.

            Most top-drawer political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> decided to sit this debate out. For
this, I am thankful. Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> desperate to spin had nobody else to
chat up. (Of course, dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, it would have been far more pleasurable to be
sitting in my hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and dashing off mail to you.)

            There seemed a consensus, to which even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> couldn't really refute
with a straight face: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> looked truly wobbly. Not that he did himself any
sort of long-term damage. But he seemed to be unsure with his responses. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> penalized him for it. As he coughed out answers or recycled lines
from the stump speech, some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nice Republicans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> actually
laughed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> watching the debate on TV in a remote location weren't so
kind.

            A final note. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> worked like hell to avoid engaging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>
in conflict and conversation. This seemed to piss him off even more. Afterward,
he was heard muttering something about being an "invisible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massa Frank</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
