
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, Harasser

            So far, there have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct phases to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign. In the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phase, which lasted until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early autumn</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> high-handedly ignored the
fellow running against him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primaries. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> phase,
which lasted until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-November</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> shook up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, welcomed Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s exciting challenge, and began responding to it as a vigorous
competitor. Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign has now entered a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, much more
aggressive phase, in which he nips too eagerly at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s ankles and attempts
to bury his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> under a mountain of inconsistent and often spurious
charges.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has passed up no opportunity to whack <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. He has
criticized him over the cost of his health-care plan, its consequences for a
variety of different minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, for his past positions on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, for his lack of a position on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, and even for not saying
whether he would reappoint <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>--a decision that will belong to the
current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, not the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. As my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Saletan</ENAMEX> recently
argued in a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>"
column, there's nothing wrong with negative campaigning per se. But if some of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s criticisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> are fair, others are totally unfair, and all are
part of a transparent effort to keep his opponent on the defensive. It's
obnoxious political behavior. So why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore baiting Bradley</ENAMEX> like a schoolyard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bully</ENAMEX>?

            You can get a better sense of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is doing by looking closely at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
of his latest onslaughts, over the largely phony issue of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
intends to raise taxes. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> sat down for an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . Asked what he
would do if his health-care plan required a tax increase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reasonably</ENAMEX> responded that he doesn't believe it will require a tax increase,
but that if it does, his options would include cutting other spending or
raising taxes, and that he would make a judgment at the time. He was doing what
any wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> does, which is refusing to indulge a hypothetical
question--though even his non-answer was more than he should have said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s response looked like a juicy patch of exposed flesh for his crazed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pit bull</ENAMEX> of a rival. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> stated
he would be willing to raise taxes to pay for his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion-dollar</NUMEX> health-care
plan," said a press release sent out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3</TIMEX>. "That
might be his worst idea yet."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s comments was unfair. Though various analyses
have suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health-care plan may require more funding than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has yet acknowledged in order to be effective, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has offered a
plausible plan to pay for his proposal out of projected budget surpluses. And
in his interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> didn't put forward raising taxes
as an "idea." He said that because he couldn't predict what would happen to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, it wouldn't be prudent to rule out raising taxes in the future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">categorically</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign answered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s tax-raising charge by pointing out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> have essentially the same position on future tax increases.
Neither thinks raising taxes will be necessary to pay for their own various
initiatives, including health-care reforms. Nor has either of them made a
read-my-lips pledge not to raise taxes under any circumstances (and indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, campaigning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, specifically declined to make such a
pledge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>). In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign might have gone much further in
pointing out the disingenuousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s attack. Having campaigned with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on a middle-class tax cut in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore reversed</ENAMEX> himself and supported
a (necessary) tax increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has supported tax increases
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as this year</TIMEX>. Also, it just seems crazy for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to
start demanding "no new taxes" pledges from other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Then again,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are now charging each other with endangering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, which suggests that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has to some extent been brainwashed by
the other's propaganda.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s mild rebuttal provided an opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to slam him even
harder. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s zigs and zags over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX> raise questions
about his steadiness as a possible steward of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Lehane</ENAMEX> said in his next release, dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 6</TIMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> he says
he'll consider new taxes to pay for his flawed, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion-dollar</NUMEX> health-care
plan. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> he says he didn't really mean it. ... These are confusing
enough messages from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. Just think what those statements would
do to the markets if they came from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>." And in a subsequent press
release issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>, entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can</ENAMEX> We Trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> To Keep the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy Strong?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehane</ENAMEX> added: "Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s statements
raise questions as to whether or not he has the vision and the experience to
keep the economy strong." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> repeated these charges in person at an
appearance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University Law School</ENAMEX>, where he received an
endorsement from former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
of "proposing" a tax increase and described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s approaches to
the economy as "if it ain't broke, let's break it."

            The unfairness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s accusations escalates in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
attempts to defend himself. Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s position on tax increases is
reasonable or not, he clearly hasn't zigzagged on the subject. He's been
entirely consistent. But a near-universal assumption in politics says that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has to respond to charges made by serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, lest those
charges be generally accepted as true. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> once again answered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
accusation, this time by getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> with credibility on economic
issues--former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Volcker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kaufman</ENAMEX>--to issue a
statement defending him. This prompted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign to put out yet another
release accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> of stonewalling and, somewhat bizarrely, of
"name-calling."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> seems to be assuming that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has to spend his time answering
such charges, he won't be able to get his "positive" message out. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stratagem</ENAMEX> is even more diabolical than that. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> explained to me,
the pepper<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-spray</ENAMEX> of criticism leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobson</ENAMEX>'s choice. Either he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ignores it, in which</ENAMEX> case the charges damage him, or he responds in kind, in
which case he diminishes his carefully cultivated reputation for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">high-mindedness</ENAMEX>. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> descends from his pedestal and begins trading
insults with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, he loses his aura of saintliness and becomes just another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scrapping politician</ENAMEX>.

            I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has quite figured out how to deal with this dilemma.
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Hauser</ENAMEX>, told me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s assault "is not changing
our strategy. It is not changing the dynamics of the race." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> himself
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that he is intent on running a positive campaign and that
he intends to shoot back only when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> hits him with something "outrageous."
What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to have banked on is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s accusing him of something
outrageous every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">few hours</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
