
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frat-Boy Charm</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo</ENAMEX>,

            Forevermore, I'll think of my glasses and you, dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>. There are so
many other matters for which I need your advice. But perhaps it is best that I
save them for a more private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>.

            On the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> cannot fully appreciate his appeal from television
debates and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-morning</TIMEX> interviews. These settings exaggerate his
weaknesses, and that may be a fatal flaw. But there's a reason he has raised
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65 million</NUMEX>. A whiff of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frat-boy</ENAMEX> charm is a powerful thing. Or in my case,
I got a whiff of his jockish charm. When I interviewed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, he had just
returned from a jog. (Actually, he doesn't really smell.) Approaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>, I heard a voice scream from the beyond the gates, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>." As the gates opened, there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, dripping with sweat
in shorts and T-shirt. "I got dressed up just for you." And then pointing a
finger at me, he joked, "My odor better be off the record." The next thing I
know, he's whisked me through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> of banter, offered me lunch, and has
me sitting out on the patio. Though I had spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> concocting a strategy for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teasing</ENAMEX> information out of him, he answered my toughest question nearly at the
start. None of his answers struck me as especially stupid or brilliant, but
rather they were rather convincingly earnest. This question on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> will hover over the campaign, I suspect, for the duration--a
matter that will be hashed over in many a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>.

            Finally, we should update <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> on a priceless headline from this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morning</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that has been a subject of much discussion
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> wrote, it was a "heart-wrenching story about a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who concealed the accidental death of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>,
leaving her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> in their home because he was afraid of being sent to an
orphanage, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes with the bad taste headline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Died</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kept Mum</ENAMEX>." For those who were
wondering, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> editions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> went with a more tasteful "Mother
Died, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kept Silent</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> has been a joy, dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glibness</ENAMEX> is really quite underrated.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jed Purdy</ENAMEX> be damned.) But it's back to my job as unironic newsmagazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>,
which has its virtues too. Many thanks. I'm missing you already.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massa H.</ENAMEX>

            
               Coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bell</ENAMEX> visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast</ENAMEX>
Table.
            

         
      
   
