
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debating Dubya</ENAMEX>'s Debut
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential debate. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> protests
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s performance was tepid and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">formulaic</ENAMEX>--these include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Birnbaum</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Ballot Box</ENAMEX>'s roundup, click here.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> )--the only pundit, liberal or conservative,
who doesn't seem to be pulling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>--scoffs at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>'s reaction,
noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> still has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-point lead in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> and remains the
most secure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> in "living memory." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
Late Edition ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ] make
similar points.)

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> won the debate, and many--like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>--appreciate his jokes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s
mortality and his own temper. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late Edition ] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> may actually have started the
"temper" rumors; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> notes that the issue allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> to pose as both a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of unfair innuendo and as a passionate war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> with fervently held
political beliefs.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> also praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>'s eloquence, though none
thinks the evangelical is a serious threat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> says that, according to
e-mails received at his Web
site, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> won the debate. (Suffice it to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' empirical
methods may be open to question; for more on his Web site, click here.)

            The commentariat splits on the merits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>--and not along ideological
lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gigot</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich Lowry</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> ) as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> )
as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour and Capital Gang</ENAMEX> )
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ). Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits flay President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for his "I-feel-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX>'-pain" comments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> notes that the
exactly marginal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clift</ENAMEX> acknowledges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
has done a poor job selling his free-trade stance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> points out
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has emerged as a stronger supporter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
free-trade policy than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> and both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlsons</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>--blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> for treating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> gloves
("a weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, I'm afraid, a kind of cappuccino sipper," jabs
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowry</ENAMEX> argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX>, who favor the imposition of
higher labor and environmental standards, actually want to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
more power. Free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, however, call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>
arrogant for its highhanded dismissal of the protests. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The Spin" and "Frame Game</ENAMEX>" also give their takes
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> demonstrations.)

            
               Election notes: On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> says he would not accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> vice presidential
nomination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) announces that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> will soon make joint campaign appearances, promising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
that if they are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> they will devote themselves to campaign finance
reform. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> also predicts a more aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> on the
horizon.) Appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition , This Week , and Meet</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, REF-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, speaks in favor of free trade,
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX> would be a viable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>,
and says he plans to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX> service).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jekyll</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s debate
performance a mixed verdict--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> inspired idealism and was sharp on foreign
policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> says, but his knowledge of domestic issues was weak and he
wasn't aggressive enough. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flatly</ENAMEX>, "I thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> bombed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>." Why the shift of
emphasis? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> suspects that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> holds a clue: The
NewsHour format permits a more leisurely, nuanced discussion, while on
Capital <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gang Shields</ENAMEX> has to moderate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> and probably
felt compelled to foil his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>' unstinting praise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
performance.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crumpets</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>?
            

            Question: Who is more out of place--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connecticut Yankee</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>'s
court or a courtly Brit * on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> ? To
give his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some</TIMEX> economic heft for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> discussion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> invites
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Thomson</ENAMEX>, to participate.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right Honorable Gentleman</ENAMEX> From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> seems astonished by the
whole, well, vulgarity of the debate. Every time the camera lands on
him, he is staring at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clift</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowry</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blankley</ENAMEX> with mouth agape,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX> silent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> even ribs his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> on his wardrobe (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomson</ENAMEX> is
wearing a dapper suit--with vest--and spectacles). Later in the program,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomson</ENAMEX> looks directly at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> and says, "Anybody with a temper [like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s] shouldn't have a distinguished position anyhow," to which the host
gives a knowing smile.

* See below.

         
      
   
