
   
   
      
         
            Present at the Creation

            Among the many things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has claimed credit for introducing to the
world is apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>. This is a refundable credit paid
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> to below-median-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> that has, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 25 years</TIMEX>,
swelled both in size and in the esteem with which it is held by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> alike.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have wrapped their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> around this sturdy reinforcement
for the efforts of ill-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, but few if any have been so fulsome in
their embrace as was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               Magazine . In commenting upon his
rival <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s proposed expansion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> asserted, "I was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of that proposal. I wrote that, so I say, welcome aboard. That is
something for which I have been the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> forces jumped on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">veep</ENAMEX>'s claim of authorship,
pointing out in an ad that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX> became law in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was
elected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            Who then can claim credit for this invention, which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> distributed
close to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> in refunds to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 20 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> knows because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> really was there--or at least close by.

            Just for the record, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX> was the brainchild of the powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Long</ENAMEX>. Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Long</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of Huey
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX>, the flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> immortalized in All the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Long</ENAMEX> was anathema to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, who
viewed him as the major roadblock in the way of a more generous welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
And, indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch opponent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family</ENAMEX>
Assistance Plan, which would have doubled the size of the welfare rolls by
extending cash assistance to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX>."

            Long didn't like the idea adding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the rolls, but he
wasn't at all adverse to the notion of giving poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a helping hand--as
long as it was done in a way that would encourage rather than discourage work.
So he asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Stern</ENAMEX>, to work out the details of a
plan that would do just that. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Stern</ENAMEX>, in turn, asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of hers from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Institute</ENAMEX> to help out. The final plan, which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance Committee</ENAMEX> reported out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, was remarkably generous--certainly more
generous than the welfare reform enacted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> of which both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> brag. It guaranteed a job to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> head
needing work. True, the wage in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> jobs was sub-minimum, so as not to
encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to abandon their private sector jobs for the perhaps less
demanding public sector. But to help out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working in poorly paid jobs,
Long came up with the idea of rebating their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> taxes as a "work
bonus."

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Stern</ENAMEX> was assigned to work out the details of how the EITC
would be computed, he insists the idea really was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX>'s. "He liked the
idea because it rewarded work," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>, who is now with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Investment</ENAMEX>
Company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Institute</ENAMEX>.

            The net cost of the plan was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $4.3 billion</NUMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>--big, big money in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> and more than a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> increase over
what the feds were then spending on welfare for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. As former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Rivlin</ENAMEX> noted at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, when she and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> were on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> together, if someone other than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Long</ENAMEX> had proposed this, they would have been acclaimed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. But
because it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX> product, it was branded by the press as "slavefare" and
went nowhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX> continued to press for the EITC part of his
plan, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, while the fight over welfare reform was still raging, it
quietly passed into law. So quietly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> apparently didn't notice
it.

         
      
   
