
   
   
      
         
            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Hunting</ENAMEX>!

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADMISSIONS PLUNGE AT U. OF CALIFORNIA FOR 3 MINORITIES</ENAMEX>." That was the
headline over the lead story in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX> edition of the New York
Times . A similarly disturbing message ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acceptance</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX> to UC
Plunges") topped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The figures did seem grim. At
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> campus, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the share of the three
"underrepresented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Indians</ENAMEX>--fell
from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23.1 percent</NUMEX> of admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.4 percent</NUMEX>. Black admissions
dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.CL</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> told us, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>'
share fell from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19.8 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.7 percent</NUMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX>. The
fears of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX>, which eliminated racial preferences in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, seemed to be coming true--despite the efforts
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to compensate for the end of race preferences by giving an edge
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who have overcome economic hardships. "This shows that economics
will not substitute for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore M. Shaw</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP Legal Defense Fund</ENAMEX>.

            But those were only the figures for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> UC <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX> in all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> who don't get into one campus
sometimes get into another one. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> after the release of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX> numbers, the university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> released the
figures for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC</ENAMEX> system. The news wasn't nearly as grim. The total for
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> fell, but only from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17.6 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15.4 percent</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> share of admissions fell, but only from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13.2</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.9 percent</NUMEX>. The
black share of admissions fell, but only from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.5 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.8 percent</NUMEX>--a
loss of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> over all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> campuses. Even that
number may be misleading, since it doesn't include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> who chose not to
check the optional box declaring their race. Indeed, the large increase in the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> declining to give their ethnic origin was one of the more
striking, and heartening, phenomena in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC</ENAMEX> admissions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stats</ENAMEX> (and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ignored in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX> story). University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> seem to believe
that these "decline to state" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are overwhelmingly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>,
but nobody knows for sure.

            The point isn't that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s set of numbers was wrong and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s was
right. Presumably they're both right: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> admissions fell most at
the most selective campuses. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> are now more concentrated at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC</ENAMEX>'s
less desirable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside</ENAMEX> campus (or its famously gorgeous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>),
that's news in itself. But there was no "plunge" in the overall UC figures, as
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX> headlines erroneously imply. ...

            And why couldn't both sets of figures have been released on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>?
Why release the "bad news" <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, then let the "good" news out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days later</TIMEX>
when it is sure to be buried under the wall-to-wall <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula-Jones</ENAMEX>-dismissal
coverage? Call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> paranoid--you won't be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>!--but could it be
that pro-preference university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> want to discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 209</ENAMEX> by
painting its consequences as more dire than they actually are? ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>
Lightfoot, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, denies any "motive to tell
a bad story." He says the release of admissions data has always been left up to
the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>, and it simply took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> to calculate the
overall university-wide figures once the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX> numbers became
available. ... Hmmmm. Almost convincing. ...

            For the record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 209</ENAMEX>. Even if the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC</ENAMEX> were cut by a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks 209 would be
a good bargain, because those who are admitted won't have to worry why. If the
decrease is only from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 to 15 percent</NUMEX>, it's a very good deal. ... Take it
away, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephan Thernstrom</ENAMEX>! ...

         
      
   
