
   
   
      
         
            Chatterdump

            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-hating gossipmonger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> actually do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a
favor by forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> story out into the open before special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecutor Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> could wire her up and get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to say something
damaging on tape, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> apparently planned to do?...

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has had affairs with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, where are all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> he
hit on and didn't have affairs with? Does he score every time? When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>
hits on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, its success rate is--well, let's not say what the rate is. But
it's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 100 percent</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 50 percent</NUMEX>, even ...

            Which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> is happiest about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s current predicament? Chatterbox
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nominates Gary Hart</ENAMEX>, who must have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX> wondering how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> got away with it ...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paranoid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks</TIMEX> after a front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
story on the disappearance of lucrative speaking engagements for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX>, a huge scandal breaks that will surely revive demand for...speeches by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, who can now retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titillating</ENAMEX> tidbits ("Let me tell you
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> I know ...") Mere coincidence? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>, who pointed this out, thinks not ...

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wing</ENAMEX> hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal pundit</ENAMEX> wrote: "It would bother me greatly if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was still
messing around after the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> interview--let alone after the
election. That would reveal a brutal willingness to deceive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>--way
beyond the normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' cynicism--as well as a frightening lack of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-control</ENAMEX> ..." Who was the liberal pundit? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>, now

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. Prepare to be bothered greatly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> ...

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>: In retrospect, maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> wasn't so crazy
to be concerned about ridding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holdovers</ENAMEX> when her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> took office. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holdovers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, made the tapes that
now threaten the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency. Bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> wish they'd gotten rid of
her in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, along with the travel-office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> ...

         
      
   
