
   
   
      
         
            Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot</ENAMEX>! We're <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Animals</ENAMEX>!

            Never mind the ethics of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paparazzi</ENAMEX> who torment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKibben</ENAMEX> wants the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> who shoot wildlife to lay down
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leicas</ENAMEX>.

            Writing in the fall issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubletake</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Coles</ENAMEX>' slick magazine
of essays, photographs, reportage, and poetry--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKibben</ENAMEX> accuses commercial
wildlife <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">needlessly stressing caribou</ENAMEX> and other critters by
stalking them by airplane. He also damns them for staging the "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">jillions</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>"
pictures of emerald boas eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">parrots</ENAMEX> because it creates false expectations
of what the wilderness is all about. Evidence that the public has gone mad on
wildlife photography can be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yellowstone Park</ENAMEX>, he says, where wildlife
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">porn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s phrase, not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKibben's</ENAMEX>) has convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> that bears
are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">approachable beasts</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bears</ENAMEX> that become habituated to people
usually end up getting snuffed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rangers</ENAMEX> because they become dangerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pests</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKibben</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX>? A moratorium on new commercial wildlife photography. He
calls on the top nature magazines and TV shows to pick a date and refuse to
purchase any photos taken after that. It's not as if there aren't enough
photographs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> points out that she reviewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>
slides of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> while planning a story on them.

            This isn't censorship, it's editing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKibben</ENAMEX> writes. "Self-restraint is the
uniquely human gift, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> no other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> possesses
even as a possibility."

         
      
   
