
   
   
      
         
            Bad-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Nostalgia</ENAMEX>
            

            Think your analysis is spot-on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>. (How's that for a disincentive to
keep reading?) It's no coincidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golin</ENAMEX> had his apprenticeships at both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Cosmo</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> unlikely ever to be accused
of sentimentality or pretension. The crucial lesson taught by those two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX>, and successful mass-market mags in general, is a rigorous
anti-elitism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GQ</ENAMEX> posit, explicitly or by inference,
that only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> will be let into their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s Advertising
Age, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GQ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Cooper</ENAMEX> asks why condom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> bother to take
out pages in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX>, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> is composed entirely of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masturbators</ENAMEX>. I'm pretty sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> was joking, but the dis was clear.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GQ</ENAMEX>="classy." <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Maxim=hopelessly déclassé</ENAMEX>. But who wants to be
classy anymore? The recent vogues for cigars, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cocktails</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rat Pack</ENAMEX> were
not wistful evocations of a more civilized time; they were wistful evocations
of the last great period of big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Straight White Guy</ENAMEX> fun, before the broads and
the fags came in to ruin it all. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pack</ENAMEX>'s bad-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> behavior the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-'90s</TIMEX> ersatz swells are celebrating, not the fine tailoring on his
three-button suits.

            The tits in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, likewise, are not there for the purpose of
"trouser-rousing" (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Details</ENAMEX> so delicately put it in its current
issue). The photos are rarely "hot" in the manner of pornography or even in the
manner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> tanned-fleshy swimsuit numbers. They
are more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'90s</ENAMEX> answers to the calender <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and pinups of the mid-century,
suggestive more than titillating, festive more than funky. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s-mag
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T&A</ENAMEX> is really about providing a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>-only atmosphere in
which the complicated tradeoffs involved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX> of negotiating with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s lib can be neatly tuned out.

            This is not really anti-feminist, since much of the new laddism seems to be
coming at the behest of a new generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cosmo</ENAMEX>-trained sex-addled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fembots</ENAMEX>. How terrifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s blithe attitude toward phone sex must
have been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, talking nasty to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is just
fun. And how irrelevant is capital-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F Feminism</ENAMEX> now that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">NOW et al.</TIMEX> have
given a tacit thumbs up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sexual harassment of an intern (an
issue that even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> would have provoked mau-mauing of the highest
order)? We've come a long way since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>.

            Indeed, feminism feels like a
dead letter both in magazines and in the culture at large .

         
      
   
