
   
   
      
         
            You Don't Know Jackboots!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> yields to no content-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> when it comes to condemning special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecutor Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s excesses--in particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s attempt to
criminalize criticism by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> into the grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury room</ENAMEX>. But the reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s subpoena of the records of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s purchases at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> bookstore has been mindlessly
critical. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congresswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Schroeder</ENAMEX> immediately called the
subpoena "repugnant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>" and "a scenario that belongs in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> harrumphed about "the right to buy books without government
scrutiny," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Action</ENAMEX> drew a
comparison to "some of the worst abuses under a totalitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>." Nicholson
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>, whose phone-sex novel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vox Monica</ENAMEX> allegedly bought, went for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cute</ENAMEX>, somewhat forced sound bite by saying that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> should get down on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kneepads</ENAMEX> and beg the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s pardon for undermining the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> charged ... well, you can imagine what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> charged.

            Everyone should calm down. Can't books be evidence? If someone bludgeons
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> to death with a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Halberstam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Children</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> hopes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> will be able to check whether any of its enemies
previously purchased that worthy tome. If someone blows up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>,
it's worth knowing if the prime suspect bought <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Anarchist's Cookbook</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Reagan</ENAMEX>'s book on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World Order</ENAMEX>." And, to pick another
hypothetical example, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s tape recorder
that she, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, had phone sex with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 3</TIMEX> after buying a
copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vox</ENAMEX> , isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> permitted to try to support the accuracy of
those taped recollections by finding out if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> actually bought the book
around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that date</TIMEX>? Were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> trying to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> for her thoughts or
tastes or reading habits or speech--the way he was threatening to punish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>--all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>-are-coming hysteria might be justified. But there's
no evidence that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to</NUMEX>, nor is it a likely scenario. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STUPID CLINTON DEFENSE</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX>: Meanwhile, the self-humiliation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of the president
continues apace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> has been a reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX>, but his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> column suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> should hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> in contempt (and even
throw them in jail)if they keep publishing "stories without attribution based
on gossip, speculation and innuendo." Here is an idea that really is "repugnant
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>." ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> proposes his censorship in order to prevent
sheep-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> from being swayed by publicity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> he's
thinking about is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> civil suit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. His opening example of
irresponsible press activity is the "overwhelming television and print
coverage" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s allegations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> can't really be proposing to
suppress the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> interview--which was, in truth, not a story
based on "gossip" or "innuendo" but first-person testimony about the behavior
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>, about which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are surely entitled
to form an opinion--in order to protect a puny civil suit for money damages? By
the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' column you realize that yes, that's exactly what he means.
... By sacrificing the ideal of informed political debate in the name of the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of justice," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is at least hewing to his prior reputation
as a pathetic court-worshipper. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> more or less argued
it didn't matter if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lied under oath in a court case. Chatterbox wonders
what this "don't-worry-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX>-perjury" principle would do for the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of justice." ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paranoid</ENAMEX>'s Corner: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> really wanted to escape <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> for
good, here's what he'd do: Have a fresh, previously unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> come forward
alleging unwanted sexual advances along Jones/Willey lines. Let her story get
big play in the press. Let her have a packed, nationally-televised news
conference. Then have her confess that it was all a lie, that she was in fact a
tool of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vast Right-Wing Conspiracy</ENAMEX>! ... Her example would not only
retrospectively discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>, it would protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by
prospectively discrediting any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who might come forward in the future. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> would never try this. ... Wait. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excuse Chatterbox</ENAMEX> for a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> ... What's that on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX>? ... Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zercher</ENAMEX>
...

         
      
   
