
   
   
      
         
            I <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sing the Body Elected</ENAMEX>

            As everyone knows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> gave ex-intern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> an
inscribed copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Whitman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leaves of Grass</ENAMEX> . And a fine gift it
is--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> frequently gives this very volume to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with whom it is not
having sexual relations. But perhaps the book contained some deeper, more
personal meaning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. 
                  Slate
               's crack
panel of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> has convened in emergency session to draw our
attention (and that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX>) to the following passages:

            ARE you the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> drawn toward me?
    To begin with, take warning--I am surely far
        different from what you suppose;
    Do you suppose you will find in me your ideal?
    Do you think it so easy to have me become your
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>?
    Do you think the friendship of me would be
        unalloy'd satisfaction?
    Do you think I am trusty and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>?
    Do you see no further than this facade--this smooth
        and tolerant manner of me?
    Do you suppose yourself advancing on real ground
        toward a real heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?
    Have you no thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> dreamer, that it may be all
        maya, illusion?

            --from "Are You the New <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, drawn toward <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX>"

            Only what proves itself to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is so;
    Only what nobody denies is so.

            --from "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Whitman</ENAMEX>"

            I pour the stuff to start <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> fit for
        These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--I press with slow rude muscle,
    I brace myself effectually--I listen to no entreaties,
    I dare not withdraw till I deposit what has so long
        accumulated within me,
Through you I drain the pent-up rivers of myself,

            --from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Woman Waits for Me</ENAMEX>"

            Do I contradict myself?
    Very well, then, I contradict myself;

            --from "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Whitman</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
