
   
   
      
         
            Views <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Can Use</ENAMEX>!

            The newsweeklies are choosing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s
Magazine. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s increasingly creepy mouthpiece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>,
cooperates with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s long, generally
sympathetic piece on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's World</ENAMEX>," which portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> as her
"surrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>" and describes, presumably on some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, the ex-interns own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thoughts</ENAMEX> (e.g., "You didn't do anything wrong!"). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> has frosted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , which is perceived to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. A short
critical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> and his "appetite for the high life"
notes that he "declined ... to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ".... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ,
meanwhile, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX>. Indeed you could plot the array of competing
newsmagazine allegiances:

            

               

                  
                     
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
                     
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>

                   

                  
                     
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                     
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>

               

            

            There's nothing necessarily sinister about these match-ups. It's a natural
ecological phenomenon. If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> mag has locked up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, as it were--it's only sensible for a competing mag
to quickly secure the competing food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> should simply be aware, as
they weigh what they are told, that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> has an incentive to
please--or at least not totally piss off--its primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>....

            Which is not to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> still won't try to throw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> a
few bones in the hope of gaining his cooperation, or that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> won't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skillfully</ENAMEX> let him make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> of himself. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's World</ENAMEX>," for example,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> says of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>: "I was there at the beginning. I kissed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s inner thighs when she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days old</TIMEX>--I said 'Look at those little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polkas '</ENAMEX>." What's that all about? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is getting Freudian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overload ... Ginsburg</ENAMEX> is also heard boasting "I truly am the avuncular Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>," and he condescendingly predicts that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will let"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "limp to the end of his term." Mighty avuncular of you, Mr.
G!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WOULD YOU BELIEVE HE LUSTED IN HIS HEART?:</ENAMEX> 
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> are among those who have been privileged to receive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
trial-balloon explanation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "complicated" friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. You know, he may have had an ... er, avuncular , implicitly
sexual and probably inappropriate relationship that was, alas, never actually,
physically consummated ... Call it the "modified limited hangout" strategy
...

            
               CHATTERDUMP: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX>, running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? Yes! declare
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> rumormongers ... And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has no right-wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>! ... Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> wasting time waging a big fight with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aide Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>'s testimony is protected by "executive
privilege"? Does anybody really think that even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> is required to
answer every question, he'll actually incriminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? At best, he'll say
"I don't recall"... A joke that produces consistent hilarity at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX>
parties: Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have to get blowjobs from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>? Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> hadn't joined his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> yet! ... But seriously, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wants to
defend "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grassy Knoll</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> against those who trash him for giving advice
to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> while he was still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> was writing for an opinionated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, after all, if
not for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> -style "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of opinion." He gave his opinions
to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. He gave his opinions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. Where's the conflict? If
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> call to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s advice, they'll get it!... The problem,
in principle, would come if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> was giving different opinions to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> and to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> (something he's not accused of) or if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> were somehow misled into thinking they were getting a dispassionate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>. But any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> who didn't realize that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> was massively ego-invested in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' success just wasn't
paying attention ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> hopes this stout defense won't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>
from ordering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>-intimidation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s
private life. What fun! What publicity! ... For the record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has
never done anything avuncular, though it tried once in college ...

         
      
   
