
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox Goes Right</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Mathis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX> caused a stir in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> circles with her
report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Wednesday</TIMEX> that presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aspirant Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashcroft</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
had all but locked up the oh-so-coveted political consulting services of former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mathis</ENAMEX> notes that "Every chance he gets,
it seems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> praises and promotes" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashcroft</ENAMEX>. She adds: "If and when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> decides to make his presidential ambitions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> will
disappear from the market." Wrong! says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, in its best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> voice. Think about it for a moment. Who benefits if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> gets in
the race and splits the social conservative primary vote with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>?
Answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>' biggest potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s other potential client,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, that's who. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> entry might also
kill the candidacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, thereby freeing up the
allegiances of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, radio moralist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dobson</ENAMEX>.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> is with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> all the way. Trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> on this one. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Faux-Groveling</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/19</NUMEX>) shouldn't have been as
nasty as it was about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Broder</ENAMEX>'s front page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s detractor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> should have
been nastier! Not only did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> forget to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reporter Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s contention that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> had changed her story at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> also forgot to mention that--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> had
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half</TIMEX> earlier--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> had taken <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,000</NUMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> after shifting to an anti-Willey posture. ... Not that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> is lying. Not that she isn't. But given the volume of detail the
Times provided on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s past, including her attempts to sell
her story, you'd think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> would at least mention the main questions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surrounding Steele</ENAMEX> ... Now it turns out, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> also met with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>, who claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> was
asking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX>. ...

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, cont.: As predicted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/23</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> is heavily wedded to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s credibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
is wedded (slightly less heavily) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey's</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> still
don't know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele-Isikoff</ENAMEX> dispute, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s tabloid dealings,
though they know all about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s aborted tab and book deals. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
also somewhat sleazily ends its anti-Willey piece by noting that a grant of
immunity "may help protect [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Willey</ENAMEX>] from prosecution in connection with any
financial or tax improrieties," without ever saying what those improprieties
might be. ...

            
               No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Think This One Might be a Dealbreaker:</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> have tried to suggest they are former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, but when the dust
settles I think they'll be okay."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Moody</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, referring to the friendship between his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> secretly taped and exposed to a
potential perjury prosecution.

         
      
   
