
   
   
      
         
            Fondlee, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen: Isikoff</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stand</ENAMEX>?

            A potentially significant conflict is opening up between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who's been a driving force in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> scandal,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX>, the erstwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> who says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> told
her to lie to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>. As discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterboxes</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2/3 and 2/18</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long ago as last August</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> initially told him (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1</NUMEX>)
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had told her about an unwanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pass on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> it happened.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> also reported, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same August</TIMEX> story, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> then recanted, and
told him (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had only "told her about the incident weeks
after it happened, saying only that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had made a pass at her." Now
Steele claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> didn't mention anything at all about a pass, wanted
or not--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> has signed an affidavit (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#3</NUMEX>) claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> "never
said anything to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made sexual advances toward
her." What's more--and this is the key point--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX>, through her lawyer
denies telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> what he reported she told him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> after
her recantation, namely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had still talked of a "pass," if not an
unwanted pass.

            This is a direct conflict; the question isn't what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> but
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> told him <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> talked of a
"pass." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> denies telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> this. (In effect, she says there was no
Version <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX>) ... But there's more: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> also reported, in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX> issue
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> had told him a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had
indeed mentioned a sexual advance. He wrote: "Just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> repeated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had told her about a sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'overture</ENAMEX>' by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>." Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> deny telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> this as well?
Presumably yes. (Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Luque</ENAMEX>, said she would try to reach her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> back. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is still waiting.) ...

            Unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s credibility is somehow destroyed, this isn't a petty side
dispute. It bears directly on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s credibility--has she changed her story
to exculpate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>?--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> is currently the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> undermining
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>. Whom to believe? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> is standing by his story. "We have no
intention of printing any retraction," he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>; it does know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s money is on him. This doesn't sound
like something he'd make a mistake about, and he wouldn't print an untruth. ...
Could it be a case of confusion and miscommunication? A lot depends on the
specifics of just how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff grilled Steele</ENAMEX>, which he presumably did. Which
brings us to ...

            
               A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> issue: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> remains important, it's hard to see why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> shouldn't try to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s testimony regarding what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX>
told him. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will Isikoff</ENAMEX> testify if subpoenaed? ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s unsolicited
advice: Spill your guts out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>! It's not as if you'll be protecting the
identity of a confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX>, like other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, have an
obligation to testify. The alternative view, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> have a special role
and special rights, is snooty corporatism! (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chatterbox 2/26</ENAMEX>) ... But
probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> will resist ...

            
               A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> issue: why doesn't the press report <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Steele</ENAMEX>'s purported change
of story? If you read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> you have no idea that there was an issue
regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> just reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> says
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> didn't describe it as sexual.") Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> doesn't want to get
into a pissing match with a rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. (Oh, go ahead!).
But what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' excuse? Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX>'s front page story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> recantation manages to run <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 24</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inches</ENAMEX>, not counting a reprint of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> affidavit, without mentioning this
significant factual dispute .... That's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> has embarrassed
himself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>. (The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>? His sophomoric sneering at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chatterbox 3/1</ENAMEX>) ...

         
      
   
