
   
   
      
         
            "I'd 'I <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do' Dodi": Di</ENAMEX>

            Who said loyalty is dead? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trevor Rees-Jones</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> who is the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> of the car crash that killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, reportedly has been
recovering his memory of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fateful night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rees Jones</ENAMEX> now says he heard a
female voice cry out for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX>. He remembers seeing a white hatchback,
similar to the mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiat Uno</ENAMEX> thought to have collided with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>,
giving chase to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Finally he remembers that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Paul</ENAMEX>, seemed sober, even though blood tests showed he had three
times the legal limit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> in his blood.

            No one is more pleased than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rees-Jones</ENAMEX>'s mending memory. Well,
no one except possibly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rees-Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>),
department-store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed Fayed</ENAMEX>, who paid the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> who has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supervised Rees-Jones</ENAMEX>' recovery. Besides feeding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayed</ENAMEX>'s general feeling (not
entirely unjustified) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> is out to get him,
Rees-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' memories might lessen the liability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fayed</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>,
which provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">inebriated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>.

            Using mystical far-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> techniques, an antique <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tesla</ENAMEX> coil, and a regimen
of multivitamins, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has extracted future recovered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rees-Jones</ENAMEX> memories
and provides them exclusively to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of this column:

            "Yes, yes, it's coming back to me now,...a white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat Uno</ENAMEX> driven by a
papparazzi! And he's yelling...what?...oh, yes, he's yelling 'we're out to get
you! Up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX>!'...And I hear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s voice--yes, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. She's
saying 'Dodi, I love you. And also your wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. I so wish they'd give
him citizenship!...All that silly talk about [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">garbled</ENAMEX>]...it's so unfair...I'm
dying ...Tell everyone to shop at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrod</ENAMEX>'s!'"

         
      
   
