
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox Cares</ENAMEX>

            Is Chatterbox obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>? Yes. Is this obsession justified?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ivins</ENAMEX>,
everyone associated with the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Primary Colors</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> speaking as one, say no. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles "Bhagwan</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Monthly</ENAMEX>, one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who gave
credence to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> tapes early on, argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> rightly
don't care much about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX> because they've known the rough contours of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            Let's concede what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> apparently believe: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been a good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, especially considering the alternatives. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> fully expects
that within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of his leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--whenever that happens--we'll want him
back. So why care about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> reasons, in order of ascending
impeachability:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The ease of his corruption: We knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had affairs and lied
about them to the press and public. We didn't quite know the unhesitating grace
with which--if the current charges are true--he orchestrates a campaign to
deceive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, you don't have to turn over those gifts if you
no longer have them in your possession! (It was especially shocking to see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX>, who worships the legal process
and has taught at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law</ENAMEX>, glide smoothly over the distinction between
lying to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and lying under oath.) True, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lies about sex
that doesn't mean he necessarily lies about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. The slope isn't
all that slippery. But it's a slope. Does anyone doubt that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lied
under oath about sex he also lied about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX>? About what was given in
exchange for campaign contributions? Maybe it stops somewhere, but where?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The overconfidence: What kind of alarmingly self-deluded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>, knowing what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must have known about his own behavior, would
have failed to settle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case? So she upped her demand to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>? Pay it! There is a failure of judgment here. One day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">hypertrophied</ENAMEX> faith in his ability to pull anything out of the fire with a
flurry of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX> salesmanship will prove wrong. Actually, it's already
been proven wrong, since the election, on the "fast track" trade issue, and
maybe on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The role mottle: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> has complained about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">annoying</ENAMEX>, cloying quality of the modern babble about "role models." He's right.
Unfortunately <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitchens</ENAMEX> didn't design the human brain, which learns by
imitation. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>, notes, we give our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> a lot, and in exchange we ask them to be a little better in
the moral example <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> than the rest of us. (See this piece by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> for the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> story.) Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> want to restore the family
in the ghettos? That will require suppressing the very impulses that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
himself has so conspicuously failed to control.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> equality: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>--including those ordinary
focus-grouping <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--offend the most when they suggest that a certain
latitude in moral and criminal matters goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s exalted
position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX> says "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who get a lot accomplished have
powerful libidos. What's the problem?" The big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> gets many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>! That's
been true through most of human history. It's not supposed to be true in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, in this sense, is a conspiracy against human nature--and not
just in that we expect monogamy when the rule of history has been polygamy.
More perversely, we also expect social equality--nobody is better than anyone
else, we all play by the same rules--when the characteristic of previous human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> has been the instinctive ranking by status. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is saying is
that he doesn't have to play by the same rules. He's too important to be sued
while in office. He's too important to be subject to the intrusive,
out-of-control sex harassment inquiries that bedevil his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. He boosted
the GNP and brought us disaster relief, and we should be grateful and shower
him with fleshy offerings. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, what's the fuss about? He gave a blow
job to the economy" is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-on-the-street interview <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> expects to
see any moment now.)

            Chatterbox always suspected that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who focus compulsively on the
income charts (ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>) would be all too
willing to trade off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s precious social equality for a minor increase in
income equality and prosperity. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is making that deal explicit. An
impeachable sin? Maybe. Maybe not. But (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than</NUMEX> reasons <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) it goes
to the fundamental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, not of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> but of our national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX>--something that's worth impeaching even a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to
preserve.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has spoken!

            
               IT'S EVERYWHERE: Note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s ultimate sin--the sin of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corporatism</ENAMEX>, of seeing society as a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> with individual human
components performing different social functions and having different, unequal
rights--is the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s sin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> thinks his role is so goddamn
important that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> get a special right to criminalize free speech
as "obstruction of justice." Less obviously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sin is the same one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> commit when they denounce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> for impeding "our ability to gather
information for the public"--as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> were a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> with
special privileges and (inevitably) obligations, the eyes of the social corpus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nobly</ENAMEX> gathering information on behalf of poor, ignorant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Better to
stick to the social-egalitarian line: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, with the
same rights and obligations as other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> (same as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, same as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>, same as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>), which include the right to say nasty things
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
