
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harmonic Convergences</ENAMEX>
            

            You're right, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX>'s strong point is that it's totally unsentimental
and ungenteel. It's a sendup of the old model, but in a different way than,
say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> was, and the difference (surprise) reflects the sexual
culture of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. With its belligerent grossness and misogyny,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> rebelled against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mags</ENAMEX>' class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condescension</ENAMEX>, the earnest philosophizing about the sexual revolution, the
"thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s sex bomb" <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>, at the same time that it was deliberately
goading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>. It came right out with the anger that the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s mags
tried to hide. Maxim pokes fun at its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">progenitors</ENAMEX> but with considerable
ironic affection. It's not angry. In fact, while its fondness for the most
idiotic, juvenile humor knows no bounds, any strong emotion is taboo (unless
you count horror at having your penis mangled)--that's part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
influence, I guess. And feminism isn't an issue, at least not directly--partly
because its basic ideas have been assimilated and are taken for granted, partly
because politics in general and feminism in particular barely exist in the
consciousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX>'s age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whereas Gear</ENAMEX>, which retains
certain elements of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s mag ethos, and the old hostility--and not
incidentally runs somewhat longer articles--does worry about and argue with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feminism</ENAMEX>, as in its recent piece on sexual repression in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, in which
it is argued, after a fashion, that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) we can't suppress male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' urge to
rape and harass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> without suppressing the urge to kill that's the
military's reason for being, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) sexual harassment crusades interfere with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s equality, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women soldiers</ENAMEX> aren't men's equals anyway, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) why do
we need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the military in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place?)

            Another thing I've noticed is that the trajectory of the new men's magazines
and that of contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> seem to be converging, at least
compared with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>. There used to be an enormous gulf between the sense
of entitlement to the good things of life, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, that pervaded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s mags and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s anxious obsession with self-improvement in order to be
worthy of male attention. In young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> now, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cosmo</ENAMEX> being
the paradigm, there's a much more bluntly instrumental, "male" attitude toward
getting sex of the quantity and quality desired. Beauty is as central a
preoccupation as ever, if anything more so, but the preoccupation has much more
of a narcissistic, self-pampering quality and less of a desperation to make up
for some irrecoverable, primal imperfection. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, there's
much more of a sense that if you want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to give you the time of day, you
have to make some effort to find out what they want and give it to them. In the
old model, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> needed advice on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or sex, they got it from a male expert
like the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy Advisor</ENAMEX>." Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX> features advice from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on such
matters as how not to give the wrong impression on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> date.

            On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> still don't like to express anxiety directly--I'd
guess that part of the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s mags have gotten sillier is that they've
seized on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s time-honored method of covering up insecurity by clowning
around. Regarding your suggestion that these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> a safe place to
be together without their heterosexuality being questioned: That sounds like
more of a hope (on their part) than a reality. Because it's ultimately
self-doubt that really matters, no place can really be safe--hence the
need to escalate the jokes.

         
      
   
