
   
   
      
         
            Chatterdump: How to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stop Drudge, Etc.</ENAMEX>

            
               THEY MAY have finally found a way to neutralize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>--make him
famous! Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Mess</ENAMEX> broke, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> has apparently been so busy giving
interviews and making television appearances that he's had no time to write his
famed dispatches. The last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 21...Did</TIMEX> you notice on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>'s face seems to curve from top to bottom like a giant
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-moon letter "C"? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peyronie's Disease</ENAMEX> of the chin?.... While Chatterbox
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loves Drudge</ENAMEX> (except for that nasty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> business), on TV he does
come across as one mighty weird <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>...

            
               MUCH CHATTER about what a relaxed good mood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
was in when he showed up at a dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Wednesday</TIMEX> honoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated</ENAMEX>
Press. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> story had broken that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CHATTERBOX</ENAMEX> WAS GOING to predict that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> would be the first prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might
have to resign....Really we were...But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> beat us to the punch with his
declaration in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could not survive
admitting an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s comments
"carry special clout" because "he is one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s most respected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, seen as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> on matters of ethics and values." In truth,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s remarks were as predictable as the sunrise. He's been getting press
by stabbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the back since before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s election. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Moynihan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endorsed Nebraska</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> primary. Later he
publicly undermined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s health care plan. Then he undermined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
welfare plan. Anyone who reads <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s recent book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX> to Go will
see he strongly dislikes, if not loathes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He may have good reason
for this disdain, but it means his resignation talk doesn't carry much weight
at all. He probably thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should resign before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
scandal.... Like the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Phillips</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> is a convenient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure reporters</ENAMEX> know they can count on for a
faux-contrarian remark...Who will be next to stick in the shiv? Chatterbox
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predicts Kerrey</ENAMEX>, who knows he shouldn't but who won't be able to resist...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEPARTMENT</ENAMEX> OF GROVELING: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McMichael</ENAMEX> e-mails about a Chatterbox
item speculating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> must be happy at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s troubles: "That was
a very cheap shot against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>, and my guess is that he is gloomy over the
whole mess, not experiencing any schadenfreude." If so, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX> is a bigger man
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Chatterbox</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox magnanimously</ENAMEX> concedes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMichael</ENAMEX> has a

            
                editorial page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> goes on about
"anti-social personality disorder, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> now call it," only to
conclude "in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s case a strict diagnosis does not hold..."

         
      
   
