
   
   
      
         
            When Is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B___ J___</ENAMEX> Not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B___ J___</ENAMEX>? etc.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SUNDAY</TIMEX>'S <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NEW YORK</ENAMEX> TIMES
                says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> mess appears to have
"blurred the boundaries between mainstream and tabloid news." Blurred? The
lines have actually crossed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> instance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">semi-unflinchingly</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> said she could be "Special Assistant
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">b___ j___</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> was
actually more decorous, describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s fantasy job title as "Special
assistant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for (oral sex)." Even that was too much for the
hoity-toity tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , which said only that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> joked about her
alleged romance by saying that she was 'special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.'"
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>! ....

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WITH MONICA WOBBLING SLOWLY</ENAMEX> IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIND</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> incident
may now assume more importance. Do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize just how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creepy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
behavior was, if the worst reported details of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s testimony are true?
Here is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has been caught misappropriating funds, who must
find a way to repay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$274,000</NUMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. She's desperate (indeed, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
would commit suicide before the deadline). She needs a job. She goes to see the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, who at this moment of temporary advantage takes her into a side room
and gropes her breast and puts her hand on his genitals, saying he "always
wanted" to do that. If true, this is not a consensual affair with Gennifer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Flowers</ENAMEX>, or even a tryst with an employee like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. This is
casting-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch piggishness</ENAMEX> of a sort that would make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Packwood</ENAMEX> blanch.
...

            
               WHAT IF <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLINTON</ENAMEX> manages to survive? Consider the psychological
effects on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Right Wing Conspirators</ENAMEX>: They thought they had him, but he slipped
away again. Contempt for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> (and democracy) among this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skyrocket</ENAMEX>. Some already seem practically ready to pick up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and join
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">militias</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Media Elite: Scan</ENAMEX> the talk shows. Who among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commentariat</ENAMEX> actually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">believes Clinton</ENAMEX>? Practically nobody. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punditburo</ENAMEX> has reached its decision,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> don't want to hear it. The same goes for your average
inside-the-Beltway political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. Nearly all of them think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
blatantly lying, but they are constrained by popular demand and the additional
strictures of "objectivity." The inevitable result? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> will take it out
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in other ways, on more permissable, more substantive topics. If,
say, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> numbers don't add up, expect him to be roasted for it with a
ferocity explicable only by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>' frustration over what they perceive as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Lie</ENAMEX> about sex.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonistas</ENAMEX>: The most intriguing case. They may or may not believe
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Lie</ENAMEX>, but they can never admit it in public. Maybe they can't admit it
even to themselves. Just as old lefties could never concede that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX> was
guilty and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> hands must keep downplaying evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s recklessness,
they'll keep on spouting the spin. Further study will be required on the
long-term psychological impact of this denial, a condition known clinically as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorenseniasis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX>, this means you! ...

            Chatterbox always wanted to do that.

         
      
   
