
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey Grope</ENAMEX> 'n' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gripe Extravaganza</ENAMEX>!

            
               A <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">FEW MORE</NUMEX> POINTS about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> incident. As noted in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, if true <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s story is the worst of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
alleged sexual indiscretions--worse than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, worse than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. But
is Willey telling the truth? In his original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> article on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey/Willy</ENAMEX> business, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> initially confirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s account, saying she (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>) had heard the
gruesome details from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of the incident. But in the same article
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isikoff</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> had later recanted and said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> "had asked
her to 'lie' about what had happened in order to give credibility to the
allegation that she had been harassed." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> now said
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> only told her that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had made a pass at her," and not
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> after the incident. ...

            
               ARE WE TO BELIEVE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s recantation? Or had the same Mystery
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Suborner</ENAMEX> who gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> anti-Willey "talking points" to give to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>--"you now do not believe that what she claimed happened really happened.
You now find it completely plausible that she herself smeared her
lipstick"--also given them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX>, with greater success? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has no
idea what the answer is. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s testimony will clearly now be very important.
But the mere existence of the "talking points" casts a retrospective cloud over
her semi-exculpatory recantation. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STEELE</ENAMEX>'S NEW ACCOUNT is only "semi-exculpatory" because she did tell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> had talked to her about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> making a pass (just not an
unwanted pass). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , rehashing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s reporting
in a front-page piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>, conveniently omitted this point, leaving
the false impression that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> had heard about any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
pass was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> called to ask her to lie when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> "was on his way to
her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>." ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ONE ANTI-WILLEY CONSIDERATION</ENAMEX> is this: her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> apparently stole
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $274,000</NUMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s money and didn't repay it. Instead, with the
repayment deadline looming, he committed suicide. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in insurance money after his death, and apparently didn't give
any of it to the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> whose money was stolen. Indeed, she has
fought through protracted legal proceedings to successfully stiff him. Is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> alone in finding this behavior deeply troubling? ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DESIGNATED SCANDAL VILLAIN LINDA TRIPP</ENAMEX> , of course, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> that
when she ran into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Willey</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey's Oval Office</ENAMEX> encounter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> looked
"flustered, happy, and joyful"--not harrassed. But is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s account really
all that incompatible with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s? Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had made an unwanted
grope, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> still could have looked "flustered and happy" afterwards, and
maybe even have failed to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> she was at some level appalled. After all,
it must be a heady thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> make a pass at you, even an unwanted
may have been "joyful" that she was going to get the job she desperately
wanted. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior was piggish, it's a bit unfair to expect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> to get instantly angry and dress down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
as if he were the heavy in some "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How to Stop Sex Harassment</ENAMEX>" training
video.

         
      
   
