
   
   
      
         
            The Hell of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates, Jr.</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> is light on ads (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> picked it up and
for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> !) but thick with highbrow
Clintophilic rationalization in the form of an essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX>
You thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> was about sex and perjury? Wrong! It's really about the
decline of loyalty among former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Panetta</ENAMEX>, and the nefarious spread of atomistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> loyal to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abstract</ENAMEX>, "uniform set of principles" such as "impartial truth." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>
is the embodiment of these inhuman principles, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enlightenment's...curse</ENAMEX>."
All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was doing was trying to "struggle with the gummy, vexed
exigencies of the merely human."

            Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is right about the gummy part, for sure. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> questions,
though:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Who says there's more disloyalty in this scandal? Chatterbox
carries no water for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/25 and 2/2</NUMEX>). But his sin is
less his disloyalty in acknowledging a potential crime by his ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> than
his failure to confess his own complicity in that crime. Overall, the striking
thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is not how much disloyalty there has been but how
little . Nobody from inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has yet broken ranks
(though there have been rumblings from cabinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riley</ENAMEX>).
There is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dean</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>. Compare those <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> betrayals with
the watered-down subversion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX>, which amounted to
saying on television what was obvious--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is in trouble unless he
explains himself soon--and you would conclude that loyalty has been on the rise
since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. (Maybe what has changed is we no longer expect a loyal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to admit even the obvious. We're so accustomed to spin that common sense
sounds like treason.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> includes a few "to-be-sure" paragraphs about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>,
and then proceeds undeterred. Like a thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Apple</ENAMEX>, he surveys
various <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>--even tracking down that familiar standby,
the unnamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>"--and reaps a harvest of self-congratulatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harrumphing</ENAMEX> along the lines of "I come from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> when loyalty and gratitude
were regally honored," not like these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whippersnappers</ENAMEX>, etc. He cites
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Lincoln</ENAMEX> as one of the ancient paragons of loyalty--the
"embodiment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courtier</ENAMEX>'s discretion." Would that be the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> who after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s death, according to 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>,
"circulated stories that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> had had adulterous trysts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>"
and "spent the remaining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32 years</TIMEX> badmouthing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>..."? (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s piece.)
Sounds a bit like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> defending Bill by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">badmouthing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Do we really want to place loyalty over truth? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' main straw
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Godwin</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1793</TIMEX> argued that if you can rescue either
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fenelon</ENAMEX> from a burning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, "you go for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archbishop</ENAMEX>, since he has the greater social contribution to make." [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>'
words.] In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' essay, those who would favor a stand of principle over the
ties of blut and boden (or even business)--whistle-blowers,
antiwar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissenters</ENAMEX>, anyone who says "I often place my duty to society above my
duty to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>"--are characterized as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Godwin</ENAMEX> types all, letting
their own dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> burn to a crisp with nary a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought while they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandly escort</ENAMEX> some silk-bedizened cleric to safety." Worse, they're selfish,
rootless cosmopolitans--sorry, they're selfish "moral illuminati" pursuing
their own vision of individual "authenticity," of "unbridled self-assertion,"
at the expense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and group ties ("the intricately reciprocal character
of a life lived within community"). Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> comically stacks the deck
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Godwin</ENAMEX> example, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Godwin</ENAMEX> asks that we rescue the cleric, not in
the name of truth but in the name of some sort of obnoxious aristocratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">utilitarianism</ENAMEX>. (Nor is betraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> exactly like burning your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.) In reality, of course, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> who are making the
utilitarian arguments about the overbalancing value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s "greater
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> contribution." A larger point concerns the value of loyalty--whether to
family, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, or other social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Is it really such a great
thing? Loyalty, in this sense, has given us wars, racism, tribalism and
genocide. Selfish uniform principles have given us science, human rights, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>....The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enlightenment</ENAMEX>! Individualism! Take it away, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon</ENAMEX>
Wieseltier!...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> should be loyal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> , why should the
rest of us? By the end of his piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> has subtly slipped from
attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-aides</ENAMEX> who criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to attacking anyone who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticizes Clinton</ENAMEX>. We must all, he says, start "learning to talk about right
and wrong without recourse to abstract principles." Anyone else is a
mama-barbecuing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>-style fanatic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> never explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>,
or any other ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>, owes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the same loyalty as Stephanopoulos
does. If the charges against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> are true, isn't it he who has
betrayed us?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> could go on and on. Didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> champion the very "new
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>" of rootless, skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-agents</ENAMEX>--the very disloyal types <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> claims
threaten to subject the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to the laws that apply to other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>?
Would we have been better served in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> if fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had quit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to protest the war--or if more had quit, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, and
more loudly? Why should we spend valuable time reading the journalism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> if he is happy to place his loyalty--to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>? his race?
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>? to The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>? , to the academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> he's building
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>?--over an annoying abstract principle like truth? Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>
has seen On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterfront</ENAMEX> too many times. But should we really root for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who poison <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlon Brando</ENAMEX>'s pigeons?

         
      
   
