
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Questions About Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etc.</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Jay Epstein</ENAMEX> has sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> the following e-mail
message, subject: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Preliminary Concerns I Have About Monica and Other</ENAMEX> Babes
From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s roots may be relevant. Her mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Lewis</ENAMEX> (a k a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>), a former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporter reporter</ENAMEX>, wrote a book about "The
Private Lives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Three Tenors</ENAMEX>." In the cover blurb, to help sell books, she
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teasingly</ENAMEX> suggests that she had an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placido Domingo</ENAMEX>. The claim was
false.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> achieved her internship not through her scholarship at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis & Clark</ENAMEX> College but through the intervention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kaye</ENAMEX>, who
donated enough to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> to be invited to sleep in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> Was this the reason she later got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s attention?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Can anyone really believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
insider (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX>), would recklessly tell a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> to perjure herself
when he has so many safer, legal ways to achieve the same end? For example,
getting her a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, who, like all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, would let her know her full
scenario of options. (I can't.)

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Is it coincidental that prior to befriending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> had engaged a literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Goldberg</ENAMEX>, who specializes in expos,s
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life and had copies of the tapes? And what was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s
interest in writing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX> case?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> tip off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>? If so, did it
lead to the following <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> events: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alert POTUS</ENAMEX> that she was about to be deposed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> returned the call on
her voice mail. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> dispatched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> to find out why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> to depose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> have helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> get a job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX> if he knew a)
she was about to perjure herself at his request and b) his help could be
construed as a bribe to facilitate the perjury? Or would he have helped her if
she assured him that she had had no affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and he was therefore
merely helping an ex-intern with fund-raising connections who, if disposed of
and deposed in a friendly manner, would be one less problem.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Which elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s story suggest she is given to telling
the truth?

            a) Her affidavit: She never had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>;
b) Her alleged statement to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>: She never had sex with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>;
c) Her recorded statement: She always lies
d) Her recorded statement: She had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> over a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year</TIMEX> period.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Will it emerge that she had previously falsely charged that other
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in her life, like her high-school and college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, had had
sex with her?

         
      
   
