
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox Buries</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Lead</ENAMEX>!

            
               MANY OF CHATTERBOX'S <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">COLLEAGUES</ENAMEX> were impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Fritsch</ENAMEX>'s
analysis, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" section, of
exactly where the various parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> scandal come from. Chatterbox
thought it was a festival of cheap shots. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fritsch</ENAMEX> implicitly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chastises Newsweek</ENAMEX> because the tape transcripts it printed "took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half minutes</TIMEX> to read aloud," when the entire tape was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90 minutes</TIMEX> long. So
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> was supposed to print all the boring parts about shopping? Did
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> print <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every minute</TIMEX> of every <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> tape during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, or
only the relevant parts? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fritsch</ENAMEX> also charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> "left the
impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> had heard tapes containing all of
the most serious and salacious" accusations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-e</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">g.</ENAMEX> about oral sex. Chatterbox,
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, did not get that impression. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fritsch</ENAMEX> chastises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> for reporting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX> had told its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thought oral sex wasn't adultery. "The newspaper
had never before printed those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> old comments from the unnamed
troopers," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fritsch</ENAMEX> sniffs. Of course, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> had
rushed those charges into print <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fritsch</ENAMEX> would probably have
been the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to call it irresponsible. And clearly "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> old comments"
are more credible <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than comments made recently, in the middle of a
feeding frenzy, would be. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONFLICT OF INTEREST DISCLOSURE</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isikoff's</ENAMEX>, whom it worships like a god. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> recently applied for a
job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>. For some reason they've been too busy to return the
call. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CREDIBILITY-ENHANCING ANTI- NEWSWEEK ITEM</ENAMEX>: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
reprinted something that looks like the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-Tripp "talking points"
in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX> issue. The document appears to have been typed on a manual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">typewriter</ENAMEX>. Aha! thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>--whoever wrote them was so worried about
keeping them secret that he or she pecked them out by hand--perhaps on a
replica of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX>' old Woodstock! But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">no. Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has learned that what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> printed was...let's say a reenactment of what a more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photogenic</ENAMEX> version of the talking points might look like, presumably as cooked
up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. Apparently the real talking points look
more like they came out of a laser printer.

         
      
   
