
   
   
      
         
            "Full-Service" Chatterdump

            
               HOW LONG can famed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX>--former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Medavoy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Perelman</ENAMEX>--stay
out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinterngate</ENAMEX> mess? In Hit and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX> , their highly-regarded
expose of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early-'90s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> studio debacle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Griffin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Masters</ENAMEX>
report as follows: "At a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>'s home, which took place
after [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> had slept in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom</ENAMEX>, she told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thePatricia</ENAMEX> later said she
gathering that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was 'a full-service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.' 
meant to refer only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s hospitality, but her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> didn't
interpret the remark that way." ...

            
               AN EMERGING DEFENSE of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s evidence is
somehow tainted because she's been out to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> all along. But if
she were really out to get him, why would she have contradicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey's</ENAMEX> reported story that she (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>) did not welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s advances?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> did not seem upset at the time, but
instead looked "flustered, happy and joyful." Certainly it would be more
damaging to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> was distraught and angry, an obvious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of harassment. ... Also, why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">would Tripp</ENAMEX>, in order to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to
settle the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit, have urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that she
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>) had been blabbing about their sexual encounters? Tipping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> off
would only help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Settling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case would have helped him
too (avoiding the whole perjury issue). But it would also have gotten Tripp out
of testifying (and contradicting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>). Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> is telling the truth
when she says she was really terrified of having to testify, not hell-bent on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">destroying Clinton</ENAMEX>. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WE LOVE HIM WHEN HE'S ANGRY: Is Chatterbox</ENAMEX> alone in feeling that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address was actually much more forceful because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> seemed a little tense and pissed off--not doing his usual
ingratiating, good humored sales job. Something really seemed to be at stake.
...

            
               THERE'S BEEN A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOT OF</ENAMEX> TALK that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has broken an "implicit pact"
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that was struck after he confronted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>'
allegations in his famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> interview. But what exactly
was this unwritten deal? Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Goodman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Alter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ) seem to believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> effectively promised
not to screw around again in the future. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Ferguson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> argues
that since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> didn't care about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>, "an implicit bargain was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">struck</ENAMEX>," which held that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would only screw around with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "roughly
his own age," and do it discreetly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> believes the
implicit bargain was this: Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> didn't care about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>, they'll
let him get away with it again. That's the problem with those "implicit"
bargains. Memo to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>: Next time get it in writing. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEEN ON A BULLETIN BOARD</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX> (honest!):

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERN WANTED FOR GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC '99 AND CC '00 ELIGIBLE 15 HOURS PER WEEK/UNPAID</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
