
   
   
      
         
            Do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Have Any Interns in That Basket</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> seems to have largely bought the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> has strongly denied the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb. 6</ENAMEX>, which suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Currie</ENAMEX> into work on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to
help shape her potential testimony about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Tribune</ENAMEX> , for example, said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> had issued "a strongly
worded statement saying his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> was in no way coached by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to provide
misleading testimony." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> repeated the "not coached"
formula. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Greenfield</ENAMEX> suggested that the statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> was the sort of categorical denial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself should make.

            Wait a minute! Let's take another look at exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX>'s lawyer
said:


            Can you spot the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonistic</ENAMEX> fudge in that paragraph? That's right, the key
word is "recollection." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> isn't really denying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was trying to
coach her. She just denies that he was trying to change her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recollection</ENAMEX> . Of course he wasn't. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Currie</ENAMEX> presumably recalls perfectly well
where she was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. She was in her
office next door, most likely. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s not trying to get her to think she was
somewhere else. But, as has been widely speculated, he could have been trying
to get her to testify that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> wasn't "alone" with him because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> was
within "shouting distance." In other words, he was merely schooling her in the
special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> definition of "alone," as in "I was never alone in a hotel
with her."

            Since the statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> was drafted at the request of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, you can bet each word was carefully weighed and vetted. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> had really been denying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tried to influence her testimony, she
would have said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't try to influence her testimony , not her
"recollection."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> statement offers a good example of a major species of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weasel</ENAMEX>: The strong denial of something weak. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> hope you will be
so snowed by the phrases "absolutely" and "slightest suggestion" that you won't
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> that what is being "absolutely" denied isn't all that much.

            The only other statement released by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> contains a subtler
Clintonism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> is not "aware of any legal or ethical impropriety by
anyone." But of course she might not be "aware" that a semantic discussion on
what is meant by "alone" was improper. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> issued this
statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself employed the Strong/Weak trick to great effect,
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>--unambiguously--that she's not aware of any unethical conduct."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s answers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> scandal remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> of nothing so
much as an old routine by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> comedy group Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fringe</ENAMEX>, parodying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertrand Russell</ENAMEX>'s televised reminiscences. In the sketch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> confronts
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>, the philosopher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.E. Moore</ENAMEX>, who is sitting by the fire with a
basket on his knee. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> in that basket," asks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>. "No," replies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, do you then have some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> in that
basket<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>. "No," replies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>'s final lines:

            "'Moore,' I said, 'do you then have apples in that basket?' 'Yes,' he
replied, and from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> forth we remained the very closest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>."

            
               HYPED STORY OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">WEEK</ENAMEX> : That would be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>'s account
of the testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX>, erstwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>. "Now,
another key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> could end up doing [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Paula</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> more harm than good,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">report Jay Branegan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viveca Novak</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s issue. They note that Jones
had hoped to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s tale that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had made an unwelcome advance in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. "But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> tell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hiatt Steele</ENAMEX>, once a close
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey's</ENAMEX>, signed an affidavit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, at the request of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, suggesting that the encounter may have been more innocent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Willey</ENAMEX> claims and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> asked her to lie about it." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dramatically</ENAMEX> recounts how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> says she was called by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> and asked to lie
even as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX> "was on his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>."

            Sounds important, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> could be forgiven for getting
the impression that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> had discovered something new. Trouble is,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s recantation, and the accusation against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>, was not new at all. It
was reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>'s original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> story on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>.
The whole saga, including the dramatic call while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> was in transit, was
also reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>. (See
Chatterbox for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>.) The only new element in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> story was that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX> has now signed an affidavit saying what everyone thought she would say
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX>.... Plus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steele</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) fudge on the not
insignificant question of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> has consistently said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
made a pass--wanted or unwanted--at her. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> was
"left with the impression that there was nothing more than 'mutual affection,'"
...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONFLICT OF INTEREST DISCLOSURE</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was blown off recently
when it sought employment at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> .... The bitter ravings of a
disgruntled reject, or trenchant media analysis? You, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, make the
call! .... For its part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> absolutely and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unambiguously</ENAMEX> denies any
item was solely influenced by any lack of mutual affection with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . It
goes without saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is also shocked and dismayed.

         
      
   
