
   
   
      
         
            WAPO BURIES THE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LEAD</ENAMEX>!

            The juiciest bit of news in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> was entombed
in the last paragraphs of a story on page <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A-21</ENAMEX>. The piece, by media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howie</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Beast</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX>, revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> has "been
helping" an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> "research an article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s Whitewater
probe," even to the extent of asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> to cooperate with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. And the favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>!

            That wouldn't be the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX> who wrote a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> hit piece calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> "a bit nutty and a bit slutty,"
would it? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX> whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopergate</ENAMEX> article revived the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
sex scandal and portrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> as a
foul-mouthed bitch who orders state troopers to fetch her tampons? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brock</ENAMEX> whose subsequent book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> practically called her a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commie</ENAMEX>? The
nipple-baring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brock</ENAMEX> who then played the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> article
(illustrated with an exhibitionistic photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> in an open shirt posing as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Sebastian</ENAMEX>) when, despite his hit pieces and sleazy red-baiting, right
wingers snubbed him for supposedly going soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>? (He concluded, for
example, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was to blame in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater.</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>
who even in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> article defended his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopergate</ENAMEX> snooping? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> last tracked palling around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nemesis Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>? ...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is pausing to un-reel its mind ... There. Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question. Has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> gone insane? ... OK, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more question: Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX>'s whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>was-a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim-</ENAMEX>of-the-right routine a brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nosenko</ENAMEX>-like cover that has allowed him
to penetrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp's innermost recesses--gaining the confidence of
the normally closed-mouthed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX>--after which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> will turn the tables on
his original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>? True, one interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s recent anti-right
attack is that he's undergone a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">metamorphosis"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX>'s word). But another
is that he knows the publicity-grabbing value of a strategic conversion to a
contrarian position. What will the self-promoting, contrarian conclusion be
when his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> piece comes due? ... For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s critical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review of Brock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> book (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> "slings enough mud to drown
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bangladeshi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>") click here.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KURTZ'S SECOND JUICY TIDBIT</ENAMEX> is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> nickname for
conspiracy-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.K.</ENAMEX>," which stands
for "grassy knoll." ... But enough filching from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">********</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CHATTERBOX INTERGALACTIC EXCLUSIVE</ENAMEX>********

            Must credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHATTERBOX</ENAMEX> or feel its mighty wrath.

            ***EXCLUSIVE***

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Lewis</ENAMEX>, used
certain familiar epithets to describe her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard</ENAMEX>, when she divorced
him back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>. The epithets? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creep</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmucko</ENAMEX> ... the very same phrases <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> would later reportedly
use to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on the scandalous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes! ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> could of course use this info to portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> as a deluded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fantasist</ENAMEX> who is just borrowing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s story for her imaginary tale ...
Take it away, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.K.</ENAMEX>! ... Oops. Chatterbox forgot. You're portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> as
the sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> ... Well, you can savage her next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, then!

            With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>'s report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> met with Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s deposition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s recent <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Name-That-Scandal Contest--"Flytrap</ENAMEX>"--becomes more apt
than ever ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is already saving up for its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Snitch Set Him Up</ENAMEX>!"
T-shirt ... Does that come in long?

         
      
   
