
   
   
      
         
            Talking Points for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>!

            To: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Editorial Board</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Coming Anti-Workfare Editorials</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has just concluded a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-part, front-page series slamming
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s workfare policies (e.g.,"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EVIDENCE IS SCANT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">THAT WORKFARE LEADS TO FULL-TIME JOBS"</ENAMEX>). Even now, presses are stamping out the
capper, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of what will probably be many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">righteous</ENAMEX> editorials denouncing
the program. It happens that workfare is an old hobbyhorse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox's</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks it's the key to successful welfare reform (which is the key
to solving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most pressing social problem, the problem of "ghetto
poverty"). And, aside from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to give
workfare a try. If it can make it there ...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> point your series made seems indisputable: If what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Swarns</ENAMEX>
reported is true, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> simply doesn't have an adequate day care system in
place yet. He'll have to do better. As for the rest of the series, let's stick
with the major conceptual problems:

            
               Misconception <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1</NUMEX>: It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Overriding Goal of Workfare</ENAMEX> to Move
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> into Private <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> like to say the purpose of welfare
reform is to move <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "from welfare to work." That's certainly a
goal. But it's not true that unless welfare reform takes all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX> and gets them private sector jobs, it's failed. The overall goal of
reform, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said in a neolib moment, is to "break the culture
of poverty and dependence." It's a culture that traps the poor in isolated,
fatherless ghettos. It's also a culture that hurts the larger society--not just
those on welfare--by producing crime, destroying urban life, fanning racial
tension, etc. To change that culture, you don't have to get every unmarried
welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> into a job. The idea is to establish the principle that every
family has to send somebody into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. Enforce that principle,
and some of those on welfare will go to work. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> may choose to live
with breadwinners and spend time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> not on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX>--and this is the big payoff--may decide not to become single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> at
all, postponing childbirth until marriage. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of
fatherless welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of intact, working
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. That's the idea, anyway.

            Even if you think the point of welfare reform is to get everyone into a
private job, that's not the immediate goal of workfare. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workfare</ENAMEX> is
usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> part of the larger welfare reform plan. Most plans attempt to
"divert" those who apply for welfare into private jobs. They require those who
do apply to search for work. Only those who fail to find private sector jobs
are then offered workfare jobs so they can earn their benefits. Workfare, in
effect, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> of last resort. (A fine old liberal notion!) It's crazy
to expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wind up in these last-resort workfare jobs--about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,000</NUMEX>, out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">236,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> on welfare in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>--to be the ones who
will fly out the door into the private sector.

            
               Misconception <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX>: We should worry because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a third</NUMEX> of those who leave
welfare quickly turn up on the tax rolls as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has
made a big fuss about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state survey showing that "of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who came off the welfare rolls in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1996</TIMEX> through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1997</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 29 percent</NUMEX> found full-time or part-time jobs" in the first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full quarter</TIMEX> after they left welfare. Yes, we want to know how many more people
are working thanks to welfare reform. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> welfare reform will push
most successfully into the private sector are those who now never show up at
the welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place because they realize they'll do
better just getting a job. The survey completely misses this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            For those who do go on welfare, the survey only counts those who then work
for private sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> who report them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for tax purposes. It
doesn't count self-employed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>, domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and others if they don't
report their income. It doesn't count those whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> don't fill out the
required forms. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> who do file their forms do it late. Experience
with earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of welfare-leavers shows that the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX> figure will
rise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX> more percentage points (to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40 percent</NUMEX>) when these
late-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filers</ENAMEX> eventually comply. Finally, just because someone doesn't get a job
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first quarter</TIMEX> doesn't mean they never will. A study of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s reform
discovered that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX> of those leaving welfare had earnings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the quarter</TIMEX>
they left, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> had earnings within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2.5 years</TIMEX>.

            Even if a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> leaves the rolls and doesn't get a job,
remember, that doesn't mean reform has failed. She might have moved in with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, even gotten married. She might be getting help from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. If former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> were showing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX> or on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, it would be bad news,
but that doesn't seem to be happening.

            
               Misconception <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workfare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> shouldn't do work unionized city
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> used to do. At times, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> object that workfarers do
"menial," unskilled, dead-end work. At other times they complain that
workfarers have taken good, desirable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> jobs away from others. Which is it?
It can't be both. The truth is that the more the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> asks workfarers to do
useful work, like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-cleaning, the more they will probably be doing work
regular city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> once did. So? Is the work low paid? Sure. If workfare is
going to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> of last resort, it can't pay good, union wages, or
else half the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> will go on welfare to get a workfare job. Nor did the
Times show that any regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were laid off or fired to make way
for cheaper workfarers.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will go for now. Give 'em hell!

         
      
   
