
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Curse</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Opel</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is glad the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> voted to retain their innovative labor contract, with its
stress on teamwork over bureaucratic work rules. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have every
right to be angry. They took a risk, moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, and managed to build
about the only small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> made by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three</ENAMEX> that matches the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
in reliability--in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> Consumer Reports ratings it's right up there
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX>. So what reward do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> get? The other
divisions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> up to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> the capital it needs to add
a midsize <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX> or a sport-utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> to its line. There is also the
sneaking suspicion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> covered by the old-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> work
rules aren't exactly happy to be shown up by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saturn</ENAMEX> finally got permission to sell a midsize <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> decreed that it would
be built, not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Hill</ENAMEX>, but at an ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delaware</ENAMEX>, which will not be covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> labor agreement.

            All these insults have been covered in the press. What hasn't been
emphasized enough--the blow that will probably seal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX>'s fate for good--is
the precise nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that will be assembled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>: It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reworked</ENAMEX> version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vectra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX> made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Opel</ENAMEX>. To
say that the record of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Opel</ENAMEX>-designed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> has been
disappointing would be an understatement. For example, the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX>--designed after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> bought a chunk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> automaker--is also based
on an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Opel Vectra</ENAMEX> chassis. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> reliability
charts, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> ranks a distant last in reliability out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">midsize cars</ENAMEX>
listed, with a rating of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> worse than average. (The next worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge Stratus</ENAMEX>, is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 40 percent</NUMEX> worse than average.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s expensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Catera</ENAMEX> is also a reworked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Opel</ENAMEX> design, and it too is proving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unreliable</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Automobile</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. The magazine reports that
"while climbing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-mile-long grade in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> gear at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 4500</TIMEX> rpm, the
smell of burning oil wafted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. When we pulled over, a small bluish
cloud enveloped the engine bay." After this and other experiences
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Automobile</ENAMEX> said it had "no choice but to question [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catera</ENAMEX>'s]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reliability</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will be very surprised if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s attempt to pass off yet
another warmed-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Opel</ENAMEX> as a reliable, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Hill</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> is anything
other than a disaster that kills off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> name for good. Maybe that's the
whole plan...

         
      
   
