
   
   
      
         
            Name <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Scandal: And the Winner Is ...</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has harnessed the vast power of the Net in search of a handy,
irresistible name for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-Tripp-Willey-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s pathetic little hard drive now overflows with the results--more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215</NUMEX> responses, containing no less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX> distinct suggestions. All we
can say is, For God's sake, stop! The contest is over!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explicitly disobeying Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s instructions, many entries contained the
despised "-gate" suffix, including the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most popular entries--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fornigate</ENAMEX>"
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23 submissions</NUMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tailgate</ENAMEX>" (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13</NUMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zippergate</ENAMEX>" (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX>). Despite the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insubordination</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> actually likes each of these; "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fornigate</ENAMEX>" may well
wind up the name that wins out in popular usage. But somehow we can't see the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> adopting it. So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will pass over these excellent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entries</ENAMEX>, taking the advice of contest entrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Weisberg</ENAMEX> to look for a
name that might at least conceivably wind up in a high-school history book.
Plus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't want to have to buy the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Leaves</ENAMEX> of
Grass it would take to reward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fornigate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigade</ENAMEX>.

            Several other entries also fail the "history book" test. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitefluid</ENAMEX>" is too
dirty for anyone except <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> to use, as are "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pussygate</ENAMEX>,"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billygoat</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Deep Throat</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">69</NUMEX>," and one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chattterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-lot</ENAMEX>," with its evocative, ironic historical reference. (Some Chatterbox
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> seem to have spent a bit too much time going through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">X-rated</ENAMEX> bins
down at the video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.) The same goes for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby Dick</ENAMEX>," despite the useful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allusion</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s Ahab-like pursuit of proof of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sinfulness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> also likes "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Incredible Sucking Sound</ENAMEX>,"
but doesn't want to annoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>. Anyway, wasn't it a "giant sucking
sound"?

            "Daughtergate" is cute but ugly. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interncourse</ENAMEX>" doesn't exactly flow easily
off the tongue, while "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Intern</ENAMEX>" rests too heavily on an ephemeral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>-culture reference that will be lost on future generations. "Potus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interruptus</ENAMEX>" is pretty good, but too long for convenient headline usage. The
same goes for "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>," which might also attract unwanted scrutiny
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>'s antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> likes "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson Presidency</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Sexpot Dome</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nookiegate</ENAMEX>," the last so reminiscent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Weiss</ENAMEX>' prescient admonition to the
press: "Follow the nookie." But no.

            Some of the entries are too awful to actually list here. Here is a list of
them: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ejacugate</ENAMEX>," "Whit 'n' tits," "Suck 'n' <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fellation Conflagration</ENAMEX>,"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonlingus</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spewinsky</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> offered "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lobster Thermidor</ENAMEX>," which
required a long explanation (you don't want to know). Chatterbox was puzzled by
another entry: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Screw You</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> or two brilliant entries may have been lost
because they were MIME. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIME</ENAMEX>, though it doesn't make a big
deal of it.)

            Numerous entries played on the names of the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>-gate," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr Chamber</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Starr Trek</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Starr Grazing"</ENAMEX>) and the
scandal's mad secret taper ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trippwire</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Tripplash</ENAMEX>"). "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr Tripp</ENAMEX>" combines
both names nicely. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> believes neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> will
go down in history as the scandal's central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>--although "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trippwire</ENAMEX>,"
submitted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, actually packs quite a bit of info about
the scandal into a small package.

            That leaves a few slightly more anodyne but serviceable (sorry) entries.
Both "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Clintern Scandal</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Clintern Affair</ENAMEX>" will do fine. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lewinsky Affair</ENAMEX>" fits in with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tradition of naming scandals after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unlucky people</ENAMEX> or objects, and it sounds great in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. But Chatterbox
prefers "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>." It's short. It makes at least a bit of a joke. It can
accommodate the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> yielded to temptation as well as the
(not completely incompatible) possibility that the whole thing was a vicious
setup. And it was only submitted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can
tell.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wanders off into <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">El Nino</ENAMEX> in search of the sole remaining copy
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Leaves of Grass</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Capital Area</ENAMEX> to send to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>" at
Index <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishing Group</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. Congratulations. Thanks as well to all who
dared to share their good and, more courageously, their bad ideas.

         
      
   
