
   
   
      
         
            No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'04</NUMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> bears a heavy burden of responsibility in the crisis now engulfing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. It is imperative that we not get ahead of ourselves and that
we avoid a speculative rush to judgment ... Oh, what the hell. Let's speculate!
Suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> resigns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. If Chatterbox
reads <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 22nd</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment to the Constitution</ENAMEX> correctly, that means <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can
only run for the presidency once, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. (The 22nd <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> says you can
only be elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> twice, and if you serve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two years</TIMEX> of a term
"to which some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was elected" you can only be elected once.) If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
wants to maximize his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">potential years</TIMEX> in the presidency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has to hang on
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least Jan. 21, 1999</TIMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can serve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two years</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s term and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> full terms of his own ... Of course, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
drags it out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> and then quits, he'll probably be so unpopular
that he'll pull <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> down with him. And he'll deprive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> of a crucial year in
which to build his own record of accomplishment.

            Memo to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Peretz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> : You've
enthusiastically supported the ambitions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, your former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>--you've
said confidently that you intend to own the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> until "the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. You even sacked your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX>, at least in part because, in his "obsessive" (your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX>) attacks
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> ... how to put it ...
failed to completely appreciate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s virtues. If you've been reading the 22nd
Amendment too, it must now be tempting to use your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to at least help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prop Clinton</ENAMEX> up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two-year</TIMEX> deadline is past, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can run twice. But
if the above analysis is correct, the last thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> needs is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to
dangle, injured, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>-like, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX>. You need to get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
now, even if it means <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is a one-and-a-half-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> at best. The
obvious solution: Bring back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>! Go for the kill! ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyway</ENAMEX>, in retrospect,
hasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s "obsessive" anti-Clintonism been a wee bit vindicated?

         
      
   
