
   
   
      
         
            There Once Was a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Columnist From Nantucket</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the cruelest month</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed
page not on vacation. Listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Baker</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 19</TIMEX> column about absolutely
nothing save the fact that he has summered on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nantucket</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>
used to be when you took the ferry out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nantucket Island</ENAMEX> you were really out
of it....That was part of its charm." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> goes on to complain about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX>'s new popularity and the ostentatious displays of wealth. Less fortunate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may not quite share <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>'s indignation.

            Under an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 27</TIMEX> dateline of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Tisbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, that well-known news
hotspot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX> Just takes the political pulse and finds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vineyarders</ENAMEX> less excited
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s visit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. He also describes in detail his moments
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Milk Meadows</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>. On the same page, under a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me.</ENAMEX>, dateline, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul H. Nitze</ENAMEX> contributes a piece ostensibly about
industrial smog. His lede: "For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 60 years</TIMEX> I have vacationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>."

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> op-ed page, as it turns out, has subtle ways of
taunting work-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24</TIMEX> page offers straight-ahead pieces on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike and on current understanding of the cosmos, but the datelines
are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Hampton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chilmark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX> Given that the page doesn't publish
datelines for every op-ed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> can only sense that he is being
mocked.

            Even when pieces don't carry datelines, as is the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX>'s
column of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>, the section still finds a way to scald those still
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">straphanging</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>'s heat. "Lovely day at the shore--warmed by the sun,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> begins. "Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> appears, bringing the shadow that travels
with him now."

            No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> hasn't just joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX> at the beach. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">39th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>--is an imagined presence.

         
      
   
