
   
   
      
         
            What Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Know</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When Did He Spin It</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> is shocked, shocked to think that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s been screwing around! Or, rather, in his recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> essay
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX> issue), he is "livid." He feels "betrayal." He doesn't "know whether to
be angry, or sad, or both." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> thus adopts the only defense he
has--a plea of ignorance--to the obvious charge (see, for example, Chatterbox
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/25</NUMEX>) that he himself helped mislead the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> when defending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> against a variety of zipper-related charges.

            Poor trusting little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>! During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1992</TIMEX> campaign, however, this naivete
must have been rather hard to maintain. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, rounded up
affidavits to squelch an article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX> by groupie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie Hamzy</ENAMEX>,
who said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> propositioned her in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>. Then he
helped squelch an early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s womanizing. Then he
participated in the vilification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>.

            Can it be true that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> entertained no serious doubts about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? Of course not. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>'s own book on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> campaign,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quest for the Presidency</ENAMEX> , reports "the secret suspicion, widely shared
in the campaign, that some of the rumors about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> were true and that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> story might just be one of them." (Indeed, the core of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>'
account--that there was an affair--was confirmed during the campaign by one of
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX>.) Later, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandy Grunwald</ENAMEX> were so demoralized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lack of
candor that they crashed on a bed together, "too numb with fatigue and despair
to speak."

            Even now, in his current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> essay, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>--spinning his
own crisis of credibility--admits "I assumed without asking that something had
happened between" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>. Well? Doesn't that mean he knew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
was, at best, misleading and dissembling in his famous <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>
interview? If you persist in foisting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in the face of
such doubts, it's a little much to cry "betrayal" later. If Stephanopoulos
didn't know all along, his self-enforced ignorance (why did he go on "without
asking"?) was the equivalent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' "reckless disregard of
truth."

         
      
   
