
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brox Crox Redux</ENAMEX>!

            Turns out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>'s recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> confessional didn't quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confess</ENAMEX> to everything. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> writes that "a major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contributor to Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOPAC</ENAMEX>" introduced him to the "gothic world of
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintonism</ENAMEX>." Why would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX>, in his tell-all, decline to name this "major
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">contributor?</ENAMEX>" Now we know. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Sweet</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, did more than introduce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> to the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> world. He paid
Brock <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> for "research expenses." ... What's wrong with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> taking
money like that? Nothing, at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s book. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> apparently
wasn't a full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> at the time. So
someone who wants a story written paid him to research the story. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> does the same thing, they call it a prestigious fellowship! ... But
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> thought it was OK to take the money, why did he seemingly hide
that fact in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> ? And why did it apparently take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> showing the
cancelled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> check to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet</ENAMEX> to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> to fess up? In the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post , Brock</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying "I didn't immediately remember, but I never
denied it. ... I said if [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>] has the documentation, I'd be happy to confirm
it." Do you believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> didn't remember getting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> from a secretive
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> operative? Private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> don't run around offering that kind of
money to freelance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, at least that has (unfortunately)
been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s experience. It's especially implausible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> "didn't
remember" the payment when he had just finished writing what was supposed to be
a confessional article detailing his own journalistic missteps in the service
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-haters--an article that included criticism of "the GOPAC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moneyman</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>) for offering to give "legal expense" checks to the
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> troopers. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> is dissembling about his memory of the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>, what else is he dissembling about? .... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> didn't return a phone
call asking for comment. Here Chatterbox goes the extra <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">mile</NUMEX> to be fair, and
look what happens! ...

            
               Follow-Up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>!: As predicted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, the
relatively good news contained in the overall admissions figures for the entire
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-campus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX> system--which showed black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
admissions dropping by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 17 and 7 percent</NUMEX>, respectively, in the wake of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Prop. 209</ENAMEX>'s rollback of race preferences--was either ignored or buried by the
press. Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> carried the
story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ran a below-the-fold piece on page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A3</TIMEX>, the
headline and lead paragraphs of which discussed the non-news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC</ENAMEX> plans, as
it always does, to offer qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> rejected by their chosen campuses
spots somewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC</ENAMEX> system. Only in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> paragraph does
education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Weiss</ENAMEX> note the "figures released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> showing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX> systemwide did not fare as badly as they had at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX>'s most competitive campuses." Contrast this with the front-page
treatment given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days earlier</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> to the bad news about the large drops in black and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> admissions at those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most-competitive campuses, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s paranoid fears have been borne out! This will only encourage him.
...

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> wondered why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> made such a big deal about the delayed
release of the UC systemwide figures, since the figures for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">individual UC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX> were available <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, and indeed were printed on the
back page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> in a chart accompanying the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX>
story about the grim <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> results. Couldn't any intelligent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>--or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>--have just added up the figures from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX> to
get the systemwide total? The answer is no. If you did that, you'd double-count
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who was accepted, say, to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. Only when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX> itself recalculated the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8-</NUMEX>campus figures to eliminate this
duplication were accurate systemwide results available to the press. Too bad
they didn't get reported. ...

         
      
   
