
   
   
      
         
            Dish of Currie!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> hears that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> was
irritated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> overplayed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s initial denial of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story regarding her testimony before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>....If you recall, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Wechsler, Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, issued a
statement saying she was not "aware" of any legal or ethical impropriety.
Apparently the idea (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/18</NUMEX>) was to leave open the possibility
that others might interpret the facts, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> told them, to involve an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impropriety</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> immediately seized on the statement and declared to the
press that he was "pleased that Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> stated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unambiguously</ENAMEX>--unambiguously--that she's not aware of any unethical
conduct."... Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also used the "aware" fuzzword, it's not clear what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wechsler</ENAMEX> found so irritating. Perhaps he was more annoyed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
spinners, who turned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s statements into a denial that she' d been in any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> coached....But, hey, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wechsler</ENAMEX> is irritated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is
irritated....

            
               The big question in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at this point in time: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Did Clinton</ENAMEX> use
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> to "get to" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> and convince her not to contradict the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in her testimony?... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> was the one who contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">panicked White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> couldn't locate her early in the scandal. (She
wasn't at work because she was testifying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>!) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> "has provided spiritual counseling to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Currie</ENAMEX>...in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> "seemed
uncomfortable when asked about his relationship with Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX>"....But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> is also quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> as doubting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> would have
acted on her own volition when she asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> a
job. That tends to undermine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s case... Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> actually planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souljah</ENAMEX>'s revenge?...

            
               All the heat on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> think: Was the sprawling,
seemingly loony essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis "Skip</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/3</NUMEX>) actually a far more
narrowly-targeted appeal than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thought--specifically, an appeal for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> to lie for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Mary Woods</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">essay</ENAMEX>) is thought to have lied for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>?... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sorry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skip</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s sources
(like everybody else's) say that nobody who knows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> thinks she'll lie for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spinners have also portrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> as incorruptible.
They may, to their regret, be right...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has also learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> once told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> lead such separated lives that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> only learned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was testifying before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> when he saw it on TV!...

            
               Oedipuss at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excelsior</ENAMEX>! To gain new insight into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
lawsuit, go buy a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Maraniss</ENAMEX>' acclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> bio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> in His
Class . Turn to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> photograph, a weathered old portrait of Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>.... Wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX>, that's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. That's a photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Kelley</ENAMEX>!... The similarity is giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> the
Freudian heebie-jeebies, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. (The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was that
business about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> kissing the inside of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thighs</ENAMEX>.)... Those who say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> is too unattractive to draw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>' s
attention--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX> defense--should be forced to ponder the implications
of this photo...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Least Plausible Perjury Payoff Dept.</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
noted ominously that shortly before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> ex-judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Coulson</ENAMEX> gave a
deposition denying a sexual relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "named her
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to come up with name recommendations for his
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>." ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, there's that and more in it for you if you keep
quiet!... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Personally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would have held out for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>....

         
      
   
