
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secret Gore Strategy Revealed</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is doing his part to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from
impeachment. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> strategy apparently calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to be as annoying
as possible, thereby reminding congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decisionmakers</ENAMEX> of the potential
cost of removing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> initiated his campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>,
when he announced plans to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 to $50 million</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money to
implement a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> brainstorm of his: Putting a continuous, live image of
planet <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, as seen from space, on the Internet! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Goldin</ENAMEX> has
been dragooned into supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s goo-goo caprice. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Pike</ENAMEX>, director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Shogren</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> : "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> is big and the
weather is slow, so it's not like there is perceptible motion. It is about as
exciting as watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> grow." Sort of like watching the vice president
himself! ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> continued his scare campaign by phoning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Len Downie</ENAMEX> to complain that a photo the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
had run of the big-blue-marble <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> was upside down! Only after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> hung up
did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downie</ENAMEX> realize that there is no "right side up" or "upside down" when you
are looking at a sphere from outer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign appears to be
highly effective, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s approval ratings have kept rising despite new
and dramatic sex charges. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, calling on its extensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of
insider contacts, has learned details of future components of the still-secret
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GoreBore</ENAMEX> initiative, which will include: A national campaign to convert
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> fields to the metric system; a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Engineering</ENAMEX> Olympics to be
televised during halftime of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> championship <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> game; a gigantic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple of Science</ENAMEX> to be built on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, featuring animatronic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">demographers</ENAMEX> discussing overpopulation; and a proposal to have "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of the
world ... gather and study environmental information on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis and
communicate that data to the world through television." ... And everyone will
wear their underwear on the outside, so we can check! .... Actually, that last
bit about having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> gather <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> environmental information isn't phony.
It's genuine Gorebore ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">QUID PRO QUO</ENAMEX>? 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> sure pulled out all the stops on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> look good. The black-and-white photograph of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Landow</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> who allegedly pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> to keep quiet, made
him look like a vicious psychopath. The photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX>, who says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>
told her to lie, made her look as if she'd just tried out a vacuum cleaner on
her abundant graying hair. ... All this may be part of the implicit deal 60
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> strikes with an important source like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> should be
warned. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> knows how this game is played, mister! ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> conducted a similarly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>-gloved interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> mess ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s worst sin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>? He brought out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had the hots for her from an earlier incident when
then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had asked her to bring some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken soup</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
But then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> neglected to ask the obvious question: since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> was aware
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s interest, wasn't she hoping to use her sexual attraction to help
her get the paying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> job she desperately needed? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> might easily
have answered the question--she might have even said, "Yes, but I didn't expect
him to jump me right there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>"--without undermining her story.
But it would have been nice if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> had asked ...

            
               INTO THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VOID</ENAMEX>: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> almost flunked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journalism 101</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> definitely flunked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX>. What possessed them to release their
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX>-page trove of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> documents on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>? Doesn't every sentient
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> know by now that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> is when you release news you want to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bury</ENAMEX> , because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> news gets reported in the little-read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
papers? ... When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> reveals what it did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, you can bet it
will be on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>! ...

         
      
   
