
   
   
      
         
            Picture This

            When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> gutted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX>, they predicted that art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> from the private sector would come
forward to fill the ensuing culture gap. Balderdash, said the art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
But proving them wrong are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>, which commissioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> historical portraits by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Balma</ENAMEX>, to be unveiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEI</ENAMEX> reception in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon House</ENAMEX>
Office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Building</ENAMEX>.

            Without actually viewing them, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can't comment on whether or not
these are great paintings, but we are prepared to judge these works by their
titles:

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shared Vision</ENAMEX> pairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>. Yes, they
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX>, bringing compromise and tact to everything that they did. Also,
they shared a vision, and are historical. Good job, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEI</ENAMEX>!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resolution</ENAMEX>, we're not so sure about. This painting depicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
War All-Star starting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cheney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scowcroft</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>. Historical, yes, but haven't all of the subjects
crawled under consulting/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>-speaking/book-promoting rocks since the end of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>? It might not be very good, but it's very big--a
whopping <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">144 square feet</NUMEX>.

            Making the strongest argument for the return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment</ENAMEX> is
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Statesmen</ENAMEX>, depicting everybody's favorite '70s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valery Giscard d'Estaing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Callaghan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Schmidt</ENAMEX>.

            Can we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Finley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piss Christ</ENAMEX> back, please?

         
      
   
