
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap Cure</ENAMEX>

            Chatterbox sort of likes the idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> so desperate to avoid
impeachment, to demonstrate that his private behavior doesn't affect his public
conduct, that he is driven to an orgy of accomplishment. First, peace in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>! Then, a tobacco deal! If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wavers on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
reform--well, we can always release a few of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s tapes! ... We know
you got that hummer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>, so you better fix <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> while you're at it. Then
replenish the ozone layer, democratize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, figure out an efficient way to
store electricity, and solve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Color Map Problem</ENAMEX>, and we'll think
about keeping you on. ... Finally, a cure for the consitutional problem of
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-term lethargy! ...

            
               Now we know: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Today</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingon Post</ENAMEX> business section carries a
long front-page piece explaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Johnson</ENAMEX>'s decision to step down as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterboxes</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4/13 and 4/9</NUMEX>). It turns out that although
the announcement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s replacement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raines "</ENAMEX>surprised many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>" -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> source
said it seemed to happen quickly at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>--it was really a
long-planned "crafted departure" that "culminated a process begun several years
ago" when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> decided to "limit his tenure with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>."
You see, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> also believes in "the enormous importance of an orderly
succession," and desired a long period of "extended overlap with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>"
to insure "'the smoothest transition possible.'" Plus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raines</ENAMEX> was ready to go,
and they had to snap him up--even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raines</ENAMEX> had wanted to stay in
government until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> problem was solved. ... That's really all
there is too it. A long-planned departure. An orderly succession ... Nothing to
do with, say, the brief exit "window"--the interval between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
dismissal and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> report-- during which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> can
leave without looking like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> jumping <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> would have
mentioned that if it were a factor. So it must have nothing to do with it. ...
Just a smooth transition ...

            
               Almost <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everything You Need to Know About Washington in One Quote: In</ENAMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Baker</ENAMEX> reported on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> who are
annoyed at former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Panetta</ENAMEX> for continuing to urge the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to come forward and say what happened between him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX> is contrasted with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> apostate, who has a lucrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> contract. An anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
official tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>: "The difference with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon</ENAMEX> is some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wonder, 'You're
not getting paid for this. Why do you keep doing it?'" ... But if you
are getting paid, treason is OK? ... Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX> is saying it because
it's what he thinks about an important issue. .... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyah</ENAMEX>. Can't be.
...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gratuitous Automotive Item</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chtterbox</ENAMEX> says don't give up your
stereotypes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> as economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-producers</ENAMEX> just yet. Consumer
Reports just published its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Auto Issue</ENAMEX>, which contains the most
useful <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-page spread in automotive journalism. These pages (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60 and 61</NUMEX>) rank
the reliability of most new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> sold in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, based on a large reader
survey. (Note this is not a ranking of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s enjoyability--who reads
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> for that?--only of whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is likely to break.)
What leaps out from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s chart is the way <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> have
maintained their edge over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three</ENAMEX>. The top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> are still
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, and the very best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>--such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acura Integra</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda Prelude</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maxima</ENAMEX>. and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SC300</ENAMEX>--are still
built in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> itself, not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. ...
Like many ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>-bred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is back
on top only when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> makes a car <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> might actually want to buy. ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.K.</ENAMEX>, there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SVT Contour</ENAMEX>. But its reliability is suspect.
...

            Another news flash from the Auto Issue concerns the sad performance of the
formerly best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> since its tragic Gaudi-esque redesign. It's
now one of the least-reliable medium sized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> more problems
than average. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, it may be ugly, but it doesn't work that good either! ...
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> is even sub-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX>---the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">900</ENAMEX>, pilloried in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/13</TIMEX>,
has improved somewhat. It's now <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20 percent</NUMEX> worse than average. ... But the
award for the most depressing performance goes to [drumroll] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX>!
With <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86 percent</NUMEX> more problems than average, they're the worst vehicles ranked,
except for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camaro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Firebird V-8s</ENAMEX>. ... Meanwhile, the wildly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attractive Audi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A4</ENAMEX>, contrary to all expectations, may actually be reliable.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> ranked it above even the vaunted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camry</ENAMEX> (which
slipped a bit, but remains <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> better than average). ..."<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Less Gaudi</ENAMEX>,
More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audi</ENAMEX>," is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s new motto. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scariest Quote of the Week:</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Generation X</ENAMEX> pool could care less what role model their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> presents. They want someone to help them stop their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from
smoking."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>

            You mean they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> already? Those punks? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is feeling
ancient indeed. Maybe it's time to plan an orderly succession. ...

         
      
   
