
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox Goes Too Far</ENAMEX>!

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s tale of groping and fondling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>
seems credible is this: if she were making up a story, she could have made up a
much better one. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Bradley</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> that
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made his pass, she remembers saying to him, "Aren't you afraid
that somebody's going to walk in here?" Not exactly the strongest or most
plaintive objection she might have lodged. The pass itself could easily have
been made cruder, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> could have alleged it was repeated--if she'd been
in a fabricating, sympathy-generating mode. Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>, we
have evidence that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> wants to make up a story, she knows how
to pull out all the emotional stops. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> when Willey
decided to get back at a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaun Docking</ENAMEX>, she told him she was
pregnant. But not just pregnant, pregnant with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>! Then she told him she
would have an abortion. Then on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> the abortion was supposed to
happen, she had her then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Steele</ENAMEX>, tell him she'd called it off.
Then she had her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> tell him she'd had a miscarriage! Could any hack
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> have milked that scenario for more drama? Contrast that with the
banality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> story. So, in a perverse way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s tale
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s pregnancy lie actually tends to support her veracity when it comes
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. ... Okay, maybe that's going a bit too far. But you get the point
...

            
               Save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> First! Some pretty good evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> has
seriously distracted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> reports that at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gridiron Dinner</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21</TIMEX>, he sat next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and asked the president
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> reform proposal, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> had unveiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week earlier</TIMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Allen</ENAMEX>'s analysis.) For any president
interested in, say, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term legacy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s plan was a reasonably big
deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s solvency is one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> major domestic
issues facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and "saving" the system was a central theme of his
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> hasn't been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loyalist</ENAMEX> and his social policy proposals (e.g. on welfare) don't always fly, he
speaks with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> as ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX>.
His plan was also considered radical, coming from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX>,
because it suggested using part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s payroll tax to fund
"voluntary personal savings accounts" that would supplement regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> benefits. (Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> was almost immediately blasted from the
left.). Yet, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "did not seem familiar
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s latest plan...." Whatever else you want to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
he's not usually inattentive or uninterested in domestic policy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>
Plan is something he would normally be on top of, were he not preoccupied with
other matters ...

            
               True Love: An excellent conspiratorial moment at a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, party given for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> magazine. Present were: presidential aide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newscaster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ivins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX>, stunt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray Waas</ENAMEX>, the oddball
investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who has been chronicling the machinations of the Vast
Right <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wing Conspiracy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> . At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
point, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waas</ENAMEX>, looking around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> as if to make sure noone was following
him, snuck out the rear door into the unlit back yard. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few seconds</TIMEX> later,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> slipped out the same back door to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waas</ENAMEX>. They could then be seen
having a brief, but intense, tete-a-tete in the darkness. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonus Automotive Item</ENAMEX>: The complaints by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>
about the purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolls-Royce</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> of the previous
acquisition by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rover</ENAMEX>, another prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> marque whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> had
achieved an unfortunate reputation for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less-than-bulletproof</NUMEX> reliability. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old-guard Rover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> complained to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Clarkson</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>'s
quality control policies were "stupid. They just won't tolerate any mistakes at
all." ...

         
      
   
