
   
   
      
         
            Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nukes</ENAMEX> and Bras

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> politicking over the nuclear test ban treaty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the mounting toll from flooding and landslides in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, a
story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers. The WP
leads locally, reporting that charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> are among the most
popular in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> in existence, charters already enroll
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly ten</NUMEX> percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX>'s public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> from both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> agree it's unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will be
able to muster the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> majority needed to approve the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test</ENAMEX>
Ban <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty</ENAMEX>. The question now is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, a vocal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of the pact, will be able to bring it to a vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this week</TIMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embarrass Clinton</ENAMEX> with a defeat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> hopes to persuade moderate
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who largely dislike the treaty but are reluctant to vote it down
because they fear that action would make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> look weak abroad, to put off
considering the ban for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to a year</TIMEX>. A vote to delay needs only a simple
majority, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> are looking for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defectors</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floods</ENAMEX> and mudslides have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 250</NUMEX> in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of record-breaking rain, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernesto Zedillo</ENAMEX> calls it "the tragedy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> --which puts the death toll at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">330</NUMEX> despite an earlier deadline than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's--reports from the hard-hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teziutlan</ENAMEX>, where at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> were killed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> when a terraced block of concrete
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX> slid down a mountainside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's off-lead reports on an upcoming battle in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on the
future of stem-cell research, a promising but highly controversial form of
medical exploration that draws material from human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">embryos</ENAMEX> and aborted fetuses.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> predict that stem cells may provide the building blocks for
treatments to ailments from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's disease</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. In their calls for
more stem-cell money, they're backed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient groups</ENAMEX> but opposed by
right-to-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> will take up the question <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts some good news for AT&T: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX> voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to relax rules on how much of the cable
industry a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can legally control. In its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> ruling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
smiling on corporate consolidation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> said that because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have
begun offering new kinds of service over cable wire--namely high-speed Internet
access and local telephone service--competition will be bolstered by changing
the ownership laws, not stifled. The decision means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s recent
purchase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media One Group</ENAMEX> can go forward without the telephone giant
having to sell off other cable properties.

            Also on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's front is the news that the computer industry may
soon have trouble keeping up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s Law, the oft-cited rule maintaining
that computing power doubles every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX>. In an article in the journal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> , an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul A. Packan</ENAMEX> reports that as silicon
chips continue to shrink, their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> are running up against stubborn
physical limits for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time--already, the smallest transistors have
insulating layers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a few atoms</NUMEX> thick.

            An LAT front-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pager</ENAMEX> tells of growing cracks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">façade.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disunity</ENAMEX> and chaos were the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R.P. Minnesota</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> watched his approval rating plummet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> points--and heard
calls that he should resign from the party--after the publication of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> interview in which he ridiculed organized religion and said he
wouldn't mind being reborn as an extra-large bra. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX> are
now confronted with the possibility that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> very different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will
jockey for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> presidential nomination: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of those might have something to say on the bra issue.)

            The WP fronts a report that early campaign-trail promises by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, if enacted, would eat up nearly all of the projected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trillion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> surplus over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has made the
costlier pledges so far: his ambitious universal health-care initiative would
by itself use the entire surplus, according to some estimates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s spending
plans include tax cuts up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 billion</NUMEX>, universal preschool, and his own
more modest health-care package.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>, who reported on his share of
culture-war skirmishes as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s chief theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '90s</TIMEX>, weighs in on the controversy surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week-old</TIMEX> exhibit "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> casts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>--who has
threatened to shut down the exhibit of work by a group of young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
because he thinks it's full of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, "sick stuff"--as a schoolyard
tough who likes to pick on scrawny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. "Could it be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> asks, "a struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in an outer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">borough</ENAMEX>, is easier to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> cultural mecca with a heavy-hitting board bulging with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>?"

         
      
   
