
   
   
      
         
            Defending <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rudy, Part II</ENAMEX>

            The dispute over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> can force the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum of Art</ENAMEX> to
withdraw from its new "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>"
art exhibit a painting depicting the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> covered in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant dung</ENAMEX> (and
surrounded, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> neglected to mention 
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last time</TIMEX>, by photographs of genitals scissored out of porno <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>) has
entered federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Abrams</ENAMEX> to sue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. Here is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX> said in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28</TIMEX> complaint for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">declaratory</ENAMEX> and injunctive relief (which ought to be on the Web, but
isn't):

            

               
                  Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> may generally choose to fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> as it sees fit, it
may not make funding decisions for the purpose of punishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s
constitutionally protected expression. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s repeatedly announced
decision to retaliate against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMA</ENAMEX> is in violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment of the Constitution</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, as made applicable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourteenth Amendment of the Constitution</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            Does a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s constitutional right to free expression, which is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undeniable</ENAMEX>, really include the right to demand a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidy? (The city
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> provides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>'s budget.) To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>,
the notion is transparently absurd. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preeminent</ENAMEX> first-amendment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justly</ENAMEX> celebrated for defending the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon Papers</ENAMEX> case. Can he possibly have the law on his side?
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> jumped into the fight by voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unanimously</ENAMEX> to
withhold <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>; click here to read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>'s account.)

            Guided by a pretty good news analysis piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> (which has
been reflexively anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> in most of its coverage), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> looked up
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s most recent
ruling touching on this question, in a case where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Finley</ENAMEX>, the
performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> famous for smearing chocolate on her breasts, sued the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX> for withdrawing a grant. The decision, by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Day O'Connor</ENAMEX>, gives much comfort to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> by
flatly stating that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> certainly has application in the
subsidy context." Here is some more language from the decision that bolsters
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  We have stated that, even in the provision of subsidies, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
may not "ai[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>] at the suppression of dangerous ideas," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regan</ENAMEX>, supra , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">461</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">550</NUMEX> (internal quotation marks omitted), and if a subsidy were
"manipulated" to have a "coercive effect," then relief could be appropriate.
See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkansas Writers' Project, Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragland</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">481 U.S. 221, 237</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>)
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>, dissenting); see also <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Leathers v. Medlock , 499 U.S. 439</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">447</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>) ("[<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>]ifferential taxation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> is
constitutionally suspect when it threatens to suppress the expression of
particular ideas or viewpoints"). In addition, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> itself concedes, a
more pressing constitutional question would arise if government funding
resulted in the imposition of a disproportionate burden calculated to drive
"certain ideas or viewpoints from the marketplace." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N. Y.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Crime Victims Bd</ENAMEX>. , <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">502 U.S. 105, 116</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>);
see Brief for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Petitioners 38</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">n.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>.
               

            

            But is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, in withdrawing funding that indirectly subsidizes a
shit-smeared madonna, suppressing an idea, or merely saying it wants no
part in promoting it? (In practice, the most efficient way to publicize
an idea is to condemn it; the madonna painting has by now been reproduced,
albeit in miniature, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and countless other news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>. If
you missed it before, click here.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mister Justice Chatterbox</ENAMEX> humbly dissents from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>'s
view that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> has any "application in the subsidy
context." This puts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mister Justice Chatterbox</ENAMEX> in agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurist</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is not in the habit of praising. Scalia, though
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concurring</ENAMEX> in the decision (which ultimately favored the NEA
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finley</ENAMEX>), wrote a somewhat mocking critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX>'s muddy
reasoning on this question that was so lucid that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will give him the
last word:

            

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> reads: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> shall make no law ...
abridging the freedom of speech." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.Const.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amdt</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (emphasis added).
To abridge is "to contract, to diminish; to deprive of." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. Sheridan</ENAMEX>, A
Complete <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of the English Language</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6th ed.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1796</TIMEX>). With the
enactment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">§954</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did not abridge the speech of those
who disdain the beliefs and values of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, nor did it abridge
indecent speech. Those who wish to create indecent and disrespectful art are as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unconstrained</ENAMEX> now as they were before the enactment of this statute.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Avant-garde artistes</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> remain entirely free to
épater les bourgeois ; they are merely deprived of the additional
satisfaction of having the bourgeoisie taxed to pay for it. It is preposterous
to equate the denial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> subsidy with measures " ' "aimed at the
suppression of dangerous ideas." ' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regan</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxation</ENAMEX> with Representation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">461 U.S. 540, 550</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>) (emphasis added) (quoting Cammarano
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">v. United States , 358 U.S. 498, 513</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>), in turn quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speiser</ENAMEX> v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">357 U.S. 513, 519</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>)). "The reason that denial of
participation in a tax exemption or other subsidy scheme does not necessarily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'infringe</ENAMEX>' a fundamental right is that--unlike direct restriction or
prohibition--such a denial does not, as a general rule, have any significant
coercive effect ." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers' Project, Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragland</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">481</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">221, 237</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>, dissenting).
               

            

         
      
   
