
   
   
      
         
            On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rereading G&uuml</ENAMEX>;nter Grass

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Günter Grass</ENAMEX> won his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have argued that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grass</ENAMEX>' political views make him a parody of a left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>:
Who can take seriously a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who mourns the lost asceticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Germany</ENAMEX>?
But the question the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish Academy</ENAMEX> forces us to address is not whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grass</ENAMEX>
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> apologist. The question is, is he now or has he ever been a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>?

            Pretty much everyone agrees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX> is not a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> now. Nothing
he has written since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, when he completed his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> novels-- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danzig Trilogy</ENAMEX> , that is, which is made up of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tin Drum</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dog Years</ENAMEX> --is memorable, and a lot of it is bad. That
includes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Flounder</ENAMEX> , published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, an epic
disquisition on the perfidy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grass</ENAMEX>' leftism does not extend to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feminism</ENAMEX>) that is narrated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and continues through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, with
asides on matters of sexual and culinary history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> has not read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grass</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> novel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rat</ENAMEX> , but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Buruma</ENAMEX> has described it as "tales of
the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX> riding through the forest in
which concentration-camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> disguised as mutilated fairy-tale characters
were roaming around the poisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>." ("This typically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> combination of
dark ecology and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> trauma found such disfavor," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buruma</ENAMEX> continues, "that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX> went off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> to sulk.") <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> read large chunks of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grass</ENAMEX>' latest novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Century</ENAMEX> , to be published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this December</TIMEX>, and it seemed like a decidedly minor book--a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ragtime</ENAMEX> -like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fantasia</ENAMEX> comprising <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> short monologues, each narrated by someone with some
connection to one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 100 years</TIMEX>, none of them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.L. Doctorow</ENAMEX>'s wit
or affection. In any case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish Academy</ENAMEX> has explained why it gave Grass
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>--because of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tin Drum</ENAMEX> , published in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish Academy</ENAMEX>'s defense of their selection echoes the conventional
wisdom on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tin Drum</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 40 years</TIMEX>: that it made German
literature plausible after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> had made it impossible. Specifically,
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Tin Drum</ENAMEX> brought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> literature back to life
"after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linguistic</ENAMEX> and moral destruction." This statement harks back
to a famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> essay by the literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steiner</ENAMEX>, who asked
"whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> language had survived the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> era, whether words
poisoned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goebbels</ENAMEX> and used to regulate and justify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belsen</ENAMEX> could ever again
serve the needs of moral truth and poetic perception."

            What is it about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tin Drum</ENAMEX> that unpoisoned the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> language and
made it safe for moral truth? The novel tells the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oskar Matzerath</ENAMEX>, who
was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danzig</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX> himself was), a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> on the border between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oskar</ENAMEX> possesses an adult awareness from birth but develops
a powerful revulsion against the petit-bourgeois society in which he finds
himself, so at the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> he decides to stop growing up. This he achieves by
throwing himself down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar stairs</ENAMEX>. Thereafter he plays a tin drum in lieu of
speaking aloud and, when anyone tries to take it away, screams so shrilly that
he shatters glass all around him. Kept home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, he becomes an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unblinking observer</ENAMEX> of the world around him--his mother's adultery, the rise of
Nazism, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> , the invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, the ravages of war, and
after the war, the "economic miracle."

            Contrary to the popular understanding of the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oskar</ENAMEX> does not provide
its moral <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. He is not anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>, nor does his story per se serve
as a critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>-era <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. Whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Tin</ENAMEX>
Drum is an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> novel, they invariably cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> scenes. In the
first, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oskar</ENAMEX>, sheltered under a rostrum at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> rally, disrupts the
proceedings by pounding out the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX>-time beat of a waltz and
confusing the marching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, so that everyone waltzes off. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> scene
occurs during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of broken glass when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis</ENAMEX>
destroyed most of the synagogues and many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oskar</ENAMEX> discovers that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> who sells him his tin drums has committed
suicide in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, while storm troopers rampage around his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX>, poking it
with puppets and dropping their pants to shit on the floor.

            It soon becomes clear, however, that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oskar's</ENAMEX> drumming nor his
thoughts on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> toy-store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> are politically motivated. He is a
perfectly amoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> with the self-absorption of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>; an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> but
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> who neither is nor isn't a responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, he's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grass</ENAMEX>' disturbingly neutral allegory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oskar</ENAMEX> will
willingly play his drum for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. Nor is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> a sympathetic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. In an earlier scene, he seemed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>-era movie: a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>
obsessed with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, in this case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oskar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, whom he begs on
bended knee to run away with him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tin Drum</ENAMEX> has a negative take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazism</ENAMEX>, it is expressed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obliquely</ENAMEX>, through explosive bursts of irreverent language, and by dint of the
fact that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX> talks about things such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> --something few other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> did at the time, at
least not so boldly. In the toy-store scene, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oskar</ENAMEX> says of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> who also took part in the great national pogrom, though he wasn't in
that particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyn</ENAMEX> was not there," he says, "just as the ones who
were there were not somewhere else"--a swipe at all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> who claimed not
to have been around whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> crimes took place. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> has not read
the book in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, but those who have say the writing is stuffed with
similarly witty phrasing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Magnus Enzensberger</ENAMEX> has
written of how Grass ranges with masterly skill from high-flown parodies of
Catholic litany to the impersonal tone of case histories to slang to dialect
and so on.

            But does relentless, even brilliant, irony remain an adequate response to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Reich</ENAMEX>, knowing as we do now so much more than we did then? The German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholar Ernestine Schlant</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>) doesn't think so. She
recently published a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Language of Silence</ENAMEX> , about German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">literature</ENAMEX>'s relationship to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, in which she accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grass</ENAMEX> of a
flippant disregard for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]here is an ingrained obtuseness
and insensitivity to those who suffered and died, evident in a language where
silence is veiled in verbal dexterity and a creative exuberance rooted in
pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aesthetics</ENAMEX>." This seems strong--you can condemn a criminal regime
through an unsympathetic portrayal of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> as well as through
sympathy for those they killed--but it's true that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Grass'</ENAMEX> dance of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macabre</ENAMEX> does come off as weirdly timid. Compare the eeriest passages of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tin Drum</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Jonah Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s descriptions of the wintry death
marches by means of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> killed off most of the remainder of their
concentration-camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the war</TIMEX>--exercises in pure
surrealism, with skeletons moving slowly through a well-fed German
countryside--and suddenly even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX>' fertile imagination seems
impoverished.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grass</ENAMEX>' sarcasm is a welcome respite from the heavy-handed literalism of so
much contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> narrative, from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> television series
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX> (another mass catalyst for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> self-awareness) to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List to the odious <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jakob the Liar</ENAMEX> . And yet, for all
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grass</ENAMEX>' rage at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s crimes, the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tin Drum</ENAMEX> rarely
names those crimes or explores their existence, and seems so focused on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, with little empathy to spare for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, makes the
book feel more like a step on the way to something than like the thing
itself--whether that thing be a more moral or simply a greater work of
literature. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years</TIMEX> after the book came out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steiner</ENAMEX> himself doubted
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX> really was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> literature that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were
making him out to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Steiner</ENAMEX>'s name. His quibble was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grass</ENAMEX>' efforts to
come up with an adequate description of the brutality of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> society had in
many ways brutalized him: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX>," he writes, "is nearly always too long;
nearly always too loud." But, he concluded, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Totalitarianism</ENAMEX> makes provincial.
... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grass</ENAMEX>'] ponderous gait, the outmoded flavor of his audacities, are part of
the price <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> literature has to pay for its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in isolation." In short,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tin Drum</ENAMEX> did restore <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> literature to the world and the world to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> literature. But like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX> himself, what once seemed a masterwork has
been overtaken by history.

         
      
   
