
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler Endorses Buchanan</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>'s scheduled debate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at its national
convention over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s possible presidential endorsement of either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> is meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times front has only a postage-stamp-sized reefer to its Page B1
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> story, choosing instead to follow up on its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
flood/mud aftermath, a story nobody else fronts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's emphasis
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is on the spreading unrest among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 200,000</NUMEX> displaced survivors
demanding faster distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
which fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>, leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s strong
opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> thoughts of supplying heating oil and other aid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , is that such supplies
might shore up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s political position by alleviating public
discontent. The line the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has drawn is relieving ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbians</ENAMEX>'
suffering, yes, rebuilding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>, no. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , often thought to be hung up on the federal
government, homebodies in a big way, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> front-pagers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twanging</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">local</ENAMEX> instead. The paper stuffs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> convention and leads with
the resignation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> coverage lends plenty of credence to the idea that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> is genuinely undecided about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. In the third
paragraph it quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> saying he's uncertain of the outcome and waits until
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> to quote a union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has "a good chance." By
contrast, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is "assured" of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>'s endorsement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> is a bit less emphatic, saying that
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> now say they have the votes.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> include an observation that impugns the
choice's significance: If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> does indeed make a choice now, it will be
its earliest endorsement since going for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mondale</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says
that was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> front the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colt Manufacturing</ENAMEX>, a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of handguns (and, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out in a nice historical touch, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">six-shooter</ENAMEX>), to abandon much of its retail handgun business. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will
still sell to law enforcement and the military but will basically stop selling
weapons to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> who aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> of old-style commemorative <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>.
Apparently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s motivation is to avoid legal liability and money
damages possibly arising from verdicts in any of the lawsuits currently being
brought by various local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colt</ENAMEX> shift was discovered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , a fact mentioned in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .

            An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity Barringer</ENAMEX> makes an observation that
raises deep questions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s true values: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> following the
simultaneous breaking of well-researched allegations of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> massacre of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> war and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura Playboy</ENAMEX>
interview, less and less was said about the former and more and more was said
about the latter.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has instructed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health Service</ENAMEX> not to prescribe the new anti-flu <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glaxo</ENAMEX>. Given that this is what the headline says, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> might well
conclude that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brits</ENAMEX> believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is dangerous. That's why it's a
mistake for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> to wait until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> paragraph to mention
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> merely thinks that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> isn't cost-effective.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> gives op-ed space to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> so that he can continue to develop his foreign
policy position on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Der Patzer</ENAMEX> tries to firm up his view that
before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s declaration of war on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, it posed no strategic threat
to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> including an appeal to ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, who said, "Everything
I undertake is directed against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. If the West is too stupid and too blind
to comprehend that, I will be forced to come to an understanding with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>, to smash the West and then after its defeat, to turn against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>." Gee, wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> didn't quote the clearest thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
have to make in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>."

            The LAT fronts a report about tighter rules regarding personal uses
of office computers and how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are increasingly using sophisticated
tracking technology to enforce them. Examples in the story of concerns where
the new technology and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> resentment it breeds are in evidence:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Bell</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Airlines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX>. There's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> company
that almost surely is a hotbed for this issue that the story makes no mention
of: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
