
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bomb Letter Bomb</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> each lead with the latest development in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s attempt to stave off a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> defeat of the comprehensive
nuclear test ban treaty--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s submission of a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> asking him to postpone his planned floor vote on the
treaty. The papers report <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s reaction: The letter isn't enough--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
must also agree not to bring the treaty back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>.
Which, so far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has not agreed to do. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
plays the story on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, leading instead with its latest poll (undertaken
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>) showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> percentage points closer
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> than he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s last survey <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
would beat both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> quoted in the story says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore/Bradley</ENAMEX> is headed toward a "toss-up" and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> seems to have his
party's nomination "wrapped up." (The story saves the number of people
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">polled--976</ENAMEX>--for the last sentence.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> makes it seem that the
fate of the treaty is genuinely up in the air, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraph</ENAMEX> suggests a deal may be in the works that will avoid the treaty's
certain defeat. Ditto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which says (even in its headline) a
"plan" is in the works that will achieve just that. But even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
sees a lot of brinkmanship yet to come and admits a vote could come as early as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            Everybody explains that ratification (which is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is
contemplating) by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> perceived nuclear capable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> is required to
make it effective. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> helpfully adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> have
signaled that they will "take their lead" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote. The
Times also does the best job of explaining the politics in play right
now, noting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> is "tiptoeing" between a majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who
are probably against the treaty but don't want to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> a diplomatic
setback on the one hand, and hard-liners in his party on the other who want to
kill the treaty at all domestic and international costs; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Daschle</ENAMEX> has to contend with a minority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who want a
vote now so that once defeated, the treaty becomes a viable campaign issue.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does better on the big picture, explaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s
additional demand for postponement until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> is designed precisely to immunize
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> from the treaty during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2000</TIMEX> election. And although everybody
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed the treaty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, it's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> that explains where it's been since then: bottled up in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Relations Committee</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front the likelihood that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
soon) will mark, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever, the planet's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> totaling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. The thrust of the stories--and of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> op-ed (and of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>"
takeout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>)--is that, in the shadow of the dizzying number there
is non-Malthusian news. It's noted that thanks to education efforts and the
wider dissemination of birth control, the population growth rate in most places
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> what it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation ago</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , by the way, makes
the point that this fact doesn't show that books like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Population Bomb</ENAMEX>"
were nuts--it was because of such alarms that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> started
attacking the growth rate problem.) The main storm cloud the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> sees
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> distribution ( not food supply , which is generally
adequate) needs to improve, while the LAT wonders if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> will
continue to stay on top of reproductive "care."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> runs a fine feature about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s obstinate attachment to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Soviet</ENAMEX> era big ticket weapons systems and its concomitant failure to fully
tap the potential of newer, smaller ideas. This is no cliché-spouting
editorial, but rather a long detailed narrative of what's become of unmanned
aerial drones in the hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20 years</TIMEX>. The primary
problem has been that traditional weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> in uniform have seen drones
as threats. For instance, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>, so the story explains, the plan to
develop unmanned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> ran into the formidable opposition of the carrier
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">admirals</ENAMEX>. The upshot is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> is still spending only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> on
this idea, compared to say, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> it wanted for the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fighter</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports inside that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Command</ENAMEX> held a formal ceremony where it was renamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Forces Command</ENAMEX>.
The change involved new banners and command insignia and new stationery. But
the regional area of responsibility--the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX>--remains basically the
same. The point of the name change is to emphasize the importance of the
various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> working together. But it's a real lapse for the
Post not to have told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> what the non-change change cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX> leading the revolt against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. And off a front-page picture, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> inside reports on the
egg-throwing protest by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chefs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> against a new tax structure they
feel hurts traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX> and aids fast food. These are interesting sorts
of stories, but one has to wonder if there isn't another reason why they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staples</ENAMEX> of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>: to help justify having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> stationed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, which although a great place to live, produces virtually no real
news.

            Upon seeing the headline over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">op-edder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Collins</ENAMEX>' effort,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Papers braced for embarrassing personal revelations of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un- Times</ENAMEX> ly sort. The column, which instead turns out to be about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> being so profoundly solipsistic that he couldn't remember the names of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is slugged "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Boy Spot</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
