
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erudition</ENAMEX> vs. Sense
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Alan</ENAMEX>:

            Oh no, we agree! We've really got to stop this collaboration across the
political spectrum. At this rate, we'll be singing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Shall Overcome</ENAMEX>" before
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> is over. And what happens to the "culture wars" when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on
both sides start laying down their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>? This is terrible. In addition to his
other offenses, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> is apparently the one we can blame for this
alarming development.

            Before I resume my trashing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>, let me admit that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>
contains many passages that are beautifully written. As we saw in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>'
previous book, he can be quite a sculptor with words. And there are occasional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flashes of insight</ENAMEX>. For instance <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> almost casually notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was
"always happier in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here and Now</ENAMEX>. His tendency to reminisce ... was not a
looking back so much as an eager application of history to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>."
This is exactly right, and an apt response to many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who have
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> accused him of incurable nostalgia and trying to take the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> back to the past that never was. Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> could care less about
"turning back the clock." He employed the imagery of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">e.g.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proceeding West</ENAMEX> in covered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagons</ENAMEX>) to construct a kind of imaginative portrait
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>; then he worked relentlessly to bend the future (e.g. space
exploration and entrepreneurship as the modern equivalent of the early
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">settlers</ENAMEX>) to his vision and his will.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris admires Reagan</ENAMEX>'s imagination and will; it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s intellect and
cultural taste he cannot help but disdain. Sample passage: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like Charles Ryder</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brideshead Revisited</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> found himself homeless, middle-aged and
loveless as his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> waned. Or, to quote a book he was more likely
to have read, there was this passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kings Row ...</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>'s book
is full of this kind of snobbery.

            But once again, let me raise the question of who is the real sophisticate
and who is the ignoramus. I don't deny that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">connoisseur</ENAMEX> of
wine and literature than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. But when statesmanship requires that the chasm
between ideas and action be bridged, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> becomes evident and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reveals</ENAMEX> himself to be, well, a complete idiot.

            For instance, here is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s famous "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tear Down This Wall"</ENAMEX> speech, drafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speechwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Robinson</ENAMEX> and staged
before an enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brandenburg Gate</ENAMEX>. After a sneering account
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s remarks that entirely misses their political significance, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
writes,

            

               What a rhetorical opportunity missed. He could have read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Frost</ENAMEX>'s poem
on the subject, 'Something there is that doesn't love a wall,' to simple and
shattering effect. Or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edna St. Vincent Millay</ENAMEX>'s lines ... 'Only now for
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I see/ This wall is actually a wall, a thing/ Come up between
us, shutting me away/ From you ... I do not know you any more.'

            

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> kidding us here? Or has erudition drowned out all good sense? I
suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edna Millay</ENAMEX> would be fitting in this context if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> were trying to
strike up a romantic relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frost</ENAMEX> example is even
worse. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> seems to have totally missed the point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frost</ENAMEX>'s poem, which
concludes with the observation that good fences make good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. Would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> have been better off saying, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, good fences make good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>"? Thank you, speechwriter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>! And now: off to the insane
asylum!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>, perhaps you and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will consider me unduly harsh, but I
think I am being duly harsh. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> may be a wordsmith and an aesthete, but he
is politically incompetent to evaluate his subject, a thoroughly political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
And he has missed an opportunity that cannot be recovered: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> had a level
of continuous access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> that no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> will ever have. He has
abrogated his moral responsibility to history in a manner that is close to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unforgivable</ENAMEX>. Which leaves the big question: Who picked this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>? And why?

            Best,
Dinesh

         
      
   
