
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Ho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A-Merging We Will Go</ENAMEX>

            In a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-column lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> announces the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI Worldcom</ENAMEX> merger, which was hinted at in the papers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115 billion</NUMEX> deal (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$108</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion</ENAMEX>) will be announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--barring an unlikely last-minute offer from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell South</ENAMEX>--and will likely be approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
front this story but lead with the largest-ever successful claim against an insurance
must pay to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> lost value when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX> ordered
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> to make repairs with low-cost, generic parts. (It works out to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $100</NUMEX> for each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policyholders</ENAMEX> in the "class" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> taking
action against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> argued that the parts were
sub-standard, while the insurance industry and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer groups</ENAMEX> argued that
using generic parts keeps down premiums. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX> insures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and the verdict will almost certainly
lead to higher industrywide premiums within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> county
court awards fraud damages, the bill for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could reach <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>.

            The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> formed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI-Worldcom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> will control <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 30</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> long-distance market--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX>--and
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 billion</NUMEX> will be the biggest telecom in the world, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . The merger
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> the increasing importance of wireless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and data-voice
integration. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> has a large data network, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> a large wireless <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.) As
usual, the papers spice the abstract financial story with corporate intrigue:
The code names for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> were "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snow</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
explains--thus the deal became known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow White</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oooh</ENAMEX>.) When the "upstart
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">telecom Bell-South</ENAMEX> made an offer, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was called "Project
Blue." All the stories are sourced to anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> "close to the
deal."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> investigates the ban on cell-phone use during commercial
flights and finds that it is not supported by any empirical evidence. The ban,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes, is actually an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> rule, not an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> rule, designed
to limit interference with ground-to-ground cell communication. (Air-to-ground
signals sometimes override those on the ground.) A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> study commissioned by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> analyzed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>'s worth of inflight instrument-malfunction reports
and could not trace a single incident to a cell phone. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>
have bombarded their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> with cell waves and failed to record any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interference; Boeing</ENAMEX> still recommends that phones not be used in the air--but
to prevent electronic interference similar to (though slightly stronger than)
that of a laptop or CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> on corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jets</ENAMEX> use cell phones <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of times a day without incident, while
commercial air <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> must use airline-installed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Airfones</ENAMEX>" at rates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>
times that of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>-phones. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> are reported to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
percent of this take.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> have announced a joint
venture to develop technology for online teaching. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> will initially
invest <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. What is unusual about this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> in
corporate-sponsored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R&D</ENAMEX>, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , is that this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX> serves the core interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> more than those of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dismissive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> are already referring to the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-Campus</ENAMEX>--as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSMIT</ENAMEX>."

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> editorial page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Zelikow</ENAMEX> defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s refusal to denounce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>,
as other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have done. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelikow</ENAMEX> compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s stance to that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Eisenhower</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> let his work in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> speak for itself rather
than attack isolationist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Taft</ENAMEX>. "The shouting about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s
defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> isolationism in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelikow</ENAMEX> writes, "has
deflected attention from the real task: Defeat the ideas, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to
read 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ballot Box" on Buchanan and the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>.)

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Allen Paulos</ENAMEX> notes that no
amount of technological advance will repeal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy's Law</ENAMEX>--hence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars Climate Orbiter</ENAMEX>, which crashed after being fed data in pounds
rather than newtons. Increasingly complex human systems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulos</ENAMEX> writes, will
never escape the clutches of foolish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. "To the contrary, it may be that
the more complex a gadget is, the more links with quite fallible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
necessary." (To read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulos</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> dispatches in

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>," click 
here.)

            How strong is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s economy? So strong, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
that many corporate recruiters are doing something unprecedented: hiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal-arts</ENAMEX> graduates. "I don't want to say [graduating liberal-arts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>]
are wined and dined," says an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ursinus</ENAMEX> guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>, "but they are taken
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care of.</ENAMEX> They come with presents! Day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> and stress balls and fun things
that keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> with that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s name in mind." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> still
has his 
                  Slate
                baseball cap around here somewhere
...

         
      
   
