
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Charm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s Hair
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweetie</ENAMEX>--

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> win! Also, as long as I'm on parochial issues, it is freezing cold
here, and the radiators in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> are making those knocking and
whispering noises that make all prewar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> seem like they
were built on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> graveyards. Furthermore, there is yet another
Op-Ed piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> today on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> show,
this one by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philippe de Montebello</ENAMEX>, in which he characterizes the works on
display there as by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> "who deserve to remain obscure or be forgotten,"
boldly opining, "I have seen the exhibition, and I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> has no
clothes." Strong words for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> not long ago devoted a
heavily promoted show to the designs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX> featuring such
culturally important artifacts as the famous safety-pin-adorned dress worn by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Hurley</ENAMEX> to, I believe, the premiere of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Weddings</ENAMEX> and a
Funeral .

            I like your conspiracy theory, but where most such theories fall apart on
the unlikelihood of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> being sufficiently organized to carry off
such a thing, yours falls apart on the unlikelihood of any alternative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s being sufficiently disorganized not to understand the benefits of
serving the interests of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>. Also, while I don't like to quibble, I
don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> is a self-admitted cokehead. Did you happen to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX>'s interview with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tearful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> senior on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>? I don't think it would be an exaggeration to say that you frequently see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grittier</ENAMEX> reporting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">VH1</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behind the Music</ENAMEX> , especially the part where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was so overcome with emotion while reading a letter he wrote to a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had been killed in battle during his
administration that he was unable to continue, and had to hand the task over to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> (on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> --that's never happened on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behind the</ENAMEX>
Music , although I didn't watch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every minute</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poison</ENAMEX>, so you
never know).

            I think Pokémon are adorable, and also don't want to hear any more bad words
about those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> ads. I like those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> ads, because I always feel
sympathy for the zombie-like teen.

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX> I read your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mojo</ENAMEX> memoir of playing to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70,000</NUMEX> baffled
rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hyde Park</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deviants</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. I particularly
enjoyed the picture of you wearing a very <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> garment that makes you look like
a giant amphetamine-crazed Q-Tip. What the hell is that thing? What were you
going to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX>? I interviewed him recently, and found him to
have a charm so forceful that it was akin to encountering a major climatic
condition, which surprisingly few of the professionally famous do. In fact, if
there is a sad thing to know about interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> whose work you admire,
it is that their work may well be the only thing about them you do. Also, the
record that came out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> is very good.

            Have you had any coverage out there of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s possible presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">candidacy</ENAMEX>, or is that just a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> story? Now, there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who understands
the benefits of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, since I don't see how he could get his hair to
stay like that without liberal applications of it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
Mim

         
      
   
