
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            You know the stock market isn't feeling especially jaunty when the best news
it gets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> is that economic growth might be slowing. But there are all
sorts of things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to be worrying about, despite the fact that
earnings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the latest quarter</TIMEX> are expected to be exceptional and that it
increasingly looks as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> won't raise interest rates when it meets on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. Among the worries: It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halloween</ENAMEX>, you see, really freaks
Wall Street out. Anyway, it'll be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October all month</TIMEX>. Which should mean that
I'll have a lot to write about, at least. And so, on to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s Cocktail
Chat.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "3Com's shares continued to do well as the market reacted to the news
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is planning to spin off its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> . Of course,
if you're 3Com, is it really good news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> think more highly of a
division that accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 12 percent</NUMEX> of your revenue than they do
of the entire rest of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Successive headlines on 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TheStreet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX> news
page read: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Central Bankers Look Set to Lengthen the Good Times</ENAMEX>' and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Leaders Fiddle As World Burns</ENAMEX>.' In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX>, apparently, burning worlds
are good times."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Rumors swirled about a possible deal between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America Online</ENAMEX> and
broadband-access provider <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Excite@Home</ENAMEX> , a deal that would finally give AOL
entry into the world of high-speed Internet access. Actually, the deal would
really be between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, which has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58 percent</NUMEX> of the voting shares
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Excite@Home</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite@Home</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> say no deal will be done without
their full approval , but it's a little unclear what that means. Can they
filibuster like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, or what?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "TiVo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of that device that lets you save TV programs to a hard
drive and replay it whenever you want, went public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and saw its
shares double . I'm still not sure how different this thing is from a VCR.
But I do want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, which has to bode well for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avon</ENAMEX> issued an earnings warning, and saw its stock price get
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clubbed</ENAMEX> . Of course, what else can you expect when you consider that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avon Lady</ENAMEX> way of selling is essentially the anti-Internet. Whatever the
opposite of a .<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> stock is, that's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Avon</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "Calling for an end to the patchwork of state and local tax rules,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Armstrong</ENAMEX> complained that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had to file
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39,912</NUMEX> different tax returns in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> alone. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> and tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> are reportedly confused about exactly why that's
a problem."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "The 
                  Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
                said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> blamed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
stock-market volatility on 'a change in the composition of the Standard &
Poor's 500-stock index, shock at the soaring price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, rumors that some
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> were madly selling stocks to cover losing bets
against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end-of-month</TIMEX> portfolio changes, anxiety over interest rates and
worries about possible market troubles as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> approaches.' What about
the plague of locusts and the rain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX>?"

         
      
   
