
   
   
      
         
            Pachydermatitis
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Steve</ENAMEX>:

             Hope all's well. I myself have
been keeping busy maintaining the aftermath of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Spiegelman</ENAMEX>--just got the new issue of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comics Journal</ENAMEX> with your quotes in it, by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>--but I honestly wish this whole thing would go away. But as an editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX>, nothing depresses me more than the overnight disintegration of the
once-interesting "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" section--where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> cartoons each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>--into the
same mainstream tripe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
"Perspectives" section and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
editorial page offer. It was never perfect, but the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" used to
run the more daring and adventurous editorial cartoons around (stuff that
actually editorialized!) by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Tomorrow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tom the Dancing Bug</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bolling</ENAMEX>,
and yours truly; now it's back to cross-hatching, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> and donkeys, and
dumb gags about the news. Can you and I agree that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> who uses
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pachyderms</ENAMEX> to denote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> should be dispatched to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> for ritual
stoning at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talidrome</ENAMEX>?

            I know few of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftie pals</ENAMEX> will be sad for the Colt
gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which is laying off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Hartford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, workers
and trashing its consumer business because it's been savaged by lawsuits. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are a legal product, and I find it yet another statement about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-Clintonian</ENAMEX> world we live in that we don't have the balls to simply make a
product illegal but see nothing wrong with using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to harrass its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> out of business. For instance, smoking should obviously be banned
as the No. 1 cause of premature death in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, not to mention of
countless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and forest fires. But since no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> has the guts to
advocate such a drastic (in my view, rational) measure, we end up with zillions
of lawsuits by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've always known that smoking was dangerous against
tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. It's the same with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>; if we as a society decide that we
want to get rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Second Amendment</ENAMEX>, then let's do that instead of abusing
the court system and driving perfectly law-abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> into
bankruptcy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Kinzer</ENAMEX> continues his dispatches from the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyrgyzstan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s New York
Times . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, it was a missive from a yak farm about that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
ancient tradition of nomadism; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> he's covering an enclave of ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> who live near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bishkek</ENAMEX>. I just got back from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX>--I passed through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uzbekistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyrgyzstan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kazakhstan</ENAMEX>, western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir Province</ENAMEX> (from where, incidentally, I can report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> now
occupy a large part of what used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>-held <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> in a bid to bring
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> over to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> fundamentalist rule), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> proper. Kyrgyzstan
is a stunning place of amazing mountains and lakes, grinding poverty and lost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideology</ENAMEX>, and of course oodles of history. There's a chance <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will be
sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> out to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming years</TIMEX> to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> oil
interests, so we should all be reading up on this stuff. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinzer</ENAMEX> is an
awesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.

            I was leaning toward supporting a mainstream
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, because he's the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who understands that
the budget doesn't much matter if global warming puts the entire planet under
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">water</ENAMEX>--until I read this morning's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> interview
with campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Brazile</ENAMEX>. She refers to herself as a "diva." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divas</ENAMEX> sing. They sing well. Really well. I checked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cdnow</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> just now,
and couldn't find any <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Brazile</ENAMEX> CDs. This trend of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> confusing divas
with anyone arrogant and annoying is itself seriously annoying.

            The beginning of the trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Henderson</ENAMEX>, who's
accused of beating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX> to death in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laramie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyo.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>,
coincides with more calls for hate-crime bills as well as for the death penalty
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who ought to know better. All lives ought to be considered equal
under the law; if you kill someone because they're gay, it shouldn't be worse
than killing someone because they like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX>. It's still damned awful, and
you shouldn't see much sunlight for the rest of your life either way. As for
the death penalty, it's not like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> don't deserve to die; of course they
do. It's just that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> shouldn't be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of killing them--it
turns every single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> into a killer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> voted for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reagan</ENAMEX> budget, which
pushed <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Generation X</ENAMEX> into underemployment and student-loan hell for more than a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, destroyed the welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and symbolized the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> view that
no one should give a damn about anyone else. For this reason alone, he deserves
to never hold any kind of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            Wow--am I ever cranky <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>! I'd better go get
some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>.

            Your turn.

            Very truly yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
