
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aesthetic Inconsistencies</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mick</ENAMEX>--

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. Do you, as a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, miss the great
headline-writing abilities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ? They have
an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum of Art</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>-opposed
exhibition of young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Stink-ular Sensation</ENAMEX>," a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reference</ENAMEX>, as I'm sure you know, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Ofili</ENAMEX>'s use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant dung</ENAMEX>, among
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, in his painting of the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>. This editorial asserts that
"the greatest fear among cultured folk is that they will say something critical
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a perplexing new painting, play, book, or novel that will, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>' time, be considered a towering masterpiece." I like to think that I'm as
timid as any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the cultured folk, but my greatest fear is public
speaking.

            In a less catchily headlined article on the same event (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"With Art Battle in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spotlight</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mayor Revels in the Glare"</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , reviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s
appearances on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-morning</TIMEX> talk shows, quotes him as saying, in
furtherance of the argument that he bases his position on principle rather than
personal distaste, "Taxpayer dollars shouldn't be on either side of this
dispute. We can't support religion. We shouldn't support vicious attacks on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>, either." I would like to say, flat-out, that it is not my fear of
being looked down upon by the cultured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX> that
drives me, cowering, to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ofili</ENAMEX> painting doesn't to me look like an
attack on religion, vicious or otherwise. In fact, it looks religious. But, to
move to less disputed territory, although I haven't had time to go to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to check, I have a distinct recollection that
they have quite a few depictions of various religious images in their
collection. Does this mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is going to pull the funding they
receive from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>? I think if he's going to be coherent in his aesthetic
politics, he should give it a try. According to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> article,
he rebuts the accusation that he is doing this just to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative</ENAMEX>
Party nomination on the grounds that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> poll shows
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> oppose him 2-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> on this issue. Am I wrong in
thinking that this rebuttal has nothing to do with the accusation? Since when
has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX> picked its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> based on their poll-based
potential for winning? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> debate seems to me to be the epitome
of the kind of issue on the shoals of which the contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX>
always <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX>.

            Elsewhere in the world of politics and culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was
reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, in an unusually affectionate mood, to have not been
to see a movie in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. And why, indeed, should he bother putting down
his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> bucks to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> meet violent and untimely ends, when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most weekends</TIMEX>
he can just drive out to wherever they do the lethal injections and see one
that he himself sanctioned?

            I feel that I haven't given you anything to really start a fight about here,
so I am going to close by saying that I really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backstreet Boys</ENAMEX>,
especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howie</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
Mim

         
      
   
