
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Policing and the Crack Epidemic</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear George</ENAMEX>,

            It's too bad that life's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> routine has to interrupt our correspondence.
I am sure that by the time we get the rhythm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our week</TIMEX> will have ended! While I
have read some of your work and even used it in classes, clearly I should have
got to know you before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most disturbing trends in public policy has been the distortion
of social-science research to support an ideological agenda. As you point out,
this abuse has been practiced on the left and the right. Criminal-justice
policy and urban policy have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> of the ideological wars in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. I don't know if you saw the article in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dissent</ENAMEX> in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Tomasky</ENAMEX> maintained that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>" disagreed with your "broken
windows" theory and that the policies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal mayors</ENAMEX> caused the increase in
crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s cities <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1960 and 1990</TIMEX>. I had a piece in the same
issue that pointed out that your theory was not ideologically based. You
mentioned that you were asked to help reduce subway crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTA</ENAMEX> runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subways</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Koch</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">progressive Democract</ENAMEX>, was directly involved in funding and implementing your
strategy. Also, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Dinkins</ENAMEX> who found the money to hire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX>
more police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> under his "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe Streets Safe Cities</ENAMEX>" program.
In fact, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> all the credit for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s declining
crime rate don't know that crime started to drop during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. Moreover, as you know, crime has been declining in
every major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s policies may have provided
"value added" for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, its hard to argue causation for local policies when
there is a national trend at work.

            This actually brings me to an article on the front page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 19</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . The article is about crack use in poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. A recent study by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control and Prevention</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> is cited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . The study found
that diminished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> warfare related to crack has been the major reason for the
sharp drop in violent crime nationwide. At the same time, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> survey of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute for Justice</ENAMEX> shows a change in attitude by
the young. They are simply not using crack, even when they are using other
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. I cite all this evidence because I can't help but take social science
seriously. The conclusion of the article is that the decline in urban crime is
primarily due to the decline in crack use and not changes in policing. It
always struck me as strange that in the period when crime was increasing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> blamed the problem on the pathologies in the inner-city
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. However, once crime declined it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> who got all the
credit. No one bothered to check, until now, whether something might have
changed in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. I know this is your terrain. What do you
think?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warmest</ENAMEX> regards,
Ester

         
      
   
