
   
   
      
         
            Why Hasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">U.S. Gone Metric</ENAMEX>?
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 23</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$123 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Climate Orbiter</ENAMEX> was lost when it veered
off course and burned up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Martian</ENAMEX> atmosphere. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> revealed
the cause: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> part of the orbiter's navigation system was speaking in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
units and another in metric. Why hasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> adopted the metric system?

            The metric system originated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 th century</TIMEX>
to combat rampant commercial fraud by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeepers</ENAMEX> who used the
varied systems of weights and measures to their advantage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> were also
demanding a standardized system to facilitate international cooperation on
research. While old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> seemed arbitrary, the new standardized system had
an apparent basis in nature: The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> was defined as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/10,000,000</NUMEX> of the
distance between the equator and either pole (it has since been redefined in
terms of the speed of light). It was also easier to remember than other systems
because it was based on the decimal system.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> officially adopted the metric system in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1800s</TIMEX>, and the rest
of the continent quickly followed in hopes that a standardized measurement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> would spur international trade. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next hundred years</TIMEX>, the metric
system spread globally. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Commonwealth</ENAMEX> resisted abandoning their
traditional measures, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>--under the slogan "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Metric: 10</ENAMEX>
times better"--they, too, metricated. (Some road signs and body weights,
however, remain "customary.") Today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is one of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only three</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--along with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myanmar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>--where the metric system is not
commonly used.

            Officially, at least, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has gone metric. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX>, the pound,
and the gallon--prototypes of which were once held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>--are now
officially defined by reference to metric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, the federal
government adopted metric as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s "preferred measurement system" and
established the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United States Metric Board</ENAMEX> to manage the transition. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">changeover</ENAMEX> was ineffective, however, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, the only tangible
progress was that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> had to be labeled in liters. Metrication was
revived in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> required that all government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> be metric
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> to the extent "feasible." Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with large international or
scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>--like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense and NASA</ENAMEX>--are almost
fully converted; others--like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX>--have done little,
citing the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to decide such matters. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s private sector is
similarly mixed: Large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> with overseas exports are at least partly
converted, but most small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> still use the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> system.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> metric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> encountered stiff opposition in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s and '80s</TIMEX>.
Labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> would be unable to learn a new system.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Businesses</ENAMEX> protested that redesigning machines and products to metric standards
would be costly. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> objected to the expense of replacing road signs and
revising laws. And average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> argued that change was unnecessary and said
the metric system--with its multiples of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, instead of the more intuitive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">halves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> of English measures--was not compatible with human
experience. In contrast, there was no natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> for the pro-metric
cause.

            But similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> were encountered--and overcome--in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
So, some metric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> attribute <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s non-conversion to national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individualism</ENAMEX>, they say, makes us more resistant to
government-mandated change than other cultures. For example, Mother
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Cowboy Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> sued to block
metrication, claiming "the West was won by the inch, foot, yard, and mile."
Metric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> also see xenophobia in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' distaste for a foreign
system of measurement. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> suggested that metric road
signs would facilitate a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> invasion.

            Others ascribe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> inaction to logistical obstacles. It is a classic
instance of path dependency: Once a course is chosen, it is difficult to induce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to switch. And until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> had little incentive to do so,
since the economy was sufficiently dominant in its trade relationships to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">enforce English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> on its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. (This may soon change, as the European
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> plans to ban products labeled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>.)
Also, unlike other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' metrication legislation has been
entirely voluntary, so few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have transitioned. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Metric</ENAMEX> Program--which took up the cause when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Metric Board</ENAMEX> was
abolished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>--now focuses on outreach to the business community, instead
of legislation. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The year</TIMEX>'s marquee event, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Metric Week</ENAMEX>," begins this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 10th day of the 10th month</TIMEX>.

            ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> recounts the struggles of "the
least powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> ," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Metric</ENAMEX> Program. Also see the Web page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">U.S. Metric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> for exhaustive information on metrication.)

            Next question?

         
      
   
