
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doesn't It Cost Less To See a Bad Movie</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randolph B. Cohen</ENAMEX>, an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Business School</ENAMEX> (who is
not to be confused with 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX>), raises an interesting question about movie-ticket prices
(see "
In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Praise of Movie Ticket Prices"</ENAMEX>). Namely: Why do movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> always
charge the same amount, regardless of how good or bad the movie in question
might be? Movie-ticket prices vary, of course, but only depending on factors
such as whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> or whether the ticket is
purchased in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> or in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>. Why not charge a premium for
movies that, for one reason or another, might be more worth seeing than
other movies? To quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  Wouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay more to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Titanic than Wild, Wild</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> ?
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> does not mean to suggest that movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> should charge more for
movies that cost more to make (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bronfman</ENAMEX>, who was "just smart
enough to get it completely wrong," once proposed). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> explains:

            

               
                  The price you sell a unique good for is not determined by what it cost to
make it. It cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX> little to paint "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunflowers</ENAMEX>," but that doesn't mean
he or anyone else should sell it for little. Instead, the price is based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' willingness to pay. And presumably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be willing to pay
more for the best movies, so why not charge more for them?
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> would define "best movies" not according to
subjective aesthetic criteria but rather according to how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to
see them. By this definition, a popular movie would be a "better" movie
than an unpopular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s hypothetical scheme, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s
response to a movie's popularity would not be the current, egalitarian method
of opening it in more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, but the inegalitarian method of pricing the
"better" movies out of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s reach. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Poorer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have to rent.)
It sounds barbaric, but such demand-based pricing goes on all the time with
other commodities, even other entertainment commodities:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broadway</ENAMEX> does seem to charge more for big hits like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Miz</ENAMEX> ,
and the effect is even more extreme in pay-per-view cable, where prices range
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 to $50</NUMEX> depending on the appeal of the event. Similarly the software
business has huge "desirability premia"--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Office</ENAMEX> costs far more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> that presumably had similar development costs. Publishing seems to
be in between--books by [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crichton</ENAMEX>, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>, and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstars</ENAMEX> appear to get a small premium (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $3</NUMEX> more in hardback based on a
casual flip through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>). [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> pauses here to note that the
big superstores have also been known to do the precise opposite--i.e., sell the
most popular books and cd's at a specially low discount.]

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> points out that movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>' seemingly perverse pricing mechanism
is also used in a few other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of the entertainment business:

            

               
                  The record industry doesn't appear to charge more for popular albums
(except in the cutout bins, which are more analogous to low-cost <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-run
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theaters</ENAMEX>). Similarly, video rentals all cost the same except for new releases
vs. old.
               

            

            Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s attempt to explain movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>' seeming lack of greed:

            

               
                  The best theory I have so far is signaling: By giving a film a low price,
you let the world know it's lousy; then they really don't want to see
it. So instead, everyone charges what the best films charge, hoping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will
perceive the film as good.
               

            

            This sounds right. Since most movies are bad (both in the subjective
aesthetic sense and in the cruder sense of being unpopular), discounting the
bad ones would bleed revenue while probably not persuading many moviegoers to
make the tradeoff between quality and cost. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> pointed out in his
earlier item, movie tickets are fundamentally inexpensive , so you aren't
going to lure many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into seeing, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut by</ENAMEX>
slashing the already low price of first-run admission. (To the extent the
discount audience exists at all, it's mostly a rental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, because renting
saves money not only on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> price of viewing but also on parking,
babysitting, and other incidental costs associated with going out; perhaps most
important of all, the rental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> knows it can bail out with greater ease
if the movie in question proves unwatchable.) To make a buck, the movie
business has to lure large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into seeing bad
movies, and to get them to pay as much as they would if they were seeing
a good movie. That's the bad news. The good news is that when a movie is
good , pretty much everyone can afford to see it, which isn't true, say,
of a concert reuniting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX> with the E <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Street Band</ENAMEX> (though in the
latter case the price differential is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>'s fault, but rather the
fault of ticket scalpers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX>).* (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>'s
explanation of why <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> charge less than the market will bear.)

            *The scalpers-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> point was brought to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s attention by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randolph Cohen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>, who is an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of history at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syracuse</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
