
   
   
      
         
            Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI-Sprint</ENAMEX> Merger Anti-Competitive?
            

            The proposed merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> obviously raises
important antitrust questions, since the devouring of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest long-distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest might very well not be
in the best interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. You don't hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying "Why did they
ever break up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>?" much anymore, and that's mainly because the fierce
competition for long-distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> has driven prices inexorably down.
Eliminating a key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in that market could reduce the pressure for price
cuts.

            It could reduce the pressure, but it probably won't. Although the telecom
industry on the one hand is succumbing to merger-mania, on the other hand it's
seeing new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> spring up regularly, and it's now seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wannabes</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCN</ENAMEX> and Qwest becoming real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>. And in the simplest sense, having two
big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the market is not meaningfully different from having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> happily divided up market share like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> divided up the world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16 th century</TIMEX> are long gone, if
they ever existed. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> raises my rates above the current <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7 cents</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>, I'll be happy to move.

            Still, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> effect of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom/Sprint</ENAMEX> merger would be to increase the
pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Bell Operating Companies</ENAMEX> (RBOCs)
to offer long-distance service. For a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bell</ENAMEX> to be able to offer
long-distance to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, it first has to demonstrate that it has opened
the market for local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, which means not only that it isn't
blowing up its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vans</ENAMEX> but that it's giving its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> reliable
access to that last <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">mile</NUMEX> of copper wire that runs into our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, and that it
isn't making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> jump through hoops when they want to change phone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            Up to this point, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bell</ENAMEX> has actually been able to demonstrate
this--rather than welcoming competition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBOCs</ENAMEX> have tried to repel it at
every turn. This is not surprising. Everyone wants the markets they're not
allowed into--long-distance, in this case--to be open, and the markets they
dominate to be closed. But it has been a frustrating spectacle. Changing local
service should be as easy as changing your long-distance carrier, and as
risk-free.

            In any case, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> now has an application to provide long-distance
service before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>, and indications are that it has a good chance of being
approved. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has undergone close scrutiny, has performed a battery of
tests to show that it's being fair to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, and has lost enough
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>--though still a tiny fraction of the overall number--to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> to suggest that it doesn't have a complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX>. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> can start providing long distance, that will put added competitive
pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX>.

            Eventually, then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> will be a full-service phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and
that will probably be a good thing in the long run. But before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> says
yes, I'd like it to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> answer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question: Why does it cost me
more to call <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> than it costs me to call
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
