
   
   
      
         
            Defining Deviance Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ester</ENAMEX>:

            I am not certain whether we were to wrap up our conversation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> or
today, however, I will send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> more message. The quote from your last
message is, of course, the crux of the issue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wolfe</ENAMEX> raised and has
been at the core of much of my thinking.

            I, too, view myself as a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>; however, I've been mostly out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> since I left a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX> seminary in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>. Having studied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
existentialism, indeed all existentialism, avidly in college and seminary, I
was wrestling with the idea of freedom from secular and religious institutions
in terms of my personal morality quite early. And, for me, morality is a very
personal issue. Over time, however, as the power of authoritative institutions
waned--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, state, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--I was increasingly struck by the reality
that while many have handled their "moral freedom" responsibly, many others
have used lack of external constraints to exploit and prey on
others--personally, financially, sexually, violently, etc. Moreover, I became
persuaded that society's reluctance to come down on such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> for minor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incivilities</ENAMEX> and offenses, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense, trapped these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--especially young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>--into believing that there were no consequences for anything. So, we
decriminalized virtually all minor offenses, we refused to confront young
persons meaningfully for minor offenses--in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> even burglary was for
all practical purposes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decriminalized</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> didn't even bother investigating
it)--and to use <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s phrase, we "defined deviance down." To get into
trouble, one really had to be a "bad-ass"--that is be outrageously
confrontational and violent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX> was a bad joke to them until they ran
into "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> strikes, you're out": the disastrous outcome for both society at
large and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> when society fails to meet its responsibility to take
preventive actions early--both nurturing and controlling actions.

            So, I still wrestle with your phrase about moral authority. How can society
maintain civility when everybody is "free" to define personal morality on their
own terms, while some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of society are eager to use this "freedom" to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intimidate</ENAMEX>, exploit, and prey on others?

            To provide an answer to my own question--"Why now" does the "great
disruption" seem to be receding?--I would suggest that society in broad terms
came to an understanding in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX> that we had largely lost control of
a relatively large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> and public spaces. And, a new idea
developed: We had to enforce a balance between individual liberty and personal
responsibility--certainly with nurturing and moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, but even with
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>.

            Anyway, I hope that sometime we can really have breakfast. I hope that your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are well. I checked on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, and all seem to
be doing well. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> refused to be seated in the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, and consequently
ran into a massive assertion of parental authority.)

            Be well,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
