
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A.: Too Much for the Man</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>,

            As always, it is a treat to read your cogent insights. I agree with you that
the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> here involves the changes in capitalism and especially in the
nature of work. Unfortunately, I think it would have been a much stronger book
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> saw it that way. ...

            First, I have an urgent message for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>: Get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> as
soon as possible! There is a real world out here with real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in it. If
possible, bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester</ENAMEX> before his spirit is crushed forever beneath the
weight of all those muscles. We're waiting for you!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>'s book has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great strengths. First, she engages with a big
and profound set of questions that affect all of our lives. She does this with
great earnestness and deep commitment. She devoted years of her life to the
undertaking. How many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> will do that? Too few, I think. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s
interviews with an unusual selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are masterful gems, each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> cut
and shaped by profound empathy, vivid observation, and keen listening. They are
rendered in rich romantic prose that pungently conveys the disparate worlds of
her interlocutors. I love the way she lets us in on the action through her own
responses of compassion and bewilderment. She is always there, never silent, as
we feel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> opening up to her, trusting her, bonding with her, so
much so that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>, they continue to call and bring her up to
date on their lives and their troubles. What I cherish about this book, and
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX> herself, is the way she surrendered to the mystery and adventure
of this intellectual journey. She began with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of assumptions and allowed
them to transform, as she herself was transformed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> she came to know.
Her personal authenticity was the backdrop against which these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were able to
turn their experiences into words with an anguished and heartbreaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transparency</ENAMEX>. Without being mawkish, I think one can say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>
reached beyond her role as a feminist, or even as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. She reached toward
her own individual humanity and through that medium reached a deeper truth with
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> she sought to understand. Between her introduction and her
conclusion, each of the "empirical" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>--on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipbuilders</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citadel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cadets</ENAMEX>, the "gangstas," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spur Posse</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> vets, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militiamen</ENAMEX>, the porno film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, the fashion tyrants
and their slaves, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>--can stand alone as testimony to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> and unique life-world.

            The question inevitably arises, though: What does it all mean? Here I
believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX> gets it mostly wrong. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> critical intellectual
errors that form the very foundation of her undertaking: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> substantive, the
other methodological. I was hopeful when I read on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> her complaint that
"popular accounts of the male crisis and male confusions are almost
unrelievedly ahistorical," but I was crestfallen some pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, when she
identifies some of the deep historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> that might have allowed her
to unravel her data, and then dismisses them as irrelevant:

            

               I'm not speaking simply of the economic shift from industry to service ...
nor about a shift from a society organized around industry to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set up around
electronic technology. And I'm not speaking simply about the irony of men
supporting a massive military-industrial effort to produce machines ... that
ultimately would replace them ... Those changes were only surface symptoms
...

            

             There is no way to talk about these historic shifts "simply." And this is
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I have heard these monumental issues in the evolution of
material life referred to as "surface symptoms"! Whoa! If that's the surface,
then we must be talking about something very deep indeed that is the cause of
all this angst. But what is it? Well, by Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">596</NUMEX> we arrive at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s
definition of the heart of this particular darkness: The deep pain experienced
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> she meets is explained by this confession and complaint: "My father
never taught me how to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." So, here we are once again on a canvas of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ahistorical</ENAMEX> pop psychology, where the silence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> and their devotion
to commercial culture has crippled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, leaving them no source of meaning
other than "Were they 'sexy'? Were they 'known'? Had they 'won'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            If there is a crisis of masculinity, then it truly can only be understood
through history. We are now completing, at least in the West, the last feudal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in any society, a majority of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
educated and informed. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in any society, a majority of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use their brains and not their backs to accomplish its work. The bonds
of hierarchy and patriarchy are not dissolved, but faded and weakened as never
before. The fixed productive and reproductive roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, once
determined by anatomy, are now giving way to an exhilarating and terrifying
plethora of choices. The concept of work has been forever transformed and the
boundaries of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> have followed suit. These are the deep structures that are
in motion. These are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of the ruptures with the past we all face.

            If there is a crisis, then rejoice! The old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of meaning that kept us
each in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX> are dead or dying. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are being crushed as
the tectonic plates of history roil and split and mow them down. They complain
and whine and wail for a world that is vanishing. OK. It hurts. But this is
their opportunity to not just be he-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but human beings. If they can't be
useful by protecting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and "making" things--then it's time to embrace
the usefulness of supporting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, learning new skills, committing to
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and finding new ways to teach their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and contribute to
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. The old world had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in a box and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in a harness. No
one was allowed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> outside their roles. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> were silent, its
because that's how they thought the script was written. Don't pine for that!
Get on with the challenge of forging a new life and writing your own, better,
script.

            Finally, the methodological fallacy at the heart of this book: "If you want
to see what's happening in the stream called our society," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s
"patriots," "go to the edges and look at what's happening there ..." This
alleged "societal dynamic" becomes her methodological justification for using
the stories of the "underemployed, contracted-out, and laid-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to illuminate more general male losses... " It must be said that
this kind of approach is very tricky. If you are going to pick a few cases to
illustrate the larger whole, then you have to have some pretty compelling and
well-articulated reasoning for their selection. I am surprised, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>, that
you find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s characterizations of the male crisis to fit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
profile. I think that what she has unearthed in grisly detail is the uniquely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shallow</ENAMEX>, instrumental, and crass culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> (which I once heard
described as "high school with money"), where looks, fame, and income compose
the ranking rules for a truly wacky hierarchy. Lamentably, she has lost sight
of just how weird and out of the mainstream that culture is. It is not our
culture. It is not our society. It is not the grain of sand in which the real
world that most of us live in is etched. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militiamen</ENAMEX>, the
porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, the over-the-top football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>--they're all fascinating, but I
don't think that any of them says very much about most of us. But then, I live
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, where ornamental culture has made little impression, except possibly
through a widespread interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX> catalogue.

            Once again, a plea to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester</ENAMEX>. Move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>. It's not too late.
We'll love you here even if you have a paunch or imperfect thighs!

            More later,
Shoshana Zuboff

         
      
   
