
   
   
      
         
            More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Grandstanding</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear George</ENAMEX>,

            It's been raining heavily in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">NYC this morning</TIMEX>. So if that wasn't enough to
put a damper on anyone's mood, some radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> decided it was a good time
to let us now that after all the spraying of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquitoes</ENAMEX> (the stuff seems to
kill <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and also adversely affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>),
we could have the same outbreak of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX> fever encephalitis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX>. Of
course, the "dung on the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary"</ENAMEX> has taken over the headlines from our
public-health problem. In the latest twist, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>
conspiring with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie's</ENAMEX> to inflate the value of the art collection in the
exhibit. I'm sure some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the hard-pressed, cash-poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> were
wondering why they hadn't thought of doing that in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place! The
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandstanding</ENAMEX> is moving us even further away from confronting the
very real public-policy challenges that you outlined in your letter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> had a very thoughtful column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> today. He sees all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> as serving a very narrowly defined self-interest. He criticizes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> for mounting the offensive exhibition in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, and
he also is offended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s confrontational litigious position. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pitting</ENAMEX>
the "right to free artistic expression" against "accountability of public
funds" isn't the right fight. He argues that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> needs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX>, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gladiators</ENAMEX>." This position seems like the right <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to me, but it has the
luxury of ignoring the political reality in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stepchild</ENAMEX> when it comes to fund-raising and cachet, so they need both the
attention and the money. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> "seen his opportunities and took 'em," as
Plunkitt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tammany Hall</ENAMEX> would have said. Once again, important issues of
public policy are decided in a crisis atmosphere and the public's view is
largely irrelevant.

            I'd like to think more about your position on charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and vouchers.
I, too, have been struggling with this issue. Now, I am off to tape a cable
show sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens Union</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter</ENAMEX>-revision propositions that
will be appearing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> ballot in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election. This is actually
an important issue, but alas, has no sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, or rock 'n' roll angle to it,
so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> has covered it minimally. Maybe I can come up with a hook before
the show. Should I show a picture of a nude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>, comptroller
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> urinating on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">City Charter</ENAMEX>? It wouldn't be
difficult, they are all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warmest</ENAMEX> regards,
Ester

         
      
   
