
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mysterious Fascination With Young Adults</ENAMEX>
            

            The successful debut of Once and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Again</ENAMEX> , the new drama (from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirtysomething</TIMEX> , no less) about having a love life as a
divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>, has drawn plenty of hosannas from TV-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> who feared that
the tube had forever been given over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson's Creek</ENAMEX> and its myriad
clones. Once and Again 's success has been taken as a sign that a show
doesn't have to appeal to that desperately sought-after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-to-34</NUMEX> demographic in
order to be a hit.

            As it happens, Once and Again 's success doesn't necessarily show that
at all, because it is in fact a huge hit with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-to-34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. Its share
of TV-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is as large as its overall share, and larger than
the share received by new shows such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freaks and Geeks</ENAMEX> and Now and
Again . In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Zwick</ENAMEX>'s show about yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> is proving more
popular with the young<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'uns</ENAMEX> than his show about yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, My So-Called
Life .

            What's weird, though, is the assumption Once and Again had to combat
in order even to get on the air: that nothing is more desirable than those
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-to-34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>. This is not an assumption unique to television. It's
certainly at work in movies, and has also been propelling changes in the
magazine world, most notably in the ascent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pseudo-lad</ENAMEX> magazines like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX> and in the pressure that's being felt by older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> to make
themselves more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>-friendly. But the fact that the assumption is ubiquitous
doesn't necessarily mean that it makes sense.

            Now, I'm part of this fabled demographic, albeit at the high end
chronologically, and in a lot of ways--willingness to consume, love of new
stuff, appetite for pop culture of all kinds--I'm an ideal target for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. So I have no problem with TV programmers, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX>, and
magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> trying to appeal to me. But I am perplexed by the avidity with
which I am being courted, because of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> simple fact: There aren't that many of
me.

            I don't mean that I'm unique. I mean that literally there are fewer--many
fewer--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> ahead of and behind us.
And while it's certainly true that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late '20s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '30s</TIMEX>--at
least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, where those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are less likely to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>--have a
lot of disposable income, it can't compare, in absolute terms, to that still
wielded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>. Even in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX>, earning power rises with
age. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make a lot more when they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> than when they're 30.

            So, why do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> think we're the ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>? Partly because of our
ability to spend without worrying about our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">childrens</ENAMEX>' education; partly
because some advertising is aspirational, so that you push products that people
will want to buy when they can afford to; and partly because of ill-considered
assumptions about brand loyalty, in particular the idea that if you hook me on
a particular kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or suit or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>, you'll have me for life.

            But surely an important reason for the hegemony of the young-adult audience
is simply that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> tend to be the ones who are buying advertising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, designing the ads, and, increasingly, writing and programming the shows
and films that we see. I become the ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are the
ones selling me the products.

            The picture is more complicated than this, of course. There aren't many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21-year-olds</TIMEX>, even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, writing ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiat Day</ENAMEX> or programming for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>.
(Though I suspect there are a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year-olds</TIMEX> doing those jobs who think
they're still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>.) And I'm not sure if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson's Creek</ENAMEX> and
Felicity are really targeted at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28-year-olds</TIMEX>. (In fact, I pray they
aren't.) Finally, at the bottom end of the demographic, there a lot more people
than at the top end. Those are the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo Boomers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> should
really want them.

            The point is not that the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18-to-34s</NUMEX> should be disregarded. It's just that
from a purely economic point of view, they shouldn't be regarded with such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fascination</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the combined ratings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Buffy the Vampire</ENAMEX> Slayer
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson's Creek</ENAMEX> added up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 13 percent</NUMEX> of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
were watching television while those shows aired. And even a very stylish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
percent of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> you could be reaching is still just, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
