
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            I'd say it was a week dominated by merger talk, but
then it seems almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> is dominated by merger talk. It might have been
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> dominated by talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>, which decided not to raise interest
rates but did shift its bias toward tightening, but the truth is that except
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, when the announcement came, there wasn't too much talk about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. (Though it's worth noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Berry</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who often appears to have a
direct line to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>, was wrong in his forecast of no rate hike, no
shift in bias.) So instead it was a week in which the stock market demonstrated
its continued resiliency, coming back strong after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s mild sell-off, and
in which the prospect of buoyant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-quarter</TIMEX> earnings (which are all going to
be announced over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX>) outweighed everything else. Oil prices
were down, the dollar was up: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a week</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> refused to destroy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. So eat, drink, and be merry, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> ... You know the rest.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "In a rather surprising blow to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ovitz</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> decided to award its newest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> rather than to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> . The deal will include a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700 million</NUMEX>
franchise fee and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $300 million</NUMEX> for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $200 million</NUMEX>
of which will be supplied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> money. That's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> total, for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> that will play <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> home games a year. I'd love to see what the return on
that investment looks like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years from now</TIMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Internet portal Yahoo!
reported blowout earnings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the most recent quarter</TIMEX> and said its revenues
had soared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$155 million</NUMEX>. That means by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will be doing
close to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in revenue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. Once it's a profitable <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, do we get to stop hearing the cracks about how
no one's making money on the Internet?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "In the midst of the bidding war for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomberg News</ENAMEX> ran a story with this headline: 'Bell <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Sweetens</ENAMEX> Offer for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> Says.' As opposed to, I guess, 'Bell
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Sweetens</ENAMEX> Offer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Encephalitis-Carrying Mosquito Says</ENAMEX> .'
"

            3a. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that day</TIMEX>, Bloomberg
changed the headline to 'Bell <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Sweetens</ENAMEX> Offer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> Say.'
Don't you think that really begged instead for 'They Say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell South Sweetens</ENAMEX>
Offer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "Protesting tire-maker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michelin</ENAMEX>'s plan to cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,500</NUMEX>
jobs from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lionel Jospin</ENAMEX> told reporters,
'We didn't renounce the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> of the proletariat
just to replace it with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. ' ...
Actually, you did."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin Klein</ENAMEX> has hired
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lazard Freres</ENAMEX> to weigh the possibility of merging with another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or entering into a strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>. Apparently just adding
'.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>' to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s name was considered but then rejected as tacky."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "The stock of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Micro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devices</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s erstwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> and perennial disappointer of
expectations, rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 5 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> reported a smaller-than-expected loss in the most
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>. Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> did lose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>
cents a share, which might make a typical investor hesitant to back up the
truck. It's a little-known fact, but the phrase 'Hope springs eternal' was
actually coined to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "Before moving on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom/Sprint</ENAMEX> merger,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> first cleared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bell SBC Communications</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75 billion</NUMEX> acquisition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ameritech</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> did lay out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> different conditions that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX> will
have to meet before the deal can go through. Among them: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX> has to agree to enter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> new markets in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 30 months</TIMEX> .
Will <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> have to do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> chin-ups in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>, too?"

         
      
   
