
   
   
      
         
            Don't Worry, Be Happy
            

            My dear, thank you.

            My primary news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> today have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Op-Ed</ENAMEX> page
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV News</ENAMEX>, venues in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitney Houston</ENAMEX> addressed the
need for compassion and optimism in this old world of ours in ways that were
disturbingly similar. I leave you to guess which in which venue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">happily</ENAMEX> commented on the decrease in noise, graffiti, and panhandling in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, as I would like to say only
someone who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, as he does, could, except that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live
here do also, although it does to a large degree depend on where you live. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> who come into my neighborhood make every bit as much, if not more,
noise than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> who have gone out. I used to have a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
among the homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crack-addicted</ENAMEX> mentally ill in my neighborhood <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or so</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, and although this friendship was not financially a totally equal
two-way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, I did borrow money from them on a few occasions when I was
running late and didn't want to stop at a cash machine. It's true that they
were smelly and that the sight of poverty and desperation are not pleasant, and
they all told the same self-serving lies for my benefit, and could never
remember no matter how many times they were told that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> don't think
it's a compliment to be told they have big legs, and they were noisy, although
they would pipe down if you cared to go out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three in the morning</TIMEX> to ask,
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> sure won't. I occasionally still see some of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have gotten clean, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> live on and deteriorate, but the other
half-dozen faded from view, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> because they died, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of those in
circumstances directly related to the more dangerous, harder-assed
neighborhoods into which they were swept by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s quality-of-life
campaign, one because he was set on fire. In other words, I find it hard to
rejoice about the improvement in my quality of life brought about by no longer
having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> urinating in public up and down the block, because it wasn't
really my quality of life that was at issue, and anyway, overall as far as I
can tell, quality of life did not so much improve overall but redistribute
itself.

            I'm sorry you didn't get to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX> and the death squads. I also fear
that every attempt at universal health care will be sandbagged by the health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, not to mention that now that I have been so very critical of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, it's only a matter of time before the police kick in my door and hall
me off to jail, as if I were a dangerous criminal, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Boone</ENAMEX>. In the
meantime, I'm happy to have lived long enough to think I recognize a sample
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Andrea True Connection's "More, More, More" in LEN's "If You Steal My</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunshine</ENAMEX>."

            Big love to you,
Mim

         
      
   
