
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CollegeBoy</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
puts atop its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> indictments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> money-laundering case, a story
fronted by the other papers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s
announcement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> will have to take complete
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control of East Timor</ENAMEX>--an effort expected to cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $1 billion</NUMEX>, of which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is obligated to pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 percent</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> had been expected to play a
role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>'s transition to independence, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> says pillaging by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>'s plebiscite has left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in
disarray. (For a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> primer, click 
here.) The other papers stuff this story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s partial capitulation on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> rights" legislation: In
the face of more sweeping legislation sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> reversed position and wrote an alternative bill giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> the
right to sue their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> fronts, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers,
this story.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>'s warning that inflation may be on the horizon--an advisory
delivered along with a decision not to raise interest rates. (The markets
dipped and then recovered.)

            A federal grand jury indicted former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, and a business associate with conspiracy to transmit
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $7 billion</NUMEX> illegally. The indictment--which falls short of federal
money-laundering charges--accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of
operating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> money-transfer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> without a state license from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, when the investigation became public and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BoNY</ENAMEX> fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> raided a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>--known for its political
connections--as part of its investigation into related money transfers. It
doesn't end there: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are
investigating suspicious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BoNY</ENAMEX> accounts held by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tatyana</ENAMEX>
Dyachenko, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX>. (To learn more
about money laundering, click 
here.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post front</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s provocative speech on education, in which he proposed a
major expansion of federal loans for charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> for
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. "Too often, on social issues, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has painted
an image of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> slouching toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gomorrah</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said. "Too often, my party
has confused the need for limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with a disdain for government
itself." He also proposed federal incentives for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to participate in
national elementary-age testing programs. Writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>,
sometime
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contributor Walter</ENAMEX> Shapiro laments that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s remarks were over-rehearsed and "totally skirted such contentious issues
as public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> run on a for-profit basis and the merits of teaching to ace
tests." (For 
                  Slate
               's take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s education policy,
click 
here.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> has been
lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to pardon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Hearst</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>-magnate scion
who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> was famously kidnapped and "brainwashed" into robbing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> with
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captors</ENAMEX> (the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symbionese Liberation Army</ENAMEX>"). Although many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are opposed to a pardon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst</ENAMEX>--now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst Shaw</ENAMEX>--has been a model <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> since he commuted her sentence
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , is a potential but reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> in
the upcoming trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Jane Olson</ENAMEX>, a recently captured former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> of trying to sell her testimony for a pardon.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that college tuition and fees rose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 5</NUMEX>
percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>--twice the rate of inflation but the lowest rate of growth in
many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. (How many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> doesn't
specify.) Cuts in administrative and educational expenses at private schools
and increased state funding of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> account for most of the gains,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Board</ENAMEX>, which conducted the survey. "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 50 percent</NUMEX> of people
who go to college pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $4,000</NUMEX> for fees and tuition," says an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , "which is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,000</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. If a person works for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, they'll probably earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $1 million</NUMEX> on that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,000</NUMEX>." On the
Post opinion page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ignatius</ENAMEX> drives this point home by quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>'s new
book on meritocracy (buy it here): "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here</ENAMEX> is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> looks like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," writes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>. "A thick line runs through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been to
college on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who haven't on the other. The line gets
brighter all the time. ... As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> plan their lives and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
lives, higher education is the main focus of their aspirations (and the
possibility of getting into the elite end of higher education is the focus of
their very dearest aspirations)." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s book was also discussed in

                  Slate
               's 
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> profiles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> who didn't buy into the meritocracy
racket. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Prigel</ENAMEX>--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> who turned down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> for a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> scholarship at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Christian University</ENAMEX>--broke the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Online</ENAMEX> was looking to buy part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> in a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scoop</ENAMEX>, which was posted on his new website <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">StreetAdvisor</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and later
confirmed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> themselves, caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Excite</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>'s stock to rise
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.2 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. Who says you need a guild card to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
