
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mixed Legacy</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dinesh</ENAMEX>,

            What a relief. Something would be very wrong if we found nothing to argue
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. It's also a relief to be able to put aside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' book, which we both
agree is a strange and wrongheaded failure, and talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> directly.

            And what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>? Like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, I was horrified by almost
everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> did as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Today, I consider him a much more
impressive figure than I once did and can even admire some of what he achieved.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX>, in his simplistic way, and you, in your much more knowledgeable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, go much too far, I think, in your claims about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s importance to
history.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years ago</TIMEX>, I wrote a long essay of my own about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, the only
time I've tried to write anything serious about him, for a presidential
reference book; and I was surprised by how much more sympathetic I was to him
than I had once been. He deserves considerable credit, I think, for restoring a
sense of possibility and optimism to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> popular culture. There is, of
course, an easily crossed line between confident optimism and arrogant
jingoism, and that line was sometimes crossed--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> himself and by many
others--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> (just as it was, much more disastrously, by many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>). But on the whole, I think he was a positive force in the way he
reduced the rancor and disillusionment that had grown so corrosive in the late
'60s and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'70s</TIMEX>.

            I also think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> made some (I emphasize "some") important
contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> social policy. He continued and accelerated a
movement in both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> and popular thinking about welfare policy that had
largely begun in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>: that welfare should be much more closely tied
to work, that it should be (to use a phrase created, but never really acted
upon, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>) a "hand up not a handout." That movement has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">culminated</ENAMEX>, at least so far, in the welfare reforms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, for
which both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are responsible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s own
understanding of the nature of the welfare system and its effects was, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris'</ENAMEX>, largely simplistic and uninformed. But his instincts were at least
partially right, and like many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, I was slow to recognize that. I now do
believe, as I think most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do, that getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to work is the best
thing a public policy can do to lift <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of poverty and redeem their
lives. I note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Julius Wilson</ENAMEX>, certainly no conservative, has argued
this quite eloquently in his recent book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When Work Disappears</ENAMEX> . And I
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> deserves some credit in legitimizing that notion, even if his
reasons for doing so are not necessarily ones I would support. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
administration was, I think, gratuitously punitive toward some of the poorest
and most desperate welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and put much too much of the burden of
its supposed deficit reduction on the backs of those least able to afford it
(and on programs so meagerly funded that their contribution to deficit
reduction was meaningless in any case). The same could be said for the
unattractively punitive features of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> welfare reform. But it has also
gone largely unnoticed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> supported some of the
early state back-to-work experiments that eventually showed impressive results,
and that it expanded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>, which has now (after its much greater expansion
under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>) become one of the great success stories of contemporary social
policy.

            On the larger question of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s economic policy, however, I am less in
agreement with you. No one can deny that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy grew impressively
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, that the stock market rose astronomically, that there was much new
investment, and that many important new economic sectors flourished. Credit for
that must be distributed widely, but the economic policies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
administration undoubtedly contributed. On the other hand, the economic boom of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> is unlike any previous economic boom in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history
in creating a very substantial upward distribution of wealth and in benefiting
those on the bottom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the economic ladder very little, if at
all. Blame for that must also be distributed widely, but I have no doubt that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s economic policies--cutting taxes mostly for the
upper brackets while watching higher social security taxes eat away at lower-
and middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> incomes, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> example--contributed to this large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> failure.

            Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>
and many others made contributions to the denouement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, and
all deserve credit for that. But to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was more responsible for
the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX> and the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>--or
that either of them was more responsible for it than the cascading economic
crises in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX> itself--just doesn't make sense. Yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> economy
had never done as well as Western economies and had often experienced crises.
But the erosion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> economic life in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 10 years</TIMEX> of its existence
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was much more serious, rapid, and destructive than anything that
had come before. Certainly part of the reason for that was the very high levels
of unproductive military spending. But those high levels had been eroding the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> since well before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> ratcheted up the arms race. (That was, after
all, one of his rationales for doing so.) There were many other grave problems
as well, not least--as I mentioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Afghan War</ENAMEX>, none of which
were a result of Western policy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s statements had a tremendous ideological
effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is the weakest way to support the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
importance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, whatever their views of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, are
much too proud and nationalistic to take to heart <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s or any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s
denunciations of them. But while I give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> credit for recognizing the value
of working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> and doing nothing to obstruct the changes that were
occurring and that were quickly moving well beyond what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> himself
wanted, I can see no basis on which to attribute the central role in this great
historical event to him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Washington</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
Revolution; we do not credit that event to him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was rather more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">complicit</ENAMEX> in the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> was in the end of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> monarchy, but it was not ultimately his doing.

            You make a much better case for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> does, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> will
certainly be debating these questions for generations. But I suspect that in
the end, the judgment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> will be considerably more mixed than yours (and
perhaps more mixed than mine as well).

            It's been a pleasure discussing these issues with you. I wish I could say
the same about reading the book.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
