
   
   
      
         
            Rads

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">BEVERLY HILLS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s speech at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan Library</ENAMEX> was
well-attended by national political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>--more than he had seen since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, when he made his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> announcement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> hadn't flown out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> just to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. They were in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> hoping for an announcement that will be far bigger news if it ever
occurs--that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>'s
candidacy. At a benefit dinner for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Action</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> was scheduled to tease a massive
international press corps about the possibility of running--I mean receive the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt Award</ENAMEX> and deliver a speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyhow</ENAMEX>, it sounded like too glam
an event to pass up, so I ditched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>--about whom more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> event, held in a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballroom</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton Hotel</ENAMEX>, was
sort of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Correspondents Dinner</ENAMEX> but with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> kept apart. We caught only distant glimpses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicholson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX>. Also in attendance were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Marshall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX>
Reiner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faye Dunaway</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Love</ENAMEX> teetered in and out on
preposterous stiletto heels, flaunting a strategically situated rip in her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blouse</ENAMEX> (which was pretty much see-through anyhow).

            Events like this remind you of what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">limousine</ENAMEX> liberalism was like, circa
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. When I arrived, the warm-up program was already underway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lila Garrett</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, was saying something about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> was not
a defensive alliance but a structure of oppression. "Keeping up a permanent war
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> requires a permanent war," she noted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrett</ENAMEX> calls the bombing in
defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78-day</TIMEX> reign of terror."

            Elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> represents a more liberal alternative
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. Here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is viewed as just another centrist sell-out.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> a grudge against him for voting in favor of aid
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contras</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. Sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is for extending health-care
coverage to the uninsured to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--but he's not for a
single-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payer</ENAMEX> system. Sure, he's for campaign-finance reform--but not for full
public financing of all federal elections. This explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
enthusiasm for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s interest in the race.

            The event began with an elaborate tribute film, which might run verbatim as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> attack ad against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>. It had clips of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Penn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Diller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Wellstone</ENAMEX>, Goldie
Hawn, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McGovern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>
and others, praising and joking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>, interspersed with clips from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX> appeared in a
Bulworth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> of wraparound shades and a black knit cap. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Roseanne</ENAMEX>
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> a "fine piece of ass" and threatened to run against him for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Reiner</ENAMEX> offered to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s running mate. The only really
truly funny bit was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Shandling</ENAMEX>'s cameo. "Listen, if you run and get
elected make sure you get your name above the title of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States of America</ENAMEX>," he said. The most astonishing
bit, to me at least, was the wrap-up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX> With a schmaltzy
violin score in the background, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlesinger</ENAMEX> called on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> to "keep up the
debate and save our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>."

            As a performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s address was overlong and uneven. Parts of it were
relatively clever, such as the peroration in which he offered advice to an
imaginary "drum majorette" who felt she had something to contribute to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political debate. This was a nice metaphor for his own flirtation with
a campaign. Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s jokes weren't bad. "I've been on a listening tour
of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six weeks</TIMEX>," he said. Another good one was his question
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley-Gore</ENAMEX> race: "What's this insurgency of a centrist against a
centrist all about?"

            But most of the speech had an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ishtar</ENAMEX> -like quality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hemming</ENAMEX>-and-hawing style of delivery gets tiresome pretty quickly ("I want to
thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>, uh, Action"), as do his repetitive screeds
about the special interests, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, and the plutocrats. You do have
to marvel at the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prada</ENAMEX>-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> to sit at a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500-</NUMEX>a-plate
dinner at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel</ENAMEX> and decry overpaid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> and rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
general as if they were an alien species. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> referred to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> as
"those moneyed, honeyed voices of ridicule."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s speech was delivered too late in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> to receive extensive
coverage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But if you watched it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-Span</ENAMEX>, you did learn
what his political views are. Like most of those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, he is a
wooly-mammoth liberal, pining for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubert H. Humphrey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> said
he was accepting the award as "an old-time, unrepentant, unreconstructed,
tax-and-spend, bleeding-heart, tax-and-spend liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>." That about
covers it. He also said he thinks the domestic policies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon B. Johnson</ENAMEX>
were all good programs that didn't get a fair shake because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> is annoyed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> has become, in his view, a copycat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. "We don't need a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>," he said. "We need a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>." He wants
to recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, pass single-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payer</ENAMEX> health-care insurance, install public
financing of elections, and spend more money on every social problem ever
discovered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> did not mention anything about being pro-life, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
Drudge claims he is since becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. That's about the only thing he
could have said that would have got him booed by this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>.

            It is certainly true, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> says, that there is no one currently in the
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> who represents an orthodox liberal position. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mistaken</ENAMEX> and perhaps a bit delusional is in attributing the failure of his
ideas to corporate power and corruption. He described our political system as
"a slow-motion coup d'etat of big money interests over the public interest."
This is the same paranoid view he articulated, much more wittily, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> . The movie never really took off. Based on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s
indications, neither will the campaign.

         
      
   
