
   
   
      
         
            Beattying Around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court's decision to take on for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the question of whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> have the right to visit their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> even when one or both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> object, which is also the top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead also covers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s decision to review the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Violence</ENAMEX>
Against <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Women Act</ENAMEX>, a recent federal hate crime law that gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of sexual
assaults the right to sue their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tormentors</ENAMEX> for money damages. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s sum-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s new term describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VAWA</ENAMEX> case and
several others, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> testing a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> law making it a crime to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, protest, or communicate within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 feet</NUMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 feet</NUMEX> of
an abortion clinic, and one about how to apply the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> statute of
limitations to refunds, but reserves its headline for one concerning the legal
liability of managed care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> accused of cutting costs and doesn't
mention the grandparenting case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
goes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s passage by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> of a continuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> that keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> running through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 21</TIMEX>. This means,
explains the paper, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> have bought time to work
out their myriad differences on expenditures without bringing about a
government shutdown. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to agree to back a single
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, thus auguring the continued dominance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that
has elected every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>. This story is also fronted
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front what the latter
calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s "first detailed policy speech," outlining his health-care
plan, which would extend coverage to lower-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> by allowing them to
join at little or no cost the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> or
by providing tax credits toward their private plan premiums. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> runs a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece on the
proposal. The papers point out that the plan is more ambitious than the one
unveiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>, in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s attempts to make health
care available not just to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but to nearly all currently non-covered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front says one
reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> investigation into possible laundering of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> money through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> has been so halting is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the law enforcement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> with responsibilities in the case--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan D.A.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>--have not been cooperating with each other. That's putting it mildly-- the
Times reports that each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX> even
discussed filing obstruction charges against the other.

            The WP fronts, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs inside (crediting early editions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ), the death of an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> while
undergoing gene therapy for a metabolic disease. Although, explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>,
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have by now been treated by such experimental techniques, this
is the first death associated with them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> had a mild form of a
genetic disorder that was well controlled with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and diet, but he
volunteered for the experimental therapy hoping it would lead to a cure. Both
papers are careful to point out that so far it is not known if the therapy was
the cause of death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> about
saying that if this is indeed the case it could be a severe setback for gene
therapy.

            The LAT fronts and the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> put inside the latest assessment of the writing skills of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The bottom line is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a quarter</NUMEX> of them are proficient in
writing, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 1 percent</NUMEX> are advanced. The stories also note a
significant gender gap, with girls handily outscoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> at all grade levels.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> will look in vain for comparisons to results from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior years</TIMEX>, but
as the stories explain, the tests given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of their kind
and so cannot be meaningfully compared to previous writing scores.

            A column by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ignatius</ENAMEX> and an inside story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
reveal that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> has come up with a new way to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> keep pace
with the explosion of information technology and get better connected to the
young brilliant minds that are powering it. It is starting up an information
technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture fund</ENAMEX>, to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"In-Q-It</ENAMEX>," with a field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, that will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to develop such things as
better intel-related search engines and improved computer security.

             

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> at the same prayer breakfast where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> he
confessed that he had "sinned" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
thanked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (seated nearby), his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, and his circle of religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX>, saying, "I have been profoundly moved, as few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have, by the
pure power of grace, unmerited forgiveness through grace." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs the story inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX> is reiterating its opposition to the repeal of the
estate tax, pointing out that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 2 percent</NUMEX> of those who die each year
leave estates large enough to be subject to it. A letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> makes a wholly different but equally striking
tax observation: The idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> impose a net cost on society and
therefore should have to pay higher taxes (say, though an increased cigarette
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tax</ENAMEX>) is wrong. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Research Service</ENAMEX>, he writes, has concluded
that "all in all, smoking has apparently brought gain to both federal and state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>." For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing he adds, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Medicine</ENAMEX> concluded that "smoking cessation would lead to
increased health care costs."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times fronts and gives its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life</ENAMEX>" section "cover story" over to the
question of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> might declare his presidential
candidacy in a speech he made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> last night post-press-time. It seems odd
not to have merely waited until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> to report rather than wonder. An
indicator of the paucity of actual information available about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s
thinking is the following simultaneously filed pair of observations.
USAT : "After all, this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> about whom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carly Simon</ENAMEX> was rumored to have written the hit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">song, You're So Vain</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> : "He is, after all, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> about whom
an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carly Simon</ENAMEX>, wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're So Vain</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
