
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">War Patsy</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mim</ENAMEX>:

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> again. This time it's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cigarettes. I've been
writing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> on some kind of destructured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX> roll out of which I
have yet to make sense, so I guess this serves as a return to comparative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sanity</ENAMEX>.

            I promised that I'd explain why so much money is being heaped on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to make him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and here goes. If the predictions don't actually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pan</ENAMEX> out, and I actually pray they don't, it's also a classic example of how to
build a high conspiracy theory from the ground up. The trick is to combine
totally separate news stories as factors in the same scenario, and take it from
there. In this case, the first clue was provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul Beaver</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Weekly</ENAMEX> reporting on the massive proliferation of a class of cheap,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">post-Scud</ENAMEX>, surface-to-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> with limited range that are ideal for
wars between adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> are designed to deliver
conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, but can be easily adapted to carry a payload of anthrax
or a small, dirty atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. The matching piece of the puzzle was served up
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldview</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> is seemingly about to hit a
catastrophic water crisis. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rainfall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> is down a frightening <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX> is at a
dangerously low level, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">River Jordan</ENAMEX> could be a trickle by the end of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.

            All peaceful solutions would require immediate cooperation by the nations
involved, but I doubt we should hold our breath on that. The alternative is
drought, famine, and ultimately war over the entire area. What better <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to have in power during this unfolding scenario than a completely
malleable nonentity, totally in the pocket of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>? The true face of
the alliterative compassionate conservatism? This may sound a little wild, but
what other reason is there for heaping so much funding on a self-admitted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boozer</ENAMEX> and cokehead, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX> was provided, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 40</TIMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>? After the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> has decimated itself, some compliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> has to be in place to send in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to secure the oil if it's not
too radioactive.

            Any thoughts on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pok√©mon</ENAMEX>? I've been sifting through the reports of all the
lawsuits against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> claiming that collecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pok√©mon</ENAMEX> trading cards,
with their built-in scarcity factor, is a form of insidious infant gambling. I
sympathize with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> blew a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> on the cards. (I
always sympathize with the irredeemably stupid.) I wonder, however, having now
watched the show, that it may be its impenetrable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>-ness is what really
scares <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. Let's not forget that the zombie-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> on the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>
television commercials were raised on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Rangers</ENAMEX>. Whither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pok√</ENAMEX>©mon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tots</ENAMEX>?

            I was also going to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX> and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> license
plates that carry a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> in a cowboy hat, but I fear I've
run out of space and will have to save these gems for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
Mick

         
      
   
