
   
   
      
         
            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Protests Are More Equal Than Others</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mick</ENAMEX>--

            I am utterly, utterly serious when I say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffy</ENAMEX> the Vampire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slayer</ENAMEX> and seriously felt and thought-through opposition to the death
penalty existing as they do cheek by jowl in my life, I consider them to be
perfectly compatible and cohesive elements of a unified world view. Or maybe
not so unified, since, although I still don't agree with you about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miramax</ENAMEX>, I
see that I agree even less with myself, in that I don't actually think that the
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, feminist, and gay-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
regarding their portrayals by the mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are really of comparable weight,
seeing as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> of these special interests is allied with an extraordinarily
wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> with one of the most coherent and cooperative global
network of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> in history. I mean, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>. Kidding! I mean, of
course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (and
even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX> could probably learn a thing or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two about self-promotion</NUMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> did a story on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> reference to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
story) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Lehman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>, has led the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> into the sin of wrath before, when, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>, he co-sponsored a series of films on religious extremism that included
Hell's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Angel</ENAMEX> , a scathing critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> written and narrated
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX>. As I recall, his writings on this subject are
eminently rational. While in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehman</ENAMEX> also did an exhibition involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> cartoons, which seemed to bug the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Dreher</ENAMEX>,
almost as much.

            To prove my initial point about sociopolitical cheek<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by-jowlness</NUMEX>, I would
like to conclude by saying that if I have to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Kravitz</ENAMEX> sing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fly Away</ENAMEX>"
on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> ad one more time, I am going to consider starting a personal
little war, and like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Augustine</ENAMEX>, I would consider it just.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
Mim

         
      
   
