
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skewed Priorities</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mick</ENAMEX>--

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> again win!

            I think it's being a little hard on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> to say it folded on
Dogma; it kept its commitments to the film and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> by buying it (film,
not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>) back and arranging to distribute it independently.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transubstantiation</ENAMEX> makes you queasy because it's the consumption of someone's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, or on more philosophical grounds?

            In general, boycotts against works of the imagination as the primary focus
of a political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> are suspect, whether it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX>
against Dogma or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bret Easton Ellis</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psycho</ENAMEX> , or gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silence of the Lambs</ENAMEX> ,
which is not to say that I don't think these things should be as vigorously
debated as anyone cares to debate them, and in some cases more vigorously than
that. However, even leaving aside what are, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of those examples, to
me very valid questions of interpretation (I think--I haven't seen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dogma</ENAMEX> ), given that the resources of political activism on the behalf of
special interests are necessarily limited, I would prefer to put my dollar and
my anxiety down on the side of protecting actual, real live human beings
suffering actual, real live oppression, or the threat thereof. I wish that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX>, or for that matter anybody, seemed to give a fuck about the
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> has presided over a state that's executing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at such an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ungodly</ENAMEX> (as it were) rate, some of whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> did things like fall asleep
during their trials. In fact, I even feel like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX> for having to try to
curry sympathy for death-row <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> by pointing out the procedural
irregularities in their cases; I oppose executing them even when they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monsters</ENAMEX> in human form, because, while I can easily understand why someone
would want to kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> of their near and dear, I can't at all
understand why someone would want to give the state the power to kill
them--even if it's not being abused in that exact case, it's going to be, and
probably sooner rather than later, as the much-publicized racial statistics of
the death penalty's application demonstrate. Surely this is a more important
threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> doctrine than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX>? I believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has a shallow
kind of a defense in being technically dependent on the recommendations of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> for granting clemency, but he could at least pipe up, as long as
he's being so goddamned compassionate a conservative.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
Mim

         
      
   
