
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torts</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-Us

            Torts dominate the news, with major liability decisions about health
insurance, pharmaceuticals, and the manufacture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> covering the front
pages. Everyone leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s dramatic, bipartisan passage of a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' rights" bill, which would give the consumer a broad right to sue his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> for lack of coverage or substandard coverage. (This story gets three
columns in both Times <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">es</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
front one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest product-liability settlements: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Products</ENAMEX> has agreed to pay an inflation-adjusted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.75 billion dollars</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 16</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">fen-phen</ENAMEX>, the miracle weight-loss drug
banned for damaging heart valves. (This story is reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and runs
atop the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business and Finance</ENAMEX>" box.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the
LAT front a state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s dismissal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>'s lawsuit against <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>--one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> similar suits by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> against the firearms industry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> said the attempt to regulate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> through tort law represented an "improper attempt to have this court
substitute its judgment for that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>."

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' rights" bill passed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275</NUMEX>-151 (with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> defections)
in one of the rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> votes where the outcome was not known in advance. It
dealt a major blow to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, which had lobbied for a narrower
right-to-sue bill, defeated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-sponsor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dingell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>,
calling the bill "as fine a piece of work as I've ever seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>." The
legislation was supported by the labor and consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobbies</ENAMEX> as well as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX>, and fought by insurance and business groups, who
argued it would enrich trial lawyers and cause <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to drop medical
benefits for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. It now goes to a conference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, where it must be
reconciled with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> version that does not include expansive right-to-sue
provisions. Final passage is also threatened by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rider</ENAMEX> that gives tax-breaks
for certain health expenditures--which many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, say help only the rich.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.75 billion fen-phen</NUMEX> settlement includes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.55 billion</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> who
have developed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart-valve</ENAMEX> problems and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> to monitor the healthy and
issue refunds. Benefits are not limited to those who sued: Any one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who took the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> can submit claims, and there is no statute
of limitations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHP</ENAMEX> will refund prescription fees for anyone who took the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>;
payments for those with heart problems range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000 to $1.4 million</NUMEX>. The
settlement does not cover <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> outstanding lawsuits, which could cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">another $1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> to settle. Oddly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> puts the nominal, rather than the
inflation-adjusted, payout in both its headline and its lede. The LAT
is confusing money with wealth; it should do as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> does, and not mention the nominal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> at all. All the
papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHP</ENAMEX> will take a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.29 billion</NUMEX> after-tax charge against
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-quarter</TIMEX> earnings to pay for the entire settlement. Only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> explains why this amount is sufficient: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insurance</ENAMEX> pays the
rest. Although this charge works out to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.51</NUMEX> per share, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHP</ENAMEX>'s stock price rose
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.8%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX>, apparently, prefer certain losses to the
uncertainty of outstanding claims.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front the overwhelming victory of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX>-nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bharatiya Janata</ENAMEX>
Party. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> formed a centrist coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> which is expected to be
the most stable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atal Bihari Vajpayee</ENAMEX>
pledged to devote himself to economic reform and steer away from the
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> policies that have sometimes characterized his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sonia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress Party</ENAMEX> was dealt the worst defeat in its history.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise</ENAMEX>,
alleges that it has undefined goals, does not meet its own deadlines, takes
credit for corporate contributions and community projects with which it is only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peripherally</ENAMEX> involved, and does not reveal how or how much it pays its top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> traditionally do. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> in the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle of Philanthropy</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX> should disband
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reefers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s formation of an exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> for a
presidential campaign. "Unless I thought I could win the whole thing, I would
have no interest," he tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , which notes that The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX> has
name recognition and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated</NUMEX> worth of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX>. (To learn more about
exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, click 
here.)

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> to ratify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Comprehensive</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nuclear] Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX>, which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has been threatening to put off until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. "We will not be
relying on the good will of a rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> onto its
territory," the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> write. "Under the treaty, a global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of
[verification] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> is being set up. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rejection</ENAMEX> would give great
encouragement to proliferators. Rejection would also expose a fundamental
divergence within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>."

            
               USAT highlights another boon of the Internet: cheap caskets. "When
all is said and done, a casket is just a box with a door on it," says a former
truck-parts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> who now sells caskets. Buying caskets on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>--at
sites like directcasket.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, casketgallery.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and downtoearthcoffin.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>--creates "emotional detachment" about
the purchase, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , which helps grieving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> avoid the
exorbitant casket fees of funeral <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. "You don't feel that pressure to be
done with it and be out of there," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. "It's more like
buying a suit."


         
      
   
