
   
   
      
         
            How Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> Choose Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cybill Shepherd</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell Weicker</ENAMEX> are all reportedly considering running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>
presidential nomination. How does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> choose its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>?

            Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> must prove their viability by
conducting ballot drives as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">independents</ENAMEX> in some or all of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where
the party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> is not guaranteed a slot. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has ballot status in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where local party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> have been active since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.) Reform
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> will validate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> based on their progress toward getting
on the state ballots. Since there are no objective standards for approving or
rejecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, the process can be somewhat arbitrary. And because the
party lacks nationally recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>--excepting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>, who has declined to run, and party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>, who remains a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wildcard</ENAMEX>--a celebrity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> is likely to be chosen for his
high name recognition.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next July</TIMEX>, the qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will appear on a national primary
ballot, which will be distributed to any registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> who requests <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
Votes will be cast by e-mail, phone, and conventional mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> will rank
their top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> choices, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who receives a majority of No. 1
votes will be declared the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. If nobody wins a majority, an "instant
run-off" will be conducted: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> with the fewest No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> votes will be
eliminated, and all the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> votes cast on his ballots be elevated to No. 1
votes. This process of eliminating the last place finisher and elevating all
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> votes on his ballots will continue until a majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> is declared.
(If the No. 2 choice has been eliminated from the run-off, the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> votes will
be elevated to No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> votes.) The nomination will be ratified at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2000</TIMEX>
convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> voted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1996 Reform</ENAMEX> primary. If well-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> run in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, that number could explode, and the costs of
distributing, auditing, and counting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of ballots could bankrupt the
party. Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are also anxious about a takeover by a well-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> could cast enough ballots in the
primary to wrestle the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> away from current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Even a single-issue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, such as a staunch abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, might outperform an indigenous
Reform hopeful. And <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> could cast ballots for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> they hope will hurt the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            In light of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Gargan</ENAMEX> has
said he would like to alter the rules before the primary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. But current
party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> support the present process, saying the openness is crucial if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> is to grow.

            Next question?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah L. Sifry</ENAMEX>, who is writing a book on the prospects
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
