
   
   
      
         
            Let Down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear George</ENAMEX>,

            Breakfast is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late this morning</TIMEX>. I put my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> on the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a.m.</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> seems to have taken too long to kick in. Maybe its because
I actually <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink tea</ENAMEX>!

            I share your balanced view of crime control and inner-city policing. Your
more general point about the complexity of most public-policy issues is, of
course, right on the mark. Yet, it doesn't matter whether the topic is public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, health care, or free speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> routinely look for the
position that plays best in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. Of course, the mainstream media don't do
very much to raise the level of public discourse. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were remarkably consistent in their choice of lead stories <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Museum To Sue City Over Art Flap: No Dung Deal</ENAMEX>"; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Defiant Museum Tells Rudy the Show Goes On"</ENAMEX>; and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> Sues <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Keep Mayor From Freezing</ENAMEX>
Funds." Oh yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> also gets front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
coverage for his possible presidential bid. I know that the public likes to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entertained</ENAMEX>, but would this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum story</ENAMEX> actually be playing for an entire week
if it didn't have a salacious element to it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> wasn't using it to
score points with conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>? The issue of public funding for the arts
is actually quite important, and yet there is nothing in the discussion that
would help a thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> come to some position on this public policy
issue.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> is another matter. I think he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> have got more
press on their "presidential aspirations" than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>!
Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> actually released his proposal for a health plan for the
uninsured. This is very important for urban areas, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, where
so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are uninsured. To its credit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> covered the story, but it is nowhere to be found in the
News . Yet, even the most intent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> would find it difficult to
evaluate the plan from the coverage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , but at least it was
there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s school-voucher program, another important issue for urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, was covered only in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .

            By the time you get my thoughts you will probably be completely exhausted
from driving and teaching. Can't the policy discussion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> do better
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>? Hope your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> went well.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warmest</ENAMEX> regards,
Ester

         
      
   
