
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Randomly Proportioned Cocktail</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mim</ENAMEX>:

            Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>--that eruption of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> when we
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> met, and I almost drank myself to death--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> would repeat the story
of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> would watch the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 o'clock</TIMEX> network news, but then happily
go on and take in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wheel of Fortune</ENAMEX> , even though the
problems of the presidency continued to loom. They were seeking early
confirmation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX> was as dumb as a dinner plate, but I found it one of the
befuddled old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">huckster</ENAMEX>'s more endearing qualities. You are absolutely right
when you say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy the Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX> and your
opposition to the death penalty must exist "cheek by jowl." The modern world
comes at us as a randomly proportioned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail</ENAMEX> of the portentous, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrifying</ENAMEX>, and the trivial. Although it may seem to some like ersatz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sophistication</ENAMEX>, the only way I can find to process the torrent of information
to which I find myself constantly exposed is with a trash aesthetic. While all
around grows unmanageably grave, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie</ENAMEX>
Izzard, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Elroy</ENAMEX> novel, or the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell</ENAMEX> is giving away free
alien eyeballs, and I simply have to have one, all prevent my perspectives from
succumbing to the kind of cultural isolation and spiteful tunnel vision that
has become the hallmark of modern political discussion.

            One e-mail complainant castigates 
                  Slate
                for allowing someone "who wrote a
book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Morrison"</ENAMEX> loose to practice news commentary at "The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast</ENAMEX>
Table." (In fact, it's a novel that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> just describes as "jagged and flashy," but that's beside the point.)
So what does this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> want? Another pigeonhole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak/Arianna Huffington Pundit School</ENAMEX>, where absolute and entrenched "my side
right, your side wrong" makes a marketable media commodity? Unfortunately homie
can't play that, and I don't think, dear, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mim</ENAMEX>, you can either. We both still
think too much, and are even willing to lower our sophistication, no matter how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ersatz</ENAMEX>, to the childlike simplicity of asking what's wrong with this picture
when needed.

            The reason I have spent so much space and energy
sticking needles in the voodoo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> is not because I'm a
committed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>, compassionate conservative, or
whatever. My politics are, in fact, much more murky. (In the privacy of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>,
I still weep for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IWW</ENAMEX>.) I simply don't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--and the world--to enter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a new millennium</TIMEX> ruled by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was elected
to the most powerful post on the planet simply because he had the most
money.

            Promoting my book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conspiracies</ENAMEX>,
Lies and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hidden Agendas</ENAMEX> , I encountered large numbers of very frightened
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. These are the ones who believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> are merely fronts
for the New World Order or the infiltrating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>. Oh yes, easy to dismiss
them as crazy, but they are also some of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 million</NUMEX> with no health care,
and the downsized castoffs whose manufacturing jobs have been sold south to
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> World cheap labor. Refuge in paranoid fantasy because reality is devoid
of hope creates that highly fertile soil where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> of the most dangerous kind
can germinate. The next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is going the need all the brilliance,
flexibility, and cultural insight it can muster, and I'll welcome these
attributes, if genuine, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any quarter</TIMEX> and attached to just about any track
record.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Love, l-u-v</ENAMEX>
Mick

         
      
   
