
   
   
      
         
            Me and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>, and Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mick</ENAMEX>--

            In a survey of news uncommented upon by us about which
I might at least have something entertaining or informative to say, I ran into
the commuter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> crash in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, which has so far a death toll of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> and is
of course horrifying, but speaks for itself; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom-Sprint</ENAMEX>
merger. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>. I once had such an ugly experience with the customer-service
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that I wrote its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a letter of
complaint on the letterhead of an impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in which I stated my
intention of reporting in print how unpleasant it had been dealing with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> at every conceivable opportunity and that I would consider myself to be
doing a service to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> thereby. OK, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>. This has been my first
opportunity! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX>, beware! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> was mean to me! Me, me, me, me, me! I find it
hard to discharge my punditry duties in this space without coming across as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unbecomingly</ENAMEX> stuck on myself. You have been managing this very gracefully, I
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> with (unbecoming) egotistical irritation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inside Politics</ENAMEX> is,
at this very moment, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>, going to address the question:
Can <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> walk away from his controversial comments? I wasn't
taking notes, but I think this is pretty much the exact same question that was
being posed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. I know the answer! Call on me! In a word, Yes! Yes, he
can! It seems to me self-evident that if your poll approval ratings can go from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>-something to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-something in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as short a period of three months</TIMEX>, they really
didn't mean a whole hell of a lot to begin with!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philippe de Montebello</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, I did mean to say. To get even more parish-pump,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>-publishing news of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Publications</ENAMEX> is putting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin , Vibe</ENAMEX> , and the
Blaze up for sale. And to get even more parish-pump
than that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Stern</ENAMEX> also recently announced that he was selling the
Village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> , my very first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, as you of
course know since I got the job owing to your recommendation when I had no
experience at all, because you were tired of hearing me blather on, much as I
am doing now, but more crankily, as we sat in bars back when we met in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">go-go '80s.</ENAMEX>

            Do you really think, to jump back to your initial
e-mail, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> would be a candidate worth breaking one's heart
over?

            I am looking forward more than I can say to the season
premiere episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy the Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
Mim

         
      
   
