
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Impossible Dream of Equality</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Nat</ENAMEX>,

            You strike a balanced note at the end of your message that I think is
absolutely appropriate. On the subject of heredity, you note that some portion
of intelligence does seem to be hereditary, or at least so many serious people
say. So while we should try to reduce inequality of opportunity, there will
always be some, since some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are born smarter, and that intelligence may
reproduce itself down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>.

            That doesn't mean we need dwell on the negative. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s narrative makes
clear, the current meritocratic sorting system has done a good deal to reduce
inequality of opportunity. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> was based on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and, to a much
larger extent, looks--things that are totally and overwhelmingly hereditary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> once remarked that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX> consisted of animal
magnetism married to money. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the virtues of the education-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> of
ours is that it has reduced the influence of looks, magnetism, and social
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">polish</ENAMEX>, though it will never get rid of them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> also makes it clear that the current meritocratic system is far more
egalitarian than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual founders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chauncey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conant</ENAMEX>, intended. They
wanted to create a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite class</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guardians</ENAMEX> who would serve the public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">selflessly</ENAMEX>. That was elitist, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> tends to wash away elitist plans. It
was also naive, and reality tends to smash those notions. There is never going
to be a selfless class of guardians, no matter what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plato</ENAMEX> may have imagined.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the nice things about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s story is the way it moves from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conant</ENAMEX>'s
lofty writings down to the gritty struggles of politics and campaigns, showing
how the original idea--sorting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by scientific tests--was twisted by
events.

            I finish this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> more aware of the limitations of our current
meritocracy, but not moved to support radical changes to it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> has opened
up opportunity for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> would not disagree). But I think
it would be pushing things too far to make the sorts of changes Lemann hints at
in his conclusion. That would be to try to impose an overly egalitarian plan
onto a society that is interested in opportunity and striving. If there's one
thing we have learned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, it is that you can't force-feed
egalitarianism on human beings.
Anyway, it's been an honor chatting with you about this, but now I've got to
toddle off and work on a review I'm writing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Law Olmsted</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Public Interest</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> there will skin me alive
if I miss my deadline.

            All the best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
