
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trump Card</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> politics--both the fight over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive</ENAMEX>
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nuclear] Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX> and over health care. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the crossed paths of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> is control of the
Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s foreign-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> takes to the chat-show circuit to
argue that rejection of the nuclear-testing treaty would scuttle international
non-proliferation efforts. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Shelton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> appear on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> on
Late Edition .) Since the treaty probably cannot muster the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> votes it needs to be ratified, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> actually argue
that it should be tabled rather than voted on. Many treaty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> cite
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lugar</ENAMEX>'s assertion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> will not have the
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> to simulate nuclear tests, as promised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> about this, she responds
only that there is "ongoing work" on computer models. But many treaty advocates
(such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) note that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> , no <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dove</ENAMEX>, who unilaterally stopped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> nuclear
testing--computer models or no computer models.

            Despite the apparent victory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> on short-term treaty ratification,
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> see the right-to-sue-your-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> bill (passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defectors</ENAMEX>) as a sign of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> weakness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ) notes that since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cried</ENAMEX> foul when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tried to
prohibit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> from suing their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> as part of his failed
health-care plan, it's hypocritical for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> to side with the HMOs this time
around.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> derides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> for
"trying to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination" by attacking "good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. However, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>) think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s move was smart. "I have never seen a candidate for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in my
lifetime who was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> have a better week than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had," intones <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> on both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour and Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gang</ENAMEX> .

            All the shows taped on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> focus on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-evening</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
fund-raiser in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> attended simultaneously. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
was more assertive and, some argue, more personable than in the past. (At the
start of his speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> stepped in front of the podium, looked at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>--who was seated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>--and told him to signal his consent to
a debate on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> agricultural issues by standing up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> remained seated.)
(To find out why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> might be reluctant, click here.) Many on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has revived his
campaign: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> calls his speech "a glimpse" of the endearing, "informal"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> know; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Tumulty</ENAMEX> calls it "the scrappiest performance
we've seen from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX>"; while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Yepsen</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> looked
"liberated" and that he "stopped the bleeding" in his campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> looked "stunned" after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
speech. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was "undignified"
and his hectoring of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was "beneath him," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
looked "like an elementary school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>" in front of the podium. (To learn
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is a bore and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is merely boring, click 
here.)

            The fallout from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>'s now-notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> interview continues. Grilled on This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ref</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, does not apologize but does look more chastened
than he did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, he also
says he had lunch with potential presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>.) Appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press and Late Edition</ENAMEX> , the
current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Verney</ENAMEX>--calls for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> to resign and says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> has not yet ruled himself out of the
presidential race. (This, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> note, does not bode well for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s effort to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX>'s backing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>'s presidential
nomination.) On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , the incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Gargan</ENAMEX>--defends <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s right to speak, saying
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> elected him as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>."

            

               Ivana, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marla ... Buffy</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> takes on the weighty task of
pondering whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> presidential candidacy would have a salutary
effect on the health of the polity. One pressing question: Who would be first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> is unmarried, but he has told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> that he
could get hitched "within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>" if need be.) Obligingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> suggests <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
suitable matches for The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>: a) Xena the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warrior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX>, b) Sabrina the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teenage Witch</ENAMEX>, c) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Anderson Lee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmen Electra</ENAMEX>, e) Buffy the Vampire
Slayer, and of course f) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX>. But why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> seeking public office
in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> have a theory:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Tumulty</ENAMEX>: "I can't tell what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> [of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX>
Party] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> represents. His only rationale for running so far seems to
be he has better-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>: "Now that would be a good debate!"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>: "Yeah, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> will say,] 'Show me the
evidence.' "

            
               Last Word
            

            From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang :</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron Dorgan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.D.</ENAMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is] trying to create an
impression somehow that he's different than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> agenda.
[But] his agenda is virtually identical."

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>: "You're saying that image isn't important in
politics?"

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorgan</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, image is important."

Novak: "You'd better believe it."

            [To learn more about all of these stories and find links to the smartest
commentary on them, visit <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The</ENAMEX>
Spin.]

         
      
   
