
   
   
      
         
            Who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Airhead Here</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dinesh</ENAMEX>,

            Well, let's not worry too much about our happy state of
agreement. I'm sure we'll find something to argue about--probably beginning
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            It will not surprise you, I'm sure, that I have never
been a great admirer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, although it may surprise you that I
feel, as you do, that he is one of the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> and that he displayed a certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that, whatever his other limitations, helped make his
presidency enormously successful and influential. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> seems to sense that
and at times to concede it, but he is so preoccupied with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s unremarkable
personal opaqueness that he doesn't really convey the power of his personality
adequately or fairly. And I think you are right that his own self-conscious
displays of erudition (which include his very mediocre poetry) lead him to
evaluations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> that are both condescending and politically naive.

            I confess that I have only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> worked my way through
the last chapters of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' book, and what strikes me is that it actually gets
worse as it moves farther away from its unconventional literary techniques. The
autobiographical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> are less intrusive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governorship</ENAMEX> and the presidency, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' limitations as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> are much more glaringly on display--as you also note. You and I will
undoubtedly be alarmed by different examples of these weaknesses. But let me
give several illustrations of a kind of historical simplemindedness that is in
many ways as bad as, or worse than, the simplemindedness he sometimes
attributes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>.

            Here, for example, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' riff on the
extraordinarily complicated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-year</TIMEX> history of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> welfare
state: "Under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> on welfare was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-classified as 'self-supporting' the moment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> was hired ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wives</ENAMEX> thus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'abandoned</ENAMEX>' [when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> left home to preserve welfare benefits] found it
profitable to go on having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>--by whomever--in order to notch up the family
income." This problem remained contained, he says, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, when "the
New Deal idea of 'benefits' as emergency help, to be applied for reluctantly
and granted responsibly, became the Great Society concept of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'entitlements</NUMEX>.' "
(I've left out only a few sentences of this passage and have not, I think,
altered its meaning in doing so.) It is hard to know where to begin to critique
this monumentally ignorant description of the welfare system. There is no
evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADC</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX> (or long after) caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> to
abandon their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>, and no evidence at all to support the insulting statement
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> "went on" having babies "by whomever" in order to increase their
very meager welfare payments. Even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> and beyond, there is very little
evidence to support the argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> is responsible for illegitimate
births. The Great Society did nothing to change the definition of entitlements
under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> (although it did of course add new ones--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' footnotes cite only a few stray <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> articles, a book on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s welfare reform efforts that makes none of the claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> does,
and, significantly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>'s Losing
Ground .

            The last chapters of the book are filled with these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">casual</ENAMEX>, simplistic, and uninformed observations about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public policy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> claims, for example, that the New Deal launched a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year</TIMEX> effort to
force the distribution of wealth downward. In fact, there was virtually no
downward distribution of wealth during the New Deal or in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 50 years</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>--and only a modest downward distribution during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>,
caused not by taxation but by economic growth and rising wages. Nor did any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> advocate or attempt to produce downward distribution of wealth; even
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> included) explicitly rejected that as a social
goal.

            Even more astonishing is his flippant dismissal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s economic program--a dismissal visible in the very scant attention he
gives it in this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX>-page book and in his remarks at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> points about how
bored he was to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> talk about it. I don't think much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
economic policies, although I concede that some good things flowed from them;
but whatever one thinks of them, they do mark an extraordinarily important
moment in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> can't be bothered with them. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
returns to his "tax program" in an interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> tells us that "my heart
sank, and I mentally deducted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> from the time remaining." In fact, it
seems there were many things about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s life and career that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
considered too boring to attend to. There is almost nothing in this book about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s campaigns, and an astonishing passage on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">645</NUMEX> perhaps explains
why. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> describes sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. (Whether this is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48-year-old</TIMEX> "real" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> or the 75-year-old
fictional one is not clear.) He reads him a passage from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Cecil</ENAMEX>'s
famous biography of Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>--a favorite of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglophiles</ENAMEX> the world
over--and asks for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s response. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> begins talking about some
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX> presidential campaigning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> "let my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> do the
listening. Fortunately, I had several photocopied pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecil</ENAMEX>'s biography in
my folder, and read them with surreptitious enjoyment while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> retraced his
steps to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> convention. The great clock ticked on an on." I
have a similar sensation reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' book.

            More <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
