
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> Doesn't Want You To Know
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mim</ENAMEX>:

            If, as I postulated in my book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Kitty</ENAMEX> is a
conspiracy of very small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> to take over the world, I wish they would hurry
up and get their act together, because I absolutely do not think they could do
a worse job than very rich, old and middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. I say this with some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> since I have discovered conclusively that world may well be about to
end.

            This information came from the unlikely source of the
normally ultraconservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> ,
in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenny McCartney</ENAMEX> reports how a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> science project has
discovered things are much worse than we hitherto imagined. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A quarter</TIMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s mammals are at serious risk of extinction, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the forests
have now been cleared, and most coral reefs are either dead or dying. This is
not to mention the huge chunks of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> that keep falling off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX>, or the
radiation fallout from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> nuclear plant accident that we're expecting
momentarily here on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>. I'm somewhat surprised our imminent demise
has been ignored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, and entirely disappointed that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> couldn't have come up with a headline like
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet Earth--Fat Lady About To Sing</ENAMEX>." Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eco</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has kept quiet
on this one, although I suspect his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX> told him to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ix</NUMEX>-nay on the
pocalypse-ay, not only because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> don't want to hear the bad news but also
because of all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> will annex the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Y2K</TIMEX> chaos, take away our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, and put us all in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. (Believe
me, they're out there. I met of lots of them while I was promoting my
conspiracy book.)

            Since I'm about as daunted by the prospect of walking
around with a sign saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End Is At Hand</ENAMEX>" as you are by public speaking, I
will take the entirely selfish way out. Feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>, hope things hold together
long enough for my next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> novels to get into print, watch a lot of E! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX>
TV, and resume all vices, since mere self-destruction no longer matters. It'd
be nice to make enough money to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last days</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roppongi</ENAMEX> red-light
district of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>. I was there with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the year</TIMEX> and it seemed
the perfect place to spend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Kitty</ENAMEX> uprising might also be
in full swing. Tiny schoolgirls with automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klebold</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> to shame.

            I don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> wears a toupee, but I will ask
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>, she knows about these things. (There is no hair inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eden</ENAMEX>?) My last word on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backstreet Boys</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX> has a
magnificent parody of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Want It That Way" called "Get KY.</ENAMEX>"

            If nothing more fascinating comes up, remind me tomorrow
to tell you why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> is really being given so much money to get elected.
My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> on this is no less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> , so watch out. Also, did you see that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> has an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave garment workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX>? Maybe this world should be doomed.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
Mick

         
      
   
