
   
   
      
         
            Moralityville, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mim</ENAMEX>:

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. I fear it's one of those <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> when
breakfast would seem to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>, a cigarette, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tylenol</ENAMEX>. The Decision
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> graphics are up on the TV news shows, which means we are about to fall
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 months</TIMEX> of electioneering, and here we both are indulging in it in
our own ways. I find the progressive expansion of elections is as distressing
as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">decorations</ENAMEX> now going up before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> has only marginally penetrated here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>. We have the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> coming unglued with accusation of drug
dealing and death-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> tactics, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riordan</ENAMEX> is in hiding as usual. But,
of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> thing is absolutely nothing more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more
political sideshow, and a cheap midway shuck at that. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX>,
there are going to be plenty more where that came from.

            It's a symptom of an electoral process rapidly turning
into some frightening theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, one section of which is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moralityland</ENAMEX> (the
main ride being tempests revolving in teacups labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Values</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>, etc., etc.) Fortunately only a small, if loud,
minority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moralityland</ENAMEX> any more, and that's why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> 2-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex scandals writ
small, which served only to prove that the entire political establishment has
grown so far removed from the mood of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, it's little wonder that I'm
hoping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> will run, if only to save my sanity--although I fear as a
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> he will break my heart just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX> did all those
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>--and others are looking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, if not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> then
at least as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>.

            Indeed, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> didn't declare, and some
callow pundit on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> all but called him a communist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, interviewed
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Grobel</ENAMEX>, was the single
refreshing waft of normality. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro wrestler</ENAMEX> by trade, did nameless
Apocalypse Now stuff in 'Nam as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy Seal</ENAMEX>, and
rode with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mongols Motorcycle Club</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX>. Seems as reasonable a
resume as being a quasi-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich kid</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$56 million</NUMEX> to burn on being Big
Oil's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puppet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, and indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>'s utterances on drug and prostitution
decriminalization, on the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and the oft-quoted snap about
organized religion being a crutch for the weak-minded and an excuse to stick
their noses in other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s business, are the kind of discussion I haven't
heard from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbie Hoffman</ENAMEX> took it on the lam. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> at least
seems instinctively to grasp that it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> got
himself elected, and the same old buzz words are so worn out they will no
longer play. I'm not sure I exactly want Jesse in charge of the national nukes,
but I feel much the same about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>

            And on the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>, did he, I wonder, watch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McNaughton</ENAMEX>'s film <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait of a Serial</ENAMEX>
Killer before commuting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Lee Lucas</ENAMEX>' death sentence?

            I very much miss the headlines in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , but I think I have to leave the reasons for that until the
Tylenol kick in.

            You won't get a fight out of me on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backstreet Boys</ENAMEX>.
This old rocker doesn't care which way they get it. Should liking them or not
liking them be the new political litmus test?

            Much love,
Mick

         
      
   
