
   
   
      
         
            Metabolife: Read This! No, Wait, Don't Read This!

            Chatterbox was intrigued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Orwall</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX> story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> about how the diet-pill
maker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife International, Inc.</ENAMEX>, was launching a preemptive strike against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> , which is
investigating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. As explained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> story, and in a full-page ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> took out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> is inviting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to view, unedited, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20/20</TIMEX> interview (of which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>,
following an increasingly common practice, made a videotape of its own) on a
special "screw you, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
News" Web site. The stunt has generated scads of publicity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>,
and has prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> to make the blustery threat that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from now</TIMEX> on
interview subjects will be forced to sign away their rights to make public
whatever it is they tell its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intrepid reporters</ENAMEX>. (How any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewee</ENAMEX> who isn't
also guaranteed that the story will be a puff piece could possibly be induced
to sign such an agreement remains to be seen. Perhaps those who don't sign will
be forbidden to take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to the forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toy Story</ENAMEX> sequel.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> believes that sunlight is the best disinfectant for everybody,
including the press, and looks forward to comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s raw footage to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">20/20</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> whenever it airs.
(It has yet to be scheduled.) Chatterbox clicked on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metabolife</ENAMEX> Web site
to give his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> some preview of what the controversy in question is all
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. Being only human, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was especially intrigued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> story's claim that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20/20</TIMEX> interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s chief
executive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ellis</ENAMEX>, was asked

            

               
                  to address some embarrassing
personal baggage: his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> conviction for using a telephone to facilitate drug
trafficking, after he was arrested in connection with a methamphetamine lab
that was operated out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> he rented. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX> received <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>'
probation in the case.
               

            

            But when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> actually got to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metabolife</ENAMEX> Web site, he was
confronted with an unbelievably complex "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> agreement" requiring Chatterbox
to promise in advance to eschew any "reproduction, broadcast, retransmissions,
or nontransient storage" of the matter contained therein.  The Web site's
contents "are only for your personal, noncommercial use." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>. Is Web
journalism "commercial use"? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> does get paid to write this column.) The user
agreement went on to clarify:

            

               
                  [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ou</ENAMEX> will not access or use, or
permit others to access or use, this website for (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) print, video or audio
publication, broadcast, retransmission or any newmedia use [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">italics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s] .
... 
                  In its sole discretion and in
addition to any other rights or remedies available to it, Metabolife
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International, Inc.</ENAMEX> reserves the right to determine whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">User</ENAMEX>(s) is
(are) engaging in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Improper Conduct</ENAMEX>, [and] charge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registered User</ENAMEX> (whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> or access rights have been used for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Improper Conduct</ENAMEX>) an Improper
Conduct service fee. ... You may not download, display, reproduce, create
derivative works from, transmit, sell, distribute, or in any way exploit the
Site or any portion thereof for any public or commercial use or any news or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> use without the express advanced written permission of
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Metabolife</ENAMEX>] . ...
               

            

            The threat of litigation tends to scare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> out of his wits, and by
now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wasn't at all sure he wanted to press ahead. Instead, he phoned
Metabolife, which referred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> to its public relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sitrick</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX>, where a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Fahn</ENAMEX> assured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that all the
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mumbo-jumbo</ENAMEX> "basically is just to make sure that nobody goes off and
duplicates the exact videotape we have because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> owns the copyright.
... You can quote the transcript." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fahn</ENAMEX> then passed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> on to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Sitrick</ENAMEX>, who repeated these assurances. "We're not trying to take what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
has done here and say, 'NBC, you can use parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Diaz</ENAMEX>'s interview.' "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Er</ENAMEX>, why not? What's it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metabolife</ENAMEX>? Indeed, shouldn't Metabolife be thrilled at the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX> would
stick it to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX> believed was out to get them? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oddly</ENAMEX>,
neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> nor any other broadcast outlet has requested the videotape so far;
though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> received special permission to run
photographs of the Web page in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s issues.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sitrick</ENAMEX> responded
diplomatically that "we are hopeful that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">20/20</ENAMEX> 's newscast will be fair and objective."
To summarize: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> wants everybody to see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20/20</TIMEX> interview. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX> says it will sue any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who tries to disseminate this
information. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX> says it isn't really going to sue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who
disseminate this information. It just wants to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> from its
broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. Or something.

         
      
   
