
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostrophe S</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' passage of a health-insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and is atop the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which usually plays up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> intrigue, reefers this story.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s criticisms of it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> is the lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Football League</ENAMEX>'s decision to pass over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Angels</ENAMEX> and put an expansion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> instead. (This story is
put above the fold by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and reefered by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .) A
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $700 million</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>--the highest price
ever paid for a pro sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>--plus a publicly financed, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX>
glass-walled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> with a retractable roof.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> (over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>) health-insurance bill
would, among other things, a) accelerate the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> tax deduction for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-employed</ENAMEX>, b) expand the availability of tax-free accounts for medical
payments, and c) create tax deductions for long-term-care insurance. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> said the bill would help <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> threatened to veto it in its present form. But the main event
is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> votes on competing "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> rights" bills, which would
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to sue their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. (On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time threw its weight behind a limited right to sue--see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> for
details.)

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , run follow-ups to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s rebuke of congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Bush</ENAMEX> of abandoning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> rank and file, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> backtracked
slightly, stressing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s image as heartless was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caricature</ENAMEX>, not reality. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
response a "backlash" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, but the other papers are more favorable to
him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story stresses the inability of
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to soften their image post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> are
still solidly conservative, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' assertions to the
contrary; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
remarks his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souljah</ENAMEX> moment"--referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
successful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> strategy of distancing himself from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s ideological
base. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Ballot Box</ENAMEX>'s take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> brouhaha, click here.)
            

            The LAT fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s
disclosure that the computer networks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>,
and of defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> have undergone a year of extensive, coordinated
cyberattacks from overseas computers--some from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> have stolen
unclassified but sensitive information on weapons research. One thing holding
up effective countermeasures, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> writes, is a culture clash between low-tech
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and the geeky computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> helping them with encryption.

            Following up on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that a diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is using a
Web
site to broadcast an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> interview of its chief executive
before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> has aired the program in which the
interview will be used. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> often make their own tapes of their
interviews with the press.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife International Inc.</ENAMEX> says that after
discovering the Web site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Diaz</ENAMEX> (titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Schemes, Scams, and Savin' a Buck</ENAMEX>"), it began
to suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s report will be unfair to its product, so it released the
entire interview on the Internet as part of a counteroffensive. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX>
envisions a world in which every interview subject is his own media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdog</ENAMEX>;
when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> quotes him out of context, the subject need not beg an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> for space or time to respond--he can simply publish the unedited
interview himself.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes the
demise of a hallowed cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>: the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding-</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> consummation.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> live together before marriage, and less than
one-fifth are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">virgins</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their wedding</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. As a result, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newlyweds</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-to-24-year-olds</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of those over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>--would
rather spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their wedding</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> engaged in non-connubial activities like
partying with wedding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> visiting from afar. "Sex, when it happens" for
newlyweds, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , "is often an
apostrophe, not an exclamation point."

         
      
   
