
   
   
      
         
            <i>Dogma</i><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Sacred</ENAMEX> Profanity

            At a press conference following the screening of his film <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dogma</ENAMEX> ,
which will have its first public showing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 4</TIMEX> as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Film</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Festival</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, and professed devout <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Smith</ENAMEX>
appeared both shell-shocked and befuddled by the outrage that his movie, sight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unseen</ENAMEX>, had provoked. We're talking about a fury so fierce (it has been
spearheaded by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> and its parent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, dropped the theological comedy-thriller like a hot cross bun.
Protests are planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Center</ENAMEX>, and all involved (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">picture</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate Films</ENAMEX>) have braced themselves for more
noise and death threats. The only silver lining, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, was that he'd
edited out that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>-dung <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> scene. I mean, it's one thing to have
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX> mad at you, but you don't want to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> mad at you."

            Finally seeing the movie, I find it hard not to share <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s perplexity. It
would be one thing if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dogma were</ENAMEX>, as charged, virulently <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Catholic</ENAMEX>
or even blasphemous. But the film, a sort of apocalyptic Miltonian vaudeville,
is among the most passionately religious and God-fearing ever made in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It's supremely moving. True, it's also raucous, bloody, smutty, and
strewn with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-letter words, and the final incarnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almighty</ENAMEX> has
little in common with depictions you might find in, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>.
Yet the qualities that make Dogma seem a work of irreverence are
precisely those that make it so spiritually reanimating. The film has been made
by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> for whom questions of faith are central to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life. It seems
only logical, then, not to segregate those questions from that life but to
weave them in with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX>'s other obsessions: friendship, lust,
drinking, love of trashy horror flicks, and the compulsion to sit around
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">b.s.'ing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> about why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creator</ENAMEX> made so many things that are patently
absurd.

            The movie's canvas--too vast to itemize completely here--features a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Borscht Belt</ENAMEX> turn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Carlin</ENAMEX>) who argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
should not be represented by gory images of his earthy demise. After all: "He
was a booster !" Seizing on a loophole in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> dogma, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bishop</ENAMEX>
plans to reconsecrate his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> so that anyone who passes through its archway
will be officially cleansed of sin and entitled to enter heaven. This attracts
the notice of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> waggish, somewhat insane fallen angels (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>, who have a hilarious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope-Crosby</ENAMEX> rapport): They have spent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>
depressing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in exile (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>) and now see a way to "go home." The
problem, then, is the tension between dogma and God's will. If the angels (who
become serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> on their trek to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, gorily murdering Ten
Commandments violators as a kind of last hurrah), succeed in their mission, God
will be shown to be fallible, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> will not hold, and the apocalypse will
destroy all life in the universe.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>, naturally, do all they can to make that
happen, while God's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>--among them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Rickman</ENAMEX> as the resonant and
wearily fey "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice of God</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salma Hayek</ENAMEX> as a slinky muse, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris Rock</ENAMEX> as the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thirteenth Apostle</ENAMEX>" (the black one expunged from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripture</ENAMEX>)--struggle to stave
off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armageddon</ENAMEX>. For reasons that would spoil a number of surprises, their
efforts revolve around a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bethany</ENAMEX> (an unprecedentedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soulful Linda Fiorentino</ENAMEX>), who goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> but feels that God
has stopped listening. The core of the film, emotionally, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bethany</ENAMEX>'s
conversations with sundry mortals, angels, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX> about her loss of faith.
The complaints about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> dogma are voiced by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apostle</ENAMEX>, who
argues that what matters most is faith and not the rituals that are supposed to
give it a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seal of Approval</ENAMEX>.

            So yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dogma</ENAMEX> is critical of organized religion. But why not regard
it as the constructive criticism of a believer? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> described it as "kicking
the tires of my faith," and added that he considers both God and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>" who would not be averse to having fun poked at them--especially when
that fun is grounded in a fervent respect for their existence and power. In the
movie's credits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> thanks a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa</ENAMEX>," who changed his life, he
said, when she declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' remark during the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Supper</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
would be the rock of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was likely facetious--a joke. Suddenly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
said, the figures at the heart of Christianity weren't abstract theological
mouthpieces but flesh-and-blood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> who spoke his language.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> believes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX>, which is authorized by neither the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>, was looking for an excuse to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> that
particular week. (Many of the letters sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinstein</ENAMEX> were homicidally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>.) But I'm not so sure that the film
would have slipped by unnoticed in any event. Another deeply devout and
religious film, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Temptaion of Christ</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>),
was furiously attacked for portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> as lost and uncertain--plagued by
doubts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> slyly echoes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s film when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rickman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice of God</ENAMEX>,
attempting to convert the reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethany</ENAMEX> to his cause, explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
didn't take it any better when told of the painful destiny that awaited him: "I
had to deliver the news to a scared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who only wanted to play with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who find threatening the idea that no serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>, no faith worth a damn--not of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, angels, or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>--could possibly
be untested.

            It's the atheists and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agnostics</ENAMEX> who have the easiest time making movies
nowadays--the ones who don't confront the issue of faith at all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, get crucified. "I tried to do something good and got hassled for
it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>. "To spread the word of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, and also throw in a few fart
and dick jokes." An amusing series of titles that open the film now urge the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> not to get too worked up--to see the movie not as a fanatical attack
on religion but as a reverent goof. But he's worried about the "good
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>" who haven't seen Dogma yet and have written to say that he
better buy himself a flak jacket. Once they see it, he said, their minds
will change--"I mean, it's got a rubber poop monster!"

         
      
   
