
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Patriotic Challenger</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIMI VALLEY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>--On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to a
breakfast speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> got a brief
briefing on local conditions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Weaver</ENAMEX>, his national political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>,
alerted him that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> waiting inside the aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hangar</ENAMEX> might include
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy DeVos</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, who happens to be married to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway Corp.</ENAMEX>, and who also happens to be a committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> of campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> reform. "Then I'll just have to emphasize campaign finance reform,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> replied, grinning mischievously. He then recalled a previous meeting
when he brought his signature issue up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, doing an impression of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeVos</ENAMEX>' reaction in a small meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> clenched his teeth, screwed up his
face, and snarled, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRRRRRRR</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> didn't spot Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeVos</ENAMEX> at the breakfast, but he
dwelt on campaign finance reform anyhow--he always does. Running on this issue
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> may be the most contrarian notion in his delightfully
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contrarian</ENAMEX> campaign. It's not clear that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> outside of reform-minded
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> have ever made up their minds about whom to vote for on
the basis of this issue. What is certain--or at least was until his
campaign--is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who continue to enjoy a substantial advantage in
raising money under the current system, see little appeal in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s ideas
about how to reform it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> thinks he can elevate the issue--and his
presidential candidacy--by broadening the issue beyond its numbing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technicalities</ENAMEX>. He hopes to link it to the apathy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel about
politics and to a larger sense of national purpose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> thinks the fact that
special interest money dominates the electoral system is a big part of the
reason that a majority of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-to-26-year-olds</TIMEX> don't register and don't vote. He
sees political corruption not just as an Augean stable to be cleansed, but as a
positive issue that can serve to re-engage the disaffected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>.
"Restoring honesty to our political system is the gateway through which all
other political reforms must pass," he said here in a speech at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>, to sustained applause and a loud cry of "Amen" from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a skirt
and sneakers who later identified himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evangelical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Democrats</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>."

            The historical role model cited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adviser Karl Rove</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Hanna</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanna</ENAMEX> elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William McKinley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1896</TIMEX> by marshalling the wealth of the robber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX> on his behalf. The exemplar
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> who became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> after McKinley
was assassinated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>. When asked by a high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX>
who he thought of as the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, living or dead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> (who was
stopping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> en route to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan Library</ENAMEX>) cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> as his living
example and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, as the dead one.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain mentions Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX> frequently. He told me
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>--a plush <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Citation</ENAMEX> borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>--that he has been
reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX>'s speeches and finding them relevant to his campaign in a number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way is as a guide to political reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, he says,
understood that in reform, the perfect was the enemy of the good. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, who
recently agreed to drop everything but a ban on soft money from his eponymous
campaign reform bill, which is supposed to come up for another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote
soon, agrees. He says that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>, shrewd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> will find the
loopholes in any finance reform bill. Cleaning up the system thus has to be a
periodic, and inevitably incomplete, process. He hopes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>-Feingold
will reduce the power of special interest money in politics, not eliminate it,
because eliminating it is impossible. He has focused on soft money--unregulated
large contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>--because he thinks that they are the single
biggest problem, just as corporate contributions were when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> got them
banned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> sees other points of commonality with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> as
well. He frequently points out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s status as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conservation</ENAMEX>--a topic he plans to emphasize at an appearance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. This should be a fruitful theme for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, because there is
really no other claimant to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s environmental legacy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. Though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> fits the moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> profile in other respects, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
anti-regulatory, pro-business views steer him clear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX>.

            The most important link to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, however,
isn't any single issue. It's the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> aspires to draw political reform,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">environmentalism</ENAMEX>, an internationalist foreign policy, and more together in a
call for renewed civic engagement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s vision was summed up in the
phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Nationalism</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s somewhat ungainly slogan, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriotic Challenge</ENAMEX>," owes a debt to this. Sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> defines his
patriotic challenge in terms of political reform, as he did here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>, where he called it "a fight against the pervasive cynicism that is
debilitating our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>, that cheapens our public debates, that threatens
our public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, our culture and, ultimately, our private happiness."
Other times, he casts it as an "ask not" call to public service. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rapids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> says he wrote his new book in the hope that "young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might
pick it up and read it and realize the great virtue in committing themselves to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s cause." In his view, this includes all kinds of public service. "It
doesn't have to be military," he says. "It can be in a mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Forest Service</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>."

             

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has not yet managed to communicate his charisma
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, or to the young, in anything like the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> once did.
But his "new patriotic challenge" seems to strike a chord nonetheless. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> calls upon the rest of us to serve, he asks from a position of utter
credibility, based on what he sacrificed in serving. This is something that is
not true for any of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
