
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel Committee High on Grass</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the radiation leak from an uncontrolled chain
reaction at a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> processing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> not far from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> that hospitalized
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, contaminated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> more, and forced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> to
stay indoors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> seems to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s
criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> budget proposals that defer tax credits to low-income earners
is more important--it runs that story across <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> columns at the very top while
tucking the nuke puke underneath. Nobody else fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX>'s finding that household earnings reached record
(inflation-adjusted) levels last year--a median of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38,900</NUMEX>. The new stats
indicate particularly strong income surges in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and the suburbs and
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>. The LAT fronts the story, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> stuff it. Most of the income headlines muddy the real
news point somewhat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CENSUS REPORTS BROAD U.S. GAINS IN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INCOME</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (online at least) has RISING INCOMES LIFT <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.1 MILLION</NUMEX>
OUT OF POVERTY. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , seizing on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13.5 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor children</ENAMEX> cited
in the report, somehow manages to come up with a headline saying in part that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POVERTY CHANGES LITTLE</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> bigprints it best: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POVERTY</ENAMEX> AT <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-YEAR</TIMEX> LOW.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunter Grass</ENAMEX>'
winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize for Literature</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> accident was caused, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, when too much
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uranium</ENAMEX> was poured into a purification <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>. (This is not the only simple
mistake leading to a big one in the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> all cover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s
admission that the reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Orbiter</ENAMEX> was lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> was that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> did calculations for the mission using pounds and feet, while others
used the metric system.) The consensus among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mishap</ENAMEX> is nowhere near as environmentally threatening as either the meltdown at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mile Island</ENAMEX> or the far worse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX> catastrophe. However, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes a nuclear safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> saying that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most seriously
hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> may have received more radiation than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> at
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagasaki</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> emphasizes that the incident may well have political, as well
as real, fallout, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> are already predicting a
strong public opinion backlash against industry and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which was
seen by many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> as responding to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s events rather slowly.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that in response to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story about an
alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> massacre of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> war,
fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> has promised to
undertake a thorough investigation. The WP front-pager on this states
that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> "brushed aside" these very allegations, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>'s front effort calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s current stance an "abrupt
about-face."

            Only the WP fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s launching of a major ground offensive
inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers it). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> government
has cloaked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> in secrecy, saying only that ground fighting is
already underway, and indeed, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
had been fighting just inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> border for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that in a speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX> will urge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to end "indiscriminate" bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> and
to ease off on roundups of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, while offering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> help in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">combating Russia</ENAMEX>'s growing terrorism problem.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report inside that despite the likelihood of a
presidential veto, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> passed a bill that would establish new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> penalties for anyone who injures or harms a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> while committing
another federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>. The politically loaded aspect of the bill, explain the
papers, is whether or not it establishes a measure of legal standing for
fetuses that could be used to chip away at <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe v. Wade</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports inside on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> interview in the newest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> . In the interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nietszchean</ENAMEX> line on organized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>, calling it a sham and crutch for the weak, and says the charges
against naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aviators</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tailhook</ENAMEX> scandal were "much ado about nothing."
The comments were condemned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, but were defended by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>.

            A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out a worthwhile approach to the current
gun imbroglio that's not been mentioned much: the availability of increasingly
effective non-lethal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, such as electronic stun devices and chemical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sprays</ENAMEX>, effective at much greater ranges than earlier versions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> is
absolutely right and his observations might have carried more rhetorical impact
if the paper had told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> via an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ID</ENAMEX> line that he is a former government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> in this area.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports on, but hardly seems to notice the irony in, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Thrift Supervision</ENAMEX>'s decision to budget <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> in government funds
so that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming months</TIMEX> celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX>
anniversary at various outings, including a jazz brunch cruise down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potomac</ENAMEX>. The paper quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> saying, "We consider it reasonable
considering what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> have gone through in those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>," but never
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bothers</ENAMEX> to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> what those hardships were.

         
      
   
