
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of Crime and the Last Squeegee Man</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ester</ENAMEX>:

            You, of course, raise the issue that has split criminal justice and
criminology right down the middle in your last note--why has crime gone down?
And you are right on the mark regarding the role that ideology has played in
this debate. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> (media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, etc.) has become the focus
of this debate. The arguments against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bratton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safir</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simplified</ENAMEX>, are along the lines you suggest: changing drug patterns, changing
economic conditions, and changing drug-use patterns. Even many who concede that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> practices were central argue that the crime reductions came at an
unacceptable cost in terms of police brutality.

            My own position is considerably different than claims on either side. Again,
trying to put forth a complex argument in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short</TIMEX> note is difficult, however,
let me try. As you know, long before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and "crime reduction"
stories, I was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of community policing. By that, I did not mean that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> should be "nicer" or that they should do, in effect, community
relations. I argued that to deal with crime, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> had to be involved with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, etc., and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> had to
reclaim public spaces and control and nurture youth. To use <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> as an
example, that is exactly what happened. Think of the activities of citizen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, business improvement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>, the transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> in
removing graffiti and reclaiming the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, the restoration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant Parks</ENAMEX>, the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midtown Community Court</ENAMEX>, etc., etc. In other
words, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> had been reclaiming itself for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 15 years</TIMEX>. And you
were right, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Brown</ENAMEX> (his police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>) did substantially
increase the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. Moreover, by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the second</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins-Giuliani</ENAMEX> mayoral race, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> were running against "squeegee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>." Also, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bratton</ENAMEX> got credit for eliminating
squeegeeing, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Kelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX>' last police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>, who brought
me in to lead the problem-solving exercise that figured out how to do it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, however, provided the "tipping point" that accelerated a process
that you properly note: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crime</ENAMEX> had been slowly dropping for some period of time.
The steepness of the drop after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bratton</ENAMEX> was largely unprecedented
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. (A large part of the dramatic nature of the drops has to
do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> practices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. As I am certain that you are aware,
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have been so preoccupied with preventing corruption
that "staying out of trouble by doing nothing" became a unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> art for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bratton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> changed.)

            The fact that this is a national trend and that the stories are different in
most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> I find both not surprising and comforting. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has begun to
find ways to reclaim public spaces and control and nurture its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> on its own
terms--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, etc. There is no one story, because of
the uniqueness of each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.

            But, in closing for now, I went to a fascinating discussion put on last
night by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX>. It was a discussion by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX> (of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Mason University</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wolfe</ENAMEX> (of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston College</ENAMEX>) about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great Disruption</ENAMEX> . The most interesting part of
the discussion focused on "why the disruption<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX>, it was largely
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>; for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>, it was the addition of "moral
freedom" to economic and political freedom; and, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Podhoretz</ENAMEX>, who
offered some comments, it was the power of a set of ideas that changed things
overnight.

            And, finally, yes it would have been fun to have met before this
"conversation." But, I must be off to my guest teaching. I will write again
later. Have a good breakfast.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Kelling</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
