
   
   
      
         
            In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Praise of Movie-Ticket</ENAMEX> Prices

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> loves to go to the movies. Mostly this is because he loves
movies, but partly it's because moviegoers enjoy one of the last great consumer
bargains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. This is not widely recognized. Especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
(where prices for movie tickets, and most other things, are higher than they
are elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are constantly grandstanding
about the high price of movie tickets. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Vallone</ENAMEX> issued a press
release urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> to intervene because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loew</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cineplex</ENAMEX>
had just raised ticket prices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.50</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vallone</ENAMEX> kicked up a
similar fuss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Loew</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Lincoln Square</ENAMEX> Multiplex
raised prices to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade earlier</TIMEX>, then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Koch</ENAMEX> actually urged a
boycott when movie-ticket prices rose from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 to $7</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s coverage of the earlier controversies.) The boycott fizzled because
... well, because, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> wasn't all that much to spend on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX>'s
entertainment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fun City</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, where a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> visit to what is
widely recognized as the area's spiffiest movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Deco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uptown</ENAMEX>, costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.75</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX> if you purchase an advance ticket by phone).
That's still "high" by national standards; according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion Picture</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of America</ENAMEX>, the average movie-ticket price <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was a mere
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.69</NUMEX>. Is that higher than it used to be?

            Take a look at this chart, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> found on a Web page about inflation that
was forwarded to him and several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>,
the economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Journal</ENAMEX> . Observe that in constant <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX>,
movie-ticket prices more than doubled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1935</TIMEX> (when they cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX>;
that's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.93</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> dollars) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> (when they cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.55</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.68</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
dollars). Prices for movie tickets peaked, in constant <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX>, during the
1970s. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, movie-ticket prices had dropped to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2.69</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.46</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
dollars, where they stayed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. Constant-dollar movie prices dropped a
bit more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, stabilizing during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle 1990s</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.70</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.80</NUMEX> (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> dollars), where they remain.

            It's interesting to note that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> when the price of
going to movies reached an all-time high, was also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
movies were better , in the aggregate, than they've ever been before or
since. This was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Godfather , Chinatown</ENAMEX> , and more great films than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can count
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Altman</ENAMEX>. It's tempting to conclude that
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> paid more for movies, they would get better movies. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>,
which produced movies that were worse in the aggregate than movies being
made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (and much, much worse than the movies that were being made
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>) would seem to disprove that hypothesis, because movie-ticket
prices were higher then (in constant <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX>) than they are now.

            Perhaps the reason movies were so good during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> had to do with the
size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. According to data (not available, alas, online) from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> movie admissions dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">78 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX> to an
all-time low of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15.8 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> admissions stayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> for
most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, rising to the low 20s during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. (Chatterbox assumes
this has something to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> demographics.) Conceivably the shrinkage
caused the moviegoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to become more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutique</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> in a supermarket--i.e., less interested in mass-produced items, and
more interested in quirkier handcrafted products. But if that's true, it cannot
be extrapolated that movies continue to get worse as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> continue
to expand . If that were true, movies would be worse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (weekly
admissions numbered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for which data are
available) than they were in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> (when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> admissions numbered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>). But in fact, movies are better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (assuming you don't count
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> ).

         
      
   
