
   
   
      
         
            All in the Same <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boat</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>'s Stiffed
argues <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are suffering from a masculinity crisis, but it isn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s fault. She conducted a wide range of interviews over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
across the grain of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipbuilders</ENAMEX>, magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Keepers</ENAMEX>, aging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>. The crisis of masculinity she describes
appears on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fronts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> involves "utilitarian masculinity," which is the
pride of self <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> feel thanks to their skills, their commitments to their work,
and to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the course of accomplishing a task. The other sort of
masculinity she calls "ornamental," and it is just that, the ornaments of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cigars/</ENAMEX>leather chairs/Porsches/babes that festoon the pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Details</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Men's Fashions</ENAMEX>" supplement. The
utilitarian male is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>, the ornamental male is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s view, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> suffer from the
changes in work that more largely frame <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s capitalism. This is a
short-term world in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are constantly changing jobs, dealing in
intangibles of information and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> rather than making solid things, a
world in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsman</ENAMEX> who nurtures a skill over his lifetime is out of
place. Correspondingly, male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are being sold fickle and impossible
images of their sexuality and their social honour: fickle because the clothes,
face creams, and similar goods now change like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s hemlines, offering no
stable sense of self, impossible ornaments because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>
cigar lie in the realm of fantasy for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> struggling to make ends
meet.

            Put so baldly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s argument may seem just another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">version of Demon Capitalism</ENAMEX>. But she is too good an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> to be trapped
in that cliché. When she interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipbuilders</ENAMEX> losing their jobs, for
instance, she shows how the old-fashioned pride in doing a good job remains
even when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipbuilders</ENAMEX> have come to the very end of their employment; their
craft pride transcends any whining about being capitalism's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. No more
does the ornamental male wear his jewelry of self comfortably; the buffed pecs
and washboard stomachs portrayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of anxiety rather than pleasure.

            Perhaps the most spacious dimension of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s
argument is that she, unlike many feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, has a real feel for male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bonding</ENAMEX>, and for the need of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to feel they can hold their heads up with
honor. She doesn't succumb to the simple-minded idea that male honor inevitably
requires female oppression. Again, in her interviews with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-Vietnam</ENAMEX>
generation, she reaches out to understand the bonds forged by the violence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> at war. Above all, while she rejects the notion that the crisis of
utilitarian masculinity in the workplace has resulted from the gains
middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women workers</ENAMEX> have made in the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, she also shows
that many women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> have been insensitive to the confusions of self that
the new economy has bred in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            The very openness and depth of her interviewing poses
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question I have about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stiffed</ENAMEX> . Is this
really a book about maleness, or is it a reflection in the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of
something more generally applicable to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society, female as well as
male? Isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX> describing a society in which social honor and self-respect
are largely in short supply, or supplied in a fashion that can give no real
satisfaction? In interviews I've done with female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> and mental-health
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, for instance, I've found the same sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>, and the same feeling
that the short-term cost-cutting of the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> leaves them no room to
realize their own inner potential.

            A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> large question: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ornamental</ENAMEX> culture," Faludi
tells us, is "at its core ... a virulent voyeurism" with sex being its "gold
standard" [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">p.505</ENAMEX>]. But the interviews she conducts, as with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Keepers</ENAMEX>, seem to me more about the ornaments of fatherhood and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>-hood, an
inability of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> to find on the tube or at the movies images of how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> ought to deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX> of parenting and
long-term relationships. Either the domestic male is portrayed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">goody-goody</ENAMEX>
moral saint or as a guilt-ridden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of the intimate realm. Sex isn't the
issue, I think; the consumer culture has trivialized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> experiences of
responsibility, flattened out intimacy so that it appears a zone in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, are pulled between self development and
obligation to others: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ozzie and Harriet</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> (a film that for all its sex tries
to show sex is anything but the "gold standard" for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>; the inchoate but
strong impulse to break free is what really drives the male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>).

            Finally, as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> living abroad, I was struck in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reading Faludi</ENAMEX>'s interviews how resonant they are with issues of self-worth and
self-image among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. It's easy for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to imagine that
our mobile, placeless society doesn't give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> much outside themselves with
which to identify; indeed, in her interviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX> finds many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> longing for
a mythical time when they knew where they belonged. But that longing for a lost
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, a secure sense of self, appears equally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>--or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. And
this brings us back to the issue of capitalism. The disturbances of work and
consumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX> so brilliantly depicts are, I think, global in scope,
they cut across the boundaries of gender, and they transcend sexual vanity.

         
      
   
