
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shape of Mud-Slinging To Come</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear George</ENAMEX>,

            It seems that everywhere I go <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>,
freedom of speech, art, religion, and, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. So try as I might
to interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter</ENAMEX> revision, I'm afraid budgets,
bureaucratic reorganization, and mayoral succession just can't compete with
larger-than-life egotistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX>, the war of the righteous, and raunchy
art. It makes me wonder how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> will conduct her campaign for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. He's already baited her on being "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Catholic</ENAMEX>" for
not opposing the exhibit. One thing for sure, the press is going to have fun.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> has already told its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that she's "dissing" the
city by choosing to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, where as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>
she'll host the national celebration. Do you think we will actually get any
attention paid to issues in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute Forum</ENAMEX> sounds a bit like the high-and-mighty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> lamenting their loss of authority over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>. I must admit
that I am only rarely invited to their events. Apparently, my questions at past
forums have been too "pointed" for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest speakers</ENAMEX>.

            If there is a biological drive toward order among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, I have yet to see
it appear among my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>! And while I am a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, I don't
trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in our religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> to set the moral standards
for the rest of us. Politics and religion have become too intricately
intertwined.

            Believe it or not, I'm going to give a talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's City Club</ENAMEX> on
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NYC: The End of the Liberal Experiment?</ENAMEX>" Now what do I mean by that title?
It's surely a topic for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX>. It's been great meeting you over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>. Take care.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warmest</ENAMEX> regards,
Ester

         
      
   
