
   
   
      
         
            Hook, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Line</ENAMEX>, and Sinker
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dinesh</ENAMEX>,

            Like you, I find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' book extraordinarily disappointing--particularly
given my expectations. I like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.R.</ENAMEX> book very much, and I like him (although
I don't know him well) and consider him an interesting and very intelligent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. But something went badly wrong with this book. I don't want to
psychologize, but clearly he simply found himself unable to manage this large
and difficult subject, floundered, and grasped onto a series of unwise devices
that derailed the project--of which the fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrators</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>, and
not the most disastrous.

            Like you as well, I find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> as something close to an
empty suit inherently implausible. I suspect that spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">many hours</TIMEX> getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> to talk about the past (which he is astute enough to realize does not
mean much to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> except as the source of well-worn anecdotes) must have
given him an exaggerated sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s detachment from any engagement with
the present. My view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s powers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is perhaps different from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yours</ENAMEX>. I agree with you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was a tremendously effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>--partly
because he was attractive and a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>; but even more because he was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of absolute certitude about his core convictions and was able to convey a
sense of assurance and self-confidence. Where did that certitude come from? One
thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> does convey pretty well, I think, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> formed
convictions fairly early in his consideration of a question and that these
convictions then became more or less impervious to challenge from evidence that
might contradict them. That did not always make these convictions useful bases
for policy or action, but they did make them extremely effective as vehicles
for shaping opinion and attracting support. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is clearly impressed by
those moments when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> demonstrated his powers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and persuasion,
and he concedes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> had an enormous impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. But his explanation of where that power came from is at odds,
as you note, with his dismissive view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s own personality and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>.

            But my larger problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is undoubtedly very different from yours.
As I noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> seems to know very little about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. And yet he is, on the whole, a completely credulous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> of most of the assumptions and ideas we associate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganism</ENAMEX>. I
mentioned yesterday his preposterous summary of the history of the welfare
state, which sounds like one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s uninformed anecdotes about welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">queens</ENAMEX> and his uninformed analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keynesianism</ENAMEX> and the New Deal economic
order. But the largest example of his credulity in this book involves the part
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s presidency in which he takes the greatest interest: the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.
It is an article of faith among many <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> "won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War." I do not deny that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s policies, and his relationship with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, were important in shaping the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> ended. But I don't
think many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> would argue now, and I don't think many will argue in the
future, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>--or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> policy generally except in a very large
sense--had much to do with the unraveling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. That had much
more to do with the grave internal weaknesses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> system than with
anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> did. If there was an event that really precipitated
the unraveling, it was not anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> did, but the disastrous invasion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and its aftermath.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, however, selects a few incidents in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s presidency and
attributes to them a historic importance for which there is no real evidence.
The "evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>" speech, for example. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s use of the word evil, he says,
"penetrated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> as surely as the cadmium poisoning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beets</ENAMEX>."
It produced a shock of self-recognition and, presumably, contributed to the
decline of popular legitimacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. The evidence for this, he says,
was gathered over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>--but what evidence does he provide? An interview
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Kampelman</ENAMEX>, who was presumably expressing his own anecdotal reactions
after conversations with a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>; and an article by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the
speech. Or later, the "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, tear down this wall" speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> may speak condescendingly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s language, as you noted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. But he also argues that this speech resonated throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> world and helped spawn the will to resist that culminated in the
revolutions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> and beyond. And what is his evidence for this extraordinary
claim? An article by--once again--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the speech.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> himself
have had obvious self-serving reasons for making such arguments--for insisting
that a major event in world history that arose out of a vast confluence of
factors was the result of the policies and the rhetoric of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. But
what is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' excuse? He has simply accepted the claims at face value, just
as he seems to have accepted his views of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> domestic policy on the basis
of a few rhetorical statements that seem to him plausible. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, then, he
has done exactly what he (and many others) claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> often did.

            You think the book is a great injustice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, and in many respects it
is. But it is also an injustice to history, because it accepts far too
credulously the claims made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> about his accomplishments and
his influence.

         
      
   
