
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journalist and the Biographer</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is, natch, the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>'
controversial biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. Other issues include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>'s
no-holds-barred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> interview and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s campaign against
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" art exhibit.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is becoming desperate, and some say he's now the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underdog</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> himself tried to claim this mantle by imploring <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, "I think in many ways you ought to count me the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> in
this race <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. ... I think if you look at the most recent poll in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>, you'll see it that way." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate's Ballot Box</ENAMEX> 
explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s motivation.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> moved his campaign headquarters from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>; fired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>; challenged the
putative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, to a series of debates; had his campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Coelho</ENAMEX>, accused of past corruption by a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>; and
raised less money than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last quarter</TIMEX> (according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s FEC
disclosures). On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> says he will keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coelho</ENAMEX>. He
also calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> a quitter for resigning from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and impugning the
party system in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, rather than supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> ticket.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the worst week</TIMEX> of any presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX>'s quasi-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> scandal broke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> think moving his campaign to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> was meaningless--"You can
take your campaign out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K Street</ENAMEX>, but you can't take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K Street</ENAMEX> out of your
campaign," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wags</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition )--but some, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>, say it helped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> weed the non-loyalists from his campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s impressive fund
raising, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ), means that unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, he'll have the money to continue campaigning if
he does well in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ), and 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live</ENAMEX> )--say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is still the favorite and note
that he is far ahead in most national polls. Some attribute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s problems to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fatigue," but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Newshour</ENAMEX> ) notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
approval rating is higher than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s [popularity]
problem would [still] be there if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> disappeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>," Sheilds
says.

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits criticize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> for attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' plan to balance the budget by fudging with the benefits schedule
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> sounds exactly like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," laments <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ). On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Cox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calf.</ENAMEX>, defends the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> plan--even though he co-chairs
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> campaign. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, however, think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s triangulation
is shrewd and helps flesh out his "compassionate conservatism" philosophy. EITC
wouldn't be an issue, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), "if [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>] had cut the budget like they were supposed to. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
are so hooked into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> that he could dance naked through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
and they'd say, 'Well, he had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.' " Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> )--criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for hammering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> but
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) says these two
positions show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is more of a social conservative than an economic
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> continue to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>' new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memoir of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> (buy it here). For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since chattering about the book
began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ago</TIMEX>, many of those commenting on it have actually read it.
(
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s Culturebox 
explains this phenomenon.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Cannon</ENAMEX> says the book actually
"subtracts from our knowledge" of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historian Haynes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannon</ENAMEX>, appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ), notes that the book
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> mention of supply-side economics. Defending himself on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> calls his conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX>" and explains "the basic inability of the ideological mind--such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>'s--to comprehend that a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can sometimes be
comically fallible in private." He continues: "I have no doubt whatsoever that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, but some of his conversation in
private was astonishingly banal." (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinesh D'Souza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Brinkley</ENAMEX>
discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> in 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s 

Book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> defends his attempt to withdraw taxpayer
money from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" art exhibit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>. He appears on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three Sunday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> shows ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week , Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> )--none of which interviews a supporter of art subsidies. Meet
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> flashes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> poll showing that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 30%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yorkers</ENAMEX> agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> agree with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, a
poll of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX>'s Web site shows <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX> support for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. ... On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> says she is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>--and the only woman
ever--to lead a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the armed services (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX>, when she was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>).

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Original Sin On Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, I-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, about his explosive
interview in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> , in which he calls organized religion "a sham
and a crutch for weak-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need strength in numbers":

            
               TR: "Do you believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> and nuns and rabbis and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> [in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>] could be considered 'weak-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?' "

            
               JV: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, I don't--not necessarily. And being weak-minded is
not necessarily a detriment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>. It just means that you have a weakness and
therefore you go into organized religion to help strengthen yourself. That's
the context in which I talked about it, and for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's OK."

            Asked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX> whether he believes in God, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> replies immediately
that he does--although he belongs to no denomination. Asked, in separate
questions, whether he considers himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and whether he believes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s divinity, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> pauses each time but answers yes.

            Later in the program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX> interviews evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> and former
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reggie White</ENAMEX>, author of the conservative-values book Fighting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Fight</ENAMEX> (buy it here):

            
               TR: "Are you 'weak-minded?' "

            
               RW: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I think that all of us end up being weak-minded
until we come to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> says, 'We are weak but He is strong.' ... I
think that anyone who lives any kind of way he wants to and do [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ]
anything he wants to is weak-minded."

             

            
               Last Word
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actors</ENAMEX> are trained not to focus too closely on their individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>,
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX>. ... What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> saw through his myopic eyes was a general blur
of smiling, affectionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX>--that's how he saw his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, that's how he saw
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, that's how he saw the world."

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> )

         
      
   
