
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dummies</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Alan</ENAMEX>:

            How I want to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>. How much I have
looked forward to his book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. I've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> speak twice at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise Institute</ENAMEX>, where I work. He is urbane and sophisticated,
and the model of gentlemanliness and charm. When I enrolled at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth</ENAMEX> as a
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, I met <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> who exuded learning and grace and
wit. I wanted to be like that. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> is one of them. And, let me be
candid, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> is not. Yet frankness also compels me to acknowledge
that, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> succeeded in his great enterprise and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> failed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who became an extraordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is an educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has written a profoundly foolish book.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> is so disappointing is that
it gives no vivid sense of the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was first
elected. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>, the landscape looked dismal, both
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and abroad. Inflation was in double digits, eroding pension plans and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> accounts; interest rates had reached <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX>, the highest since the
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bear</ENAMEX> was on the prowl, having gobbled up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1974</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> fell, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> invaded
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. There was an energy crisis, with long lines at the pump and talk
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> rationing. And who can forget the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, held captive by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mullahs</ENAMEX> who denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">great Satan</ENAMEX>"?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> promised to bring inflation down, and he did. He
cut taxes to energize economic growth, and after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the recession of 1982</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> went into a juggernaut of growth that has still not abated. Interest
rates fell, so that new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> could get loans and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> could buy
houses again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> decontrolled gas prices, and the energy crisis
disappeared. The technological revolution accelerated in part due to the
explosion of venture capital that became available in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. No more real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estate</ENAMEX> fell to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s watch. Indeed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>
itself came under unendurable strains and began to collapse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> pulled
out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aghanistan</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, the year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX> came
tumbling down.

            Not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>, it's safe to say, can claim a
comparable record of achievement. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX> have been peaceful and prosperous,
to be sure, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> inherited a growing economy and a global environment
rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> menace and open to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">multinationals</ENAMEX>. Of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deserves some plaudits for preserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reaganism</ENAMEX> (this is his true
legacy), but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> deserves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of the credit for turning the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and the world, around. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> articulated a moral vision of
what it means to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> that I, for one, sorely miss in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> dimly perceives that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> is implicated in
these huge events, but he has no idea how or why they happened. Hence the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX> that is manifest throughout his book. Like some of the petulant
letter-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who have been weighing in on our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' premise seems
to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Clifford</ENAMEX> once put it, an "amiable dunce." So
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> tries to apply the premise to the astonishing turnaround of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>.
And it doesn't fit. How could a dunce enjoy the continuous successes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> did? Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> got lucky once or twice, but could luck account for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s triumphs in the multiple ventures he pursued and the multiple policies
he enacted? Did luck account for how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> got elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
and then re-elected? After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, is luck the true reason
that the seemingly invincible inflation dragon was slain? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> wanted a world
in which the market, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, runs the economy; by the time he left
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> such a world was in the making: more luck?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> knows this is ridiculous, but he cannot figure
it out; he becomes confused. He goes into a long depression. He suffers from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s block. Then he "solves" the riddle: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was a dunce with incredible
imagination and will. Never once does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> question his premise. What if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummy</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> made him out to be? What if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
was intelligent and perceptive, far more imaginative than all his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> put
together, infinitely more resourceful in implementing his agenda, eerily
indifferent to much of the acrimony and pettiness around him, resolute and
far-sighted in keeping his eye on the long ball of history?

            Suddenly the events of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1980s</ENAMEX> make sense; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> did
them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris senses Reagan</ENAMEX>'s involvement, but he does not understand it. He
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compares Reagan</ENAMEX> to a glacier that carved a deep valley. But he is too captive
to his original "dummy" hypothesis to question it and abandon it when it does
not fit the facts. This is why, despite his strenuous efforts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> finally
fails to make sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganism</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Deaver</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">picked Morris</ENAMEX>, seem to have assumed that because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> admired a rugged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outdoorsman</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' previous book, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
would also like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> was an intellectual and a polymath. He invited
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zoologists</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to discuss the fine points of botany. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">well-bred</ENAMEX> and self-conscious. He wrote books and quoted poetry. By contrast,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R.R.</ENAMEX> was a simple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, self-made, with ordinary interests and no intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pretensions</ENAMEX>. Visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX>, recently purchased by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young America's Foundation</ENAMEX>, and look over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s bookshelf. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plutarch</ENAMEX>,
no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frost</ENAMEX>; just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis L</ENAMEX>'Amour westerns and
books about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Highways</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, who fancies himself a cultural sophisticate, is obviously appalled. His
suspicions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> are confirmed: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> strikes him as a brainless yahoo.
And so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> finds himself set on his disastrous course that takes up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> of his life, ruins his reputation, and does a grave injustice to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and to history.

         
      
   
