
   
   
      
         
            Battle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> Underdogs

            Running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> means convincing everyone that you're going
to win until they don't believe you, at which point you must persuade them that
you're behind.

            You can see this dynamic in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore-Bradley</ENAMEX> jockeying of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>. Two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-president</ENAMEX> was thought to be so far ahead as to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unassailable</ENAMEX>. He was running against the putative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, not against his benign <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> challenger. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> did not acknowledge
that the primary was a real contest. The name "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>" did not pass his
lips.

            But thanks to a steady stream of media negativity toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and his
campaign (and sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>), polls began pointing to a closer race. And
once it became competitive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> needed to play the expectations game in a
different way. By moving his campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> and challenging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to a series of debates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is trying to recast himself in the
position that has served <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> well: as a scrappy challenger and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>
rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX>. He is trying to build down expectations for
himself far enough that winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary
by a slim margin will count as a victory, rather than as failure to meet
expectations.

            You might think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> would be pleased by his opponent's
acknowledgement that it's a horse race. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> hates being called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-runner</ENAMEX>. At a press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, he bristled at the notion that
he was expected to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> primary, even though he is ahead there in
the polls. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is hoping for is a surge to lift him up early next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, carrying him to victory in the big primaries in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>. A wave that crests now could be a ripple by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early March</TIMEX>.

            All this is happening so early that we might well go through a few more
turnarounds before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> actually pick the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is deemed
viable by the press, he's beginning to receive harsher scrutiny. A few
skeptical stories about him have already appeared. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX> will be articles
suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is far from done for--he has the wonder-economy on his
side, is more moderate than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, has the superdelegates locked up, etc. And
the whole expectations cycle will replay itself.

            This dynamic has not set in on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> side--yet. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is
still running as if he lacks any serious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>. But at some point, expect
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> to start treating some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> as a plausible and promising
contender. Polls will show a challenger "closing the gap" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>. He (or she) will make the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . At that point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
will appear with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s script before him. He will call for early debates,
embrace "change," and say he welcomes the challenge.

            P.S. I will try to start this groundswell for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s attempt to become the media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
