
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Finally Makes Moving Speech</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
lead with--and everybody else fronts--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s announcement that he is moving
his campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, a move designed to symbolize a break
from inside-the-Beltway politics and a too-close association with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. It is largely perceived by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> as a sign of distress in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> calls "lagging" and the
Post calls "troubled"--references to a fund crunch
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s much improved polls. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
appeals court ruling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> can be sued for negligence for
promoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in such a way that they would appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. The
unprecedented decision is stuffed elsewhere. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">STATES</ENAMEX> TO TIE
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEACHER</ENAMEX> PAY TO RESULTS," about how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, at a national education summit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in attendance) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will agree to test a program in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faculty</ENAMEX> checks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> grades go hand in hand. With the federal government
having just given itself pay raises across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> without having produced a
budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fiscal year</TIMEX> that starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> looks in vain for the
alternative headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">STATES TO TIE POLITICIAN PAY TO RESULTS</ENAMEX>." Oh well.

            Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> seem way too caught up in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> move. True, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls it "largely symbolic"--but not until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">10th</NUMEX> paragraph,
after first calling it "a dramatic upheaval" and "part of a broad make-over."
And high up, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports, without breaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stride</ENAMEX>, that the campaign's other new changes include "an updated wardrobe."
There's also the pseudo-drama of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> describing
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> summoned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to tell them of his
decision to move and asking them if they would move with him. "Both replied
yes, although," throbs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "other stunned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> were uncertain what to do." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s announcement: "The air of nervousness and tension in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was
palpable," giving as evidence--hold the front page--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> first headed
toward the wrong microphone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analytical</ENAMEX>, spending much of the top part of its story focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s money
troubles, even noting that the move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> will mean lower rents.

            The papers contain reports of the discovery in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timor</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> badly burned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, almost surely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. Lest one slip into
thinking this is something only "they" do, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> go top-of-the-page with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> scoop that former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
have recently revealed that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX>, they
machine-gunned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> research was
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">thorough--130</ENAMEX> interviews including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all 24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
response thus far has been that there is no archival evidence of any such
incident. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> should have dug up the initial denials issued by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-siders when My <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lai</ENAMEX> was first reported.) On the other hand, there's this
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> who claims to have been there, quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> : "On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer nights</TIMEX> when the breeze is blowing, I can still hear
their cries, the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> screaming."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> announced that he would cancel
all <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.7 billion</NUMEX> of the debt owed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> desperately poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>,
provided they channel the money thus saved into the likes of education and
health. How to explain the meager play the announcement gets? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , for instance, puts it on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government's warning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should not sleep in the same bed with a child
less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 years old</TIMEX> because of the danger of accidental smothering or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strangling</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts the story inside. The
Times notes that the recommendation was met with
outrage from many pediatricians and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, on the grounds that bed-sharing
provides many benefits, such as bonding and the promotion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breast-feeding</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
runs a commentary by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> saying that yes, he is seriously
considering a run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and will make his mind up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>. He
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that he has been influenced by the entreaties of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> and
further convinced of the appropriateness of running by the tepid response among
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> remarks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> lays out a few
positions, promising to get tough with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> and saying no to the stock
marketization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. He offers as proof of his fiscal acumen his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the repair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wollman Skating Rink</ENAMEX>.

held a press conference to deny rumors (launched by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> of his
campaign) that he's had an adulterous affair with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>. The papers put the
story inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> effort features a sampling of
policies of various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in public life designed to avoid baseless rumors of
sexual misconduct: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX> has refused to be alone in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with
any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> besides his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX> insists on
having a male staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> present whenever he meets with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Ensign, running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, will not be alone in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
