
   
   
      
         
            Springtime for Haider

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
lead with the release of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> statistics on health insurance coverage in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44.3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are uninsured, up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 million</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reefers this story,
leading with tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> suing for access to the raw data from
anti-smoking studies, so that they can better refute them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BellSouth</ENAMEX>'s offer of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 billion</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint Corp.</ENAMEX> takeover battle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>'s chief executive
favors a friendly merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI Worldcom</ENAMEX> (which offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$93 billion</NUMEX>); either
would make the takeover the largest ever. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> have entered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 1996</TIMEX> truce, and that skirmishes with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> ensued. (An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">untimely NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troop insertion</ENAMEX> is
imminent.) The LAT fronts the results of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>'s
parliamentary elections, where the far-right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Party</ENAMEX> made major gains,
possibly supplanting the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Party</ENAMEX> as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest
party in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> report that this could topple the current
ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (which reefers the
story) downplays the results, and the menace posed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joerg Haider</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> figures suggest that access to
health insurance has not kept pace with economic prosperity. More than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic Americans</ENAMEX> lack coverage, outpacing all other racial
and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The number of uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> climbed by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 1 million</NUMEX>,
while the number of uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> actually dropped by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 100,000</NUMEX>. The
number of uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> has changed little, despite a major <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> program
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">targeting America</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11 million</NUMEX> uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>. The papers blame the lack
of coverage on welfare reforms that have trimmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> rolls. They disagree
as to how well private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> have taken up the slack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says a "bright spot" of the report finds that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now
receive insurance from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, but doesn't mention the possibility
that this is simply because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> cuts removed a more affordable
alternative. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> suggests that
employer-provided insurance has exacerbated the problem: many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> have
cut benefits or raised premiums, and many new jobs come from small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>,
which are less likely to provide insurance.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Social Democrats</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Party</ENAMEX> was formed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> specifically to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haider</ENAMEX>'s
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX>, anti-NATO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> from power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> had
threatened to withdraw his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> if they lost too much
ground in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s polls, which is exactly what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> say happened. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> claims that a
close finish and low turnout make the elections a nonevent, and that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is backing down from his earlier statements. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> allude
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haider</ENAMEX>'s controversial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> praise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Reich</ENAMEX>'s "sound employment
policies," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes his resemblance to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX>, right down to his "amiable grin."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> has subpoenaed data from an influential
study linking secondhand smoke and lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> say that
surrendering the data would violate the confidentiality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were
promised and threaten future research. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> traditionally win such
cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> predicts a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>
because the presiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has ruled in favor of the tobacco industry
before.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> deny that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> skirmishes are
the beginning of a full invasion; they only seek to establish a security zone
to control traffic in and out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>, and to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX> from
invasion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> focuses on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, a
former refuge for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>, which has recently suffered severe
attacks even though there is currently no indication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> presence in the
village. The death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akio Morita</ENAMEX> gets front page mentions at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> (a
story ran in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>). All agree that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morita</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> revolutionized the consumer electronics industry, helping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
emerge as a postwar economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>.

            According to the WP
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were "ecstatic" after a ground-based missile interceptor
tested well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> warn that this success was only a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step, and much more work is required to provide comprehensive protection.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> warn that such protection is virtually impossible, and that further
efforts will dampen relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. If current plans
(beginning with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> interceptors in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>) are implemented, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> must
either amend or break its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.

            
               It's crazy, but it just might
work: It's a testament to our cynical times that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> can make news
by declining to sling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' upcoming TV ad blitz will deploy a radical new tactic, addressing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s stances on education and tax cuts while ignoring, or actually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">praising</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
