
   
   
      
         
            Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Kill Someone Twice</ENAMEX>?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder Isn't Always a Crime</ENAMEX>" claims the tag line for the new movie
Double
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeopardy , in which Libby Parsons</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashley Judd</ENAMEX>) is framed by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
in his faked murder. Upon her release from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, she plans to kill him--for
real, this time--since, as everyone knows, you can't be prosecuted twice for
the same crime. If this plot were real, could <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX> get away with it?

            Legal precedent for these circumstances is lacking. However, most legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX> would go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for the second
murder--even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s records would show that she was convicted of
killing the victim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX>'s defense in the movie--double jeopardy--is derived from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment of the Constitution</ENAMEX>, which says that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> "shall be subject for
the same offense to be twice put in jeopardy of life or limb." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX>'s problem
is that double jeopardy can only be claimed when multiple prosecutions arise
from a single criminal action. For example, a double jeopardy defense
would certainly fail if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> claimed that he couldn't be prosecuted for
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> assault on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> just because he was convicted of assaulting her
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years earlier</TIMEX>.

            The obvious objection to this analogy is that, while you can clearly assault
someone twice, you can only kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> once. Therefore, the evidence that
would prove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX>'s guilt in one crime would necessarily clear her of the
other. The problem with this defense is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is free to overturn or
disregard earlier factual findings if new evidence--say, a recently killed
body--proves them to have been incorrect. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX> would have welcomed this
flexibility if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> had discovered that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was alive while she
was still imprisoned.) If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX>'s defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>) grossly
mismanaged the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case in a way that resulted in her wrongful conviction,
she might be able to sue for damages. But it would not affect her second
trial.

            If convicted in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX> might argue that she had already
served her time and should be set free. Depending on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in which the
murder was committed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> might have some leeway in reducing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX>'s
sentence. But convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> are almost never given suspended sentences,
and in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX>'s case the circumstances might increase her punishment because the
murder was premeditated.

            Next question?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks 
               
                  Slate
                
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader Mason Stockstill</ENAMEX> for
suggesting the question and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King County</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Downing</ENAMEX> for helping to answer it.
            

         
      
   
