
   
   
      
         
            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Writing Gone Bad</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dinesh</ENAMEX>,

            I am pleased to have the opportunity to discuss this
book with you, although as we both know, the book has already been so widely
discussed that we are already part of a much larger conversation. And while I
suspect we may disagree in some ways in our evaluation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
and of his legacy, it seems we agree in many ways on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' book.

            It is almost impossible to start reading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX> (which, because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> embargo,
I was able to begin doing only on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>) without focusing--at least at
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>--on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' unusual biographical techniques. There has already been a
storm of criticism of his innovations, and I'm sure there will be many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
who will begin with some hostility toward him on the basis of the mostly
uninformed reports they have read. I have to say that the prospect of reading a
biography that tried to break with the fairly rigid forms of the genre was
appealing to me, as strange as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' approach sounded, and I approached this
book eagerly.

            The test of an innovation in any kind of writing, but
particularly in nonfiction writing, is what contribution the innovation makes
to our understanding of the subject the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is trying to illuminate. And
there are times in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' quasi-fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, his film scripts,
his invented encounters, his blurring of the line between fantasy and reality,
and his many other tricks of the trade do offer some interesting points of
entry into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s elusive inner life. But I have to say that, on the
whole, and like you, I found these devices intrusive, omnipresent, and highly
distracting from what should have been the central task of the book. It's not
just that these techniques make it hard to know what is real and what is made
up, although they do. It's also that they make it very difficult to concentrate
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and much too easy to concentrate on the made-up cast of characters
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flitting</ENAMEX> around him, improbably preoccupied by him even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> before he
was important, writing back and forth to each other about their fictional
encounters with him and with each other, telling the story of their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in almost as much detail as they talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s. I was
particularly disturbed, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>, by the presence of invented footnotes for
the fictional parts of the book. But even without them, there is a surreal
quality to this biography that makes it hard to focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' real views of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s personality and place in history--which are also somewhat bizarre
(although more about that later).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is not, of course, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to try to
blend fiction and fact. Some very distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> have experimented
with doing so in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, some with great success. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Demos</ENAMEX>, an eminent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> of early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, wrote a fascinating book <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX>
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Unredeemed Captive</ENAMEX> , about a white woman
in colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> who was abducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> and lived much of her life
among them. Demos augmented the known story of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with an imagined
story of how she might have viewed her life with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>--something for which
no evidence exists. It stirred some controversy, certainly, but it was a
serious, inventive, and in the end I believe successful experiment. My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colleague Simon Schama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Certainties</ENAMEX> , also now
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years old</TIMEX>, was a deliberate effort to play with the elusive boundary
between fiction and history and to suggest how the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> might be fruitfully
joined. That book, too, seemed to me very provocative and interesting.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' potentially interesting effort to expand
the boundaries of biography seems to have gone out of control. Partly, I
suspect, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is such a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>--once he started experimenting at
the edges he couldn't help himself from going all the way. Partly, perhaps,
because he was genuinely puzzled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s apparent opaqueness--although as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, it seems strange that he would be surprised
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> giving others little access to his own inner life. (I've spent
much of my scholarly life working on and around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, who is
similarly opaque but has nevertheless been the subject of excellent and
penetrating biographies.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, though, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' real problem is
that he doesn't understand <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics well enough, and doesn't know
enough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history, to be able to make sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> in anything but
personal terms--and that in the absence of an accessible personal story he was
left, in effect, with nothing. The result is this hodgepodge of distracting
literary techniques that are only intermittently effective and mostly deeply
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distracting from</ENAMEX>, even destructive to, his principal goal.

            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, I'll try not to talk about this already
overanalyzed aspect of the book and comment, as you have already begun to do,
on what it says about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> himself.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Brinkley</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
