
   
   
      
         
            Slick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hustlers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahoo Spectacles</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mim</ENAMEX>:

            No, I don't think I'm being too hard on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> and their behavior regarding
Dogma . I can appreciate that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Miramax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Weinstein</ENAMEX>
made a pragmatic move to ensure the film was seen, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> wasn't embarrassed,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX> could go away feeling that it had achieved something. I
know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weinstein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> probably brokered the best possible compromise, and
that it's a classic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Su</ENAMEX> tactic to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> to withdraw without loss
of face, but, for me, it's a "don't ask, don't tell" solution. On prior
restraint, I fear I'm a bloody-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">absolutist</ENAMEX>. Prior restraint is a secular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sin</ENAMEX>, so no more compromise; rip away the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX> curtains on all
these pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. While I have no information on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Donohue</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cohorts</ENAMEX>, all too often what's revealed is an unappetizing confederacy of rabid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bigots</ENAMEX> and slick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hustlers</ENAMEX> with mailing lists who know funds can be extracted
from the demented to attack everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Sawyer</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX>.

            On the death penalty, I am also an absolutist. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> cannot aspire to
a higher moral standard than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>, it can only be labeled as barbaric.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> for an eye is the cry of the savage, and neither revenge nor the
extermination of the socially unmanageable can ever be a civilized objective.
I'm not sure capital punishment is against any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> doctrine, however. I
believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Augustine</ENAMEX> OK'd it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth century</TIMEX> at about the same time
as he invented the concept of a "just war." That it is practiced so gleefully
in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot shriek</ENAMEX> of the macho political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>
sickens me, and yet moral reasoning seems to have no effect. Standing outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Quentin</ENAMEX> with a candle also appears wholly ineffective. My feeling is that
maybe executions should be televised in prime time, and let everyone see what's
being done in their name. If we are so horrified by the cruel and unusual that
we demand repeal of all death-penalty statutes, then hope is possible. If the
process of slaughter becomes a savage yahoo spectacle, then we are indeed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">barbaric</ENAMEX>. I recall in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, when I was growing up, it took the proved
hanging of the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate occasions, plus the execution of an
attractive young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>-sensational, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>-quarrel murder trial
finally to turn public opinion.

            We seem to have come a long way from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Buffy the Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.

            Much love,
Mick

         
      
   
