
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Funding of Art</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Received last night.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ester</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, this is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> attempt to respond to your last message. Apparently,
I was writing to slowly for my service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>. It inquired whether I wanted
to stay online, and despite my assurance that I did, I was promptly
disconnected--losing my draft in the process.

            What I was writing about was your initial discussion of art and funding, as
represented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> dispute. Frankly, I sidestepped the issue
because I am of a very mixed mind about the whole thing. On the one hand, I
treasure the principle that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> should be able to express themselves in
relatively unrestrained fashion. On the other, I have concern about public
funding of art. I am uncertain about the extent to which public funds should be
used to fund art--whether that art be kitsch or politically controversial
statements.

            Likewise, I am perplexed by public funding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> to provide certain
kinds of social or other kinds of public services. In each case my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is
not just on the impact on the public or public policy but also about the impact
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. Is it possible that the public funding of art or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> social services (or schooling) has a deleterious impact on their
integrity? Moreover, should the state be funding activities that the general
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX> finds offensive or services that compete with public services? As I
noted above, I find myself really quite confused in each case. School vouchers,
alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church schools</ENAMEX> all compete with
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and probably challenge public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to improve. Moreover, such
school programs offer the working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and the poor the same opportunities
that the wealthy have to send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Yet, it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> to ask whether the diversion of public funds from public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> weakens
and further threatens what was once a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of upward mobility
for the poor and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>.

            I guess that pushed to the wall, I would choose school choice, if only
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have suffered from the same kind of stifling bureaucratic
climate that has so hindered so many public services. Yet --.

            So, as you note this is an awfully late breakfast. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>, my response
will be at breakfast.

            Be well,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
