
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saving Out-of-Town News</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> just caught up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> article containing the
distressing news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Out-of-Town News</ENAMEX>, the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Harvard Square</ENAMEX> newsstand, is
losing business to the Internet. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Computernewsdaily</ENAMEX> 's reprint of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> piece, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordana Hart; Chatterbox</ENAMEX> found the article while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cruising Jim Romenesko</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MediaGossip</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.) According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> piece, the appeal
of paying "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $9.95</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> " isn't what it was
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> (and just about every other hard-to-get
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>) was available, gratis, online. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Out-of-Town News</ENAMEX> sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> copies of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Miami Herald</ENAMEX> ;
now it's down to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 10 and eight</NUMEX>, respectively. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">newsstand</ENAMEX> has lost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of its newspaper retail income.

            This makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, whose news addiction was fed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Out-of-Town News</ENAMEX> at
an impressionable age, very sad. (It also makes him feel guilty about the times
he purchased a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> from the tartier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nini</ENAMEX>'s Corner newsstand
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> recognizes that it is unquestionably a social
good for the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, and electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> such as

                  Slate
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> and the clumsily named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intellectualcapital</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> , to be available to everyone with a
computer--and not just to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cantabridgians</ENAMEX> and others lucky enough to live within
walking distance of the small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that sell
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> from around the world. Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> hates to think that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Out-of-Town News</ENAMEX> will become some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of print, a precious relic of
a bygone age. (As it is, it's been a tad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>-like since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>, when
it relocated to the inside of an antique subway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosk</ENAMEX> that fell victim to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-'70s</TIMEX> modernization.) With that in mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to
offer up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fray</ENAMEX> (scroll down to see how) suggestions about what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Out-of-Town News</ENAMEX> should do to stem its losses. Entries mocking the soppy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> sentimentality of this exercise, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s low moral standing (as
a cyberjournalist) to be fretting about this problem, are not welcome.

         
      
   
