
   
   
      
         
            Policy Corner: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Ed II</ENAMEX>

            There are some decent things in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s second big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> proposal that got overshadowed by his implicit attack on conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. One is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s offer of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> in loan guarantees to spur the
construction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>. Consolidating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 60</NUMEX>
federal education programs into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> categories isn't a bad idea, either.

            But the central thrust of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "Culture of
Achievement" plan, which relates to standards and testing, deploys just the
kind of unwieldy regulatory mechanism <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is elsewhere trying to eliminate.
Indeed, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s top education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> don't think this aspect of the
proposal makes much sense--except in political terms.

            In the plan unveiled at his speech to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> proposed that states be rewarded or penalized with
federal dollars on the basis of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> performance improves in the
future. This implies standards and testing: If you're going to have a system of
rewards and punishments, you have to have some way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who deserves which.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>'s idea of merit pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> points, in fact, toward something advocated
by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, and countless other education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>:
national standards and tests. National standards
would set a benchmark for what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of different ages should be expected to
know. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> tests would allow for objective evaluation of how well various
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were teaching them.

            But this runs smack into a big political problem.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> reject anything that smacks of federal control of education
policy, funding, or curriculum. In particular, the right is paranoid about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX> setting curricular standards or
administering tests. They see national tests as a violation of local
prerogatives and a step toward a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> takeover of education in
general.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> splits the difference, opting for what you might
call local-national standards. Here's how his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rube Goldberg</ENAMEX> system would work,
as far as I can understand it. In line with conservative dogma, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would be
free to set their own standards and select the tests that they would be
obligated to give to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> between grades <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and eight</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, as
a condition of receiving federal money. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would pay half
the cost of these tests.

            The problem: As with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of the plan, which
deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Title One</ENAMEX> funding (see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Policy Corner: Bush Ed"</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> themselves
determine whether they deserve more or less money from the feds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is not
entirely unaware of this moral-hazard problem. To counter it, he adds another
"optional" test, this one federal. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> "asks" (in other
words, tells) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to participate in the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Assessment</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education Progress</ENAMEX> (NAEP). The idea here is, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> once said, "Trust
but verify." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> don't have to participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAEP</ENAMEX>, but if they don't,
they must pay for an alternative test themselves and prove that the results can
be "equated" with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAEP</ENAMEX> results. So what would happen if the state test and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAEP</ENAMEX> differed, as they inevitably would? This is left ambiguous, for obvious
reasons. If federal money is actually tied to performance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAEP</ENAMEX>, then the
state tests are a meaningless sop to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. And if the money is tied to
state tests, then the whole incentive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>--and the idea of making valid
comparisons among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--collapses.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s education "surrogates," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Ravitch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, spoke to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> before his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> speech to explain and defend his
proposal. Neither was able to do so very well for a simple reason: It
contradicts what they think. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ravitch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> are long-standing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of national standards and testing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ravitch</ENAMEX>, who has written two books making the case for
national standards, says there is simply no alternative for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, because of
the opposition to the idea in both parties. "It's become obvious that at this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">point Congress</ENAMEX> is not going to endorse a national test," she told me in a phone
interview. "So what would be the point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> supporting it?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ravitch</ENAMEX>, who
says she considers herself a dissatisfied <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>,
adds this lukewarm endorsement, "I think that he is in some strange fashion
trying to do the right thing."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is equally unenthusiastic. I asked him about the
standards issues after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s speech on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. "I told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> that when
I had the job [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Education</ENAMEX>], we evaluated the state evaluations,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> told me. "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety-two percent</NUMEX> were scoring above average. You add up the
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> assessments and you get a rosy picture." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> said that
while he thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s plan might be workable, "I'm more of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX>-standards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."

            In other words, on a day when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> was supposedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distancing</ENAMEX> himself from conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, he was actually caving to
their foolish dogma on the issue at the center of campaign--over the objection
of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> on the subject.

         
      
   
