
   
   
      
         
            Order out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaos</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ester</ENAMEX>:

            Sorry you had trouble with your e-mail account. Actually, last night I had
trouble getting at an open line. But, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, I made a second pot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and
am settling into my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at home.

            Like you, I read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX>'s piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> issue in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> . It was on the mark. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s ad on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">B10</NUMEX> of the
Times only confirmed his point. It's as if everybody has their script
and dutifully follows it--including the media and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>. In my own
experience, including with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, I am stunned by how willing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are to
trivialize the concept of free speech in order to exploit it for some form of
political advantage. But, it is only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the season</TIMEX>.

            The stunner in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s news was the atrocities by some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>.
As tragic as it is to hear, finding out about it at least serves the purpose of
demonstrating that monstrous evil is not only to be found in the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The capacity of "good" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do, or at
least tolerate, evil things should never surprise us.

            Finally, for now, I have continued to think about the discussion I attended
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">other night</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX>'s book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great Disruption</ENAMEX> . 	I think that
we are slowly beginning to understand the dynamics of why the disruption
occurred: the changing role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; the interaction of that change with "the
pill"; the "freedom" that resulted for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (no longer "responsible" for
being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>); the excesses that accompanied the moral "freedom" that many
felt from normative setting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>; and many of the
other powerful ideas that caught on so very quickly (e.g., that mental illness
did not exist) and shaped social policy. (I think that I wrote you about the
conversation among, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Wolfe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Podhoretz</ENAMEX>, and others.) The
part of the discussion that didn't begin, and which I would have enjoyed even
more, was why things now seem to be turning around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. I can write what I did
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">other night</TIMEX> about why and how crime was reduced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, but it
still begs the question of why suddenly (and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> is suddenly) individuals
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> could commit themselves to successful strategies and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collaborations</ENAMEX>. Although I haven't finished <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX>'s book, he seems to
suggest a biological drive toward order and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> are rational, can see
their mistakes, and can correct themselves. I wonder.

            So, I hope your e-mail problems are solved.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Kelling</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
