
   
   
      
         
            Last <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gasp of the Intelligentsia</ENAMEX>
            

            Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are complaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> who likes
to make things up. In his new biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> has invented not just
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> at various stages in his
life. Isn't this ironic? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> himself was accused throughout his career of
failing to distinguish between fact and fiction. Yet I think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' technique
can be defended if it helps us understand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> better. Unfortunately, it does
not.

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> myself, I can testify that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is right: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
was a complex, mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who saw him on television every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX> thought they understood him, but they kept forgetting that he was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-student</ENAMEX> who graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eureka College</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was in many respects an
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Yet extraordinary things happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>: the taming of
inflation, the revival of economic growth, the technological revolution, the
beginning of the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.

            So did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> do these things? And if he did, how did such an ordinary
fellow perform such extraordinary feats? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' biography contributes little
to our understanding of this large issue. He gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> credit for his force
of will, but he does not credit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of intellect. Reflecting the
prejudices of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> in his book and in interviews has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">described Reagan</ENAMEX> as "ignorant," an "airhead," and a "yahoo."

            Yet it was this very yahoo who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX> repeatedly predicted the
fall of communism. He did this at a time when there was complete agreement
among the sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dove</ENAMEX>,
conservative and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> was permanent. So how did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> know something about the vulnerability of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> communism that all the
learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, including the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet Studies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, did not know?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> pages brings you no closer to understanding why, on this immensely
important question, the wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> proved to be wrong and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummy</ENAMEX> proved to be
right.

            Here's another question. Why did the computer revolution occur in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>?
Why didn't it happen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> is no more responsible for inventing
the Internet than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. But is it possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s policies such as
the tax cuts, deregulation, privatization of government assets, and the
celebration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> as the true <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, created the
necessary political and social framework for the silicon revolution? Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> I've spoken to say that without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> the
computer revolution may have happened, but it wouldn't have happened as fast as
it did. So what does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> think about this? Nothing. It's not that he adopts
a position I disagree with. He seems unaware that this is an important subject
of debate. In the sphere of politics, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, who comes
across looking like an ignoramus.

            Unable to fathom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s public accomplishments, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> focuses on his
personal life. Even here there are no big revelations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> speculates that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> married his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Wyman</ENAMEX>, because she threatened to commit
suicide if he didn't. But the source for this turns out to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s second
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>. All we can learn from this episode is that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>
don't like to think that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> wanted to marry their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> also makes much of the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'30s</TIMEX> considered
joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> but was turned down because they regarded him as a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">flake</ENAMEX>." Does this prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was a lightweight? On the contrary, it
reveals that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commies</ENAMEX> were even more inept than previously thought. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
would have been an unbelievably good catch, and if he had stayed with this
sorry lot, he would have been their best chance to win mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptability</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' failure is symptomatic of the failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX> in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to comprehend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. Perhaps it also reflects an attempt to avenge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s rout of the intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. We are now living in the world that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> made, a world in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> are directing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s future. So will <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> have the last word on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s legacy? In
the words of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, fuhgetaboutit . History
will remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> as one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. (The other was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>.) He will be cherished as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War and revived the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' book will
be a footnote.

         
      
   
