
   
   
      
         
            Whither the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Intelligentsia</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Nat</ENAMEX>,

            The problem with the educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> is that nobody
stays put. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the past 48 hours</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> has
been purchased and the wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> has been installed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> (another blow to the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant Establishment</ENAMEX> and another victory for
the ethnics), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Lane</ENAMEX> has been deposed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Beinart</ENAMEX> has been put in. I was with Beinart
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all yesterday</TIMEX> at a conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>. He was pulled out for an urgent call at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, but he didn't say a word about how his life had been changed. So
much discretion in one so young. Amazing.

            I will be gossiping about these maneuverings and the
current ridiculous smears against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>, but I suppose here we
should rise to a higher sphere and talk literature. I wanted to take advantage
of your presence here and ask you about the form of this book, rather than the
content. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> has written his analysis of the meritocracy as a narrative.
Meanwhile, both of us are frustrated because the analytical or polemical
conclusion to his book is so short. It seems to me this is characteristic of
book writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. We are in a great age of nonfiction narrative writing.
There have been many great biographies written over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of decades</TIMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> gets credit for writing one of them--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.R.</ENAMEX> book), and there
have been several great narrative non-fiction books. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ben Cramer</ENAMEX>'s
What It Takes comes to mind. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> himself is an
accomplished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of narratives.

            But when I look back at my favorite period of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
nonfiction--the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1950 and 1965</TIMEX>--the books that leap out were not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">narratives</ENAMEX>. Many great and influential books were written during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rise and Fall of Great American Cities</ENAMEX> ,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Organization Man , The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protestant Establishment</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silent Spring</ENAMEX> ,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feminist Mystique</ENAMEX> , The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lonely Crowd</ENAMEX> (which you worked on, I believe), The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cultural Contradictions of Capitalism</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Machine</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Image</ENAMEX> --I could go on and on
...

            My impression is that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX> there
weren't as many influential, popular but intellectual books of that sort. There
were a few-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise of the Counterculture and</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture of Narcissism</ENAMEX> come to mind, but not as
many. (To avoid looking like a flatterer I'm leaving your stuff like
Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melting Pot</ENAMEX> out of this). Then in the
'80s, a new wave of nonfiction successes hit the best-seller lists. These were
polemical conservative books, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Losing Ground</ENAMEX> ,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Closing of the American Mind , Wealth and Poverty</ENAMEX> , and so on. There was a time for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade or so</TIMEX>
when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>'s bestseller list had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> right-wing polemic on
it.

            But that phase, too, is over. Now the most notable
nonfiction books are celebrity books or narratives. I think some of this has to
do with the declining prestige of the intellectual. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '60s</TIMEX>,
it seems to me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> were confident of their social roles. There were
figures like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Arendt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reinhold Niebuhr</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Wilson</ENAMEX> doing their
thing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Jacobs</ENAMEX> and for a time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX> still followed
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> model when writing their books.

            But somehow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> sense,
lost its confidence and broad vision over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decades</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Academics</ENAMEX> started
doing more professionalized stuff that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like me never read. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> started doing narratives and biographies, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanenhaus</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Anthony Lukas</ENAMEX>.

            The narratives make for better reads, but I do miss
those big upper-middle-brow books like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Jacobs</ENAMEX> used to
write. Or more properly, I wish that the books that follow in that tradition
were getting more attention and more sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> in the social sciences as well and so just want to hear about stories and
personalities.

            Anyway, I'm just conjecturing about all this, but you
have been active during this whole period. Is my description of the trends in
nonfiction accurate? Do you have an explanation?

            All the best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
