
   
   
      
         
            Groping the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New New Thing</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has been letting tax delinquents
go without paying back taxes amounting to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes local, reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' latest plan for streamlining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: He'll "reclassify [nice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euphemism</ENAMEX>] <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 900</NUMEX> mid-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> so they could be
fired without explanation if they do not do a good job." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> during a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> speech
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Hispanic Leadership Institute</ENAMEX> for delaying consideration of Latinos
he's appointed to judicial posts.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Way</ENAMEX>, says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> candidates
for judicial posts whose nominations have been delayed longest are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> argues that of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> confirmed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>. The expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> vote has yet to be claimed by any leading
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Understaffing</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of new (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 and 1998</TIMEX>)
Congressional rules to mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> must collect all back taxes from a
delinquent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> or none, rather than negotiating a payment schedule, get a
lot of the blame for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> mess. An anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> delinquent who owes
90 grand is negotiating to settle his debt with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> payment possibly as low
as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> of what he would have paid. He calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> policy "crazy." Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delinquents</ENAMEX> are taking their chances, hoping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> won't act before a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX>
statue of limitations term runs out. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial calls on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
to act responsibly in regards to another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of arrears: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> legally
owes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in back dues.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-leads that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth Israel Deaconess</ENAMEX>
Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Center</ENAMEX> believe they've developed the first effective therapy for cystic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibrosis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX>). It involves administering large amounts of a deficient fatty
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and is based on experiments with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX>-inflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Human testing could
begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts a biographical piece about young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, painting
him as inordinately cautious, responsible, competitive, perfectionistic,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dutiful</ENAMEX>. Under his high-school yearbook picture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> ran an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anatole France</ENAMEX>
quote: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who have no weaknesses are terrible." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has certainly
proven the corollary this statement implies to be true.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wife Tipper</ENAMEX> is quoted
on her first impression of him: "I thought, 'Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>! He's good looking.' "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign is "already a matter of
damage control." His campaigning has been so "weirdly incompetent," she claims,
that "those close to him" are wondering whether he really wants the presidency
or if he's just running because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator dad</ENAMEX> always wanted him to.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also fronts a story about an escaped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> say may be dangerous. Next to it is an unrelated picture of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> festival. Wouldn't a picture of the escapee make more sense?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-leads an analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban treaty</ENAMEX>,
currently being debated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, which would ban underground nuclear
testing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Online</ENAMEX>, the piece includes a link to the treaty itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> worry
it will weaken <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s position in the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> race. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 1992</TIMEX>
moratorium on underground testing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has used computer and
nonnuclear explosive tests to check <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s nuclear stockpile. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
attached a condition to the treaty saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> would pull out if its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stockpile</ENAMEX> isn't certified. The final paragraphs carry the news that nuke tests
are more important for perfecting new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> than correcting flaws in old
ones. And according to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> study, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 1 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">830</NUMEX> specific
defect discoveries, made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1958 and 1993</TIMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stockpile resulted
from nuclear testing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> does not explore what might happen if, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> fear, "rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> develop the capacity to attack our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>," as
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeane Kirkpatrick</ENAMEX> put it.

            A lengthy LAT front piece, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-part series, states
that while restoring democracy and reforming politics and economics were top
priorities during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two decades</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, the focus is now
turning, necessarily, to eradicating police corruption.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> includes a piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
Graphics and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>. The piece describes the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who makes it big
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> as someone who recognizes "the new new thing...
[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Translation</ENAMEX>:] a notion that's poised to be taken seriously. It's the idea that
is moments from gaining general acceptance and, when it does, will change the
world." He describes a realization he had about the Internet, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All</ENAMEX>
of a sudden it was clear to me ... that I was looking at the [equivalent of
the] personal computer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said. "It was this slow, clunky
technology but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were using it. And it would get faster. I realized that
this was the thing I'd been groping for."

         
      
   
