
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Personalities</ENAMEX> and Issues
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>,

            Thank you for the sensational news: It is really
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bouleversant</ENAMEX> . I, too, found our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> affected
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> events, in this case <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Seligman</ENAMEX>'s review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Big Test</ENAMEX> in the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . On <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>, he is about where we are, except that he raises the
dread question of heredity, about which I will say a few words later. But he
reminds me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> point of form in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Big Test</ENAMEX>
I was planning to raise, and that I think of as a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> phenomenon: the remarkable detail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> has on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. I know some of them--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Karabel</ENAMEX> was a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of mine
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, and he appears in the book as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of sociology at the
go for a counter-proposition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California CCRI</ENAMEX> rather than fight it head
on and lose. On the one hand, I am irritated at having to spend all this time
on personal background when I am trying to get at the issues; on the other
hand, I am fascinated to discover, for example, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Munger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffet</ENAMEX>, and so on. It seems as if it has been decided, both
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>, that you can't get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to concentrate on the
issues if you don't build up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> involved.

            You raise some interesting questions about changes over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. I was involved in the genesis and publishing of some of the books
you mention, and why styles and tastes change over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> is a question it
is hard to answer. I think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> answer is the rise of academia, which leads to
more specialized books, narrower books, reaching small specialized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>.
Almost none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you mention as writing those important books of the
past were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>--I think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Jacobs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Wilson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. H. Whyte</ENAMEX>--or if
they were, they became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> late in life, after having been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, and
the like, for example <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Bell</ENAMEX>, and me too. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> I dealt with some of
those books.

            Yes, the story in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lemann</ENAMEX> is well researched, indeed
impressively so, but the issues are left hanging without sustained analysis,
which would have been possible.

            A final point, heredity. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> cannot be conclusive on
this but I am impressed at the degree to which serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--among them for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">example Christopher Jencks</ENAMEX>, but also others--were convinced this is an
important factor. When we say that social background determines in large
measure one's scores and indeed, I would say, one's tested intelligence, how do
we separate out the effect of hereditary factors from income, education,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>?

            I think one can't. And yet if these factors play some
role, and I am sure they do, whatever means we try to get to equal
opportunity--and we should use all of them, in principle--won't ensure it.

            Now that we are reviewing reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Big Test</ENAMEX> , I wonder how much more there is left to say? Any last
words?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Glazer</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
