
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon Becomes</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cyber-Landlord</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>'s introduction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> of its zShops
initiative--which effectively makes <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of other
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> who will pay <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> to be listed on its site and give the
company a commission on all sales--was a perhaps predictable evolution of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> business model. But that doesn't make it any less potentially
important.

            I say the evolution was predictable because <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> has
always been upfront about the fact that it didn't want to be just an online
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. Monetizing its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>--turning them into real
revenue--was always going to be more effective if you gave them a huge variety
of goods and services to buy. The real question, though, was (and is) whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> could extend its brand name and the loyalty of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to a
panoply of products, many of which it wasn't necessarily going to provide
itself.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> has recognized from the beginning is that
its most valuable asset was not its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> or even its Web site but rather
the "stickiness" of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and the information about their buying habits
that it was able to collect. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> has so far used that information in limited
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>--occasionally I'll get an e-mail suggesting I might want to buy a new CD
that's like other CDs I've bought in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>--but the more products it sells,
the more information it will collect and the more the information that will
become relevant.

            At this point, of course, we don't really know how
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zShops</ENAMEX> will be. (There were lots of items for sale on zShops' first
day of operation, but it didn't seem like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> had promised.) But
as an idea, it's an excellent leveraging of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s brand name, because it
promises the possibility of sizable returns while requiring almost no
investment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s part.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> have suggested that zShops is analogous
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> renting out its parking lot to a bunch of outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>. Let's
say, for the sake of argument, that it is. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> could rent its parking
lot, get a cut of all sales that take place there, and still not disturb its
regular business, why wouldn't it? And if it had an easily searchable catalogue
of all the goods for sale and could direct its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to items in which they
might be interested, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> would be all the more attractive.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason why Wall Street likes zShops so much is that
it is a very high-margin business, which means that the profit <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> reaps on
every transaction will be very high (since its costs will be very low). And
high-margin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are generally very good things. But it's important not
to get too obsessed with margins, because if you do you miss the real strength
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>--or for that matter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>--business model.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>, after all, has minuscule profit margins, at
least when compared with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX>. But it earns
tremendous profits, and does so while using capital very efficiently, because
it turns over its inventory so often. As long as you're selling goods quickly,
you can make very little on each good and still make a huge amount at the end
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> has been able to do in books and what it wants
to do in its other businesses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zShops</ENAMEX> is a slightly different <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> will make more on each good, but they'll sell less quickly. In other
words, it's a good business for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> to be in, and it's a logical extension
of its online power. But don't look for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> to give up its core business
just for the joys of landlordship.

         
      
   
