
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Triumph Over</ENAMEX> Collectivism
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Alan</ENAMEX>:

            Now you've done it. You have ruined our chance to make
history by achieving almost complete unanimity. I knew this bipartisanship was
too good to last. Oh well, back to the battlefront.

            I don't want to fall into the trap of disagreeing with
you by defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>. I'll concede that in the areas where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embraces Reaganism</ENAMEX>, it's generally for wrong and simple-minded reasons. The
amazing truth, which I take it you accept, is that it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
who is the political simpleton.

            So why don't we leave poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> behind to enjoy his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Frost</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edna Millay</ENAMEX>? And let's examine the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main elements of
Reaganism: his attack on the welfare state and his role in the collapse of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> saw these as a single crusade. His life was
devoted to challenging and discrediting collectivism. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet</ENAMEX>
communism was only the most grotesque version of the collectivist impulse.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> devoted his career to bringing down the "evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was
equally determined to discredit the Great Society because he didn't trust
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> to plan the economy, and he (correctly) worried that high taxes
and government programs like welfare would diminish individual freedom and
responsibility.

            In practice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> didn't cut domestic spending very
much. Actually, government spending on domestic programs grew under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. I
think this is the price that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consciously</ENAMEX> paid for fighting the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.
He knew that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tip O'Neill</ENAMEX>, would never agree to cut
domestic programs and put the money into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> settled for
keeping government domestic spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly constant</NUMEX>, while he focused his
energy on defense hikes aimed, as he put it, at inviting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> into an
arms race that they couldn't win.

            But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> lost the battle to control domestic
spending, he won the war over the larger question of the growth of the welfare
state. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> launched a powerful moral attack on the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Government</ENAMEX>.
He challenged the idea, popularized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>, that if you were an idealistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, you should join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> or do "public service," in other
words, become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> denounced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX> as a do-nothing and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>, and celebrated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> as one of the highest embodiments of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> creativity and possibility. And I think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> prevailed. The era
of the welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that began with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> effectively ended with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RR</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> admitted as much when he said "the era of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is over."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it's a settled question that markets, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>,
run the economy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>, I expect that you think this is a bad outcome.
I'm not trying to change your mind about this. But I am trying to establish
that it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> who brought about the change. Previous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> had made their peace with the welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Their
view was that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would run programs with greater attention to fiscal
responsibility than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, by contrast, proclaimed that "government
is not the solution, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is the problem." He launched a principled
attack on the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is more capable of running the country
than the private sector. And we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> to thank (or blame) for the era
that we're living in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>: the era of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>.

            So what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>? My view is that two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> deserve the credit for the fall of the evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>. Of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> deserves the greater praise because he
predicted the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, intended the outcome, and
implemented policies aimed at producing that result. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, by contrast,
desperately tried to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, adopted glasnost and perestroika to that end, and saw the system blow up in
his face.

            Your theory, which is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> suffered
from "grave internal weakness" and collapsed of its own weight, makes little
sense to me. If you are referring to economic inefficiencies, I am not aware of
any weaknesses that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> suffered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> that were not also present
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> (or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any decade</TIMEX> since the Bolsheviks
came to power). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> economy has always been a basket case and the butt
of grim jokes.

            Moreover, even if the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> dramatized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> economic
incompetence because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy was growing so rapidly, this is no reason
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> to implode in the way that it did. There is simply no
historical precedent for a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> calling it quits because it could not
compete economically or technologically. As you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX>
empires suffered from "grave internal weaknesses" but persisted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>.
Why should a ruling elite give up power because the gross national product is
declining or because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is falling behind technologically?

            I cannot hope to settle this large issue here. Nor am I
claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> single-handedly produced the result. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> was
critical, especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lech Walesa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaclav</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Havel</ENAMEX> all performed important supporting roles. And the West benefited from the
appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, an incompetent but good-natured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who played his
part as the opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> who kept throwing interceptions.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was the prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> collapse.
He united the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, and he led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> over the precipice. I
honestly believe that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> had not come to power when they
did--if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brezhnev</ENAMEX> had lived, and if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> had served a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> had succeeded him--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> would be intact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaclav Havel</ENAMEX> about this when he came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, and he agreed wholeheartedly with my analysis. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>, no fan
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, acknowledges in his book Diplomacy that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s role in bringing about the end of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> represents "the greatest diplomatic feat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX>."

            I think history will vindicate that judgment. I don't
expect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, many of whom opposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> all their
lives, to admit their errors. But the new generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, who won't
have a personal stake in opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, will recognize his achievement. As
for me, I wrote my book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> because I'd like to see him get at least
some of the recognition he deserves during his lifetime.

            Best,
Dinesh

         
      
   
