
   
   
      
         
            From the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouths</ENAMEX> of Babes

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heterogeneous</ENAMEX> leads anchor the fronts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reveals that nonprofits, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pocketed millions</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> grants that are designated to feed poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> nourishes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4 million</NUMEX> day care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> by reimbursing
intermediary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, which oversee the doling out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> says
it cannot precisely track small-scale nuclear tests, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>'s lead. After being informed of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s assessment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> decided to rush
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nuclear Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX> to a ratification vote, in the hope of sinking it
by arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> uncertainty makes the test ban unenforceable. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a local story: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> is blocking the parole
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> sentenced to terms that carry life maximums.

            An above-the-fold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> feature reviews <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> roots. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> inherited his pedantic political style from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who rose
from poverty to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. The senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> forced his son
to work the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, arguing that to achieve anything in life a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> "oughta
be able to run a hillside plow."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pager</NUMEX> examines <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s means of milking his past
in professional sports. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350,000</NUMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoopla</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
fund-raiser where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> played with former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All Stars</ENAMEX>. A similar event at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX> is expected to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>. The former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knick</ENAMEX> will
court votes by recruiting the endorsements of sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberties</ENAMEX> column provides a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s
regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> credentials. He digs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Morrison</ENAMEX>'s music and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicholson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irreverence</ENAMEX>. His literary preferences run the gambit from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Le Carr√</ENAMEX>© spy
novels to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Parker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> stories. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> doesn't do opera and he has
only been to one ballet. The troubling anomaly-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> loved <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cats</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> biographies are in the
publishing pipeline. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Son</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fortunate Son</ENAMEX> , and Shrub
are being written by independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> camp is putting out an
official version. Originally a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> was
slated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> the book. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> insinuates he was ousted for asking hard
questions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>'s communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> is now penning the party
line.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>'s presidential run quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s quixotic argument for his candidacy: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is] <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> wide and an
inch deep. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 miles</NUMEX> deep and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 inches</NUMEX> wide." Hatch
acknowledges that he has a rough row to hoe. Even some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are
unaware that he is in the race.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook</ENAMEX>" section surveys candidate statements on campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> a soft money ban and free broadcast time for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> adds a calls for public financing of campaigns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> support raising the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> contribution ceiling.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> backs banning soft money from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> want to stop all soft money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> would like to lift
contribution limits. In a refered piece, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> projects that federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> could spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> on campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            All papers devote column space to the opening-day hoopla surrounding the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" exhibit. Despite pans from art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, record
crowds passed through newly-installed metal detectors to view the art that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> abhors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts & Leisure</ENAMEX>" section caricatures
the carnival-like scene: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protesting Catholics</ENAMEX> prayed and handed out vomit bags.
Animal-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">righters</ENAMEX> waved posters of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">decapitated cows</ENAMEX>. The papers do not subject
the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> to the same withering attention. The LAT
lets the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> speak for itself: An above-the-fold photo pictures man
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">contemplating shark</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece reports that a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 feet</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 inches</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">125-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> hopes to
strike a blow for feminism by fighting a male lightweight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX>'s
officially sanctioned <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> intergender bout. The pathbreaking pugilist is
partially driven by her experience with domestic violence.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Styles</ENAMEX>" section reports a new trend in parenting: the use
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as social stepping stones. The ex-headmistress of an elite all-girls
school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">indignantly</ENAMEX> argues that "education is not a country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>" and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disdainfully</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> jockeying to make play dates with the offspring
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katie Couric</ENAMEX>. The former <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">educator</ENAMEX> allowed that social connections influenced
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kiddies</ENAMEX> were admitted to kindergarten under her reign. She graciously
explains, "It is one of the subtle ways we limit who applies."

         
      
   
