
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winking Frat-Boy</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ted</ENAMEX>,

            
Don't drink that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, you just got us off to a good start. Really
interesting about your trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>. You're right, of course--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> is
yet to be recognized by the West as a defining, driving political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in the
world. Look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. It's possible there will be no way out for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
because of that strain of wild fundamentalism.

            Did you see the Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Henneberger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Bruni</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>? It shows
how these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are not as dissimilar as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wants us to think they are. God,
his campaign is smart. I did a profile of him for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interviewed Karl Rove</ENAMEX>, his chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rove</ENAMEX> is brilliant. He talked about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irishmen</ENAMEX>, the difference between the dark, tormented <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> and the sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>.
His plan saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> as a sunny conservative, someone who could wink and reassure
his extremely conservative base while using his jocular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frat-boy</ENAMEX> personality
to beguile and soothe the rest of us. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rove</ENAMEX> understands, as few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> do,
what a dark side the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> represents to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign is especially
strong because it is very aware of how out of touch social conservatism is in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>'s. So rather than wait for some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> to say that, they'll put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
DeLay to some good use and whip him . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to mind. He's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">professional S.O.B.</ENAMEX> He knows that if all this helps get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> elected, he'll
save congressional seats as well. So what's the problem? It's we in the media
who are flummoxed by the seeming "conflict." But really they are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>!

             How about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Op-Ed</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about your diva <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Brazile</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd, Brazile</ENAMEX> was deputy
field <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>!!!) and was responsible for floating rumors
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush Sr.</ENAMEX>'s extramarital affairs. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Coelho</ENAMEX>, then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warring advisers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter Eskew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> sleepwalking through a clumsy spendthrift
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, and now ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Brazile</ENAMEX>. How can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
vote for him when he can't even dress himself?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
