
   
   
      
         
            Resisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Urge To Merge</ENAMEX>
            

            Although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> have given us a boom in mergers and acquisitions
that rivals anything we saw in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> or the go-go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years of the '60s</TIMEX> (when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conglomerates</ENAMEX> became all the rage), this boom has been distinct because the
vast majority of takeovers have been friendly rather than hostile. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would
like to believe this is because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> have realized that hostile takeovers
only magnify the immense problems any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> faces in trying to assimilate the
operations of another, but it almost certainly has as much to do with the lofty
prices that are being offered for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. (The more you're
offered, the less important independence seems to become--and rightly so, for
the most part.)

            In any case, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> consequence of this epidemic of friendliness is that you
don't hear the expression "X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is now in play" all that much anymore.
This expression was a staple of business thinking in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, and was
epitomized by the experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR Nabisco</ENAMEX>, which became the subject of a huge
bidding war after its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> tried to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> private in a
leveraged buyout. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> came into play when a buyout or acquisition offer
made the possibility of an acquisition suddenly seem likely, bringing other
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitors</ENAMEX>--or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>, depending on your metaphor--into the fray.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> came into play, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> made a friendly
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$93 billion</NUMEX> offer to acquire it. Actually, we didn't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> had come
into play, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> looked kindly on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> offer and
was, by all accounts, ready to approve it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BellSouth</ENAMEX>
stepped in to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trump MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> (which, full disclosure, I own shares in) with
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 billion</NUMEX> bid, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> was officially on the block.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>, like any public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that isn't controlled by a small group
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>, was always on the block. And that makes the whole idea
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> suddenly being "in play" dubious. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BellSouth</ENAMEX> has had years
(effectively, ever since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Telecommunications Act of 1996</ENAMEX> was passed) in
which to make an offer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>. At any point along the way, it could have
decided that merging with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> was in its best interests and bid. And if it
had done so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months ago</TIMEX>, it almost certainly could have
got a better price. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> was no more in play after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> offer
than before. Its status had not changed. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BellSouth</ENAMEX>'s urgency had.

            The point is that the phrase "in play" is a useful cover for the fact that
takeovers, particularly hostile ones, are often the result of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>'
panicking at the prospect of losing something they never even knew they wanted
until they realized they might not be able to have it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BellSouth</ENAMEX>, for instance,
has been singularly restrained in its approach to the merger-mania that has
swept the telecommunications industry. With the exception of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>
investment in high-speed provider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qwest</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BellSouth</ENAMEX> has been content to build
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> from within. But in the space of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> it has thrown that
strategy over, in favor of a massive bid for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that it will find very
difficult to integrate with, from both a regulatory and an operational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>. And it's hard to believe that this is really the way you build
shareholder value.

            It's possible, of course, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BellSouth</ENAMEX> has had its eye on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> all
along, and was just getting ready to pounce when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> beat it to the
punch. But forgive me if I'm skeptical. You can't conjure a takeover bid out of
whole cloth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> and expect to have done the due diligence a
successful bid requires. And if we learned anything from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, it's that
there's always a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horde</ENAMEX> of investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> ready to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> that
they really can't afford to let this acquisition pass them by, and that there's
always a host of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> eager to believe that bigger is
necessarily better.

            The market, unsuprisingly, recognizes that the opposite is just as often
true, which is why the stocks of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI WorldCom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BellSouth</ENAMEX> have been
driven down since they made their respective bids. The urge to merge is a
powerful <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, but resisting it is usually the smartest course. Especially when
it's an urge that seizes you only after it seizes someone else first.

         
      
   
