
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Substance Problem</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">QUEENS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> began his visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with a
stop at a charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>. Afterward, he gave an eloquent speech in
which he unveiled a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> major education policy initiative dealing with
charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, reorganizing federal education programs, and a proposal that
vaguely resembles national testing for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>- through <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-graders</ENAMEX>. Today
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> appeared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> at a city
welfare-office-turned-job-center. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> stood up and gave moving testimony
about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and ones like it steer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> away from welfare and into
work.

            After everyone spoke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> held a press conference, his only one of the
trip. Here is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> asked:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, some conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have said that your criticism
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> is undermining their credibility on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>.
Have you made a political calculation that you can afford to alienate the right
wing if that means courting more moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, there are many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> who perceive that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>, anti-black, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX>. Should he be read out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Is there <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the big tent for bigotry?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> have both decried racism and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>. ... Your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> campaign chair purchased mailing lists from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX>. When you were asked about that, you said you didn't even know
anything about it ...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>, you talked earlier about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> and the image of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. There have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> national elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>. Could you just
talk about each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and talk about how you think that's caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s
image to go off track and how that informs what you're trying to do now?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q.</ENAMEX> You say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s been mischaracterized. ... But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> there was an
actual thing they were doing that was not mischaracterized [i.e., attempting to
delay payments under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>]. It was an actual
policy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q. You</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months ago</TIMEX> that you would not campaign against this
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. But some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hear what you said over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last week</TIMEX> as
precisely that.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was asked no questions about education and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> about welfare. This
concerned a federal investigation into whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> was "improperly denying
benefits for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>." In other words, the questions he got from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> focused on politics and positioning to the total exclusion of his
actual policies and positions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> tried to provoke <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> into making news
or embarrassing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, while ignoring the social policy issues on his
agenda.

            It's not that the questions they asked weren't interesting or legitimate
(though most did fall under the category of "already asked and answered"). I've
heard far worse at other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> conferences dominated by local TV loudmouths
asking endless stentorian variations on the essential horse-race query "Who's
going to win?" And a focus on pure politics is surely better than a focus on
personal misbehavior or the issue of whether evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> should be
alone with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> not their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. But why can't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> devote at least some
of their time and intelligence to actual issues?

            I can think of a few reasons for the allergy to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the
imperative for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to move the ball on an ongoing story, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> vs. the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Advancing such a
conflict automatically counts as news. Some new detail about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s education
policy, by contrast, might or might not make the paper. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> factor is the
journalistic culture of the news conference, which rewards zinger questions
that provoke news--and discourages anything that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> televised dullness. A
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> factor is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> division between politics and policy. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> covering the campaign are well schooled in the former and only
minimally, if at all, knowledgeable about the latter. They may understand the
politics of school choice or welfare reform, but tend to be far shakier on the
substance.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> complaint of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is that the power of
special-interest money is breeding public cynicism about the political process.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horse</ENAMEX>-race journalism has more or less the same effect. It tells the public
that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> ever do is quarrel--without doing much to elucidate what,
if anything, they might be fighting about.

            
               Bushism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week</ENAMEX>
               : "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> I finish please? I
was just getting to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peero-ation</ENAMEX>."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Queens Job Center</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6, 1999</TIMEX>).

         
      
   
