
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		capital punishment uh i guess out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> has has had a lot of uh a lot of you know discourse in the paper uh apparently uh there's they haven't uh executed anybody since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen sixty seven</TIMEX> i believe
 	
 	
 		um yeah that's that's far back as i can remember well that's before my time actually
 	
 	
 		yeah they a well i we were we uh we just started we we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redwood City</ENAMEX> when we were out there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and we found that uh  you know it was a very liberal kind of community
 		but uh i i i really feel that the that the law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> uh you know puts these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> behind bars and then they they uh uh you know the lawyers these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> groups
 		get together and they uh they i think extend beyond the normal uh appeal process
 		uh you know and just drag these this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> uh his his uh ultimate uh demise out for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or fifteen years
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i i think that uh that there there's something that has to be changed in the system to to do that i i think capital punishment uh uh laws are probably stringent enough but i think the appeal process is really getting in the way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do do you feel as though there should be uh  more uh laws or or more uh you might say transgressions that would be enforceable by uh by uh uh capital punishment
 	
 	
 		well i think that currently the the way the law stands isn't so much that the laws are enforceable or not it's more they're not enforcing the death penalty itself it's
 		it's to the point where they're saying like here you're you're going on death row but you'll stay there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> and nothing's being done about it um the laws exist and too many times they're frequently upheld in in um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeals Court</ENAMEX> just because of technicalities and because of maybe small little holes that their defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> can find and it's it's really getting out of hanters in most many states
 	
 	
 		well  the term technicality the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the the</ENAMEX> law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> uh
 		uh you know has to has to separate the difference between somebody who is being set up in which uh griedous acts are done to uh to you know get somebody into a a situation where they're gonna be guilty of of a crime
 		or whether uh and and whether the rights of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> are been have been you know impugned um but  or whether there's just you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> has just made a uh
 		uh you know a a non a non critical error error though be it not the right way to do it but but you know the the merits of the case in terms of you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was a law breaker is being supported
 		now i i'm at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at this juncture i you know i'm i'm not sure you know what constitutes a a technicality you know that that's what all these these hearings are about and that's what all these you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> cases are about i mean
 		our uh our our glorious uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> away from getting out of uh out of uh the can and uh  you know he he tried to appeal his conviction
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you know it didn't work but be that as it may everybody who got enough money will pump the appeal process dry
 		um in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> you know and say round <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> times of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> you know and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages villages</ENAMEX> if you were a transgressor they
 		they either you know drove you out in the woods or you became a ward of somebody and he were you were his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> and if he didn't like what you did he killed you
 		and that has that's pretty effective
 		uh you know it's not good for civil rights i guess but it's pretty effective in that you know you've got to get along in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and if you don't you will perish either by the hand of your your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> or by being pushed out in the woods
 		so i i i mean as as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has gotten more complicated so all of the uh machinations to uh you know protect him from
 		from being uh dumped on by uh civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> in in in some in criminal actions especially you know murder cases and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		well it seems like  well it it seems as if in the past um typically there have been a lot a lot of cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being wrongly tried or wrongly punished and the whole
 		the whole idea behind the current criminal process system
 		is to protect those who actually didn't commit the crimes all be it it seems that we are failing in that in that ultimate goal
 		because there are times when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who are guilty are getting off
 		um for instance um there's a case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX> where um someone um someone who's being
 		convicted for was under a trial was going to trial for murder was let off because of a technicality that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> the arresting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> um did not read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> their rights
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and where as all the evidence was there the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> were there the everything everything was conclusively pointing to this individual yet
 		
 		
 	