
 
     		
 	
 		think is wrong with the public school system is that i think we've lately in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years or so</TIMEX> kind of lost focus with the basics
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh in order to go into this sort of specialized curriculum where uh we're teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		not a broad base of subjects but rather trying to concentrate them on particular subject areas that they think they might be interested in going into a career
 		uh about and the problem comes about if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't well rounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> that that sort of traps them in the field that they've spent all this time being educated in
 	
 	
 		i think there's something to that yeah yeah i tend to agree uh
 		well i remember now it's been quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were in high school i'm getting that old but uh i remember uh being a little surprised at the uh
 		the catalog of courses like instead of taking a survey course on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Literature you had you chose from uh it almost looked like a college catalog
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> were too specialized as you said
 		and you just read you know they they take a whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester long</TIMEX> course on uh on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> or something uh that's fine for college  but it seems kind of silly for high school
 	
 	
 		yeah that's it's i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only twenty four years old</TIMEX> so i've was through a lot of that uh although
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you'd be about the same age as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		well in my luckily up here the school system up here was intelligent enough that they didn't want to get that focused
 		and they drilled into our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> and the same thing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that i went to to get as broad of an education as possible so that you're down with the basics and then once you know what you want to do then
 		try and uh get some specific courses but i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that they were always drilling into us was the need to learn how to communicate effectively through writing
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i constantly come up against some of the writings being involved in uh computers and the like where i see other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> writing and it's embarrassing
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know it's some of these things that and i've seen papers that in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade i wouldn't have had returned uh to me which are getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> in college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the standards have really fallen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah i taught college for awhile not recently but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i remember i i was quite surprised  at uh i mean you start rejecting things on that basis you end up handing uh everybody's papers back that's probably what we should have done
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah it it  the only way that i ever you know i i took <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Comp</ENAMEX> journalism as a major and uh
 		the writing they what they would do is they would focus in on our particular problems well on the college level course and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh would then work with us as far as fixing those things i had a problem with uh writing excessive verbiage
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in my writing and i they taught me basically how to pair it down a little bit and i i don't see that in a broader
 		you know even in a public school uh situation because a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> have these large classes that they can't devote the individual attention to each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> that they may have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i suppose i guess the class sizes are bigger now i guess they must be
 	
 	
 		i remember large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in certain uh courses mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Science</ENAMEX> we'd have lectures where there'd be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if you had a question you know or or didn't understand it at all of course you're not going to raise your hand in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> group
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		thing and say i don't know what you're talking about they're going to just keep their mouth shut
 	
 	
 		right they need smaller discussion
 	
 	
 		and i think you know it's those kinds of things that
 		i i'm not sure how we go about fixing something like that other than maybe devoting some more uh
 		uh resources into <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all getting uh the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> reasonable salaries and uh expecting in return some sort of standard
 		standard and uh you know some proof that what they're doing is actually worth what we want to pay them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then try and get maybe more involvement with the parents
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to just take care of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh you know you you it's your job not mine
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i've been reading about some successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> and it does seem that parental involvement is the is the common uh factor and everybody's doing anything that works these days
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so that's probably uh one of the big keys
 	
 	
 		well how are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> down in your area these days
 	
 	
 		well actually they're pretty good uh i i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> i only moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years ago</TIMEX> but uh
 		
 		
 	