
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway i guess there was just somebody recently down there wasn't <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> was it or there was uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm not
 	
 	
 		put to death
 	
 	
 		uh i'm not sure there was the big one uh earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> that on on and off and on and off  um
 	
 	
 		um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah so how do you feel about it
 		about capital punishment
 	
 	
 		i i don't know i'm  i'm uh mixed views on it i don't i don't
 		think that it really does much good as it as a deterrent uh the old thing in in terms of uh the the the uh biggest day for pickpockets was at the when they were hanging pickpockets but in public but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh on the other hand it it the it seems like that there just aren't are uh
 		some crimes and and some lives that that that there's no other at least emotional reaction to it what about you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i've you know i i kind of like you there's certain certain crimes that i think it fits i'm for it generally speaking i think the thing that bugs me the most about it is that
 		the process itself gets so <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> out and so
 		you know i understand you need to prove without a shadow of a doubt that the guilt and whatnot but the appeal process of it i think is what really bugs me if you're gonna make it go so long you know what's the use of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it almost becomes more more cost you know to much cost and more trouble than it's worth you know to to put somebody like that to death or something that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		rather than just sentence him to life and forget all the hassle you don't have to pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> all those fees they get and whatnot because i feel like you know sometimes it gets too drug out but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think i am i am basically for it with if you know if the crime of course fits it because some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> this you got to wonder will they ever do anything i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right right that that there's just
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the time just comes that pure and simple you know you got to wonder if they're just a plain and simple menace to society or they gonna
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right right
 	
 	
 		ever reform but
 	
 	
 		right well now does does uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> have capital punishment
 	
 	
 		yes we do uh-huh and i and it's been a couple there was a oh it's been about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years</TIMEX> now there was a pretty hideous murder
 		in a hi-fi <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> where they murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and they they the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that did it they poured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drano</ENAMEX> down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s throat and they kicked a pen through another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s ear and and all kinds of things like that and and of course a couple of them ended up dying and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> didn't but
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		ah one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> involved was uh was was uh put to death oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX> and and like i said if it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about thirteen years</TIMEX> for it to happen and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is still sitting on death row you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen fifteen years later</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's why you know like i say a part of my thing with the whole appeal process kind of bugs me because here they have sat for you know fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and i i wonder about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> you know and they've got to be a little bit upset themselves and
 	
 	
 		yeah that that that's it and uh that that  it if it's gonna happen it seems like there there there's some sort of closure when it when it's over and done with i know that was one of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		aspects that covered the sequel to the case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> was was both it this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> and they've got something like over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX>  on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		death row but the other thing was whether you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> i think in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> but you know wanted to be there to to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> it and it didn't feel like the whole thing was over and that's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years</TIMEX> too i think  and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true yeah they uh
 		uh oh i forgot i lost my point but yeah that's like i say i think the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> and just if that's gonna happen they they just wanna have it done and over with but you know i agree there's got to be some appeal process because
 		it's almost you you wanna make sure in that situation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> really did commit the crime uh you wanna give him every opportunity you possible can but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's the that's the thing here in here in here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we've had a couple of cases in the last  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> was a was a murder case where it was
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at this point it's fairly obvious that it was a that a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> was killed at a high school and it was pretty obvious that the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> just picked out the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> and and uh set him up for it and uh he really didn't have anything to do with it and they  that certainly makes you think again again and yeah yeah  and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's that's the scary part especially something like this
 		i know in uh you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> case the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Liberty</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil Liberty</ENAMEX> you know they were doing anything they could to prevent it even to going as far as uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know stating the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> is not uh as cruel or is cruel and unusual punishment and in such that they just drag up any little thing they possible can to drag it out or or whatnot you know i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well now in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> what's the method it is it firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> or what huh
 	
 	
 		they use firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> is is what's used a firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what i was thinking  wasn't there a a big case
 		
 		
 	