
 
     		
 	
 		regarding uh taxes i'm you know taxes are really a necessary evil in in a civilized society but really <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get upset at taxes because you it's more efficient to do things yourself
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right hm
 	
 	
 		and uh and so as as a result uh you know it's it's a trade-off you know for the common good you know for for the benefit of others
 		you know how much of your resource should you dedicate to uh making things work for others
 		have you uh you know ever thought you know just how much of that money should should go to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that really don't deserve it
 	
 	
 		uh well yeah  i know it's it's a lot you know  that uh that i feel like you know just like you said that there's just so much that you can do yourself
 		that you take care of your own self that you don't need the money for but they're giving it to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't really need it either either
 		but yet they accept it
 	
 	
 		well the thing of it is if i wanted to just uh you know permanently become a book reader i guess i could just uh you know uh go on public assistance uh
 		you know  look look look for uh look for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to uh take care of me and uh probably a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		like so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		just you know just just con somebody to take care of me and and then you don't have to be on the tax roll
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh but taxes are are very difficult kind of thing and everybody everybody really hates it it was very timely i
 		i i always over pay my my deductions so i wind up with my getting money back on my uh from my uh withholding
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh you know that that's always a smile but of course you know i've i've paid it in and i should calculate it better
 	
 	
 		you are you in business for yourself
 	
 	
 		no
 		no i i i i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i see
 	
 	
 		so i i'm a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> yeah guess i don't sound like it huh
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh well i think i no i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are just as against taxes as as everybody else you know most of them unless you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i've blown yeah
 		oh i i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> feet in a trough you know being a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> and and and so but but i can understand that uh that you know the uh who gets benefits like every every time there is a a bond issue
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i vote no on every one of them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'm i but this this is this is tax not tax revolt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i mean there's too many every one of us most of us have our have all <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four feet</NUMEX> in the trough
 		you know plus our snout right up to our ears
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know it's not exactly that kind of a place that that that you wanna you know get into a tax revolt situation
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh um the um the local taxes here i i in in this particular area um you know i've uh i think i pay about uh oh
 		thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> for for taxes on my <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom house</ENAMEX> you know and which is a lot of money and and uh and so as as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get older and older uh you know they think about retirement and that sort of thing and
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they they're building old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> homes uh you know at tax expense sell i think you know the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ought to just bail out of here and go where it's cheaper
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty three hundred</TIMEX> dollars at or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five hundred</TIMEX> dollars i'm paying in taxes why i i i could go down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulverde</ENAMEX> and probably rent a rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for that right
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right for
 	
 	
 		you know instead instead it's it's the taxes here so course i don't know whether i wanna go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulverde</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seguin</ENAMEX> or someplace like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh there's certainly lots of inexpensive places where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> are poorer
 		and and i think really the only place you can really reduce the amount of taxes you pay is to move to an area where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> are poorer
 		if you're not gonna use them then you wanna be in in an environment that's a strategy i think that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to have to take is is how to be able to to lessen their cost of living
 		you know and i'm i'm <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five six</NUMEX> away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before i'm eligible to retire and and i'm saying well you know i really can't stay here uh as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retiree</ENAMEX> it's too expensive
 	
 	
 		after you retire yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm gonna have go out in and you know in  you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Fork</ENAMEX> someplace and and do my thing you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are in the same situation you know they their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is paid for but still their taxes are so high that you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> doesn't feel like he can retire
 		because they couldn't pay the taxes and they have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or
 		you know anything now they don't use any of those services that a lot of the taxes go towards
 	
 	
 		right they they redecorated in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nineteen seventy five</TIMEX> you know and they're not doing it again again you know so well it's certainly uh uh you must be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> employee
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 		you must be what
 	
 	
 		you must be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> employee
 	
 	
 		no i'm not  no i i don't work i'm a student i go to school i'm in nursing school
 	
 	
 		you're not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> who do you work for
 		you're
 		
 		
 	