
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so what is your opinion on on drug testing
 	
 	
 		well i can see it in certain cases where it might be uh somebody's in a position that uh perhaps a lot of lives are involved like maybe um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> that
 		um uh
 		you you know fly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> and uh maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have a lot of responsibility over a large mass of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i could certainly see it being done but in general
 		um you know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> wanna do this and i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do like factory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> that have lots of accidents are now being drug tested i know a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that are doing that
 		um so you know they kind of have gotten into the idea that let's drug test them and let's put them through rehab but
 		there's got to be like a limitation do we drug test everybody that comes in or do we kind of say well you can be drug tested and you look okay because you look this way you're you're very conservative and and
 		there's just no way that we would think that you would use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that doesn't fit the stereotype of uh the conservative or whatever could be drug tested
 		and uh you know whether legal rights and of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i don't know there's certainly a lot of things to really consider uh when you get into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing people
 		just at the work place unless of course like i said they have a large responsibility over a mass of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh that's about it
 	
 	
 		well yeah you're it it's not just a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s you're talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s liability if if if uh if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is liable for something that that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> does while under the influence of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> you know then by all means they should have the right to to to
 	
 	
 		sure sure and i think that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are doing uh more and more because there are products that are out there
 	
 	
 		to
 		to minimize their liability and there's also the case about just uh um health health and welfare of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has a healthy work force their insurance rates are low and not only are not only they low there's all sorts of a of a benefits
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		uh financial benefits associated with having you know having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> file fewer claims being sick
 	
 	
 		sure
 		exactly the only thing is
 	
 	
 		uh then there's there's there's the whole question that that a that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> that is known not to be on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is gonna be more healthy i don't think anybody would argue with that
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		exactly the only thing is uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> issue that i would take stands with is the fact that the drug testing itself can be done on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that is actually not on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and come out positive
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if they have had like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> in the past let's say once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month or twice a month</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or maybe um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that week</TIMEX> they take an Advil
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advil</ENAMEX> will apparently come out positive as if they smoked marijuana
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and there's poppy seed type things i think everybody's aware of that but um where's the line where you where you say to somebody i'm gonna drug test you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> so please do not take these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> or where's
 	
 	
 		well well the question
 	
 	
 		you know how can you how can you do it
 	
 	
 		right the question becomes what do you do about somebody who testses who test positive
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		that's that's where the real sticking point comes in it's not i don't think there's any problem with testing people it's what do you do with the information
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		sure exactly and and the the only thing that i would say on that is it could blacklist an employee later on let's say um
 		you've taken medication of some sort even though they usually have you at the time list what <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> you've taken
 		uh let's say you do come out positive and you've taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Advil</ENAMEX> or any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibuprofen</ENAMEX> products out there or you've had a cold and you've been on medication or whatever you come out positive
 		is it then the chance that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> will look at you in more of a negative fashion and say well you know
 		this is kind of iffy you know are they really on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or are they on thrugs you know what i'm saying where there might be in the back of the mind of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> that this person
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or make up they may make up their mind that let's get rid of this employee you know what i'm saying
 	
 	
 		right well yeah i think clearly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who is the line <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator line manager</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> should not be privy to the information of drug testing that should go to an entirely different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> within the corporation um
 	
 	
 		exactly and it's a they can that uh if it does come out positive the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time they need to go back and find out what <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> did that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> take you know what i mean it it's kind of like
 		uh i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are aware at least now common knowledge is that
 		
 		
 	