
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		have you ever done this
 	
 	
 		yes i have
 	
 	
 		what did you do
 	
 	
 		unfortunately
 		
 
 	
 	
 		unfortunately  uh oh  this will be interesting
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it yeah it it's it's really hard to please everybody
 		and it it takes a lot of planning a lot more
 		a lot more effort  you know you have to decided what you're going to do
 		have you ever done one
 	
 	
 		well
 		actually i'd i sort of do this uh anytime my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> comes to town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean we have a very immediate family it's not really extended
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i was an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> so we don't have
 		like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons and tons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
 		so it's really my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> are married and they have little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so you know it's basically us
 		and so when every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> comes it is very hectic
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i guess that's as close to what we have as a reunion and we do this at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmas</ENAMEX>
 		and we just did this last week
 		and so um it's hard to get
 		everyone to be able to come at the same time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's the hard part is was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was missing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> because
 		he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and he had things he had to do and he couldn't just leave but
 		uh it's really hard to get everyone together
 		but we don't have lots of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aunts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> and things like that
 		to consider
 	
 	
 		yeah our um uh the ones i was involved in was with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s family
 		and it's very extended
 		there are aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-aunts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be so much harder
 	
 	
 		and there's
 		oh  over the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years</TIMEX> depending on where we went and what we did there's anywhere from
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> to
 		fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> and sometimes
 		more than that you know during different phases of what we're trying to do
 	
 	
 		uh
 		so how often do you try to all get together
 	
 	
 		um they try every year
 	
 	
 		oh no are you all from the same place pretty much or
 	
 	
 		we're kind of in the same area most everybody is from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there are some from
 		there well there's a couple back east and they travel they've come a few times there's some from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think there's some from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where do you have these things i mean how long do they
 	
 	
 		usually we've been having them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>
 		that's where
 	
 	
 		it's at someone's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or i mean
 	
 	
 		um no we've had them out in uh kind of wilderness uh areas before we go camping
 	
 	
 		so you go camping do you i see well that's kind of good
 	
 	
 		and we've had them at resorts uh you know smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> places uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp ground</ENAMEX> things
 	
 	
 		but that way no one has all the work i mean once it's planned
 		nobody has to worry about fixing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for everybody and that kind of thing right
 	
 	
 		well we we do uh
 		we we have some traditional things and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first night</TIMEX>'s usually like a potluck
 		everybody just brings whatever they want and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we have those kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> and and then usually <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first morning</TIMEX> breakfast is just that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> does their own
 		and then have games all day
 	
 	
 		so there is a lot of planning though for things like that i guess anyway huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah there there is we we do uh
 		uh you know  we have we have quite a few we have a sing along one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> plays the guitar and sings and then everybody puts on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> show each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s supposed to
 	
 	
 		that's so neat though that's great
 	
 	
 		do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> show things and we have an an auction everybody brings in made goods or things that they do and we have an auction and then that goes into the family fund
 	
 	
 		oh
 		and who has the family fund
 	
 	
 		and well they elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're kidding i have never heard of this
 	
 	
 		uh they have uh
 		yeah they have a they have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> usually they try to elect the family
 		and inside that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there'll be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> or whatever and then each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has an assignment to
 		to you know carry out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the thing like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will have
 		um the games and one will have the food and one will have
 		the auction and one'll have the program
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's a big job for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> family
 	
 	
 		whatever it is
 		so it well well when i'm talking family it's it's like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so that'd my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and her her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i see so it's separated really yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		so it's um it uh you know it's extended it's extended family what it is is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and their
 		oh i don't know there's twelve of them or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> of them or something like that
 		not all of them are living still but there's probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine</TIMEX> that still are
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and then all of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah i see
 	
 	
 		so it's
 		
 		
 	