
 
     		
 	
 		um i don't know about you but uh i work outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in fact uh i'll be leaving very shortly to go to work and i work different shifts so are pretty much a
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a later</TIMEX> shift to where i don't have the family time uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> gets home it's usually he's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> alone and then uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">couple of hours</TIMEX> later i'm home
 		um i don't know i'm finding that more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i talk to there's less and less family time available to them and uh it seems that business wise um
 		in the business community or your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> seem to be taking more and more time away from the family
 		so you know if you do have any time it's kind of like on a rush cycle that you have to get so many other things done
 		um just just to maintain your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and maintain the things outside your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and then plus try to have that relationship with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and it it's sometimes a very it's a it's a very hard juggling act
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		and
 		you know i look at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and she's now uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> going to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and i keep saying oh jeez i don't have that much time with her
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and she's growing fast and
 	
 	
 		i know that i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and um i stay home i don't work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i know that it it must be really challenging to um try to juggle a job and and also your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> if i were gone as much as he is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we wouldn't have the influence on them that i would wanna put on them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure exactly
 	
 	
 		and i also notice that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that come over here to play that go to day care <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they don't like to be around adults
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they don't wanna play around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> they don't want to be around you they don't want you to tell them what to do they want to do their own thing and they're the very same age as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 		um-hum exactly
 	
 	
 		and i'm finding as i volunteer up at the school
 		i just a being um i'm not educated at all in um really detecting this but i can talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and tell them on a pretty good basis after i've worked up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to day care and which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> stay home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		and you can just tell in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> and how they respond to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
 		that um the ones that are are home and the ones even that are home that are getting the love and attention they need
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that go out aren't getting that it's just a different they're they are more used to being with their own age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they're not use to being with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and to responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		sure
 		sure
 		sure yeah i agree to a
 	
 	
 		um i think the trend in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> i feel really bad that it's turned so much to where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are um
 	
 	
 		i think so too
 		in fact um i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three years</TIMEX> at home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> so i i guess i felt fairly fortunate that i was able to do that and i did notice the difference between those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> being placed in day care and i thought to myself how can a mother
 		place her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of six weeks or four weeks or two weeks or three weeks</TIMEX> whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> says you have to be back to work is basically when you have to be back to work whether it be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> but how these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must
 		feel to place their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> into care and you know it's our society saying yes this um you need this job
 		it's a little bit financial type thing because uh if you look all over in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and that um their standards of living are a lot less than what ours are and that's part of it too but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was saying maybe some of the problems we brought on to ourselves is that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> back in the nineteen fifties uh were staying at home with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		and then made the decision well jeez you know i'll go out and get a part time job got a part time job and then financially they got themselves into well i'll have the boat i'll have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and it's nice
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and really women past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation women</ENAMEX> have done it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of this day and age too
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because it is now our financial situations are as
 		it almost takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to bring in an income to support a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> now and
 	
 	
 		it's hard it really is hard i know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i have to do a lot of sacrificing to keep me home and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure i did it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and uh it cost us a lot of financial problems doing it
 		and pretty soon you know you're at the limit where you've got to say okay you've sacrificed for you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> at home and you're not getting any further you know along
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you have to make that decision to go back to work part time or go back to work full time and you have to make that decision and it's a tough <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		right i think one of the things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> look at too though is um spending how they spend their time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think with working moms if you can get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> to give you almost like a rotation like they're going to do with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where you work
 	
 	
 		sure
 		
 		
 	