
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		not very good it's not been a good day
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		i went
 		i turned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twelve hours</TIMEX> early at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i finished mine up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eleven</NUMEX> and left it here with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> so i hope she's turned it in
 	
 	
 		are you eating
 	
 	
 		i just  go ahead i'll stop eating i just barely got home from the university i just barely got home from the university
 	
 	
 		no it's okay
 		say what
 		
 
 		tell you what we can do is uh i can punch the uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> then we after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> when the uh uh voice comes on we can talk <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> if we want
 	
 	
 		okay go ahead
 		fire away
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i love the irony of uh
 		talking about this subject on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> the fifteenth
 		but um i'm afraid i'm i'm i'm probably in the minority i i actually don't think that we uh pay too much in this country
 		um um particularly uh in this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where um i guess
 	
 	
 		i agree with you
 	
 	
 		i do have a uh a bone to pick with um uh the way taxes are distributed
 		um i just finished fuming at the fact that we pay an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight and a half</TIMEX> percent sales tax and no income tax when the income tax could have been deducted from a federal form
 		and the sales tax can't i think that's regressive and uh
 		um
 		it's kind of dumb
 	
 	
 		i hate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and a half percent sales tax but then on the other hand i don't mind that it's only on
 		you know things that aren't
 		like  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> and that it's not on them
 	
 	
 		well i mean nobody taxes groceries do they where
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they do
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we have a pretty low income tax i mean pretty low tax rate here oh i think that the sales tax they just got to do something about it
 	
 	
 		right it's
 	
 	
 		but that's the politicalness of trying to not create any new taxes
 	
 	
 		right
 		but i guess when i hear when when i see the comparison between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and uh any other western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>
 		uh their their rates are like uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty one forty two</NUMEX> and ours are like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty six thirty seven</TIMEX>
 		you know if you compute it as a percentage of total income all taxes lumped together we actually do pretty well
 		there's there's there's no other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that's that is taxed as low as we are
 	
 	
 		well and i still think having lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for awhile you know  the difference in living conditions are certainly well worth uh what we pay for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i'm i'm not sure i understand what you mean
 	
 	
 		well i mean i think i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> you know for several years
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i'd a lot rather pay taxes here and have what we have than have to live there
 	
 	
 		oh you mean lowest end of living in spite of lower higher uh yeah i suppose that's true yeah um probably more less so now than it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> or whenever but
 	
 	
 		higher taxes yeah
 		still is that way to some extent
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think the other problem is you know it's it's easy to complain about taxes because they're something you theoretically can do something about
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i look for example and you you're not in the quite in the same situation but like school taxes for me biggest bargain in the world i wish i didn't have to pay  any more for for to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> than i had to pay for all of my school taxes
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah since uh
 		i send my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's probably a little tougher on you
 	
 	
 		it's not it's not quite the bargain that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> would think
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i mean i pay them gladly that's a decision i think it's a dumb decision on our part because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> do perfectly well with a uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two</NUMEX> tract system in which religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> coexist with secular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for the with the same tax money
 		but uh i mean that's uh that's the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> want to interpret it i guess that's all right
 		but yeah i and if i were uh when i was single and again when i'm retired i will not mind paying uh what it takes to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> good that's always been a high priority you know
 	
 	
 		no i think that's just you though
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i do think yeah that's true i think in places i think in places like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are beginning to find that in in areas that are fairly well off
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if you add the um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of various sexual persuasions and those who never intend to marry and those who are retired and those who are um just looking for fun they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> turn out to be such a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> that they can't get the tax bill passed no matter what happens
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh  there are big sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of school age are such a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> that they can't get anything done
 		that seems um
 		um like a cultural lapse i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were always used to be willing to ante up for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> they
 	
 	
 		of course i think with the graying of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> we're gonna see that problem in lots of places
 	
 	
 		right yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would rather um increase the fire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and cut down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>  because it means more to them
 		but i think it's sad
 	
 	
 		or build roads
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">selfish</ENAMEX> and shortsighted yeah
 		well
 		uh
 		
 		
 	