
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well
 	
 	
 		so what i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		what what kind of benefit uh benefits do you have at work
 	
 	
 		well i i'm i work at a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and uh
 		we have quite a quite a few benefits and uh we have um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the best benefit i like is the uh amount of uh vacation time especially after uh working working there for a long time it really build up to the amount of vacation time i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that's one of my best benefits
 	
 	
 		oh yeah is there a something that you wished you had that you don't or
 	
 	
 		well one thing that i i uh
 		wish uh in a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> there's more bureaucracy and
 		uh less support of uh
 		what you're doing i think and uh that's something that um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is uh probably and a benefit of a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you get more support from the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you work for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i work for a relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> we're a trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX> and uh
 		our benefits are fairly good and like you say that support i mean you work directly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and you know they you get the feedback from them directly and i like that but
 		i wish i really the thing i like i guess i wouldn't mind having a better retirement plan we have just a defined benefit plan and
 		i kind of would like the idea of having a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">401K</NUMEX> or something that i could you know contribute to and get some matching contributions
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that'd be a lot better i that's one thing i wish i had a little bit more of but
 	
 	
 		you're really thinking of the future
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i don't know i'm kind of the type i just don't wanna work my whole life i'd rather be able to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		make my money and be able to retire and enjoy a lot of things before
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so that's and that's one way i can see doing it but none of them
 	
 	
 		i work i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and uh it's pretty good retirement plan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		we don't get paid very much but uh
 		retirement plan is pretty pretty good
 	
 	
 		works good
 		yeah that's like i say ours
 		we're we get uh vacation is pretty good too i mean it's you get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year two</TIMEX> after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and it goes up
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just every year</TIMEX> by a week up until i think like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> which is a lot better than anybody else i'd ever heard of uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's quite a bit of vacation to have after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> service so
 	
 	
 		did you say you work for a credit union
 	
 	
 		uh it it's a a credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union league</ENAMEX> they're kind of a trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX> we uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		kind of do a lot of the
 		uh political support and stuff like that
 		for the credit different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX> within the state
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> used to work for a credit union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> they magazine they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX> that went out to all the
 	
 	
 		but
 		oh did she
 	
 	
 		all the uh credit union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that so she was really into the keeping up on what's going on with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 		huh what what did she work for
 	
 	
 		uh it was it was a company um i think it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit Union News</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was based out of uh
 		i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boca Raton Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah that sounds pretty familiar to me
 	
 	
 		yeah it was pretty uh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		pretty glossy kind of uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		newsletter that comes out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well uh  do you get to
 		i don't know have you heard of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that kind of do this uh the cafeteria plan where they kind of let you choose what kind of benefits you get or
 	
 	
 		uh not too much
 	
 	
 		is that something that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> does or where your work the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> or you pretty much get what they give you and
 	
 	
 		nah
 		yeah just i get what what you give in uh
 		that's uh
 		not not uh
 		with not too many choices
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess a lot of the more uh some of the newer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and the up and coming real fast growing ones kind of do that way but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say it ends up costing them more because whatever
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> alike they give them say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> bucks a month and they can buy their health insurance and their retirement and whatever but
 		and if they whatever they don't use they get in cash
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> don't like to do that because they figure if you got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> might take insurance and the other won't so it saves the company money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		whereas this one you know you'd end up paying regardless
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess
 	
 	
 		but for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> it sure sounded like a pretty good idea
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but anyway i haven't uh
 		haven't got so fortunate as to get into any of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		okay well
 	
 	
 		well hey it was good talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right see you later bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	