
 
     		
 	
 		yeah i guess uh uh it's an easy one for me i think that's uh there's something seriously wrong yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what is it that you are you know particularly
 		upset about
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i guess uh i think they've lost their compass and uh
 		i'm not sure they know exactly what uh uh public education supposed to be for anymore
 		but uh
 		i voted with my feet and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to parochial school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		what do you feel that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are getting in the parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that they wouldn't get in uh the public school system
 	
 	
 		well
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> care that's one thing everybody cares about the education the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are getting and um they uh take an active relatively active part
 		which uh
 		i mean if you're uh
 		sending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX> that way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> you uh watch what goes on and you um
 		um
 		pay attention and participate and and you can
 		influence the way things are
 	
 	
 		so you're saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> who also is really paying through the pocket book for the education of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> may not be quite so conscious of the fact that they are paying the tuition for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the form of
 		uh real estate or other taxes and and consequently they're not so motivated to get involved to make sure things happen the way they'd like to see them happen
 	
 	
 		yeah the immediacy just isn't there and um  uh i also think that one one of the problems and actually i don't think this i think this is a cultural problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh problem with public education is really uh
 		really a problem with the culture and i guess my evidence for that is the
 		school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> in places like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> for example where only a minority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and you can't get a tax levy passed
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are um reluctant to pass uh school tax levies even uh when the money is needed or would be well spent because it's uh they don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the schools
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think that's a a loss of civic virtue and a loss of um  uh the cultural attitude that we used to have that education was first even if it wasn't our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		i think that's uh that's the principal problem is that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> no longer see it as uh as their problem and as an immediate problem
 	
 	
 		right it troubles me too that that the priority seems to be with my particular purse strings rather than the public good and  by definition for some of us at least the public good includes
 		having an educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> i mean the idea uh that uh you can make a sound judgment  with respect to  small votes in in the at the local level or bigger votes at the national level uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it means that you've got to be informed and you've got to have a certain level of education to do the reading and the critical thinking involved to come up with a decision
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you know i i believe that the original idea of public education in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> which i guess was controversial at the time of the constitution
 		um  you know it barely made it i think it was added afterwards  i think the real the principal reason was uh education for civic participation the idea was that everybody should have an education so that they'd be a better voter
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you couldn't pull the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> over their eyes
 	
 	
 		right it has taken on a more more more profound and you'd think we'd notice it economic uh thrust yeah
 	
 	
 		well that's exactly what i was going to say now there seem to be really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> reasons for education one is education for civic duty one is education for economic reasons and one is education for civilization i mean and i i think that one is
 	
 	
 		well i'm glad that you added that one yeah i think that one's significant
 	
 	
 		that that's what i used to think education was all about when i was a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and then i quit and got disabused of that notion but um the um uh
 		now the only thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to agree on is that education is um an economic enterprise to um train <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for jobs
 		and um i'm not sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the education establishment really know what their purpose is and i'm really sad to say this i never thought i would have but i really think that uh the educational establishment has become part of the problem
 		and uh that's why i guess i'm sort of reluctantly uh in favor of these uh choice programs
 	
 	
 		right well i  i agree agree with everything that you've said so far and the only thing i'd wanna add is that
 		i'm a little more in contact i think with public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> than perhaps you are uh except as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and the sense sense that i get from public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that i know is  that
 		they are very conscious of what they feel they should be doing and they are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things that you mentioned but they find that they are also being asked to do a bunch of other stuff which they think is only tangentially related like consumer education
 	
 	
 		right that's what
 		
 		
 	