
 
     		
 	
 		i'm ready
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta Georgia</ENAMEX> you probably have a lot more crime than we have here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patterson California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh could could be
 	
 	
 		uh this little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about eight thousand</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we is is crime a problem there do you like a major problem minor problem or
 	
 	
 		well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patterson</ENAMEX> there's it's not a problem here but like uh i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> uh until just recently
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland California</ENAMEX> God they've had like uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty seven</NUMEX> murders so far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> compared to like uh forty at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's really bad there  it's all related to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> it seems like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		is that what it's there too
 	
 	
 		yeah um i've only been here for like oh probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just over six months</TIMEX> i started started <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i came from a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and crime the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was fairly big size or not real big but we had a problem there but here it's just no comparison that much more crime uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every every night</TIMEX> the news is very depressing because it just you know they run down the list of how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were shot you know drive by shootings or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		whatever and it's it's it's pretty bad they're they're it's things are basically improved here over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> they've the they've actually taken steps to try to make it better but it still it still is a problem
 	
 	
 		yeah Like i don't know what they can do to make it better unless they just hire more policemen
 	
 	
 		well that's
 		that seemed to be what they were doing and it has and they've started stepped up more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrols</ENAMEX> in certain areas and it has has made some places safer but you you know it's very difficult i mean if you don't have an infinite amount of money to to try to stop the problem although most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wish you could
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as it is a is definitely a problem and you know the more it more less that's done about it the more it seems it tends to spread even to smaller areas unfortunately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well i i think that if they would do something to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they do catch instead of just slapping their little hands and you know then then maybe those other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be kind of scared and they would not do these bad things you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i think i think uh it's uh seems to be that
 		i don't know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they tend they do something you know they shoot somebody or whatever they go to jail
 		sentenced to jail for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> they're out in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and they're back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and then they shoot someone else and just cyclical cyclical cyclical and it seems seems as though the the system doesn't  tend to stop them unless something is drastic is done
 	
 	
 		yeah i just don't understand our our laws here because you know like in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> man i mean they're really a lot stricker than we are
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's definitely true it seems seems as though we we try to play humanitarian i think to a little to much and maybe some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't deserve the the humanitarian treatment that they get
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		unfortunately but i don't know it's a difficult situation i think and
 		some something has to be done because i definitely think it's it it really
 		plays reeks havoc with uh your quality of life when you know you can see it's going on around you but then when once it finally affects you then then it really starts to bother you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		but
 		it seems i mean it <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move like out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> because they want to get away from the crime and so they tend to spread the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> farther and farther out but you know it's only a matter of time before you know it still catches up with them you can't really run away from the problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and something you know something has to be done but
 		it's just that too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> argue about how to fix it
 	
 	
 		yeah i know when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> it was just that uh like i definitely wouldn't go into certain areas of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> by myself
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		and uh and then then again some areas i wouldn't go by myself after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dark</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patterson</ENAMEX>
 		well like i say it's so small that you can go anywhere
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		but just uh like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twenty miles</NUMEX> away see in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Modesto</ENAMEX> they have uh those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> and things over there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it's it's bad in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> also they have uh drive by shootings it seems like all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know i just i just don't know what what they can do you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's it's to bad because it's um i mean
 		the just the even the random occurrences where you know it's unsafe for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> just to walk from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some</NUMEX> in certain areas like from from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> or something and it's dangerous and it's just that's just ridiculous and
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		you know it's just uh it's just not right something you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean like even even going to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> i know we've had this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that was attacked you know i mean just uh you just you just don't know what to do anymore you know
 	
 	
 		right right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and some of the times it's happening in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> too you know so it's not always happening at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dark</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh
 		definitely unfortunate unfortunate and
 		it just
 		
 		
 	