
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you feel the same but uh when it comes to telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that they have to do uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> of service into some kind of community i don't know if that's
 		uh appropriate for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to suggest that and say you know you have to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of community service before you can be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> or you know in the aspect that we're telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that this is what is suggested for you to do
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i as far as a high school course i could see it as uh maybe a social uh sociology course to where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> would get credits if they were to be involved with some kind of community type of program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and to me that's fine to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> do that for like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> but to tell them that they had to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> there after post high school of community service i'm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not quite sure if that's appropriate for anybody to be telling somebody they have to do
 	
 	
 		hum well that's a good idea to have it as a study program for school where it'd be more on a voluntary basis as opposed to uh mandatory
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah and yeah i kind of agree with that um
 		i don't think you know it it they shouldn't have they should have the same rights as anyone else
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		you know it shouldn't be uh anything shouldn't be mandatory other than i guess like uh when you come to paying taxes or something like that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or if it's beneficial in some kind of way then maybe
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be more eagle to do it uh-huh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 		and doing it for a purpose that they want the other thing is this i have thought about this and many times when you get these uh young troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> that uh don't have like the perspective of uh
 		of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> a sense of community or perhaps the sense that they may have problems but there are other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that may have problems
 		then i can see it as like maybe a probationary type of thing you have to do so much as far as in a community service now if they were you know the abusive type of situation perhaps then they would have to work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of abuse
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or if uh they destroyed some property around the uh area then they would have to do uh to restore it and perhaps um
 		work um for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to beautify it or whatever but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i could see that working in you know cases where the it might be young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> getting in trouble with law
 		and teaching him that there is a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that is is effected when they strike out and do their crimes or whatever and that's i think they have done that and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have said well you know this is what you're gonna get for um you know a misdemeanor misdemeanor or something you may end up having to do some kind of community service so i could see that as
 		something that might occur in the court system for those that are troubled
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		uh that's a good idea uh i think they should have more programs like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think uh us being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> we pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's in jail or in trouble anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure we sure do
 	
 	
 		so they should be programs set up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that could utilize those forms in different areas
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and i i agree wholeheartedly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh the thing is that it's not enough of that kind of stuff going on uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because you like you say it's a lot of crimes and stuff or misdemeanors why why have someone in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> for a misdemeanor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and sometimes you know putting them in jail it doesn't really help
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because there's nothing in there that to rebil rebilitate rehabilitate rebilihatate them and then when they get out they because they have the stigmatism of being in jail they can't
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and there's a lot of anger sure you know especially if they haven't went through treatment and they dealt with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the uh system of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> which
 		um you you always deal with somebody that's a little bit worse than yourself next to you or whatever i would say the crimes would probably be you know if you went in for a certain crime there might somebody that has has done a crime even worse than what you have so you're dealing with people
 		um that may uh be an influence later on and uh an issue of anger would be is that i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> but i didn't get any rehabilitation or um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know but then again those that have physically assaulted somebody
 		um that's extremely tough to put them into some kind of program out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> if they're of a violent sort and to say well you have to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		
 		
 	