
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i'm are you there
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		okay i'm sure that i probably um prescribe to different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> ones that you do  i take <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doll Reader and Doll World</ENAMEX>
 		because
 	
 	
 		different set
 	
 	
 		because i collect dolls  um i also take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Homes and Gardens</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like that and then uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he just uh subscribed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> he just started a woodwork so he just sent away to get some woodworking books
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so what kind do you uh get
 	
 	
 		you know
 		well i have a bunch of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> because i'm in computer science but beyond that uh lately i've been reading i've always liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and lately i've been picking up some of the travel uh both trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and just the general travel magazines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um trying to keep up on what's going on
 	
 	
 		is it
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> also gets a lot of the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bon Appetite</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Wine and Gourmet</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to take that right
 	
 	
 		yeah and she and she still likes to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which i've never liked very much but she seems to
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i if i you know if if i happen to find it i'll go ahead and read it someplace you know if i'm in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or something like that but other than that i never i never liked that really
 	
 	
 		do you read a newspaper
 	
 	
 		i read my newspaper i can hardly wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the mornings</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> to get here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so i do like to read the newspaper
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>  and even this little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patterson</ENAMEX> puts out in fact it it puts it out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thursdays i</ENAMEX> can hardly wait to get that to get the local news
 		but uh other than that
 		magazines i don't know there's so much advertising in them anymore
 	
 	
 		
 
 		some of them i used to get for the advertising like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byte</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> which is uh
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the larger computer ones
 		i haven't bought it now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years</TIMEX> but when i used to get it it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five hundred</NUMEX> pages about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> of them advertising
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		because that was interesting i think a lot of the trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that half the fun is finding out what all the products are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know some of the get ridiculous Travel and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leisure</ENAMEX> all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> magazines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leisure Food and Wine</ENAMEX> and i think they have some others uh certainly half the pages and maybe more are pure ads plus they have the advertising supplement sections that are supposed to look like articles but are paid for and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it is it's clear that i i've bought some of these  through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesalers</ENAMEX>  and they don't care if they make any money on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> subscription they're making everything on ads
 	
 	
 		yeah right right
 		yeah well i i only you know subscribe to the things that i'm interested in i used to be into coin collecting so i used to get the coin magazine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> actually is what it was you know
 		i used to get that so now that i'm into dolls that's about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all i really really want you know
 	
 	
 		have you ever um read or subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> for any length of time
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 		um
 		i think they're interesting
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but not worth it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i've always had this one of the reasons i like to to pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in other fields is that you seem to get a very different perspective so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've always had this problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> that in the areas that i know a lot about i disagree with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i always wonder whether there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know a lot about every area disagreeing with them on everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or or what's going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i've like i've picked up now a subscription to one of the travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization magazines</ENAMEX> and
 		it's a ridiculous difference when you start reading from their perspective
 		um you know their major interest is in commissions and
 		you know there's very little talk about the quality of places or airlines their major talk is about you know commissions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> rebates and how they won't suggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s not a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the full ten</TIMEX> percent or whatever it is and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it gives you a different perspective on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum well those travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are that more or less show you different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that you could go to or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh some of them the the general travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do i don't tend to read it for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i don't expect to be traveling overseas in in the future for quite awhile but i i usually just read through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> on on domestic stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um-hum okay well i don't know any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i could talk to you about
 		um
 		i don't take anymore than that
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah i don't take in much more in myself
 	
 	
 		you know so
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well i guess that will be it then  and
 	
 	
 		okay nice talking to you
 		
 		
 	