
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> are you interested in getting next
 	
 	
 		well actually i love the car i have i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LeBaron</ENAMEX> convertible
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and i love it and i would get another one in a minute unless i could afford what i really like which would be a red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrari</ENAMEX> or you know a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corvette</ENAMEX> or something like that
 		and that's what would influence my decision to change because i like a really sporty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>
 		and i'd love an expensive one but i probably can never afford it so
 	
 	
 		uh well i understand and can sympathize with that because i also enjoy driving performance automobiles
 		um i currently have an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven five</NUMEX> liter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mustang GT</ENAMEX> that i've done a bunch of modifications to to make it uh handle and perform better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i suspect if i were to be able to get another car where object was um the best car i could get regardless of money  uh
 		i probably would be tempted by something along the lines of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> or possibly a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrari</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah well i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> here and we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> at this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> that has a beautiful new red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrari</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a three twenty eight GTS</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i couldn't tell you but it's just beautiful and i go out and i love to touch it but i can't even do that because of the  of the alarm so i just look at it a lot
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		you just go hunting go out and lust after it
 	
 	
 		really exactly but it sure is a pretty thing
 	
 	
 		so have you had the opportunity to drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrari</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm working on it  no i really haven't no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i did test drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corvette</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> before it was brand new white it was like a big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marshmallow</ENAMEX> when you sat in the seats they adjusted to fit around you
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		i mean they came in and up and out and i mean they did whatever and and we went for a test drive in that and i was able to open that up pretty good and that was really fun and i wanted it but i had a choice of that or my house
 	
 	
 		yeah there there's something about having a place to live i don't know
 	
 	
 		and i felt that i should continue to live in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so
 		yeah you know it's just necessary and i did i thought well a tent wouldn't be bad but  probably not practical
 	
 	
 		could sleep in the back of the Vette
 	
 	
 		yeah right  so
 	
 	
 		i find that uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corvettes</ENAMEX> are are becoming really really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they are they're pretty aren't they lately they really are
 	
 	
 		yeah and they've they've improved the performance and the suspension such that they're actually a lot of fun to drive
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		it's not like driving a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnebago</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		oh no no no see i'm not into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vans</ENAMEX> and things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really buying now and they go isn't that a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> and i go hm
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		not really you know how about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greyhound</ENAMEX> bus
 	
 	
 		uh nice yeah nice isn't the word i'd choose maybe practical isn't that a practical van
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean that you know there's some that are prettier than others and yeah the new type is prettier than what their they used to look like
 		but i sure don't think it's attractive you know it's not like like driving a little sports car
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's very hard to find something practical that's also attractive
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think that happens so but i i love <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> so and i i bought it because i drove a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 		and i just went home and i walked in and i picked it out
 		and he said take it home and bring it back if you want to and i never did i just went back and signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and i knew nothing about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when i got it nothing i didn't know how anything worked
 	
 	
 		oh so it was a completely new experience for you and i'm sure you enjoyed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every minute</TIMEX> of it
 	
 	
 		yeah and i've had it it's almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> actually and i've i still love it i put the top down everywhere i go i timed it when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got it and it took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> i mean <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty seconds</TIMEX> and so
 		i figured there was nowhere i was to late to go that i didn't have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty more seconds</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		and you and you couldn't get how long does it take to go back up about the same time
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> yeah that's all it takes i mean it's just a button that's it you you release it right at the top so you don't have to get out or anything
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 		so you won't get
 		yeah and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty seconds</TIMEX> you probably won't get caught in anything too substantial
 	
 	
 		well i did actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> going to the airport i just hit a downpour and i was on a highway going like eighty
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i really did i mean i was soaking wet i thought i would drown in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> that it took me to pull over
 	
 	
 		whoops
 	
 	
 		but it all dried out you know didn't take long when the sun came out but   it was kind of funny i'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around me really enjoyed it  so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh no i was just down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and the weather was pretty nice too so
 	
 	
 		oh and wasn't it pretty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> with the bluebonnets and everything yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		with the bluebonnets out yeah it really was yeah i decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> is certainly someplace that i could handle living
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say that and it's pretty far from where i live it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about hm two</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX>
 		
 		
 	