
 
     		
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nevin</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvale California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hi this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Bliss</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis Minnesota</ENAMEX> how you doing
 	
 	
 		pretty good
 	
 	
 		good um i guess the topic is trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and how we should change that or how how we would change it um i'm ready whenever you are
 	
 	
 		yep
 		hum
 		okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh what are your what are your thoughts on the subject there
 	
 	
 		well i definitely think like decisions have to be unanimous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think that's probably a a good thing
 	
 	
 		it's probably the safest thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's to to easy to get a quorum and simple majority won't do
 	
 	
 		yep i
 		no and even even like you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thirds</NUMEX> majority i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah that's yeah quorums are to easy to get and there's always that that chance that one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could be playing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for a good reason you know so it's it's yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yep
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um i don't know it i could i couldn't believe they suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> should be doing the sentencing
 	
 	
 		yeah like gives gives them a little too much power
 	
 	
 		yeah  that i i know of a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at least who would be arguing with that or arguing against that pretty vehemently but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		plus you know you may be you know doing a you know a a guilty verdict but it may not be you know may be for technical reasons
 	
 	
 		yeah about the only good thing i would see about that is that would it that it would um hurry the process up a bit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i mean even now we've got i know we've got plenty of cases out there where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been wrongly convicted and things like that
 	
 	
 		i know what i
 	
 	
 		and that's what the trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i mean jeez if it if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> was doing it himself without any checks and balances
 	
 	
 		yeah it to be there'd be much more of that
 	
 	
 		whose to say
 		yeah no doubt
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		are you involved in the legal system at all
 	
 	
 		no but i tend i tend to follow it just to
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		just to know what's going on
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i've got some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too so
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them just got his law degree
 		but um to tell you the truth i'm not real familiar with um
 		the system of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">jurisprudence jurisprudence</ENAMEX> the way it is right now i really haven't studied it in depth
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah i know a little more about civil cases when than criminal cases which is  it's more in how you present it versus you know who's right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm sure of it because a lot of those things it's all it's in it's largely a matter of viewpoint and who can argue their case better
 	
 	
 		yep
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um it's kind of weird
 		i don't know yeah i always think about watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Court</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and how weird those cases get
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		it's just
 	
 	
 		when i was uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years ago</TIMEX> involved in some pretrial stuff and like you know you go say okay we can't bring up this point because then they're gonna you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> will say this this and this and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum and it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> the stuff that they can twist around is it's pretty amazing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yep
 		and it's like the the truth really isn't important anymore it's
 	
 	
 		yeah it's not
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who bring in cases just because they want to bring them up just because like this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine's pretty obnoxious and he really gets into suing people
 	
 	
 		yep
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so he'll he'll sue just about anybody just for the chance to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and argue his case
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know it's like
 	
 	
 		that sounds like a little abuse of our system but
 	
 	
 		it is it's it's wasting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s time and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money and everything else but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah but it's for the more general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want to take responsibility
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know that's a
 	
 	
 		and uh and and most of the time they're looking to place blame um
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and stuff see you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is that right
 	
 	
 		uh yeah well originally <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		hum
 		oh okay i was just thinking i wonder i wonder how how the civil system or the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> systems differ between there and say where i am in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>
 		i mean from what i understand it's all pretty much the same except when you get to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> is completely different cause it was based on the what is it it's based on common law and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is not or something like that it's pretty strange
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		fortunately i never have had to go in even even for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't either other than
 	
 	
 		but um
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine's telling me that i might have to go in for uh as a witness he may subpoena me
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so we'll see what happens
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not really sure how we could change the legal system to make it better i
 	
 	
 		yeah it's there are too many big problems you know there's there's such a backlog of court cases right now
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		you know to try to get them all in in a good time
 		and we already have too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> as it is
 	
 	
 		yeah and if it's criminal cases we you can't put them in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> because there's no room left
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true and in fact they're even letting some go i'm i'm originally i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and it's like it seems like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they let out more and more just because they don't have room for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know that's not a that's not a good solution either
 	
 	
 		not at all
 	
 	
 		so i'm not real sure what to
 		
 		
 	