
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think um
 		uh actually i'm uh fairly pleased with the
 		benefits that we have at the
 		uh working for a large corporation
 		and for me there's absolutely no question what's the most important benefit
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think it's health care it's what i think everybody would say that
 	
 	
 		oh and then if you try to get it outside of your uh corporation you're gonna pay an arm and a leg
 	
 	
 		right belonging to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is the belonging to a health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is probably the most important protection you can have after you
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX>  sometimes i think it's more important than salary
 	
 	
 		uh do you also get dental
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes and um
 		i don't know if i would rank that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> but um since i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> uh it it can turn out to be important you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a in a given year</TIMEX> dental can dental expenses can really kill you
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 		now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Airlines</ENAMEX> and he gets uh you know the full health and dental and uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and what you pay just to have teeth cleaned is outrageous
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't have it can afford it
 	
 	
 		right it's uh
 	
 	
 		or maybe they don't
 	
 	
 		right uh and then uh
 		if the cleaning doesn't get you the orthodontics will
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		uh i guess that would be up there uh i'm not sure if i would rank uh how i would rank that next to say compared to retirement or uh
 		um
 		um pre tax savings was another thing that i think is a a great a great benefit when i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i really i think it's really something that the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> ought to encourage more because uh there are all these complaints about how we're not a saving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and where the average savings rate is something like <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well it's a lot easier to to save it when you don't get your hands on it first
 	
 	
 		right when you have the when you have the uh the economy to scale and everything that a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> has and you can uh offer some incentive
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> goes along by not taxing it when you put it aside you can really build up uh the savings and the that you wouldn't otherwise do and
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh what about what about uh lesser uh benefits perhaps for you but for for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the in the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> for example uh  oh
 	
 	
 		leave
 	
 	
 		yeah do they have even have do they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> leaves or anything like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know i i don't think so yet they may have uh just plain parental leave which either one can take uh i their uh i know their maternity leave is on the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> which i think is too short
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		oh i do too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh uh i really think that we need to
 		get into the mold where we talk about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> rather than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> or weeks
 	
 	
 		oh i think i think it's just a crying shame uh for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to have to go back to work at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right and and uh
 	
 	
 		she isn't recovered  and uh the infant needs her desperately at that point and time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		there
 		
 
 		there ought to be uh
 		uh some compromise that could where uh where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would be guaranteed
 		a uh career type position but not necessarily a continuation of exactly the same position uh in exchange for a longer period of time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right i agree
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's so important to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> then and uh and yet anybody whose gotten far enough to get a good salary is really reluctant to give that up
 	
 	
 		oh sure especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age you don't want to start over again anywhere
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 		that
 		yeah you're right i think you've put your finger on the one benefit that i that i would most like to see uh changed  um
 		the uh parental leave
 	
 	
 		well i think they're at they're coming they've come a long way um at least some companies
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		some of them uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> in particular that works for a a rental car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and uh as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and uh they have a very very poor leave policy
 		and uh
 		i just don't know how how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do it particularly single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who don't have the support at the other end
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		they do it by shortchanging their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> there no other way
 	
 	
 		that's right that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		i mean uh unless they're part of some extended family which is unlikely um with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> moving as much
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh they're just it's just a terrible choice you shouldn't have to make it uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the benefits we get of course is travel
 	
 	
 		oh right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> would i like to have that
 	
 	
 		it's wonderful  the only trouble is that you can afford to go anywhere but you can't afford to stay once you get there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh listen i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> if you'd just fly me there i'll take care of that
 	
 	
 		that's right  you have to have an awful lot of fun just just getting there is has to be half the fun
 	
 	
 		right
 		so  and uh
 		i guess the uh the idea
 		
 		
 	