
 
     		
 	
 		uh i don't know my personal perception of government and uh the way things are at this current time is that nobody can really be trusted
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i don't feel that too many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are out there to uh be self-serving to the community i think that they have their own uh wishes to uh be in the limelight
 		and to kind of say hey you know i'm a public official i don't have to do uh certain things and they just stand out more involving themselves more and more with politics but
 		uh it's really after all the things that i've seen in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and now the overdrafts uh of checks uh before that it was the wonderful uh
 		escapade that they had with uh the new uh oh God chief of uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> i'm trying to think of his name and uh what they put uh him through in regards to yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the sex the sexual harassment that kind of thing and just to see our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> react to that and then just little things that have added up where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have taken vacations on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' monies and things like that
 		i i just think it's very corrupt and whether or not they need to start with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are extremely poor and send them into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are rich
 		but it's always the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that gets into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that has uh the money to advertise the money to do to do this there's no more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham Lincolns</ENAMEX> out there uh that can get into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> even if they were poor
 		so i know that's my personal viewpoint of things
 	
 	
 		doesn't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> have a uh state uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program or health program
 	
 	
 		now they just uh they've already put through the health bill  yes it just went through and it was passed
 		and that is going to be a heavier tax burden on a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers taxpayers</ENAMEX> and a little bit more on to the medical uh
 		i don't know if that was done out of just let's be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to do it or if it was done really for the needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know what i'm saying it it's
 		right now every little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> around here is thinking about oh we need to reform the health uh system
 		and of course they think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> passed a state law the health bill
 		and it's kind of like we're the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to do it so i don't know if it's done because we're we want to be standing out as being innovative in the health system or whether it was done for uh
 		you know a real good purpose to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can't afford uh health insurance that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i i think the one of the biggest problems that uh we see in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> today is a reflection of society in and of itself
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh sure
 	
 	
 		and that is uh uh we become so debt ridden and credit oriented
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		uh instead of uh cash and carry or debt free  and therefore uh that puts a lot of undue pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">municipalities state</ENAMEX> and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it it sure does and i think it it is reflecting like you said i think society as a whole
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh you can't expect uh when we have TVs and we have things that are kind of bombarded at us for uh you know immorality and this and this and this that we can expect somebody to come off that's going to be clean
 		totally clean  and come into government uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but down the line it does hurt i mean when somebody's corrupt and somebody's doing something it's uh you know it does hurt
 		the each individual of the society when you find out that somebody's done something or the overdraft policy or you know the other things that have occurred so uh
 	
 	
 		well what is see the thing is is when a lot of things become acceptable practice uh it's hard to discern the border what has become muddy as to what is ethical and what is not ethical and then someone blows the whistle and says
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		oh this is not ethical and yes i did it too
 	
 	
 		yeah  well that's exactly what happens in government  all the time hey blow the whistle on each other oh i hear that you're doing this i've done it but oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>  and it's not going to get out exactly yeah exactly exactly it's uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah we just had a
 	
 	
 		there's no secrets in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh i don't think anymore
 	
 	
 		uh
 		right the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett Steve Bartlett</ENAMEX> he also uh was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh to the uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and he had been in that position for years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and uh he was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		however if the vote was taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the whole thing might change because he was part of that
 		uh check kiting scam
 	
 	
 		oh sure  i think i i don't think uh
 		
 		
 	