
 
     		
 	
 		up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we're the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> cleanest metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as far as air pollution i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX> was number one
 		uh we really don't have too much of a problem as far as uh industry since we're pretty technologically based as far as our industry in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> here
 		but we do have the same problem a lot of are other areas up here in the northeast have and that is the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		coming coming basically from coal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's that's that's true actually down here we don't have a big problem with uh with air pollution mainly because we don't have anybody to the either side of us
 		uh which helps out a lot as far as that goes
 		i wouldn't even necessarily thought of that except when i lived up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and up in uh you know debates would come up up there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and
 		you know in that area over uh air pollution and their attitude's basically well prevailing ins winds are to the east so why should we have to worry
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've uh was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> once and that was quite a difference
 		as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> goes i mean you couldn't really see that much  every once in a while we have these air inversions the weather
 	
 	
 		oh yes nothing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inversions</ENAMEX> and then it gets hazy around here but they're really we don't have a big problem with it
 		i think that uh what most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are going after right now is it's it's the uh ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> problem especially out in the uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Adirondack</ENAMEX> areas
 		where you know the lakes are becoming uh changing the acidity of the lakes and we're having problems now because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> are dying and certain acidic loving plants
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or alkaline liking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> are just not lasting anymore because the soil levels the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p H</ENAMEX> is changing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		as this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> continues to fall and i know that there's been battles over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> up here
 		uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> going after you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and  and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> to fix
 		what's going on down there i remember when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> the only problem was that it seemed like it may it wasn't really pollution just the steamy weather
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely yeah just muggy
 		so yes i think you're yeah i think you're right our most pollute substance down here is just water
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX>
 		i i i think you know the biggest causes though even then a lot of times are uh uh like when i was up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> just all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 		you know all over the place you just got a lot of
 		you know a a lot of pollution from those and uh you know if you don't have a wind it sticks around
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i you know i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> once and i remembered seeing some of these things coming through at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush hour</TIMEX> even with the tee
 		um just this it looked like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> massing
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		and if they sit there and then there's nowhere for the air to go i mean yeah that's what's in you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> is i think that's biggest problem
 		because when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> for a time it's all you know from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> it's like all city
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and there's really there's nowhere for this to be absorbed really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">um tree</ENAMEX> planting sometimes can handle you know stopping some of the air pollution and that and help but if you have nowhere to do anything
 	
 	
 		that's that's very true
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh you know of course then when when you're not recycling you've got these incendiary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and stuff that can be some pretty disgusting stuff
 		going up in the atmosphere
 		but i you know you've you've got you've got the industry you've got that and you got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are where where it's at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> goes
 		air air pollution i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah i you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to be at least maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
 		but i i uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX> i i don't know what the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> are down there
 		uh but you know up here we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> and that's the worst polluter they put uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you can smell ether in the air sometimes
 		keeps the neighborhoods happy i guess
 	
 	
 		i i guess so
 	
 	
 		uh cause they clean the uh
 		the lenses for cameras and they they make film here and they're the worst offender but you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulphur dioxide</ENAMEX> is the big
 		emittant from them but that's really getting under control now
 	
 	
 		right i you know i i don't know in the air down here what they do uh
 		i i haven't run across any major <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> down there that i i i've really seen a lot of
 		you know upsettedness about
 		uh
 		i i i know i've seen like uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corpus Christi Texas</ENAMEX> and i know they've there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refineries</ENAMEX> down there
 		and and that's that's some pretty potent stuff they can put up in the air
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i but i don't know how uh yeah there's a difference in what you can smell and what you uh you know what's bad
 	
 	
 		be interesting to see when as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> develops industrially whether you know without
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 		
 	