
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know what you drive now i mean what do you drive now
 	
 	
 		uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup</ENAMEX> and uh the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is a uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Caravan</ENAMEX>  and uh because we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they're under thirteen
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		throw them in the back
 	
 	
 		they sort of fit our requirement yeah i have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickups</ENAMEX> with the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		seat with a seat in the back
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and so they just fit in there when they get to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> with long legs it may not work but right now i can right now i can throw them all in the back when we have room and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		and since i do a lot of projects i throw things in the back and i kind of like having a pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> actually i think of it as a  as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that'll last
 	
 	
 		yeah you're
 		right yeah i know
 	
 	
 		i i like the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> are built and i don't care about comfort so i'm pretty happy
 	
 	
 		yeah you're looking at i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Runner</ENAMEX> i wanted a truck that i i wanted something that i could throw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the back too so i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Runner</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so i wouldn't hesitate to get another one i i never buy new so i wouldn't hesitate to get another used truck
 	
 	
 		you're just like me i've never bought a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> in my life
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and uh yeah i don't i don't i don't need to pay for the glitz i'll let somebody else uh have the showroom shine enough and i'll pay for the rest of it
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 
 		let somebody else break it in right
 	
 	
 		right and uh the van we're sort sort of we might go again on a on a van uh we we could probably do with a a something just a little bit larger than a compact in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX> next time i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we have to we we'll have to face it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> but uh i i guess we had a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> wagon
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we were real happy with that because uh my my second requirement after price is uh low maintenance and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that it certainly had that we didn't do much to it at all
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah my my the pretty much the same i i got a like i said i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Runners</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it pretty much does everything i need it to i mean it it'll tow <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three thousand pounds</NUMEX> so i can tow everything and it i can throw i've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in it before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		believe it or not and uh
 		it's real reliable believe i i mean i've had it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost four years</TIMEX> now and up until oh say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> it had never had anything wrong with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then of course <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> it decided i don't know it's the strangest weirdest thing in the world but it blew a head gasket
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-oh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		didn't do any damage to it um i caught it real early
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> at how many
 		at how many miles
 	
 	
 		um oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety seven thousand</NUMEX> so it's not real early
 	
 	
 		huh
 		and you didn't overheat it
 	
 	
 		no never overheated it i smell i smelled the uh i smelled the coolant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		went out and looked saw it was coming saw where it was coming from drove it right to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and left it off
 	
 	
 		huh well that was minimum
 	
 	
 		and that was it because i  i have that and then i have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kawasaki motorcycle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is actually the usually my preferred mode of transportation if i can take it and it's not raining
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i mean that's that's sort of my hobby though more than a vehicle it it's a i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX> for transportation i think are kidding themselves
 	
 	
 		i have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> that uh commutes to work on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when it's not raining and uh uh
 		he's a it's
 		he's pretty conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i don't think it's much of a sport for him i guess uh
 	
 	
 		i know but i bet you he really enjoys riding it
 	
 	
 		i'm sure he does yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so you know you how when was the last time you took out took your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> out just to just to go driving
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and i go out twice a week on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> so at least just for the enjoyment
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's like
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but yeah i i mean the only thing i think i might get in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or not necessarily a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but a another car um i would consider going to a a non
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to a normal pickup rather than a a covered pickup like the one i got just because there's a lot of times i wished i had the uh just an open bed to throw stuff in
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm sure i'm sure that that's very i mean you got one it's that's really convenient just be able to throw that sort of stuff in the back and
 	
 	
 		if i only had some place that i could store the uh camper top i would have it off most of the time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i really leave it on there just for just to have it out of the way because it put it on the ground it gets dirty
 	
 	
 		and to have have it out of the way right
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah they're solid uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> are built uh i mean
 	
 	
 		i think they last a lot longer than anything else
 	
 	
 		they're the only things <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> still know how to build and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> do um even though you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jap</ENAMEX> the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jap</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> are are good there too but so are the though i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevys i</ENAMEX> don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> i don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevys</ENAMEX> as much as i like the Fords
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think they i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fords</ENAMEX> tend to last a little longer least until recently
 	
 	
 		right
 		i kind of like mine yeah so  mine's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>  and uh
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine just bought or bought like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> it's it's a really a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> i mean i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodges</ENAMEX> at all but one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodges</ENAMEX> they have out now has a uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cummins</ENAMEX> turbo diesel in it
 	
 	
 		oh i heard about that yes
 	
 	
 		ah it's beautiful that thing that thing will last forever i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's the that's a serious truck
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that thing's uh that it's got a boat engine in it
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right this uh i i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> who just got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those and he's pleased with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	