
 
     		
 	
 		as far as news and uh keeping up with it i get a subscription to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News and World Report</ENAMEX> and i also stay in touch with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> whenever there's something interesting happening in the world
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh do you do you actually read all those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh God i get  a lot more than that those are just the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that i get i barely have time i usually
 		tear through um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News and World Report</ENAMEX> that's my least favorite i think i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> the most
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i uh i  i keep up with what's going on by listening to the radio in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and reading a newspaper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> newspaper
 		and i i pretty much hardly ever uh see news on television
 	
 	
 		yeah i i've if you're near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> uh i i remember hearing in the car we can pick up WBZ pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> we i also get the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> here um we we're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> so we have a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning and a afternoon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> both owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i tend to read the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> just because it's more breaking news i also listen to short wave depending upon what the world conditions are like
 	
 	
 		oh so you can pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Moscow</ENAMEX> or that sort of thing huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Moscow</ENAMEX> it it's gotten a lot stranger in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX> it's they've added commercials and they have bad jingles and everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so it's pretty much like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">radio</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		well that's what they're trying to emulate i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still head for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B B C</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Service</ENAMEX>
 		which uh i i like that for international news but sometimes it gets you know usually if something major happens now i head for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B B C</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Service</ENAMEX> is broadcast on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F M</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they have it's it's distributed through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Public Radio</ENAMEX> i guess and
 	
 	
 		by our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> radio station
 	
 	
 		yeah they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> of that yeah you can also a lot of various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> has an audio service
 	
 	
 		still
 	
 	
 		which transmits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC World Service</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours a day</TIMEX>
 		you know i in the only problem with that i have with getting the news from a lot of these places is probably the worst lately has become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> because i i just despise fluff journalism
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is bombed but no you're not going to see that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> because here's Janey age <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> on the front page blowing bubbles you know
 	
 	
 		right or here's uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate candidate</ENAMEX> saying rude things about the other one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> or something yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i it it you know the worst of them all is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> which is  i call it useless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the McPaper
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's great
 	
 	
 		well they they um they have a pretty small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vocabulary</ENAMEX> don't they they
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  it's about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> grade it's basically a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> for those that watch TV
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		it's pretty tough to find objective objective straight forward news i mean the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>'s got their own slant their basically you know they're they're i think they're addressing their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> to to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brits</ENAMEX> living here
 	
 	
 		but in
 		yeah that that's pretty they have some pretty obscure international news i mean like coming up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">next a five minute</TIMEX> report on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah they do they do good stuff on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal and South Africa</ENAMEX> you can get good stuff on and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and but it's not necessarily close to
 		stuff i'm looking for they tend to make fun of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S</ENAMEX> a lot i think
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's they they have <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Letter From America</ENAMEX> i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alastair Cooke</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		who um who's been doing that program forever who comments on what life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is like and uh
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> seem more amused than anything else
 	
 	
 		well  maybe they're right what the heck
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		so yeah i i tend to we have cable here and that tends to be pretty good for news but i also have a satellite dish so i you can watch some pretty strange news things the feeds on there
 		especially during uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> war where you could hear the anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know screaming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> letter words poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie Shaw</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah do they um do do you use any electronic type news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> like a you know computer network news services anything like that
 	
 	
 		um i i have a uh you know i i found out about the service on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comp Dcom Telecom</ENAMEX> so we have access to
 		you know there's there's um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara News</ENAMEX> and you can also get on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CompuBucks</ENAMEX> and uh read the news wires on there which you know i appreciate that one if i want to search for a particular topic you know that i know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> Net service then
 	
 	
 		yeah well either that or you can go on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara News</ENAMEX> and use it or i'm sorry uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CompuServe</ENAMEX> and use their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> if you want to follow you know certain key words and i use to do that when we were interested in following the cable industry
 		you know you wouldn't see this stuff in the local paper
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		yeah we don't get the where i where i work i don't we don't get the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> Net stuff
 		
 		
 	