
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well you can start
 	
 	
 		uh i can start
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the
 		notion of a of
 		of universal service sometimes sounds real good but
 		i i sometimes wonder whether it's if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't willing to do it
 		do anything like that on their own and i guess it would have to be really and truly universal and then i think you start running into all sorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s religious objections and  you know and and how do you
 		make allowances for everybody's culture if you try to force fit everybody into things and yeah i just i the logistics of it just seem horrendous in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		yeah i i frankly can't go along with the idea only because it's the same kind of thing that you see in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and
 		uh other places where you're supposedly for the good of society you're to volunteer and help out
 		and and do something very nicely for everyone and the problem comes into play in that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't interested in what they're volunteering for
 		and they're not getting paid there's no incentive whatsoever and really you in in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that depends on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> say uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Red Cross</ENAMEX> and something
 		uh those kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> you can actually you could actually become a hindrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> if you aren't really interested and you're just there because you have to
 	
 	
 		in what you're doing
 		yeah yeah it it
 		i don't know on the other hand there are other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> that have universal service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know which are democracies
 		uh i don't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> though are somewhat more homogeneous homogeneous
 	
 	
 		oh yeah certainly i mean there's especially especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> there's a particular the cause for the good of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> especially when it's on the defensive
 		and the region really inspires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to help out for the good of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but we have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well but they still have a universal well uh close to universal draft uh and they still run into
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to problems there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should not have to take orders from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> because it leads to
 		morality problems and i just think that you'd run into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who felt that way here not only uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> of a very strict <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> cast but also i think that a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> would have problems with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> being under the
 	
 	
 		um
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know having to take orders from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and who knows what and  uh
 		you know i just so i i you get you get really torn on the other hand
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my one of my favorite science fiction books is a book by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Heinlien</ENAMEX>   yeah
 		uh
 		called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Starship Trooper</ENAMEX> or something and he talks about you had to serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in order to have the right to vote
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		in other words you had to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> show that it meant something to you in order
 		to to have the right to say what ought to happen
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and so that you you know i'm sort of torn that idea makes a whole lot of sense too <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are just along for the ride why should they say how my money should be spent and why should they say what i ought to do
 	
 	
 		well there should be some tangible benefit uh if if you really want to get into something where you want to have a full participation and have it work well is to have something where they select
 		the programs or whatever that they wish to participate in and give them some tangible benefit for doing so to inspire uh more involvement on their part
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		in the and that's the way i think you really over take over this problem or get rid of the problem of them
 		you know conscientious objection or what have you if you give them the option of selecting what it is that they want to do i
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and and that's that'd be kind of an interesting way of doing it i think if you're going to do something like that because it instead of voting
 		for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> who votes for laws or whatever you vote by what you're willing to participate in
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think it has a lot of potential but i don't think that we're going to ever see something like that get through in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> because of the
 	
 	
 		yes but i can't get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right now
 		no probably not
 	
 	
 		mismatch of political nonsense that goes on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well and and the other thing is such for it to to truly be help
 		
 		
 	