
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well mine is very very simple i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>  i wear white or i wear scrubs  so i guess you'll have to carry this one
 	
 	
 		
  
 		uh-huh you're all set then
 		
  
 		oh geez i i'm a teacher
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and uh basically what we do is we dress for the weather especially the climates inside the school
 	
 	
 		isn't it different it is different isn't it inside than
 	
 	
 		not so much they climates out
 		
  
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> says that too that it's freezing when they turn on the air conditioning and it's so hot when they turn on the heat
 	
 	
 		
  
 		it is it's unbelievable usually we layer our clothing
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um that way we have you know we can strip off layers
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and not so much our pants but you wear a sweater and a short sleeve shirt underneath that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then you can take the sweater off
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or something that's medium weight
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and especially up here we get the you know we get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> and it's really cold and sometimes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> it's really cold too
 	
 	
 		right
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so sometimes you just leave your jackets on all the time
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		gosh
 	
 	
 		you know so
 	
 	
 		yeah it's probably pays pays for you to leave something there do you do you do that
 	
 	
 		
  
 		um not that often because a lot of things get stolen
 	
 	
 		
  
 		really
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		so  it's  mostly what you wear into work you know wear a short sleeve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> or a short sleeve blouse
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and a sweater if you're wearing slacks and if you're wearing a over the dress you wear a sweater you know a cardigan or something over the dress
 		and um you know bring your jacket you can just carry it around with you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you can wear socks to work there
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yes we can and
 	
 	
 		yeah our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> can't do that yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we have a really big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> so it's you know it gets very uncomfortable on hills
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		most the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> have taking to wearing uh track shoes
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		oh  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> have too that's interesting a lot of them are wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>'s now because most of them the prefer the pants to the dresses
 	
 	
 		you know sneakers and
 		
  
 		
  
 		
  
 		
  
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and with the scrubs too you know which is just you know scrubs are like what they wear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">O R</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		they just wear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>'s it's really comfortable i haven't done it yet
 	
 	
 		
  
 		no
 	
 	
 		but it's probably coming because we're all going into scrubs right now it depends on the area where you work
 	
 	
 		they're great
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		but soon the whole area is going into scrubs and so um-hum
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh really
 		
  
 	
 	
 		so probably i'll go ahead and break down and
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you know i guess i guess from the school  this is just not professional you know  so i'm kind of a hold out
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		
  
 		oh that happens a lot i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> she just retired was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> up here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and she always wore a cap and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh yeah she was like a real hold out
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		and then finally she took that off and that was like big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concession</ENAMEX> on her part
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and then she went to her hospital you know her uniform
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and she always wore her you know uniform shoes never wore sneakers
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		she absolutely refused
 	
 	
 		yeah and i still do that and they're very expensive they are comfortable though i i don't know i
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah that's what she was saying
 		
  
 		one thing i've noticed that's come back here are clogs
 	
 	
 		
  
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah they started to make a come back you see them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> more and more and  i didn't think i'd ever see those again
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh i know it well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> they have these oh gosh i can't think of the name of them
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		they have a name they come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and they're cork
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> straps on top like a sandal and they form to fit your feet
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		they're soft and after you wear them a day then they only fit your feet
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh that sounds great
 	
 	
 		and they're wearing those and i've seen a little bit of it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> here now
 	
 	
 		
  
 		really
 	
 	
 		but i don't know being up there if you'll see too much  they wouldn't be very practical except in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um yeah that's the new thing and it's sort of on that style you know except that it's open like a sandal
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right a lot of us during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> would wear boots and then peel them off and carry our shoes
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 		you know or just wear the shoes in and hope for the best
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		
  
 		hum things have plowed pretty well
 	
 	
 		i'm not used to that anymore i came down here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yes i remember boots and things like that but not anymore
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		
  
 		uh-huh yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> just came up from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and they had to get rid of all their a lot of their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer summer</TIMEX> clothes
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they say my gosh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX> it's eighty and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next minute</TIMEX> it's you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> and they're freezing  and they said oh what and they say wait a minute we had a mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		really really
 		
  
 		oh oh wait till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well hopefully we seem to be running on mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> lately
 	
 	
 		
  
 		they weather's changing all over the country
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah we're getting a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> than we are snow
 	
 	
 		
  
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and uh that makes it difficult on as far as clothing goes because you don't know what to put on your feet
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think anyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> owns
 		
 		
 	