
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> uh i believe in capital punishment i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and we have that in in effect down here and uh i guess i'm kind of the old school you know an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you have um has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> always had capital punishment or they ever had a period where they outlawed it
 	
 	
 		uh no sir not to my knowledge uh they've always had it
 	
 	
 		i see right from day one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'd have to confess to you that uh i don't know what the i honestly don't know what the law in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> is i think
 		we have
 		i think we have a capital murder law uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that's probably the only crime for which you know capital punishment is meted out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my own i guess my own personal feelings are  i tend to take a look at the social cost benefit ratio which sounds kind of callous but uh
 		it's basically you know it what what is the net the net benefit to society if you execute someone for a particular crime versus say if you lock them up for the rest of their lives or something of that sort
 		and in many cases i decide in favor of capital punishment in fact i think in most cases
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and there probably be a few instances in which i would think that maybe it wasn't warranted
 	
 	
 		well well uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> is capital punishment is that like death death yeah right uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's that's death right
 		and uh let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> uses death by lethal injection now right
 	
 	
 		well uh the death by the electric chair uh and uh let's see the last time that i was uh privy to it death by electric chair
 	
 	
 		oh i see okay i see
 	
 	
 		um-hum you see one of our problems is down here since we were one of the later states to join
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that uh murder was rampant i mean uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieving</ENAMEX> and was rampant down here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> and i bet you can go to any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> within the state and find a hanging tree
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know you stole somebody's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> or uh stole their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> that was a capital offense and you got hanged from the nearest limb if uh you know you were caught
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's got goes back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> now i don't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> uh golly or what they did in the old days
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s a pretty complicated state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it's uh
 		well because of its colonial you know background and then of course during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX> or during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior</TIMEX> and during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX> it was a border state you know with half the state northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern</ENAMEX> and half the state southern you know in sentiment and so forth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i suspect that like most most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> uh you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nineteenth century</TIMEX> and so forth that they certainly had capital punishment
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		uh it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaker</ENAMEX> state or something of that sort you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		and i as i said i think we we have a a capital murder law on the books right now i guess my feeling you know i can set up some hypothetical cases where uh
 		well suppose there was something uh you know a famous uh medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> who murdered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know now this you know the question is well what are the prospects of this medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> making medical break throughs that might benefit human beings in the future never mind that he murdered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that what you meant while ago uh when you said you know about about uh putting them in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> actually what you meant what kind of contribution can they make if you don't murder them
 	
 	
 		right you know and i i i think i'd have to sit down and say well what kind of contribution would they make and also what what
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 		um-hum right
 	
 	
 		do you i think another element in it in it is what kind of society do you what what message are you trying to send to society i mean like the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm actually in favor of things like uh if you're going to execute somebody you uh i don't see any reason why they shouldn't televise it you know or what have you it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it uh uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ought to be aware of what it is that you know what it is that they're doing and uh you know what what the sentence really means
 		when you uh you know if you sentence somebody to death this is what it really means just like they show you what <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> are supposedly like
 		um they pardon
 	
 	
 		what
 		well you you know you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> view
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> view is to forgive you know and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and maybe try to rehabilitation rehabilitate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course when you do that you know then your costs go up on that measure and those who have lost someone uh you know feel like that that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s escaped justice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so you know i can see that point too i'm just kind of the old line that uh i believe if you go out and kill your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> you know you can look to lose your own life
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure uh
 	
 	
 		and and it's true that uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh you know uh go out and and commit a murder and they could really uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	