
 
     		
 	
 		okay um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess if i had to rate it from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i guess i would rate it a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> in the aspect that i wouldn't want everybody to have guns
 		and i think there should be limitations of like semiautomatics uh things like that should not be just given out to anybody In fact you know i can't imagine anybody having a semiautomatic for what purpose
 		um
 		so i guess you know being that i come from a hunting family i'd rather have some restrictions put on weapons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yet allow hunting rifles uh things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would use for sporting type of uh uh activity those would be fine but when you get into um
 		a lot of the more complex weapons i would say yes we need to put restrictions on them
 	
 	
 		um that's probably i probably would have to agree with you pretty much all the way i think um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i definitely think that there some things shouldn't be limited like like you said <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX> hunting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> and probably handguns for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who use them to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly for for self protection sure
 	
 	
 		right and but i think the i think  semiautomatic weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say they use them because it for sport but i i
 		personally cannot see any use for them other than uh for for for only like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who just like have some sort of crazed
 	
 	
 		i can't imagine that yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know ambition to use have high powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		to do massive amounts of killing uh yeah
 	
 	
 		right and i mean you can only how much do you want
 	
 	
 		the only thing i can see is the police having it in a case where somebody is uh
 		uh you know going to kill a massive amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or uh somebody that's escaping that's uh very dangerous
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">semiautomatic</ENAMEX> would allow more rounds to be put out to hopefully catch a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and and uh get him down but um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i i think of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> uh they're very much into sporting and uh you know as far as hunting and also like uh clay pigeons
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		things like that so they have may have some shotguns they may have other types of uh hunting type things but i figured if the if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> had to take a hunting gun
 		out to kill somebody more than likely somebody would see it you know what i'm saying versus a
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		you know a small handgun um that can be you know put right in your coat pocket and nobody would see it but yet you can't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from having you know a handgun in their home
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		right
 	
 	
 		even if there are small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> around there's you know you can't say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that may have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> you know still have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		um i guess i i was always taught number one a gun isn't a toy
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um you know and i don't know if that makes a difference if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> sits down to them and say this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> can kill you know and don't ever play with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		um so i don't know if that makes a difference or what but
 	
 	
 		well i think partly uh in that case i think that cases like that it's definitely um i think
 		if you're to say okay we have to get rid of them all because you know they can only they only seem to do bad it it's um it's saying we're too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> would get them i mean even if they had to go across borders to get them
 	
 	
 		right right and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have them and are responsible with them are are are being punished and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you cannot take care of things yourself or like that you're not smart enough to teach your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> how to how to uh
 	
 	
 		how to use you know to make sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are put up as something as uh not a toy yeah because we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> all over our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> when we were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and not that they were laying on the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> or anything like that but um
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i never had an interest in them being in the fact that i knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> could kill and i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and never messed with any type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so it was kind of the idea that we knew that a gun could kill and that a gun wasn't a toy
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and of course we were quite young and we went through uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle uh Club</ENAMEX> and so we were taught
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know kind of at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good age ten</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and twelve to sit down with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and say okay if you gonna learn how to shoot a gun you're going to learn how to do it correctly and you're going to learn how to have safeguards and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and know how to protect yourself but yet have this you know training so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't you know they have to have a certain respect for it
 	
 	
 		right well i think i mean we i grew up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> because he used to hunt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		stopped before really before i was old enough to remember but and i knew we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and the the time my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was keeping them just for protection at the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		but we it was never my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> nor i never i mean none of us ever thought well let's go look at the gun or let's go get the gun out it was just something you knew was there and the it was your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s and you you that was not something you'd go and play played with at all
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think maybe uh and that's the type of the thing that should be you know stressed
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so and and i don't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> nowadays are different than what i i can't explain
 		
 		
 	