
 
     		
 	
 		think about this
 	
 	
 		uh do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in school um i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that are uh now just about ready to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> but i also have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that are just entering school um
 	
 	
 		i do
 		oh
 		so you see a big difference then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">before</TIMEX> and now do you or
 	
 	
 		uh well uh
 		i think they're just pushing them much entirely to fast
 	
 	
 		a lot of testing
 	
 	
 		um well it seems to me that kindergarten is now the equivalent of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven thirty</TIMEX> and doesn't get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three o'clock</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's such a long day for a kindergartner
 	
 	
 		i do too i oh i think that's awful
 	
 	
 		and uh i have a preschooler um i was told by her preschool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that she thought maybe she was to immature for kindergarten and i thought well how mature do you have to be
 	
 	
 		i know really what's the new criteria huh
 	
 	
 		and uh there is a do you have the standardized testing now
 	
 	
 		we have all kinds of testing and it's over and over it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITBS</ENAMEX> or and uh just everything everything and they test test test i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> actually and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you've heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> but it's a very transient community a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from everywhere it's just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's grown in leaps and bounds i we must have maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and fifty thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now and most of them from other places
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh JC Penney</ENAMEX>'s come down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> and we just have lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from everywhere lots of industry coming in and it's a very wealthy community
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh not that i am but other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to be and i would love to know why but i mean they do they have i i would i really would i mean they just have beautiful beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and they have everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah you'd like to know what they're doing right
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> only wear name brand things to school and it's one of these things well it does you know it really does because i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen year old</TIMEX> now and uh you know it does i mean we do it to a point but um
 	
 	
 		oh me well that makes it hard for you doesn't it
 		oh me
 		yeah it's hard to explain to them why you can't
 	
 	
 		not to where she feels different but some of them are very rich and so
 		um we just kind of have everything here and we have a very goal oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so i don't know how much of it is us and how much of it is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are expected to excel in everything
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		and it's almost impossible because you have so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and just so many activities that everybody can't be <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and they're expected to be you know their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> expect it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> expect it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> wants very badly to be considered tops in the school system and if you read national surveys they're far from it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so there's just a whole lot of testing and a whole lot of pushing to do well on these tests and
 	
 	
 		how about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> how are they coping with it
 	
 	
 		well not very well they bring home notes that say they have to get a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s sleep and eat right in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> before tests i mean they make a big deal to me the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> should just be put on the desk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> and say just do this
 	
 	
 		hum
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i just feel they do better that way and yeah and and i have older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too that now are out of high school and
 	
 	
 		yeah rather than anticipating
 	
 	
 		uh they've always done this you know i mean it's always been the same but it is it's getting worse and worse there's more pressure for everything
 		and i just think it's really awful and i i'm with you on that you don't hear too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say this but i think it's a very long day
 	
 	
 		oh it is
 	
 	
 		and my feeling is that you you know you're only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> once and you don't wanna spend your whole life in school
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> said that came home and he said he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> all we do is work we hardly ever play and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and i don't think that's right i think we should do what <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> does and include cultural activities in our school system
 	
 	
 		oh likewise
 	
 	
 		i don't  think i should have to pay for dancing lessons gymnastics piano i would like to see those things included in our school system because i think we should have well rounded kids
 	
 	
 		right
 		wouldn't that be great
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not just smart book smart kids
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so i just find this a real problem i think if they're gonna be there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> they should find time
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> once was out of school with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mono</ENAMEX> in her junior year i think it was
 		and she had a home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> for like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and when she went back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> she was ahead
 	
 	
 		is that right  oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		so what does that tell you the it tells you there's a whole lot of wasted time
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and they could be using this time better
 	
 	
 		well for example in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s kindergarten they're really finished at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch time</TIMEX> after lunch they have some uh
 		i'm trying to think if they have recess after lunch and then they have naps or rest period
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i think either send them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or do something
 	
 	
 		that's a very long day for kindergarten but i think that working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have kind of demanded this
 	
 	
 		a little more interesting i agree
 		i wouldn't be surprised
 	
 	
 		you know because they don't they don't wanna send them to day care
 	
 	
 		i doubt if they would say that it was too long
 	
 	
 		that's why they want them there because then somebody takes care of them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>  so the
 	
 	
 		um do you have the before school care at your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and the after school care
 	
 	
 		we have them at some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> like
 		
 		
 	