
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            Katha,

            Ah, yes, space, the final tedium. Do you remember the Simpsons
episode when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX> was desperate to switch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> because there was a shuttle
launch being broadcast? I'm with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Homer</ENAMEX>. I've never gotten the space thing. I
remember watching the shuttle blowing up live-I absentmindedly had the TV on in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> where I was staying at the time-and feeling it was sad and
a shame, but essentially carrying on as normal. Then I switched on the news and
everyone was having a national identity crisis. Still can't figure it out. I
tried watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> miniseries on the moon landings, but it was
like watching <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> television on the feats of the agrarian revolution. A
horrible mixture of boredom and uplift. But we better get used to it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> words
for you: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.

            Talking of dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, can you bring yourself to say something nice about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda McCartney</ENAMEX>? It seems to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> (my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beatle</ENAMEX>) really is an
admirable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>, and his marriage was of a kind that all the family-mongers
really should celebrate. True love, in all its banalizing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>-wrecking,
middle-brow glory. Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> got a terrible p.r. deal. Could <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> speak up please in her behalf? She made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tammy Wynette</ENAMEX> seem
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">countercultural</ENAMEX>. Or are we reduced once again to the charming Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasich</ENAMEX> to
speak the truth to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>?

            best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
