
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mid-Season Night's Dream</ENAMEX>

            Starting off, there are a couple of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-season</TIMEX> series to address:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> . Don't do it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s new drama has been on for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a mere two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fri.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), and is already proving emotionally manipulative in a way
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> never dreamed.

            Basic premise: In the aftermath of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s death--which, incidentally,
we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sydney Hansen</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melina Kanakaredes</ENAMEX>) returns home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, to care for her sweetly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dysfunctional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and practice real <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> in the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>. In the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> episodes alone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> are subjected to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> deaths, an aborted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wedding</ENAMEX>, an at-home birth, a wake, and the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s discovering her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> in the shower with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Compounding the emotional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploitation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syd</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Farrell</ENAMEX>) is a veterinarian, so every time the
show's tear-jerk quotient threatens to dip below critical mass, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> are
confronted by sick, injured, and dying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX>.

            Content aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> also has a few "artistic" problems. The
show is positively lousy with long, lingering, dreamy shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanakaredes</ENAMEX>'
face. Since she's unquestionably beautiful to behold, a little visual
indulgence can perhaps be forgiven. What cannot be forgiven, however, is her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hideous</ENAMEX>, sing-song voice-over--too perky and heartwarming by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>.

            Even more cutesy and annoying, we are periodically inserted into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syd</ENAMEX>'s dream
life, most of which revolves around her bickering with her dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and
making out with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> she had a crush on in high school who is now a local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>. It's reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX>'s peeks into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' inner
thoughts--but without the special effects or originality.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX> is the premiere of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s new series <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> . Yet
another variation on the ever-popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> drama, the show follows the trials
and tribulations of an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sadly</ENAMEX>, this means
we have to sit through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' tedious personal dramas as well as their
professional ones.)

            The plot lines aren't particularly surprising or clever, but the dialogue is
sharper and wittier than average and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Devane</ENAMEX> (of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Landing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fame</ENAMEX>) is particularly appealing as the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sgt. Joe Turk</ENAMEX>. Those
show's defining feature, however, is its overabundance of male bonding: A
single episode offers multiple sessions of father-son bonding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-brother</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bonding</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop-cop</ENAMEX> bonding, and so on. Thus far, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> around fall into
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories--docile, wait-at-home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and single career-gals looking to
bag one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in blue. (There is nary a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> to be found.) Perhaps
as a sop to female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> includes a fair helping of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> jaws
and cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butts</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, I'm sticking with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frasier</ENAMEX> .

            Moving right along, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s movie scene looks good-- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fugitive</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM) vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Man Walking</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM)--but after
that, the pickings get decidedly slimmer. Thank <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">god for Lonesome Dove</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family</ENAMEX>
McMurtry, this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> miniseries follows the trail of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rangers</ENAMEX>
driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> border up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Lee Jones</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Duvall</ENAMEX> are flat-out brilliant in the lead roles, backed by a strong
supporting cast featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelica Huston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Lane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Glover</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schroder</ENAMEX>.

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Ricky</ENAMEX>, if you're having trouble adjusting to the idea of
Schroder starring as the hot new stud on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Blue</ENAMEX>, you may want to catch a few
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFTV</ENAMEX> movie <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What We Did That Night</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mon</ENAMEX>.). The movie itself is dreadful--a white-washed blend of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape</ENAMEX> Fear
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Know What You Did Last</ENAMEX> 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> , with a truly annoying gotcha
ending. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schroder</ENAMEX>, however, gives a convincing performance as the creepy bad guy
who lures all of his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frat brothers</ENAMEX> back to the scene of their youthful
crime. He can't save the movie, but he definitely livens it up.

            By far the oddest offering of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A&E</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unmentionables</ENAMEX>: A
Brief History (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM). A <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> look at the evolution of underwear,
the special is as silly as it sounds. The history of the myriad painful fads
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have subjected themselves to over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>--iron <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maidens</ENAMEX>, rubber
girdles, breast binding--may help remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> what all that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> bra-burning
was about. For the most part, however, listening to lingerie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> ramble
insipidly about the form, function, and sensuousness of undies makes one
suspect that the special was conceived largely as an excuse to show shot after
shot of scantily clad breast, buns, and crotches.

            It's kind of a thinking<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baywatch</ENAMEX> .

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Cottle</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
