
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Katha</ENAMEX>,

                   Couldn't agree with you more about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. I grew up imbibing the
stuff from my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>-puffing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and can't stand it. But I'm at a loss as to
why it gets so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> steamed at a political level. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> particularly.
You'd think, if you read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich or Doonesbury</ENAMEX> , that the tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> represent the supreme evil in the universe when they're just a bunch
of lying, avaricious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> trying to make money. In my book that's legal
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and ought to be. Tax 'em to, er, death, say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX> But stop preaching
about it and passing virtual bills of attainder against them. And don't try to
persuade me that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> never knew the risks of smoking. She did. My own
theory is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and lefties have to find some outlet for their
authoritarian-moral streak. They've given up on the economy in general, having
lost the argument completely. And they know they shouldn't be sexual puritans.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> is over, so demonizing the military-industrial complex is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passé.</ENAMEX> So they hammer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>. Or rather they hammer the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco execs</ENAMEX>
in order to "save the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." Save me from saving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heartening</ENAMEX> news from the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> (apart from the
popularity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> ) is that they're smoking in ever greater
numbers. Take that, you do-gooding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> paternalists!
       Oh, did you see in the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
                that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> is finally helping out with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fathers</ENAMEX> are apparently spending more time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and on
household chores than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation ago</TIMEX>, according to a self-reported survey. Is
this a function of feminist lawmaking or the free market and empowered,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">money-making women</ENAMEX>? Just wondering ...
       More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul-porn</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> business section. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yawn</ENAMEX>. But a jolly
piece on how Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scaife</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> 's
investigative journalism into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Can you imagine what we could have done
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> ? The thing about the
right-wing conspiracy is that, like most conspiracies, it's both paranoid and
incompetent. In some ways, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been lucky to have it around, I
think.

            best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
