
   
   
      
         
            Busy, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Busy, Busy</ENAMEX>!

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> featured the following curiosity:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> to describe their vacation reading, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Virgin chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Branson</ENAMEX>, wasn't reading anything because he was "making
changes to my upcoming autobiography, 'Losing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Virginity</ENAMEX>.'" A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> correspondent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley Stahl</ENAMEX>, was "reading my own words again and
again" on "a book I am writing"--which the fall books issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> reveals to be a memoir called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reporting Live</ENAMEX> , due out in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, said he was reading <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Oxford Book of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irish Short Stories</ENAMEX> , but was either lying or had just skimmed the book
while procrastinating, since elsewhere he has said that his autobiography is
due in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon</ENAMEX>
Lederman, wasn't reading because he was composing a sequel to his book on
particle physics, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The God Particle</ENAMEX> , which he said was known around his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Trapped on Chapter Six</ENAMEX> . A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> piano <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Huang</ENAMEX>, may not even have been asked the question, but in any case did not
offer the name of a book. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>, only the basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> in the bunch,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piston Grant Hill</ENAMEX>, appears to have been seriously reading anything
other than his own prose. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> printed matter was a celebrity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">autobiography</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Reeve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Still Me</ENAMEX> .

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> of keyboard tappers so dedicated only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> have time to
lift their heads and read everyone else's prose! How sane, how fully
self-actualized! It is a commonplace of literary history that the emergence of
autobiography in the West reflects the development of the mature, individuated,
self-aware self. To quote the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilhelm Dilthey</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autobiography</ENAMEX> is the highest and most instructive form in which the
understanding of life comes before us." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dilthey</ENAMEX> hadn't read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, but
that's a small point. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PW</ENAMEX> lists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> autobiographies to be published this
fall, among them the lives and stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Von Furstenberg</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geraldine Ferraro, Barney</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">window-dresser Simon Doonan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Morrow Lindbergh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, and, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>.

            Of course, the autobiographies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> are outnumbered by those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you've never heard of. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This fall</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fawcett Ballantine</ENAMEX> will publish the
memoirs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Eckstein</ENAMEX>, a pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">therapist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX> will publish an account by
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Writers' Workshop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> of her affair with "a
drug-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-addicted construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX> will publish
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Apples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oranges: A Woman's Journey to Sexual Identity</ENAMEX> , "from a
lesbian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> who falls in love with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Regan</ENAMEX>'s imprint will publish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puppy Chow</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Than Prozac</ENAMEX> , "a tale of recovery from depression
with the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> would of course have more to say on this subject, but you'll have
to excuse her ... she's caught up in a project of her own right now. ..

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
