
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuzzy Logic</ENAMEX>

            It is said that publishing is not a business but an art. Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
are famous for knowing their box-office grosses, dollar for dollar, the day
after the movie opens. Not book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. "I'll call an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and ask how a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s book is selling, and he'll say 'Oh, gee, I don't know! Let me check
with inventory," an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> told me recently. "But of course, all inventory can
tell you--when inventory finally gets back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days later</TIMEX>--is
how many books have been ordered, not how many have been sold." Not until much
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>), after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> have returned all their
unsold copies, can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers compile firm</ENAMEX> sales figures. And even then, the
numbers are not particularly helpful. Did a book sell better in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Topeka</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> or in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>?

            There are ways to answer those questions, but the book industry doesn't seem
all that interested in the answers. Bookscan, for instance, is a system made
and marketed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soundscan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that brings you the music industry's
greatest-hits charts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundscan</ENAMEX> gets its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX> from a scanning device
installed at checkout <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 85 percent</NUMEX> of all music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookscan</ENAMEX> is trying to put a similar gizmo into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>. So far, it
hasn't caught on. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soundscan</ENAMEX>, which swept swiftly through the music
business after it was introduced, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookscan</ENAMEX> was unveiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, it was
dismissed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Association of Publishers</ENAMEX>, whose official line on it
was that it was too expensive. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX> would have to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookscan</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>.)

            Was that the real reason it was rejected? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX> could have come
back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookscan</ENAMEX> and said, we like your product but want you to bring your
price down. You'd think they'd be eager to learn whether local or national
advertising works better, or whether book tours do anything other than stroke
authorial egos. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> doesn't know how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookscan</ENAMEX> was charging, but
wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> really factored in the savings they'd accrue from
better-targeted marketing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> asked around and came up with a few other theories of why
publishing is one of the last industries to seek the comfort of hard
numbers:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX> don't want to know exactly how well their books are selling. It
might force them to stop buying the kinds of books they love publishing--the
serious books with limited sales. A corollary to this theory is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>
don't want the world to see how small the unit sales are for even world-famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authors</ENAMEX> (they usually linger under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX>)--it might make the whole industry
seem a lot less glamorous.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Hard sales data might eliminate a cash hoard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> have secured for
themselves. It turns out that most contracts between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> to withhold as much of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of royalties against
possible returns during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> of publication (and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as much as 60</NUMEX>
percent for paperbacks). Precise point-of-sale data would obviate that clause,
and force <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> to fork over all royalties right away.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> have been quietly going into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of compiling
book sales data themselves--an obvious thing to do, given their dominance of
the retail market--and don't want to give up what amounts to a competitive
advantage. This may explain why, so far, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookscan</ENAMEX> has not cut deals with any of
the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> (though they are talking to them). Also, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> are
getting the numbers for free from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, why pay for them?

            Whatever the reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> are making it clear that what they want more
than anything is to keep their sales figures secret. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that one change it had made to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookscan</ENAMEX> in response to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX>' concerns was to turn it into a "closed system." In other words, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> will not be published and no one but the publisher of a book will be able
to learn its hard sales figures. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundscan</ENAMEX>, by contrast, is an "open system.")
Expect industrywide numbers to remain fuzzy in the foreseeable future.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
