
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>? Them were the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Old Days</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>,

            Well, I'm glad you think me your equal in slyness. But do I read you
correctly to say that you long for the mores of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1910</TIMEX>, before the
progressive income tax turned us red-blooded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> into collectivist <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
at the mercy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big State</ENAMEX>? You really ARE reactionary! I keep forgetting
that.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was pretty big in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>. For instance, it outlawed
information about birth control and many other forms of free speech; it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enforced Jim Crow</ENAMEX> laws in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>; it denied women the right to vote and
barred them from many occupations and activities. It used its police power on
behalf of mining and industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> to break strikes, beat up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX>, and deport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> with the wrong ideas. What conservatives
usually mean when they talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Government</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that puts some
kind of limit on the power of business to do whatever it wants. For all your
opposition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big State</ENAMEX>, for instance, don't you oppose legal abortion?
Even though effectively criminalizing abortion would mean an immense expansion
of police power.

            What really amazes me in your posts is your reluctance to admit that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
has, or ever had, any problems or injustices or wrongs that the left addressed
and the right did not. You treat the left's record on everything from race to
worker safety, for example, as a public-relations triumph. But it was real!
(And of course I don't accept the left's responsibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> wars in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> either.) As for taxes--I would gladly give half my income to live
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> without desperate poverty and homelessness, with good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and
health care and child care for all who need it, with real environmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX> and good public services, and in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who work for a living
earn enough to live decently, as in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> too many full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> do
not. If that meant I had less disposable income it would be worth it!

            Equally unrepentant,
Katha

         
      
   
