
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: If not discrimination, what?
            

            Katha,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honestly</ENAMEX>, I don't think that lower test-scores among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> from some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> is a consequence of institutional racism at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. Do you? At
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>? And I don't think that race-blind admissions policies is racism
either. So, frankly, I don't see the alleged problem of racial discrimination
that we need to remedy. The only discrimination I think we need to address is
the recent attempt by many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> to deny many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> admission purely
because of their race. Now there's discrimination. But it's directed primarily
against hard-working, newly immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>.

            The solution to lower test-scores among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX> is better public
high school education, and more engaged and dedicated parenting. Period. Like
you, I would like to see much more money spent on public education, as long as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> don't throw it down the toilet. And I think we should do
all we can not to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> breakdown among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. But even then, I
doubt whether we would have a perfectly balanced racial mix at our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. And frankly, I don't see why we should care. Why should we be
concerned what race someone belongs to at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, as long as there isn't any
systematic system to prefer some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> over others, and as long as half-way
decent public high school education is also widely available? This racial
obsession is a legacy of past evils, and decreasingly relevant to the polyglot,
multi-racial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> we're about to enter. So I hope <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX> is
repeated across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. And I hope we make a better effort to educate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. And I hope the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> recovers. And
I hope we stop the futile attempt to make amends for past injustice by wreaking
new ones on innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            As to an all-male priesthood, I do think it's an unconscionable and
irrational form of institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sexism</ENAMEX>, and I oppose it on the same grounds
that I oppose reverse discrimination. And if we attempted to remedy it by
instituting an all-female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priesthood</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two millennia</TIMEX>, I'd be equally
opposed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> wrongs don't make a right.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cheers,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
