
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> steps in the web
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Katha</ENAMEX>,
Glad you're back. I missed my morning bouts of dyspepsia.

            I was fascinated by the story in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> of the Internet
support-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> murder confession. The combination of the web and twelve-step
meetings horrifies and intrigues me. Each forum appeals, I think, because it
creates a space where you're free to be completely frank and anonymous, while
still actually being yourself. And, thanks to this peculiar brand of invisible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visibility</ENAMEX>, we're led to believe that both are spaces free of traditional moral
consequences.

            So in AA, you only have a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name, just as on the web you only have a
screen name. And no-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> checks whether it's your real one. And in AA, you can
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confess</ENAMEX> to anything, and all that fundamentally matters is whether you have
lapsed from your obligation to sobriety, not what the consequences to others
were. And on the web, you can live out any sort of fantasy, in real time, with
limited accountability. On the web, you give up all your responsibility to the
invisible hand of the net (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>). In AA, you hand over all your problems to a
non-denominational omnipotent God. Put the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> together, and it's no wonder
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think they can confess to child-murder and still get away with it.

            But are these responsibility-free no-holds-barred forums new, in any way, I
wonder? Or are they simply updates of the confessional and the shrink, the cult
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freemasons</ENAMEX>? Is our confession-prone no-responsibility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> part of
the trend?

            And have you read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conversations With God</ENAMEX> ?

            best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
