
   
   
      
         
            Clearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s Crumbs
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>,

            You have a sly way of encoding your political slant in statements you then
present as our shared views. Very clever! Thus, just to clear this morning's
table of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s old toast crumbs, I don't share your view of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, as you breezily conclude, if by that you mean your view that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> is close to evil, uniquely immoral and irresponsible, worse than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>--whose hostility to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and gelid indifference to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, I note,
don't seem to bother you as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
fine-words-that-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>-parsnips. I also protest "reverse racial
discrimination" as a way to characterize affirmative action, which (as I guess
you know) I support. So, really, we don't have the same view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: we both dislike him, but for different reasons.

            I also don't want to leave our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May Day</TIMEX> thread without challenging your
equation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>. Yes, in some ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> was as murderous as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>; certainly, to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anarchist</ENAMEX>, and many ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> caught in
their regimes, they were equally bad news. As my ultra-leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>
says, when we speak of fascism, we must not forget to include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX> fascism. But
when you wonder why in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, a demonstration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX> is regarded
more indulgently--or, as I would say, with less alarm--than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of fascists
would be, I think you are forgetting the very different domestic roles of these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX>.

            In this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Communists</ENAMEX> includes some good
things: opposition to segregation and racism, for example, going way back to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 30s</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Left</ENAMEX> was very important in the civil-rights movement, which
now even the far right concedes was a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Thing</ENAMEX>, but which at the time it
bitterly opposed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Left</ENAMEX> stood for things that benefited lots of people
and that lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were quite anti-communist also supported--the New
Deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, the safety net, civil liberties, even (just a little) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
rights. Note: I'm not saying all these things were without their complications
or downsides, or that there wasn't an element of self-interest or calculation
involved (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CP</ENAMEX>'s advocacy of free speech, for example, which didn't extend
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotskyists</ENAMEX>, whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CP</ENAMEX> was glad to see investigated by the govt. in the
late 40s I think it was). I'm just saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Left</ENAMEX> was active in a lot
of very mainstream social causes, often on what everyone now agrees was the
right side.

            But I can't think, off hand, of any great contributions to our polity made
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, the German Bund, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX> or
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>. Can you?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Katha

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ps</ENAMEX>. Just got your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> post. More soon.

         
      
   
