
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Katha</ENAMEX>,

                   Yes, my morning ablutions are complete, and I know it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>. I've
just caffeinated, taken <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> viracepts, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> combivir, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> rescriptors, one
zantac, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> immodium, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> zoloft, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> propecia. Who needs oatmeal? But the
good news is: I'm alive and my hair is growing back.
       In fact, I was so zippy I missed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Moskos</ENAMEX>' letter. Whenever I've
dealt with him he has seemed an extremely reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> (he wrote a good
piece for me at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> on race in the ranks) but, like many military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>,
he just seems to lose it when it comes to the obvious fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>
have been happily murdering and killing in uniform for generations. At least he
didn't push the off-the-record spin that these nellies just can't hack it,
which is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flunkies</ENAMEX> were whispering to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible journalists</ENAMEX>. He
also misses a very basic point: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">563</NUMEX> violations were by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX>, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. It's rather like holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">turkeys</ENAMEX> responsible for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>. As to
the notion that gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> disproportionately leave early, this only applies
to new discharges. How does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moskos</ENAMEX> explain the enormous increase? Could it
possibly be that bigoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX>, who hate the idea that they might have to
tolerate discreet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> in the ranks, now try to flush them out early and
fast by massive amounts of intimidation? In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first sergeant</ENAMEX> is
reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Servicemembers Legal Defense Network</ENAMEX> to greet new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> members
with the declaration "There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things I hate: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">faggots</ENAMEX>." Nice to meet you, too.
       A final thought. It's interesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moskos</ENAMEX> is aware, as someone in
his position would never have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation ago</TIMEX>, that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do "come
out" at an earlier and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> age. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> has changed enormously. So all the
policy is doing, it seems, if he is correct, is successfully flushing out a
whole swath of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have the self-respect not to be ashamed
of being gay. Should the military be happy it's getting rid of all these people
and becoming less, rather than more, like the society it's supposed to defend?
And is the presence of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--who are often disproportionately committed
to their jobs--such a threat to the effectiveness of the military as a whole?
Or are we better off with a bunch of conflicted, repressed neurotics?
       As to welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, I share your abhorrence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who demeaned
motherhood, although I am probably uniquely unqualified to talk about its
onerous responsibilities. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, though, and she
works harder than I ever have in my life. Or ever will. But the apposite
question, it seems to me, is not simply whether day care is adequate (it almost
certainly isn't) but whether, as a whole, it is better that, whatever the
current problems, the old system has been shaken up and reformed in the
direction of work. Of course, welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX> being what they are, a lack
of support in health care and day care is hardly surprising. But the answer to
that is to fix the health care and day care with some of the large amounts of
money being sent back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> rather than to return to what happened
before. Or am I wrong? Is your position that welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> were better off in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dependency</ENAMEX> and close to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> rather than in work and distant (for some of
the time) from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>? I'd be crazy to believe the new system is perfect or
without its injustices. But isn't it an improvement on what went on before? And
isn't it at least a more constructive place from which to improve policy than
old-style entitlement?
       My nomination for the most boring story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>: bank mergers. And
anything to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ovitz</ENAMEX>. Who really gives a damn about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moguls</ENAMEX>?
And doesn't The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> fellate them enough for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> to
stop covering them? I loved the story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Bates</ENAMEX>, though. What a babe. I
thought the Primary Colors movie was unconvincingly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>--can anyone
believe for a moment that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> was ever deeply, morally
conflicted about anything?--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bates</ENAMEX> was great. Along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Michael</ENAMEX>,
she's my newly discovered icon.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
