
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cry Me A River</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen DeGeneres</ENAMEX> was quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times saying that she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Heche</ENAMEX>, had fired
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and publicists and were leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>--they were sick of the
homophobia they'd experienced since coming out as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
"Everything that I ever feared happened to me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeGeneres</ENAMEX> said. "I lost my
show. I've been attacked like hell. I went from making a lot of money on a
sitcom to making no money."

            What's the problem here? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heche</ENAMEX> got better reviews than the heterosexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>'s hapless comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Days, Seven Nights</ENAMEX> ,
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> she reprises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Leigh</ENAMEX>'s role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Psycho</ENAMEX> as the most
notorious murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in film history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeGeneres</ENAMEX> has two movies coming out
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Howard</ENAMEX> comedy) and is set to do a standup tour <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">winter</ENAMEX>.

            I do feel sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>. To come out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> and begin a new
relationship under such intense public scrutiny is unimaginable. I'm happy that
my own period of playing the gay megaphone, which took place on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> at age
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>, wasn't staged for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Sawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. And you have
to admit that the professional pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeGeneres</ENAMEX> was fierce, even if her
dilemma was notable mostly for its irony: Could an sitcom get decent ratings
if an out lesbian was played by out lesbian?
            

            But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeGeneres</ENAMEX> feels that her subtleties as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> are being
overshadowed by her status as a lesbian, she's the one who set it up that way.
She used her sexuality as a crutch throughout the long feud with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> that
dominated the troubled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX> of her show. She should have copped to the
fact that after a single luminous, thought-provoking, and joyful coming-out
episode in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> got lost in awkwardly orchestrated,
unfunny plot developments about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> girlfriends. Instead, she
called her network a bunch of homophobes.

            I used to think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeGeneres</ENAMEX> was funny, and I loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Heche</ENAMEX> in the little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indie</ENAMEX> film Walking and Talking back when she was just an alumna of the
soap opera Another 
               World . Now I think of them as entitlement
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">queens</ENAMEX> who whine while their careers steam ahead. Watching them make out in
front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was hard to take, but I'm sure he didn't mind.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watching Ellen</ENAMEX> screech, "They're killing us!" upon the death of gay student
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX> turned my stomach. Faced with an actual tragedy, the least she
could have done is realize how fortunate she was.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeGeneres</ENAMEX> made her announcement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> ran an
interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX>, who claimed that their comments were
taken out of context. (What context would that be?) He added they should
have been taken as "wistful," rather than literal. As for whether the two
actresses are really dropping out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> writes, "They don't have
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, still have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heche</ENAMEX> was last seen
driving through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burbank</ENAMEX>." Whatever they wind up doing, I'm adopting a "don't
ask/don't tell" policy about it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Aurthur</ENAMEX> 
            

         
      
   
