
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            Katha,
I'm duly impressed by the veritable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peoria</ENAMEX> that tippy-taps on the word
processors at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> . And thanks for giving me Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. Of
all the places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> I'd be happy to inherit, I could hardly do
better. Which brings me to the nice irony about family values. It's amazing how
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kind</ENAMEX> (married for life, totally faithful,
lotso <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>) personally eschew them in real life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marianne</ENAMEX> have no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>; neither does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, married thrice and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whipped cream</ENAMEX> on waitresses; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, ditched his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podhoretz</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX> of gay monogamy, quitting his first marriage after a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>... well... I'm not saying these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX>; or even
in the slightest bit immoral. We're all human. But perhaps their devotion to
the cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX> is related to their awareness of their own frailty. I
know, to some extent, my own support for (and admiration of) gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fidelity</ENAMEX>, marriage etc. is probably, at some deep level of my subconscious,
related to the fact that I have never been able to keep a steady <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>. I
need help!

            Couldn't it also be true that all the tweedy monogamists of the old left are
so naturally virtuous that they can't conceive how others might need social
incentives to maintain similar virtues? How many of us, after all, can aspire
to the lofty moral heights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Navasky</ENAMEX> without some social incentives to
help us get there?

            As to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula</ENAMEX>, when I wrote the editorials at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> , we were early
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of her right to a say in court and leery of those who dismissed her
veracity. I'm glad (and not surprised) you have taken the position you have,
and, like you, am unsure about her legal position. Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> is still
an absolute scandal, no? Have you taken them on, yet? Or does
no-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-left still apply?

            And re: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>, yes, I am a bit of a softy. And yes, it is possible,
I think, to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> and still be thoroughly middle class. Look at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Royal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            my love to lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
