
   
   
      
         
            If Not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affirmative Action</ENAMEX>, What?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Andrew</ENAMEX>,

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> you referred to affirmative action as "reverse racial
discrimination," which in my view characterizes it most inaccurately. Then,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, you joshed about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> all-male priesthood as the ultimate
affirmative action program (as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, had been the victim of
discrimination for which the monopoly on ordination was a recompense!). Rather
than rant and rave (I'm saving that for my column, due <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>) I'd like
to know what your plan is for remedying racial discrimination in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
In particular, I'm thinking of the story out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, where affirmative
action has been banned, and where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only around 191</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8000</TIMEX>-plus
admittees, have been offered a place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, a huge drop (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hispanic</ENAMEX> number was also small). In an interesting letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rene Redwood</ENAMEX> noted
that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> of the rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>...had grade
point averages of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 1200</TIMEX>. How can that be?
Because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> can get a higher grade point average if he or she is
fortunate enough to go to a high school that offers a full range of advanced
placement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, which poor urban school districts are less likely to do.

            "We are not talking about differences of ability here. We are talking about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> having had unequal opportunities to demonstrate that ability. Asking
that disparate opportunity be taken into account is not a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'preference</NUMEX>.'"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redwood</ENAMEX> argues that "affirmative action is one tool for breaking the chain
of unfairness." How do you propose to break that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>? If a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> can't
get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">extra</NUMEX> points because their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> doesn't offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">extra</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, why is it
"discrimination" to take that into account?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Katha

         
      
   
