
   
   
      
         
            Culture: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's in the Blood</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly L</ENAMEX>'Express had a cover story entitled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cinema: How To Fight Back Against America</ENAMEX>." Meanwhile, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> (including ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurent Fabius</ENAMEX>) went on trial for
letting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> get transfused with AIDS-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>.
These aren't unrelated stories.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has the highest number of transfusion-borne <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> cases in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is negligence. Well after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> discovery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> virus--by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, incidentally--but before screening was possible, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
continued to harvest much of its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> supply from prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>.
Transfusions are also given more routinely in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> than elsewhere--to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
post-delivery, for instance.

            But here's the big reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fabius</ENAMEX> is on trial: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> in the spring
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> failed to implement screening techniques readily
available from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbott Laboratories</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. At that time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Pasteur Institute</ENAMEX> were browbeating every politico within
lobbying range to wait for the development of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> procedure, which
they promised was only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> away. Long <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, if you were a hemophiliac.

            So why did the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fabius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> agree to hold off? Part of the blame lies
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> cultural politics--particularly the cultural nationalism of the
first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitterrand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Lang</ENAMEX> got
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitterrand</ENAMEX> to double his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>'s budget. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> things really bugged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lang</ENAMEX>. The
first, famously, was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early days</TIMEX> in office were marked by
embarrassingly thorough diktats aimed at purging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> of Anglicisms
and frothy tirades against the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Deauville festival</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bee</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lang</ENAMEX>'s bonnet was the negligible position of culture in
day-to-day life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lang</ENAMEX> was ultimately a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">materialist</ENAMEX> who felt that culture wasn't
"real" unless it was shaping politics and the economy. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>'s motto
was: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">"É</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conomie et</ENAMEX> culture--même
combat ." So he launched what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Fumaroli</ENAMEX>, in his magisterial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L'État Culturel</ENAMEX>, calls "a strategy of
opinion intoxication." He had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rimbaud</ENAMEX> selections printed for distribution to
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>. His most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ozymandian</ENAMEX> efforts in this direction were
gargantuan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodstock</ENAMEX>-style concerts on behalf of the state-sponsored
initiative "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SOS Racism</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Mitterrand</ENAMEX> and associated hangers-
on were always insistent that the concerts created a climate of tolerance.

            All right, then. Should they therefore shoulder responsibility for the
climate of medical/industrial chauvinism that led the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fabius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to let
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> die of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> while awaiting a "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>" way of testing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>?

            In their defense, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has had a fairly consistent cultural policy for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two decades</TIMEX>. The socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lang</ENAMEX> trashed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX> ; the conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Toubon</ENAMEX> decreed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of songs on the radio must be French
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chansons</ENAMEX> . I'm sympathetic to worries about being swamped by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
culture, armed as it is with theater <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX>, language advantages, and
economies of scale. It's good that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> remain a non-Anglo-Saxon exception
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">culturelle</ENAMEX> --and a certain price, within reason, is worth paying for it.

            But I'm afraid the answer is: Yes.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Caldwell</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
