
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ob Jay Dar</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">hour-long Antiques Road Show</ENAMEX> airs on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>.
It is an inspired solution to the problems that beset publicly funded arts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humanities</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>. Back then, public broadcasting and the national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endowments for the Arts and Humanities</ENAMEX> were (rightly) taken to task as
mechanisms for transferring money from working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to a handful of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite subversives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> reforms were needed
if these cultural programs were to survive: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) they had to transfer more
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dough</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Podunk</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) they had to become more prole-friendly.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road Show</ENAMEX> , produced for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WGBH</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, kills
these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> with one marvelous stone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Jussel</ENAMEX> leads a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to a different antique show in a different
far-flung city <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>. These are the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in dresses and ties you'll
see. All they do is appraise antiques. Down-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-heel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> bring various
heirlooms from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attics</ENAMEX> and cellars in hopes they'll turn out to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ob Jay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dar</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night last</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Edgecroft Hall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, we started with
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who brought a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> bracelets, which turned out to have been
given by an army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> during the siege of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Sumter</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX>!
Then a jade necklace someone's great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> had brought back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX>!
A pear-shaped <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> caddy from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the eighteenth century</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX>! There was an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteenth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> sundial (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000-12,000</NUMEX>), a pocketbook owned by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000-6,000</NUMEX>), a ball used in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Larsen</ENAMEX>'s perfect
game in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1956 World Series</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,000</NUMEX>). And that's nothing! The all-time
highlight came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so ago</TIMEX>, when some old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> found out her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>-dollar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> table was actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour</ENAMEX> card table. It sold for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$490,000</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX>.

            What's really showcased is the reciprocal exploitation at the heart of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiques</ENAMEX> trade. Urbanites rob the patrimony of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rustics</ENAMEX> who know
Chippendale only as the name of a strip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>; hayseeds bleed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwellers</ENAMEX> over
a piece of furniture they'd otherwise use as firewood. There's a reciprocal
malarkey as well: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> pretend to know offhand the history of the
object. (Which they've obviously rehearsed, since it includes such arcana as
the provenance of the ochre used in the enamel-painting for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lepine</ENAMEX> watches in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1840s</TIMEX>.)

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> pretend to care.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Caldwell</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
