
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Idiot Box</ENAMEX>

            
               Please note: All times are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Standard</ENAMEX>.
Please check local listings for times in your area.
            

            All together now, from the top . . . In the week
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> my true love gave to me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> college bowls, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 hours</TIMEX> of wrestling,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> games, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7</TIMEX> figure skaters, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> college hoops match ups, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hockey</ENAMEX> goalies, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> rounds of pro golf, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABL</ENAMEX> games, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lumberjack</ENAMEX> finals.

            OK. There are, in fact, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">bowl games</ENAMEX> in the coming
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, and pro wrestling is more "sports entertainment" than actual sport.
Nonetheless, these are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">heady days</TIMEX> for sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gridiron junkies</ENAMEX> in
particular can kick back in the Barcalounger at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:00</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Years morn</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cotton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Outback Bowl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>) and vanish into a festival of testosterone until
the final gun sounds on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sugar Bowl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30</TIMEX>) some time around
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">midnight</ENAMEX>.

            Sadly, for non-sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday season</TIMEX>
continues its grim run. The series repeats continue apace, and the movie
selections aren't much more appealing than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s offerings. Exhibits A
and B: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Willy 2</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:00</TIMEX>)--as if the theme music from the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movie didn't make you want to take harpoon lessons--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>'s
inexplicable back-to-back showings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sidekicks</ENAMEX> , the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> flop starring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Norris</ENAMEX> as himself--only taller (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed.</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00, 10:15</TIMEX>).

            Even in the darkest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, however, there is a
glimmer of relief. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX>, for instance, is showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossing</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> paean to the gangster flick. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> success notwithstanding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s 
               Crossing remains the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen</ENAMEX>'s best offering. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beautifully</ENAMEX> acted, beautifully scored, and most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beautifully</ENAMEX> shot, it gives a self-conscious nod to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>-movie romanticism
without gutting the myth a la <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> gangster hit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goodfellas</ENAMEX> .
(It also provides the best role <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Byrne</ENAMEX> is ever likely to get: half
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Burton</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Pacino</ENAMEX>)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sci-Fi Channel</ENAMEX>
launches its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twilight Zone</ENAMEX> marathon<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">--21 hours</TIMEX> of the eeriest series
ever. The show's ridiculous special effects would send <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Light</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magic</ENAMEX> into giggling fits, and much of the acting is barely <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> rate. But it
has some of the best theme music in television history, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Serling</ENAMEX>'s voice
can raise the hair on the back of my neck quicker than a scene out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Showgirls</ENAMEX> . My favorite episode: A burglar is shot dead while fleeing a
crime scene and is transported to a wondrous place where every desire is
immediately indulged--hot babes as far as the eye can see. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>,
the burglar grows bored of paradise and confronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Peter</ENAMEX>-esque fellow
in charge, arguing that Heaven is not really his bag. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heaven?</ENAMEX>" the
beatific-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gatekeeper</ENAMEX> asks with amusement. "What makes you think you're
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heaven?</ENAMEX>"

            What can I say? I was raised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baptist</ENAMEX>.

            As for more modern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fare</ENAMEX>, you're pretty safe with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> line-up-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frasier</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00</TIMEX>), and, after a
long dry spell even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00</TIMEX>) appears to be on the upswing.
Reminiscent of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first couple of seasons</TIMEX>, the dialogue is sharp and
wicked--although this time around, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt LeBlanc</ENAMEX>) seems to be getting more
of the good punchlines than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Perry</ENAMEX>), a shift that's prompted
much musing around my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> about shifting relationships between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> in an ensemble cast. (Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Perry</ENAMEX> is doing penance for his
unfortunate experiments on the big screen.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> covert romance
is as ripe for comic exploitation as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel fixation</ENAMEX>,
but it doesn't try to bait <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> into watching with the tired "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ooh</ENAMEX>, maybe
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> they'll get together" gimmick so many sit-com <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> seem
to fancy. Sure, maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>'s secret love will be revealed this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, or maybe not. What does it matter? They're together. They're happy.
They're getting laid. Life is good. I don't watch sit-coms to be
frustrated.

            (Caution: Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX> are screwing around
with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> programming, replacing the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">regular</TIMEX> line-up with
episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Pretender</ENAMEX> and the failed Wind on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX> . Viewer
discretion advised.)

            Finally, whatever your plans for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, set
the VCR to record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s New 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Rockin' Eve '99</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:35</TIMEX>). Any
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year now</TIMEX> could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Clark</ENAMEX>'s last. And should he happen to bite the big apple
while broadcasting live from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX>, you do not want to miss
it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Cottle</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
