
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Moments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap Lit</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> and foremost, of course, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quickie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> books. But after that, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX>'s column
praising philosopher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Nagel</ENAMEX>'s essay in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 14</TIMEX> issue of the
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Literary Supplement</ENAMEX> , and the essay itself. In it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagel</ENAMEX> makes two
obvious but overlooked points: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>. Civilization is impossible without
distinctions drawn between private and public life, and between the inner and
the outer self; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. A society governed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> without private lives
or inner selves is a society governed by madmen or cretins.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> caveats. In his column, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX> uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX>'s more finely-tuned
prose as an occasion to bash everyone who, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>'s words, "let[s] it all
hang out." By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is through attacking everyone who exemplies this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sixties</ENAMEX>-ish phrase (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Theroux</ENAMEX>, anyone who might have
criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s sexual escapades during his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>), you wonder
whether any speech about the sexual behavior of public figures is worth
protecting. Aren't there some occasions (date rape, say, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>-beating) where
we'd want to niggle or quibble? The virtue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagel</ENAMEX>'s essay is precisely that
he doesn't go overboard the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> does. He defends privacy without
disparaging the gains of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 years</TIMEX>. He is for the sexual
revolution--and who wants to go back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when the mention of private
acts was so taboo we had no way to talk about domestic violence or flagrant
abuses of power? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagel</ENAMEX>'s more subtle complaint is that an increase in sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tolerance</ENAMEX> has been transmogrified into an increase in sexual shaming: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What</ENAMEX>
looked initially like a growth of freedom has culminated in the reinstitution
of the public pillory."

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> caveat, this time with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagel</ENAMEX>. As often happens when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discuss Flytrap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagel</ENAMEX> lapses into a tone of world-weary, almost European
snobbishness, declaring that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s inability to respect the rules of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">civility</ENAMEX> reveals its immaturity as a society. But the immaturity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
papers is nothing next to the immaturity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>, and not even
our worst moments of national hysteria (this is definitely one of them) can be
compared to the worst moments of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> hysteria.

            
               Speaking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gossip State</ENAMEX> ... Here are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s
contributions, stolen mostly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> : A new book is about to come
out that seems likely to amount to a city-wide coming out: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Open Secret: Gay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hollywood 1928-1998</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> has already threatened to sue, even though
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ehrenstein</ENAMEX>, says the book only raises rumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cruise</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> in order to put them to rest. ... The very latest in product
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">placement</ENAMEX>: potentially, you. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX> will auction off a role in its remake of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thomas Crown Affair</ENAMEX> to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX> (the opening price is
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>). The auction is advertised in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>'s retail catalogue, but, the
catalogue copy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, there is "no guarantee that [the role] will be included
in the film's final edited version." ... Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo Di Caprio</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">spurned Lions Gate Films</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psycho</ENAMEX> , the production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is
trying to lure back the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> it had rudely kicked off the project, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harron</ENAMEX> ( I Shot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX> ). Though the whole thing was her idea in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, she was dropped the minute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di Caprio</ENAMEX> expressed interest and turned
an arty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10-million</NUMEX> feature into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40-million</NUMEX> vehicle for himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sic</ENAMEX> transit
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">gloria Hollywood</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
