
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Picture Shows</ENAMEX>

            This is not a good time to be a cinemaphile. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 50</NUMEX> repertory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theaters</ENAMEX> left in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and fewer old movies to see in them, since
the tiny market leaves little incentive for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> to strike new prints
when old ones age and break. And college film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> can't fill the gap,
since <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16-millimeter</NUMEX> prints are slowly passing out of circulation and
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35-millimeter</NUMEX> prints are too expensive for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to rent. Where's a film
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snob</ENAMEX> to go to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dean</ENAMEX> in Rebel Without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cause</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cinemascope</ENAMEX>,
rather than rudely cropped on video? The answer is nowhere. There isn't a print
to be had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>. Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurosawa</ENAMEX>, whose death would once have been commemorated
by retrospectives around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>? "I would like to do a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurosawa</ENAMEX> series
right now but I can't," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ewing</ENAMEX>, film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Museum of</ENAMEX>
Art, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>. Why not? "Well, a lot of [the prints] are owned by Toho
[a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>] and they don't seem interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> exhibition
anymore."

            The latest insult to cinemaphiles is partly the fault of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Film</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> ostensibly charged with protecting our national
film heritage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> report that they can't book
any films on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s top-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-movies-of-all-time list. Why? Because many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> with movies on the list have been pulling them out of circulation
before sending them out on national tour. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of affairs is only
expected to last through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>, but still. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire school year</TIMEX>,
imagine: no campus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> retrospectives ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Driver</ENAMEX> and
Goodfellas were on the list); no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Crawford</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Wilder</ENAMEX> series
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mildred Pierce</ENAMEX> , Some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like It Hot</ENAMEX> ); etc.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> would be glad to learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX>-studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> would
spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> watching movies not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX> list (the videos, of course, are
still available), were it possible for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> to find them. But even
the great bad movies seem to have vanished. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing</ENAMEX> reports
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>, when he tried to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s original version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Halloween</ENAMEX> --the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Lee Curtis</ENAMEX>--he discovered there
were no prints to be had. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, he stumbled across a sale by a film
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collector</ENAMEX> and bought a print for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> out of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reels</ENAMEX> were pretty
good," he reports.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
