
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trekkin</ENAMEX>'

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trekkies</ENAMEX> will tell you, the even-numbered <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> pictures have
been more or less OK, the odd ones leaden bummers. Star <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trek:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insurrection</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> feature, finally lifts the odd-number <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>. Not
that it's as stellar as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek II: The Wrath</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khan</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>) or even
               The Undiscovered 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Country</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>). It's just
pleasant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directed</ENAMEX> in plain style by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Frakes</ENAMEX> (who also appears as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">second-in-command</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riker</ENAMEX>), this is probably the closest the movies
have come to a TV episode--one of the ones in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> beams
down to an idyllic agrarian planet where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> knead dough and dress like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie Nicks</ENAMEX> and where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Captain</ENAMEX> falls in love with a headstrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and
has impassioned debates about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Directive</ENAMEX> before the phasers and the
photon torpedos come out and things blow up real good.

            The agrarians are the Ba'ku, who, thanks to "metaphasic radiation," live
more or less forever, which means their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty-year</TIMEX> apprenticeships
and the planet's needlepoint is of a high order. The bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son'a</ENAMEX>, led
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruf'afo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Murray Abraham</ENAMEX>) are ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bleeders</ENAMEX> with the kind of puffy-muslin
skin you see on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-degree burn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>; their favorite pastime is having
their dermal layers stretched and their skulls reupholstered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plug</ENAMEX>-Uglies
want to harvest the metaphasic radiation particles in the rings around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beauties</ENAMEX>' planet. 'Nuff said.

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek scripts: the Brannon Braga kind</ENAMEX>,
which feature spatial-temporal gimmicks and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Generation X banter</ENAMEX>; and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Piller</ENAMEX> kind, which focus on interspecies political coups and earthbound
(ground-bound?) ethical deliberations. This is one of the latter, and things do
get pokey. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Stewart</ENAMEX> deliberates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> listen. His stalwart
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Jean-Luc Picard</ENAMEX> is the perfect mascot for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 23 rd century</TIMEX>,
in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> no longer sport ridiculous rugs: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> seems to have evolved
beyond hair.

            The only real lapse is a strangely subdued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klingon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worf</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dorn</ENAMEX>) has
become a regular on the unwatchable <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek:</ENAMEX> 
               Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Nine</ENAMEX> ,
which means that he has to be "just passing by" whenever one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trek</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Next Generation</ENAMEX> features starts up. It's worth getting him back
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, though, because no one can utter a line like "I have an odd craving
for the blood of a live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kolar beast</ENAMEX>" with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorn</ENAMEX>'s mixture of virility and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">befuddlement</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insurrection</ENAMEX> boasts the only space battle in film history
in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> sing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> while firing on each
other--which is reason enough to go warp factor <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> to movie number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>. The only
pressing question: How can they get <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Picard</ENAMEX> together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>
            

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love and Little</ENAMEX>
Voices. )

         
      
   
