
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill Knew</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conquering</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> swagger into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, round up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of an undesirable
ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, and systematically slaughter them. The world knows all about
it but dithers anyway. Not for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after they first learn of the pattern of
atrocities do they do anything about it. Sound familiar? We're not talking
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> here. We're talking about the war which taught the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> just
how much horror an occupier can get away with.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the many unpleasant duties of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> involves rounding
out the portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> indifference to the genocide of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> during
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Breitman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American University</ENAMEX>, has just
added some new details to that picture. In his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Official Secrets</ENAMEX>: What
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis Planned</ENAMEX>, What the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> Knew (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX>), he
argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> were made fully aware of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> plan to wipe out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as January 1942</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</TIMEX> than previously thought.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breitman</ENAMEX>'s argument, based on recently declassified <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intelligence
documents, goes as follows: As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as 1939</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> decoders unscrambled
radio signals from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> special police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messages</ENAMEX> intercepted from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Front</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1941</TIMEX> showed that these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> were following behind
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and rounding up vast numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. The decoders
knew something about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> terminology by then, so they understood that "special
duties" or "pacification" meant something much worse than relocation. They'd
also heard enough to know that it was a campaign planned before the
invasion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, not some random by-product of war. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> rose all the way up to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Eden</ENAMEX>, who
quashed it, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX>, who enfolded it in grandiose speeches about
mass execution that didn't quite explain what was occurring.

            What difference would this information have made? The difference the
confirmation of rumor always makes. Had the world known for certain that the
incredible stories coming from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> were true, more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> could have
been warned. Neutral and satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> could have been pressured to accept
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> sooner. Even after the war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intelligence
reports could have helped pin the blame on the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. During the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuremberg</ENAMEX> trials, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> misclassified the special police
units largely responsible for the slaughter on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Front</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">run-of-the-mill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>, rather than as the mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> they were. The
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mass murderers</ENAMEX> of the world surely drew the obvious moral lesson.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Galbraith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
