
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idiot Box</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus Mentality</ENAMEX>

            
               Please note: All times given are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>, but check your local listings
just in case.
            

            Step right up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> and gents: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sweeps</ENAMEX> have come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. Everyone's
pandering, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is the most blatant with its sleazy
shockumentary When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Times Go Bad 2</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 11</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). The
network is trying to reach a prized demographic: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>-swigging morons <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-49</NUMEX>.
Expect a ratings blockbuster.

            The spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> seems to have influenced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arty networks</ENAMEX>, too. The
latest installment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&E</ENAMEX>'s true-life series, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A. Detectives</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 5</TIMEX>) is a slightly tonier version of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cops -- sans</ENAMEX>
the screaming drunks--in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> use dogged legwork to find the killer
in a drive-by homicide, and then some more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> go undercover to entrap
male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>. It's not quite as seamy over at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frontline</ENAMEX> , which spent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> researching the life, crimes, and recent execution of the talkative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford Boggess</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). In this absorbing real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man Walking</ENAMEX> , you don't get to see the actual lethal injection, but creepy
camerawork helps recreate his murders of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and the impact on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.

            Take a respite from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>'s portentous programs with the irreverent humor
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Carlin</ENAMEX>'s latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> live concert, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Are All Diseased</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 P.M</TIMEX>).

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, heartwarming but predictable made-for-TV movies duel with the
much-hyped <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files</ENAMEX> that "exposes" the convoluted alien conspiracy. For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mulder</ENAMEX> have been working to unravel the arcane plot while
even obsessive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> have been struggling just to follow it. The story so far: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mysterious Syndicate</ENAMEX> of rich white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evildoers</ENAMEX> has been in apparent cahoots with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> seeking to colonize the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>: infecting humans
with an oily virus that incubates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>. Or something like that.

            Want to get up to speed? Read this handy crib sheet by an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-Files
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gist-TV</ENAMEX> site, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GIST TV Sci-Fi: Feature Presentation</ENAMEX>, or tape the final <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
episodes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FX</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s conspiracy repeats on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 5</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Sunday</TIMEX>'s episode on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>) brings back repeat abductee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra Spender</ENAMEX>, who will supposedly help unlock the mystery of what
really happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mulder</ENAMEX>'s abducted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Samantha</ENAMEX>, and other
secrets. Don't hold your breath waiting for final answers.

            The roots of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s conspiracy thinking go back to the assassination of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>, which kicks off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s ambitious <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>- dimensional family drama, The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>. and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mon.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). It follows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, black and white, who
turn out to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeligs</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>'s: Their rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> turn up at
every key event from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Freedom Rides to Woodstock</ENAMEX>. It works as soundtrack
nostalgia and history lesson but flounders as drama. The acting is competent,
sometimes even affecting, particularly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Stiles</ENAMEX> as an aimless,
pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX>. But this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classics Comics</ENAMEX>-style tour of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> has neither
gripping narrative nor compelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
Dutton as an idealistic black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, aren't helped by the dialogue: "The
world is changing for the better, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. We got a long way to go but look where
we are now!" On the plus side: This show will infuriate neo-cons. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
Horowitz, eat your heart out.

            Middle-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who don't like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> are the
apparent target of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallmark Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> weepie, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Ride</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). Don't go there with them: It's a tedious
look at a troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (played by ex-sexpot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rebecca De Mornay</ENAMEX>) and
their response to the tragic death of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in a horse- riding accident.
Family healing, blah blah. Only the threat of, say, an alien abduction could
make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> watch all the way through this domestic bathos.

            A better bet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> is the delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>),
the dramedy that keeps getting richer with each episode. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Gandolfini</ENAMEX>'s
portrayal of the depressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob boss</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> has become one of the most
complex and enjoyable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on TV. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Soprano</ENAMEX> takes his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to scout a college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>, only to spot a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob snitch</ENAMEX> he may have to
whack. Complications ensue.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> can make another claim to quality programming: their film
of the hip-hop, black-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Universoul Circus</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>). Part
uplift for black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, part thrilling feats of circus daring, it's family
programming that can appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> of all races.

            The broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are keeping up with potentially strong episodes of
their flagship series. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Blue</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schroder</ENAMEX>'s tight-lipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Sorenson</ENAMEX>, opens up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sipowicz</ENAMEX> while
seeking help for an alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. It's about time. They won't be killing
off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> like they did to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Smits</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> . Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Ross</ENAMEX> is being forced out over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two</TIMEX>
episodes because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick heartthrob</ENAMEX> gives an unauthorized painkiller to a
terminally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>). The other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX>,
Frasier , has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsey Grammer</ENAMEX> directing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-vignette episode geared to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>).

            For bitchy wit at its best, set your VCRs to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bette Davis</ENAMEX> in the
incomparable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All About Eve</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinemax</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX>). To track all of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s four-star movies, check out the TV-Now website <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Star Movies</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> TV Schedule.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Levine</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
