
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Andrew</ENAMEX>,

                   We were so harmonious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in our shared indifference to news
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, Wall Street and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobacco Road</ENAMEX>. How do you feel about sports? I
follow sports from the crime angle--usually the first I hear about some
celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> is that he's been charged with rape, domestic violence,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse or, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Green Bay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Packer Reggie Whatsisname</ENAMEX>, is sharing his
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>" homophobic racist prejudices with the public. So you can imagine
how grating it is to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> wants to spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to one billion</NUMEX>
dollars of public funds building <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steinbrenner</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> a new
baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>. This is the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> we are always being told can't afford
to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is good repair, let alone cut class size. Or provide day care
for all those workfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinbrenner</ENAMEX> has pots of money--let him
build his own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>. If sports are so important, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> should build some
nice new swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> and recreation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in poor neighborhoods.
       Can you imagine the field day conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> would have if
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the billion dollars</NUMEX> was to be ladled out for effete artistic pleasures instead
of burly manly ones? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> was never more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 million</NUMEX> (I think it's down
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">98 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>), and look at the fuss over its handful of grants to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde artists</ENAMEX>. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are allowed to argue against support for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arts</ENAMEX> on the grounds of their personal tastes ("why should MY tax dollars go for
that pornographic drivel?" etc etc) how come effete <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> like me have to pay
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>? Let alone football. There's a gender angle here too--female tax
dollars paying for male (mostly male) pastimes. You'll notice no one's
proposing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion dollars</NUMEX> of public funds to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ballet</ENAMEX>!

         
      
   
