
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>,

                   You sent me scurrying to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> business pages and
there I found a potential solution for one of my life's peskiest problems. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is now producing a tiny little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that seats just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, weighs
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 770</NUMEX> pounds, goes <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">27 miles per hour</NUMEX>, costs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10 percent</NUMEX> more than the
next-smallest regular kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> (after all, this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, where la vie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coute cher</ENAMEX> )--and, thanks to a legal loophole, it doesn't require a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>'
license! To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like me, a multiple flunker of the roadtest, a micro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is
just the thing. I know how to drive, I do, I do, I do. I just get all flustered
when I have to prove it under the stern, judgmental eyes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">27 miles</NUMEX>
per hour is just about right for me.
       Of course, tootling about in my light little micro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, rather like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Little</ENAMEX> in his roadster, I would be no match for the sports utility
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> that roam <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-95</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">woolly mammoths</ENAMEX> looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">prey</ENAMEX>. I hate those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>--why should anything be bigger than it has to be? Perennial cry of one who
was always the shortest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, I know. So I would only use it on
back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, to go to tag sales and garden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>.
Those are just about the only places I want to go, anyway.
       And they ask me why I'm so keen on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>!

         
      
   
