
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox Rules</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feminism</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>

            Should feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> be allowed to apply their theories to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>? According to a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary</ENAMEX> , the answer is no.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Schoenfeld</ENAMEX>, in an article for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> issue of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Auschwitz and the Professors</ENAMEX>," deplores a recent spate of books
and studies written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (and a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>) he calls "feminist
Holocaustologians," who indulge in "witless and malicious theorizing" and "the
worst excesses" of a discipline--<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust Studies</ENAMEX>--he has no use for to begin
with. The article provoked an outpouring of letters, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of which were published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commentary</ENAMEX> 's August
issue. In them, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> is accused of sexism, recklessness, distortion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ignorance</ENAMEX>, and "trivializ[ing] the human experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> intends to make a habit of ruling on disputes of this sort. So
who's right? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> has just finished reading one of the key pieces of
evidence for the prosecution, Women in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> , edited by Dalia
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenore J. Weitzman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), and can confirm that it isn't very
good. At best, it tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hitherto</ENAMEX> untold tales about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the ghettoes and
death-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, forcing us to ponder such imponderables as: When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> is born in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>, is it crueller to let him starve or to feed him <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar water</ENAMEX> and
prolong his death? At worst, the book engages in comparative victimology by
making dubious and undocumentable claims, such as: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's</ENAMEX> training as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nurturers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>-do made them better able to adapt to camp life than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
            

            On the other hand, all fields of inquiry have their great thinkers and their
embarrassing ones, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> has never understood why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">polemicists</ENAMEX> think a
single cringeworthy quote is enough evidence to declare entire subjects
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">off-limits</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> has an answer to that, and it is a well-known <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,
having first been set forth in another Commentary essay in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great Biblical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Alter</ENAMEX>: The danger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust Studies</ENAMEX> is that,
in the proliferation of methodologies and agendas, the incomprehensible horror
of the event may be lost--eclipsed, as humanity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> was eclipsed, by a
fog of categories and subcategories and rhetorical feints at ideological
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> enough, but there are differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> worth
pointing out. One is of tone--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alter</ENAMEX> is calm, respectful, and regretful.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> is shrill and dismissive, with a tendency to distort others' words
for his own convenience. To take one of the more trivial examples, Schoenfeld
writes: "Mainstream scholarship on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> genocide, we are being told on
every side, is not so much mainstream as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'malestream</ENAMEX>.'" He then repeats the
word "malestream" throughout the piece, as if to remind us of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>'
tendency to excess. Culturebox combed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX> to find the
word in the feminist-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> literature, but found it nowhere. If it has been
used, it has clearly not been used frequently, and so is not coming at us from
"every side."

            The more significant difference is a matter of balance. Against the danger
of trivializing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> by speaking of it too lightly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alter</ENAMEX> juxtaposes
the threat of elevating the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> into something quasi-theological by
speaking of it in religious terms. Alter quotes another great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Neusner</ENAMEX>, to the effect that "the murder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>" has become
part of "the civil religion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX>." Schoenfeld, by censuring some
kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> speech and failing to offer other kinds that would be
acceptable to him, strongly implies that it is, indeed, a religious topic, for
which some words are not just inaccurate or inappropriate but blasphemous.

            In a way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> and film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Lanzmann</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who declared that after his film,
Shoah , "certain things can no longer be done." (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>'s
Explaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> to read about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanzmann</ENAMEX>'s attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
who address it in ways he doesn't like. Or click on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX>'s review in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .) But even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanzmann</ENAMEX> makes an interesting case for silence--he
believes that causal explanations of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> actions belie their deep
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inexplicability</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schoenfeld</ENAMEX> has nothing so provocative to say. His case against feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust</ENAMEX> studies can be reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main objections: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alter</ENAMEX>'s argument,
made with less subtlety; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a somewhat crankish concern that the "object of
such exercises" as feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> scholarship is "to sever <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, in
their own minds, from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> as well as from the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the sense that such treatment violates taste, decorum, and
"human decency." When it comes to discussing something as tasteless, indecent,
and indecorous as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, none of the above strike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> as
adequate grounds for censorship.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
