
   
   
      
         
            Say No to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>

            
               Please note: All times given are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>, but check your local listings
just in case.
            

            Television is a mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s programs are going to lure some
of the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>--starting with an orgy of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
coverage on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>. By the time of the actual kick-off on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:18 p.m.</TIMEX>, you
may be convinced that it's your patriotic duty to watch the game. If you
must be un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, stick to cable and watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>'s marathon
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kids in the Hall</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 p.m.</TIMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours</TIMEX> of
Absolutely <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fabulous</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>).

            But make no mistake: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> rules the TV world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> paid
dearly to win the rights to broadcast the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>, and they're not going to
let you ignore it. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the big game, for instance, they're offering
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven hours</TIMEX> of pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bowl</ENAMEX> coverage, starting at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> isn't just
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, of course, but about ads, network promotions and a new series.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is an innovative animated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> series to air in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Guy</ENAMEX> ; it previews at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Guy</ENAMEX> is
closer in spirit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Park</ENAMEX> than to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> , and not as
funny as either, but still, it's pretty inventive and daring. Don't be
surprised if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX> attacks the show for highlighting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whining</ENAMEX>, bagel-munching "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I. Jew</ENAMEX>" toy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>.

            Some other options: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent Film Channel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">... And God</ENAMEX>

               Spoke (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>), a hilarious mock documentary about two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-movie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> who are trying to make a big-budget Biblical epic, but are
reduced to casting Soupy Sales as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 29</TIMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFC</ENAMEX> also
offers an engaging documentary about a genuine indie filmmaker, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Bad</ENAMEX>
Taste: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waters Story</ENAMEX> .

            At the other end of the culture is wholesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Gill</ENAMEX>, the country music
great featured on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&E</ENAMEX>'s concert series, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live by Request</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gill</ENAMEX>'s high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonesome tenor</ENAMEX> voice is a national treasure, and his success
at pulling in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grammies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Country Music Awards</ENAMEX> shows that popularity and
artistic merit sometimes coincide.

            But there's no assurance of that when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> broadcasts another unnecessary
awards show, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide Awards</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>). It's
based on ballots by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>; naturally, The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>
Show is up for an award. These specials bring to mind <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry Sanders</ENAMEX>'
comment after watching a focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX> I know why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baywatch</ENAMEX> is the
number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> syndicated show in the world."

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, real greatness can be found in I'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Make Me A World</ENAMEX> ,
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> documentary about the lives and works of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>)--everyone
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis Armstrong</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> says: "It's hard for me to imagine
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture without black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being part of that. It would be one
b-l<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-a-a-n-d</ENAMEX> place, bland as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wonderbread</ENAMEX>."

            Plenty of white-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> blandness on display in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netforce</ENAMEX> , a
thriller about an elite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> cyber-cops in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2005</TIMEX> who are
fighting Internet crime and a powerful computer titan modeled after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). It gets mired in techno-speak and stars
the dopey-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Bakula</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX> ), who is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>,
though even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> would look silly saying things like, "Run all our
emergency utility programs. I want a full diagnostic!" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bakula</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch-enemy</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reinhold</ENAMEX>, a murderous sort who seeks to control the entire Internet with
a nefarious...Web browser! It's never made clear why , since he already
dominates the browser market. But the show does have potential as a kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mommy Dearest</ENAMEX> for computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> has its own entry in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> market, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roswell: The Aliens</ENAMEX>

               Attack (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>), the story of human-like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who survive
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX> crash in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> and plan to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> with captured nuclear
weapons. The female alien's secret weapon: seducing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. Why rent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars Attacks</ENAMEX>! parody when you can see a genuine alien film for
free?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> marks the official beginning of sweeps month, and so there are some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> pickings. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frasier</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Harrelson</ENAMEX> visits Frasier
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Boyd</ENAMEX>, the lovably dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bartender</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX> , but then won't
leave. The best sweeps <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> program of all may be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner Classic Movies</ENAMEX>
broadcasts of the original (and best) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Thin Man</ENAMEX> movie and its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequels</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Powell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myrna Loy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, a reminder of
the time when classy (if drunken) wit equalled box-office success.

            Today, they'd be lucky to win anything at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide Awards</ENAMEX> .

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Levine</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
