
   
   
      
         
            Sexual McCarthyism

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>'s new novel, I Married a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> , tells the story of a
radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> and party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> whose movie-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress-wife</ENAMEX> publishes a tell-all that
destroys him. The question of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> in certain literary circles is: Will it
be read high-mindedly, as a cautionary reconsideration of McCarthyism, or
pruriently, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>'s counterattack on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> and memoirist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Bloom</ENAMEX>? The reviews haven't come out yet, but Culturebox bets on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>.
For confirmation, see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s fall preview in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Zuckerman</ENAMEX> sits silently as another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>'s blue-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> is built up
and destroyed, this time by a self-involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> past, a
demanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> accent. Sound familiar?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> would like to suggest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> possibility: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Married a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> is about both McCarthyism and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> (there's a parody of her
memoir in the novel that's hilarious)--but what it's really about is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>.
Or, if you prefer, sexual McCarthyism: the madness that prevails when private
mistakes become daily fodder for public titillation, and are then used as
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to club the poor sinning bastards to death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Gingold</ENAMEX>, our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, is a passionate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>, a troubling fact addressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX> with all
the moral seriousness one could ask for, knowing what we know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But what
proves his undoing is not his proselytizing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, wrong-headed though
that is. It's his foolish marriage and adulterous affair, as exploited by an
evil gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> who goes on to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>.

            There are many passages in this novel that are hard not to read as
commentary on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topic A.</ENAMEX> Until the book hits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so</TIMEX>,
you'll have to make do with this sample:

            
               Once the human tragedy has been played out, it gets turned over to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to banalize into entertainment. Perhaps it's because the whole
irrational frenzy burst through our door and no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s half-baked
insinuating detail passed me by that I think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> era as
inaugurating the postwar triumph of gossip, as the beginning not just of
serious politics but of serious everything as entertainment to amuse the
mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>: McCarthyism as the first postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flowering</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
unthinking that is now everywhere.
            

            
               Frankly, my dear... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> is a little baffled by all the fuss
being made about the long-lost pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX>'s diary. So it turns out
that a teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> hated her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and sighed over her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> being
cruelly deprived of true love. Why should that be front-page news?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
