
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brow Beating</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Culturebox</ENAMEX>--

            In response to your "whole indie scene" point: To me this is the problem,
not the solution. There was once in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--let's say the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>'s for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shorthand</ENAMEX>--a thriving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highish Midbrow Culture</ENAMEX>.

            This is a culture where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Updike</ENAMEX> made the bestseller list; where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blonde on Blonde</ENAMEX>" charted; where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford Coppola</ENAMEX> made a studio
movie called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Godfather</ENAMEX> ; and where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Herr</ENAMEX> published his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War Dispatches</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> . I think this culture mattered--not
just to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who created these works, but to the lived texture of life
in middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. I think this culture mattered to as many middle-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as it did because these works were produced and dispensed and
promoted by mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, who knew how to reach them. I think these
mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> produced, dispensed and promoted these products not
because there were hard numbers because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at these
places believed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and their products.

            Now we have a vapid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster Culture</ENAMEX> and a fringy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indie Culture</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fragile Highish Midbrow Culture</ENAMEX> that ever more depends, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Culture</ENAMEX>
world of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and opera <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> long has, on the largesse of angels--think of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si Newhouse</ENAMEX>...or, closer to home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. Hold your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookscan</ENAMEX>, please. I'll
take the rumpled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who takes a bet on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorrie Moore</ENAMEX> and sticks with her
until the breakout book--and maybe buys the time by signing up a decent
cookbook.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">---Gerry Marzorati</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Gerry</ENAMEX>--
            

            I don't know. I think you're letting nostalgia cloud your vision. Then as
now, there was infinitely more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>-topping on the great cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> than
there was pepperoni, even if you lower the brow-level on the pepperoni. What
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that hit sitcom The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hillbillies</ENAMEX> ? ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> 90210
is merely a few blocks over and up from that.) Or that musical wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpert</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tijuana Brass</ENAMEX>, the pseudo-mariachi <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> that graced its albums
with photos of beautiful brown-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whipped cream</ENAMEX>? We're
talking cornball kitsch that couldn't even get an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> at a hip coffee bar
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. For books, bestselling titles like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Greening of America</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffee, Tea</ENAMEX>, or Me float to mind.
            

            Conversely, I don't think the current music scene is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as bad as you make
it out to be. Last time I logged onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billboard</ENAMEX> Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
site, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX>'s new CD was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX>. You can't tell me her serious fusion of
hip hop and rap--or, say, the razzle-dazzle poetics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wu</ENAMEX>-Tang
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Clan</ENAMEX>--doesn't speak to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the way "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blonde on Blonde</ENAMEX>" did to its
generation. Same with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp Fiction</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>. Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delillo's Underworld</ENAMEX> , which I personally couldn't stand but which spoke
truth to many and lingered on the bestseller list for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. We 
               could
go on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>, each jockeying to out-brow the other, high and low, which would
be enormously fun for us but boring, I'm afraid, for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               On another front, I have to insist that better, clearer, more rigorous
numbers would help books more than they'd hurt them. For instance, if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Bestseller List</ENAMEX> didn't fiddle with the numbers so much--only
looking at certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> and going so far as to seed the process by
sending out a list of books it's interested in tracking, as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>
Eliza
Truitt 
               reported in 
               Slate 
               a little while
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>--certain regional bestsellers, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> , wouldn't take
so long to come to national attention. I know the conventional thinking is that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Bestseller List</ENAMEX> is good for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-</TIMEX>list books, because it refuses
to track crap, but if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Bestseller List</ENAMEX> were based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> numbers, rather than guesstimates, why couldn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
still refuse to track crap? It would just have to be more upfront about how
it slices the stats and then it would do much a better job of following the
serious books throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, not just at selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.
            

            --Culturebox

         
      
   
