
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affirmative Action Wars, Part 37</ENAMEX>

            The backlash against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William G. Bowen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Bok</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shape of the</ENAMEX>
River , a liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> of affirmative action, has kicked into gear, and
much of it won't surprise you. There's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attacker</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> (with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephan</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation, Indivisible</ENAMEX> and one of the loudest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of affirmative action
around. There's the venue: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page.
There's the old juggle-with-numbers. Is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> graduation rate for blacks
at top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> proof of the success of race-sensitive admissions or of its
failure? Proof of success, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bok</ENAMEX>; proof of failure,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstrom</ENAMEX>. The white graduation rate is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86 percent</NUMEX>, so she
reconfigures the stats to show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> have a dropout rate that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>
percent higher for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> than for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thernstom</ENAMEX>'s main argument is original. She says an education at an elite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> doesn't matter as much as everyone says it does, so elite colleges
shouldn't work so hard to admit more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bok</ENAMEX> claim we need
affirmative action from top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> because that's what created the black
middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? Not so fast! says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thernstrom</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where</ENAMEX> are their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, demonstrating in some rigorous fashion that the equally
academically strong, ambitious and discipline black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who attends the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of South Carolina</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oberlin</ENAMEX> does less well in life?"
Lacking hard data, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstrom</ENAMEX> supplies anecdotal evidence: a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> who
did well in life even though they didn't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX>. It includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Tucker</ENAMEX>, editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Constitution</ENAMEX> , who went
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auburn University</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> , who went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brent Staples</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , who
went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Widener</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, who went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Depauw</ENAMEX>; and so on.

            Leaving aside the little hooks that ripple this flowing counternarrative of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>, like the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> went to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> is charmed by a certain self-inverting quality to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstrom</ENAMEX>'s argument. If like her we believe in strict formal equality in all
things (rather than remedies to past discrimination), and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't
need fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to do well in life, why should we think white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need
them either? Think of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the universe, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
Eisner, who graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denison</ENAMEX>, a university in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>. Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>, who never graduated at all. But if white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't need degrees
from tony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> to succeed, why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thernstrom</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> care so much
about these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>' efforts to level the playing field? The better strategy
would be to cede it altogether, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to enjoy their <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Pyrric</ENAMEX> victory.
More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> they, that they believe in the power of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> education!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstrom</ENAMEX> sent her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie Thernstrom</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, so we know she
doesn't accept the unintended consequences of her own argument. But that
doesn't undermine her case entirely. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstrom</ENAMEX> is translating for broad
consumption a debate raging among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>. It is widely known that there is
a huge economic return on higher education in general. The question is: Is
there a bigger <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on an education at an elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>? In other words, does it
matter where you went to college or that you went to college?

            In purely economic terms, it turns out, it matters only that you went
to college. But pure economics doesn't explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like Thernstrom care
so much about getting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>. The answer is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> does more than get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> into the middle-class, or even the
upper-middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. It plugs your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> directly into a network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
make up what used to be called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Establishment</ENAMEX>--which is exactly where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstrom</ENAMEX> would want her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to be.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
