
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            You raise an interesting point. If we consider the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
and media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on your list as actually believing their professed ideology,
which I'm not sure they all do, I think yes, orthodoxers of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sort</ENAMEX> or another
are often fighting the return of the repressed: a
stop-me-before<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-I</ENAMEX>-divorce-again kind of a thing. They're like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gaybashers</ENAMEX> who are
in flight from their own homosexual impulses. Except, in the case of the people
you mention, they do get divorced all they want to. That's what gets
me--they permit themselves a freedom they seek to deny to others. Instead of
being made more understanding by their own frailties and failures, they just
forgive themselves and condemn others.

            In any case, I don't think marriage works as a preserver of relationships.
At least not for long--just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>, in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podhoretz</ENAMEX>. (What
was the story there, I wonder.) Having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> often does make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> try hard
to make their relationships work, but I don't think marriage, in and of itself,
does that, although I know that is an argument often advanced in its favor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> just get mean and depressed, and drag about sullenly hoping their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>
will be swept away by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">El Nino</ENAMEX>. Or become obsessed with work. Or have
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whipped-cream nights</ENAMEX> out when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'s away. Or all of the above!

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">NOW</TIMEX>--Yes, I have disagreed with their policies publicly on many
occasions. Not just about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> (where I don't think their actual
position is as bad as it's been made to look in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>), but also their
enthusiasm for electoral politics, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            I have to say, though, that I don't blame them for not signing on to Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' appeal. The whole thing has become such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, either. Look what they've done to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in all this, if you ask me!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Katha

         
      
   
