
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Idiot Box</ENAMEX>

            
               (Note from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>: With <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s entry we inaugurate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s new
television column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Cottle</ENAMEX>, which will appear at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of each week</TIMEX>
and cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming week</TIMEX> in television. We know that when it comes to TV,
everyone's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, so we invite you to send your picks, pans, and flames to
culturebox@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> . We don't
promise to reply to each and every one of you. Also, all times given are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Standard</ENAMEX>. Check local listings for broadcast times in your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hometown</ENAMEX>.)
            

            With only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> viewing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> left until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, the yuletide spirit is
approaching critical mass on pretty much every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. And navigating the
rising tide of warm-and-fuzzy holiday programming can be harrowing.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will be bombarded with holiday episodes of
everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The X Files to Two Girls</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX> .
Among the most promising offerings are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tues.</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy</ENAMEX> try to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> a depressed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> through the
suicide <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Shoot Me</ENAMEX>  (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tues.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM), a take-off on
How the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grinch Stole Christmas</ENAMEX> narrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frasier</ENAMEX> star
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsey Grammer</ENAMEX>. On a darker note, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> in need of a good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cry
should check out <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thurs.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> PM). The show is emotionally
draining on a regular basis, so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s attempt by the idealistic Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah Wyle</ENAMEX>) to perform a holiday miracle on a dying teenager is
guaranteed to have you doubling up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, you should probably tune in for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ally</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal 's</ENAMEX> holiday hijinks. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM). The episode itself sounds
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iffy</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> launches a wrongful-termination suit on behalf of a major client
who's been fired for claiming to have seen a unicorn--but there's a kind of
perverse thrill in seeing what abject humiliation will befall the show's
emaciated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>. One
recent episode found Ally wedged into a toilet; in another, she got her fingers
stuck inside a bowling ball. And during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s holiday rerun, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">micro</ENAMEX>-skirted minx fell into her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and lay entangled in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branches</ENAMEX> until her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> came in and marveled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally</ENAMEX>'s sex life had
deteriorated to the point where she was humping <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>. Who knows,
perhaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this holiday season</TIMEX> the beleaguered Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McBeal</ENAMEX> will inadvertently drop
her diaphragm into some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army Santa</ENAMEX>'s collection basket.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming week</TIMEX> also delivers a sleigh-full of holiday movies and specials.
Of course there are the requisite showings of  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miracle</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">34th Street</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fri.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM) and It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sat.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). For
those who like their merriment in one concentrated dose, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> is rebroadcasting
Greatest
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moments of All Time</ENAMEX> , a compilation of
snippets from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> cartoons, movies, specials, and commercials through the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thur.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). And then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">17th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual Christmas</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fri.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> PM), complete with a special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> message from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (Come sit on my lap little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ho</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ho</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ho</ENAMEX>.) and a
guided tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> by none other than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s Vogue
cover-model, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>. 

            Some of the more terrifying movies and specials to avoid include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1997</ENAMEX> classic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Christmas List</ENAMEX> , featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marla Maples</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>'s Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scrooge</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed.</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM), starring
made-for-TV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">schmaltz</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicely Tyson</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bah-humbugging</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebenita</ENAMEX> (I did
not make that name up); and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> concert (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Como's Irish Christmas --'nuff</ENAMEX> said.

            By far, your best bet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> is a relatively new but oh-so-jolly holiday
tradition<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: 15 Days of  007</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5-19</TIMEX>). Connery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dalton</ENAMEX>,
even that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lazenby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>--they're all there. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce Brosnan</ENAMEX> has yet to
make it into the line-up, but he's also yet to make a decent Bond flick.)
Seriously, what could be more festive than voodoo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, poppy fields,
space-based laser <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, germ warfare, car chases, boat chases, ski
chases,
and a half-naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ursula Andress</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s highlights include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamonds</ENAMEX>
are
               Forever (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mon.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:05 PM</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Russia With Love</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tues.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:05 PM</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Her Majesty</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed.</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:05</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>)--yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lazenby</ENAMEX> stinks, but the movie itself is one of the best, and it's the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> gets hitched<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Live and Let Die</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thurs.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:05</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr</ENAMEX> . No (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fri.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:10 PM</TIMEX>).

            A word of warning to those desperately seeking non-holiday fare: Although
there's not an Xmas <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> or menorah in sight, steer clear of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s retelling of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tempest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM). Set in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Fonda</ENAMEX> is the benevolent plantation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gideon Prosper</ENAMEX>, whose evil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glover</ENAMEX>) plots to have him killed in order to take over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">plantation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonda</ENAMEX> escapes with the help of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>, who also happens to be a
voodoo priestess, and runs off with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Hegl</ENAMEX>) to
live in the swamps. The movie has some smashing special effects a la <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
Merlin , but it also has its share of bad acting and heavy-handed
dialogue. (We won't even go into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonda</ENAMEX>'s half-baked <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie accent</ENAMEX>.) All told,
you're better off with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> in mind that I've not had the opportunity to
actually preview many of the aforementioned shows and in many cases am relying
on press releases, written synopses, and assurances from network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flacks</ENAMEX> that a
particular episode doesn't suck. My recommendations, however, are made in good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> and based on the most up-to-date research methods

                  Slate
                can afford. Nonetheless, I will gladly and
profusely apologize for any and all bad calls.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Cottle</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
