
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweat</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spit</ENAMEX>

            Herewith, as promised, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spiterature Contest</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pomposity Sweepstakes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> thanks her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> for making the decision
such a difficult one. What could make her happier than to see how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> delight in the malice of others, and how eagerly they
engage in it themselves?

            
               Winning Entry, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Spiterature Contest:</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Patrick</ENAMEX> writes:

            

               I have never seen anything meaner (nor agreed with anything more) than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezra</ENAMEX>
Pound's "take" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. E. Housman</ENAMEX>:

               Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Housman</ENAMEX>'s Message

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O woe</ENAMEX>, woe,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are born and die,
We also shall be dead pretty soon
Therefore let us act as if we were dead already.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> sits on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the hawthorn</TIMEX> tree
But he dies also, presently.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lads</ENAMEX> get hung, and some get shot.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woeful</ENAMEX> is this human lot.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woe</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">woe</ENAMEX>, etcetera....

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> is a woeful place,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shropshire</ENAMEX> is much pleasanter.
Then let us smile a little space
Upon fond nature's morbid grace,
Oh, woe, woe, woe, etcetera....

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s note: Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Housman Pound</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> doubts it, though
she doesn't actually know. It doesn't matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX> has correctly identified
a masterpiece of spiterature: literature as a projectile of spit, composed in
the spirit of spite.

            
               Winning Entry, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Pomposity Sweepstakes</ENAMEX>:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Widmaier</ENAMEX> writes:

            

               In the spirit of the ongoing pile-on on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, I have to argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are to blame for rock pomposity. Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, we had a motley
collection of teen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and fan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club publications</ENAMEX>. Then, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crawdaddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> came out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX>
got its start in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. Both were run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Williams</ENAMEX>, Jann
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wenner</ENAMEX>) who saw rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> as modern poets and voices of their generation.
While this may have been true for a good many (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>), the
requirements of publishing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two weeks</TIMEX> meant others, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moodies</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanilla Fudge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson Airplane</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Son of Jesus"</ENAMEX>, anyone?) had to be elevated
to a similar stature. Even when they weren't ready. Some of them recognized it:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moodies</ENAMEX> responded with "I'm Just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Singer</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock and Roll Band</ENAMEX>"; Some
didn't: My personal favorite example of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-'60s</TIMEX> pretension will always be
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood Sweat and Tears' "Symphony for the Devil/Sympathy for the Devil</ENAMEX>." Maybe
we should have seen it coming: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> destroyed rock; then they trashed
the political process!

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s note: For this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> to reply merely for the sake of
having something to publish on her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> schedule would be to invite, as Wes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widmaier</ENAMEX> so rightly warns us, pomposity. Or, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Lehrer</ENAMEX> put it: If you can't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">communicate</ENAMEX>, the least you can do is shut up.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
