
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
            

            Katha,
The reason <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economic and social woes are still terrible is related to
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many-decades</TIMEX> long genocidal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> that destroyed its polity and economy,
and terrorized half the planet. Economic and social decline were accelerating
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last years</TIMEX> of the evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, and any attempt to put them right will
inevitably make some of them worse in the meantime. You can't solve such
problems before you expose them. I remember the pain exacted by Thatcherism in
its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of disastrous socialist economics had
wrought another mess of poverty, stagnation, and resentment. And, of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>, not socialism, for the mess. Now ask
neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thatcherite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> who was really responsible. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s attack on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> was, in my view, a necessary evil, given the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>'s
continuing attempt to derail democratization and market reform. And while there
are plenty of old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> still in charge in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, their opposition
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, and the opposition of the big business cartels to his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>,
suggests whose side he's really on. Why won't you give him credit? It still
seems to me part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Left</ENAMEX>'s inability to come to terms with its intellectual
and moral complicity in the murderous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several decades</TIMEX> that
leaves it reluctant to get clearly and unequivocally on the right side in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.

            As to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, I agree with you about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, but they are worthy of him.
The responsibility for all this mess lies with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and him alone, not
with the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who was appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, for
good and obvious reasons. Again, it seems to me you cannot see the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.

            But you're right. I can't imagine you in tweeds.

            best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
