
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loathing</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
            

            Katha,

            It's a very good question. Many times I have tried to figure out what it is
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that truly offends me. As you point out, I'm quite happy with
many of the results of his policies--the expansion of free trade, the reform of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX>, the reduction of the deficit, the acquiescence to the rollback of
reverse racial discrimination. Yes, I'm not so happy about his support of the
death penalty, his signing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marriage Act</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> debacle,
his civil-liberties record, his anti-smoking crusade. But then I'm not a
lock-step conservative, as you know. And you can't have everything. So what is
it?

            For my part, it's not sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and rock 'n' roll. Believe me. Some of
my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are sex-crazed stoners. I think, ultimately, it's because of
his moral vacuity on a more profound level. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnia</ENAMEX> was the clincher for me. He
said it was a holocaust, then did nothing to stop it, then claimed credit for
ending it, then apologized for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">holocaust</ENAMEX>. Anyone who can use such a grave
moral issue so glibly and cynically is pretty close to being evil. Ditto his
complete lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> on civil rights. Here is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who says he is
against discrimination, then fires more gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the military than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, signs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOMA</ENAMEX> (then boasts about it, then apologizes for it), signs a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> to expel <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the military (then says he didn't mean
it), signs a bill barring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
and asks for less money on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. It's not
the end result that gets me so much. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> might have been worse on both
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and civil rights. It's his refusal to take moral responsibility for
anything, or take credit for things he opposed, or evade blame where blame is
genuinely deserved. When someone like that is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it is
truly corrosive of our morality in the real sense of that word. Because it is
truly corrosive of any sense of personal responsibility. He has the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-ego</ENAMEX>
of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year-old</TIMEX>.

            Sometimes, I really think he is evil.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
