
   
   
      
         
            The End of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX>

            It's a good thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Crews</ENAMEX> didn't wander into the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychoanalytic Institute</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper East Side</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. The
aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> packed into the auditorium, sweating through their dark clothes
in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> heat wave (only a small desk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> recycled the stale air),
would have confirmed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud-basher</ENAMEX>'s darkest suspicions about psychoanalysis as a cult of
personality. For what were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>, in the sanctum sanctorum of
sternly silent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> who conduct long-term analyses with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> lying on
couches, in this impossible time for the famously impossible profession, up to?
Composing thoughtful rebuttals to their scientistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>? Ignoring the
outside world to present the latest advance in countertransference theory? No.
They were watching home movies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>.

            Overhearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s indulgent titters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crews</ENAMEX> would have found it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pathetic</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crews</ENAMEX> would have been wrong. The movies were taken in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>'s named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Lehrman</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who had to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battle Freud</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Old-World</ENAMEX> dislike of gizmos to gain permission to shoot the
footage. In a typical Freudian move, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> insisted on analyzing his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s obsession with filming him before letting him do it. ("Was it
historical or hysterical<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>") Notwithstanding everyone's reluctance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrman</ENAMEX> got
several <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of film that brought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of bit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and their world to
life--the seductive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandor Ferenczi</ENAMEX> at a caf, (he once conducted affairs with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> at the same time), the warm and animated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie</ENAMEX>
Bonaparte graciously introducing everybody to everybody else at <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> parties
(she later rescued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis</ENAMEX>), a dashing and alarmingly radiant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilhelm Reich</ENAMEX> (he lated invented orgone therapy). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> himself proved a
shockingly commanding presence, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of barely checked intensity lurking in
the shadows (he refused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehrman</ENAMEX>'s requests to come out into the sunlight) who
only unstiffened in the presence of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>.

            The emotional coloring of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>, though, came from the soundtrack, a
tape of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehrman</ENAMEX> explaining his footage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 years later</TIMEX> to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> meeting of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psychoanalytic Association</ENAMEX>. Over nearly every new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s image came
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehrman</ENAMEX>'s voice, giving that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s name, his psychoanalytic credential, and
then where he ended up: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, or--the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. It was, one realized, a
scene of gravity, even of mourning: Here were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>, at a time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychoanalysis</ENAMEX> seems to be sputtering to an undignified end, done in by managed
health care, psychopharmacology, and the intellectual vindication of behavioral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> by modern trends in genetics. There were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>, at
the field's most hopeful, eager beginning, when it seemed the most brilliant
secular flowering of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> life. In between them lay a physical war
that wiped out a world and an intellectual war that discredited a past. When
the movie came to an end, there seemed nothing left to say.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
