
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>? Or just his good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>?
            

            Katha,

            Actually, I do think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s inability to take responsibility for
anything is far deeper than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s. I remember that broadcast where RR
finally said that, although his heart told him he didn't exchange arms for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>, the evidence proved that he had. There. He did admit it. I don't
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was deeply involved in the arms-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> process either. In
broader areas, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> clearly stood for things--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>communism, for
example--and stuck to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> (so to speak). He remained answerable for the
results. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has stood for very little, and what little he has stood for he
has slithered away from at every opportunity, if it meant any cost or pain.
Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was better--a war he could have lost, a defensible tax-hike he paid
for dearly. There was risk because there was a small degree of conviction. With
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, there is no conviction, no risk, no reward.

            So I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are genuinely uneasy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. I'm uneasy
with it because it goes against the values I was brought up with: you tell the
truth, stick to your principles, and face the consequences of your actions. He
does none of this, from petty obstruction of justice to big-issue betrayals. I
think some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are uneasy with him for the reasons you cite; and
because they associate him with the boomer generation, whose moral and
psychological grip on reality is famously suspect. I don't think they're
jealous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bubba</ENAMEX> vote actually rallied round <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> once he became a
recognizable "redneck philanderer" rather than a "liberal pinko sleaze." As to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, she is of a piece with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, in my book, whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>
says.

            best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.s.</ENAMEX> Oh, and talking about responsibility, a hilarious (I suppose) moment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>, which reminded me of our chat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. Walking down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">17th Street</ENAMEX>
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, I was greeted by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May Day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX> march. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, red
flags, slogans about the "working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>" and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930s</TIMEX>-style poster of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> laughed at it, but I was stunned at how many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marchers</ENAMEX> were
under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> teenager seriously explained to me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ukrainians</ENAMEX> "starved
themselves." Yes, I know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of nothing. But I
wonder what our response would be if a group of young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> walked down the
street, with swastika flags, pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, and claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> never perished. Would we smile indulgently? Has our moral sensibility
become sadly dependent on identity politics? I'm not saying, of course, that we
should pay less attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s evil, merely that we need to pay more to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> has already clearly forgotten.

         
      
   
