
   
   
      
         
            An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Appeal to Your Expertise</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Andrew</ENAMEX>,

            Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to you. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s pretty boring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, isn't it? But it
strikes me that I have in you a tremendous resource: instead of wondering what
it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> can possibly be thinking when they say or do something I
don't understand at all, I can ask you! So here is my question: Why do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> so much? Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> have noted how far
to the right he is on many issues--he loves corporate capitalism (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>, for
example); his judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointments</ENAMEX> have been very centrist; he favors the
death penalty, the anti-drug war, balanced budgets, welfare reform and many
other causes dear to the right. It's true he's not a homophobe like so many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">right-wingers</ENAMEX>, but it's not as though he's actually done anything for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>
(except, as you've noted, get more of them than ever kicked out of the armed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX>). Ditto on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>--he's not opposed to affirmative action, but he
expended no political capital defending it--as in fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s Prop.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> he's done a bit more for--but even there, more for show than in
reality.

            For a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of materialist turn of mind, like me, it is hard to understand
the vitriolic hatred of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator -Scaife-Rutherford Institute</ENAMEX> side of the spectrum. And not just
there, either. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> should love this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who accomplishes so much of
their agenda while bewitching so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>! A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> could never have
pushed through welfare reform, or the crime bill, without raising a major storm
of protest.

            Is it all really about sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and rock and roll, after all?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Katha

         
      
   
