
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish n Chips</ENAMEX>
            

            Katha,
No, I'm in favor of abolishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British National Health Service</ENAMEX> altogether,
and letting the market take care of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s healthcare, and the
government coming in to rescue those who fall through the cracks. This would
probably lead, I'd guess, to more social spending on health-care as a
percentage of GNP, and would more accurately reflect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s real balance of
needs and wants. What it would avoid is the impossible politicization of
health-care. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, you regularly have parliamentary debates in which some
limit is imposed on health-care spending and some huffy back-bencher (once
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX>, now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX>) demands why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> for health just murdered his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>. It's an impossible position to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> in, and brings out
their worst instincts, of pandering, emotionalism and over-spending.

            Yes, yes, I know, because of insurance and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, there is no true
market for healthcare, but we should try to approximate one as best we can, so
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s real desires (and not some political hack's view of
them)determine the structure of healthcare. And yes, health is not a good like,
say, computers, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> should step in and help those who really can't
help themselves - but as a last resort. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, the new treatments--mainly
pioneered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> by big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> trying to make profits, not do
good--are far cheaper than the alternative of doing nothing and so economics
should and will guarantee that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need them (and can take them
responsibly) should get them. The notion that large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need
the meds can't get them is, I think, overstated. Some of the biggest drops in
death rates have been among the poor and racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. But do some people
fall through the cracks? Yes. Should we do all we can to find them and help
them? Yes. But can state-of-the-art treatment of every illness be guaranteed to
every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>? Not in a universe of limited funding, which is the universe we
live in. But without the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> freeish market health system, there would be far
less effective treatments to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            As to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, I don't think our cultural differences are merely related to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> distortion. Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I know who have lived there concur. It sounds
like a living hell. And the only way I have ever enjoyed eating <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> is deep
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fried</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">batter</ENAMEX>, wrapped in newsprint. And lots of vinegar.

            best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
