
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>, you know perfectly well that I support the right of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marry</ENAMEX>, for exactly the reasons of civil liberties and civil rights you cite.
You even anthologized my essay on the subject. So please don't get on your high
horse about gay marriage with me.

            And who exactly is this "left" that shuns "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fidelity and bourgeois bliss</ENAMEX>"?
Outside some small gay subcultures, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sex Panic</ENAMEX>, I think there are few who
take this position on principle -- i.e. yes you must have sex outside your
relationship, and no, you can't have a nice quiet domestic life with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. (I don't know that I'd call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>, world-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> many times over, "bourgeois," exactly, by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>.) In practice, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of all political persuasions are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unfaithful</ENAMEX> and choose other things -- fame, power,excitement, variety,
attention, distance -- over making a sane, responsible life with a loved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. And many -- especially in the gay world and maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
too-- have "bourgeois bliss" with a life <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and sexual excitement
somewhere else. I don't think politics has much to do with these intimate only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-conscious decisions, it comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">someplace</ENAMEX> deeper.

            Face it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>: as ideology,family values rule, left, right and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>! In
practice, they compete with all the other exigencies and opportunities of
reality and human nature.

            Just for the record: my own relationship is so square it's cubic. It's just
not a legal marriage. I think you are making a mistake to equate distaste for
wedlock with libertinism. There are many more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> to these
issues!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Katha

         
      
   
