
   
   
      
         
            Thanks for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recovered Memories</ENAMEX>

            Is it possible to forget a memory? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> poses this paradoxical
question apropos of the continuing fallout from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s controversial
newsmagazine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Tailwind</ENAMEX>." To refresh your memory, the
story's central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Van Buskirk</ENAMEX>, claimed to have watched as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX> dropped sarin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Laotian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. He also claimed to have killed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> defectors with a phosphorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">grenade</ENAMEX> during the mission. It soon
emerged, though, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Buskirk</ENAMEX> had failed to note this seemingly noteworthy
recollection in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> book on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. Why? As other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> poked holes
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> expose, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Buskirk</ENAMEX> confessed that he had "recovered the
memory."

            But how do we know that such memories represent real, rather than imagined,
events?

            Freud grappled with this very dilemma in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX>
he came up with his seduction theory, which linked hysteria to repressed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> of sexual molestation during childhood. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years later</TIMEX>, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX> decided that these were not, in fact, real memories; they were
fantasies.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fast-forward</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, the heyday of pop psychology. A backlash is
brewing against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX> who are considered too skeptical of recovered
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX>, and a new movement is born: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Repressed Memory Therapy</ENAMEX>. By the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> are crowded with self-help guides on how to deal with
"repressed memory syndrome." The message is always the same: If you're feeling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alienated</ENAMEX>, disaffected, unmotivated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> that inner voice--you probably were
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of sexual abuse. Then the inevitable occurs: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Franklin</ENAMEX> is convicted of raping and murdering a playmate of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years earlier</TIMEX>. The centerpiece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>'s case is a recovered
memory.

            It turned out, though, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> had been hypnotized by her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">therapist</ENAMEX> to help remember the details of the event. The case was thrown out a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years back</TIMEX>, but the question remains: What if these so-called repressed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> are simply the product of the power of psychoanalytic persuasion?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> asked that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ofshe</ENAMEX>, a social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> at
UC-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, and his answer was refreshingly unambiguous: "There is no mental
mechanism that could create this ignorance of memory. If anything, things of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traumatic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> are more likely to be remembered than forgotten." Recovered
memory therapy? <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Ofshe</ENAMEX> prefers the term "psychotherapy malpractice."

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Buskirk</ENAMEX>, well, we may never know exactly what happened out there.
But we do have some clues. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> who treated <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> veterans
reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had been in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank regiment</ENAMEX> visualized being trapped
inside a burning tank, though it never actually happened. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades later</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> who had never been captured acted out the experience of having been
tortured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Cong</ENAMEX>.

            Even more bizarre: As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Pendergrast</ENAMEX> writes in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Memory: Incest Accusations and Shattered Lives</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> in a
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>, recalled seeing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>'s head explode
during a firefight. When one of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group members</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to
help put together a surprise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for him, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was shocked: "What? He's
in a veterans' recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>? But he was rated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. He</ENAMEX> never was allowed to go
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>!"

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Mahler</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
