
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Idiot Box: Docudramatic Tension</ENAMEX>

            Those longing, in this suddenly post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>, for more real-life melodrama to watch on television have good news: This
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> week of sweeps brings plenty of docudramas (one starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Bacall</ENAMEX>)
and jazzed-up documentaries to slake our thirst for TV-enhanced reality. Even
the regular fictional series are borrowing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s headlines or real-life
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> ratings, a practice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as old</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>.


            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s version of truth (or something resembling it) is
stranger than fiction and often more entertaining as well. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>'s blend
of fact and fiction is part of its very design; the tube creates a living-room
world that sometimes seems as real as our own. It's the perfect environment for
biopics, infotainment, or fictional cover-ups.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Friday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>) conspiracy, with tips of the hat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files ,</ENAMEX> rules the airwaves. Homicide
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>) wraps up a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part "cross-over"
episode that began on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX> and Order <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of
crime-stoppers plumb a murky murder mystery connected somehow to a lesbian sex
scandal and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. There's even a nefarious independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>
who abuses both key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and our heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>! Unfortunately, the
story line is as convoluted as an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-Files alien episode, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>
crime shows lack the energy--and the charismatic lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>--of their glory
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. Still, it's good to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Homicide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> finally spending more
time solving crimes than pursuing their boring office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">romances</ENAMEX>.

            Dark doings continue on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Carter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Millennium</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Black</ENAMEX> (well played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance Henriksen</ENAMEX>), the grim
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ex-FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who can enter the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>, learns more about the past
of the mysterious, influential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium Group</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX>'s role.
Oddly enough, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> hasn't run into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files</ENAMEX> ' all-powerful
Syndicate yet.

            No one's bothered with the generally mirthless
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years or so</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 p.m.</TIMEX>). may be an episode to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least</NUMEX> glance at. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, fresh off his rave reviews in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rushmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, while the wonderful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Williams</ENAMEX>, the unconventionally emotional and compelling country-rock
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">singer-songwriter</ENAMEX>, is the musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> is docudrama heaven. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too Rich--The Secret Life of Doris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Bacall</ENAMEX> gives a bitchy
grande dame performance as the world's richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. There's something
perversely reassuring about a great beauty who had it all--and still ended up a
drug-addled wretch manipulated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Machiavellian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Chamberlain</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bacall</ENAMEX>'s performance has echoes of her <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tony Award-</ENAMEX> winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo Channing</ENAMEX> role,
all patrician bite and bluster. Told in flashbacks, the film drags a bit when
the younger version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay Frost</ENAMEX>, is on screen, but jumps
to life every time the formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacall</ENAMEX> speaks her mind. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, compare
Bacall with the real thing in a documentary called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Duke</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lonely</ENAMEX>
Heiress on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A&E</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>). The big mystery of her death:
Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butler</ENAMEX> do it?

            Enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seaminess</ENAMEX>: For moral uplift, check out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s Passing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glory</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>). It's a stirring true tale of an all-black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that faces off with the best white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in the segregated New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orleans</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. The film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rip Torn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Braugher</ENAMEX>,
riveting as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> leading his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in a drive to integrate school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">athletics</ENAMEX>. Although supposedly based on real events, it also feels phony at
times. Is there a federal law that says all basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flicks</ENAMEX> must end with one
shot that determines everything?

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, a series of genuine documentaries square off
against reality-inspired programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> gives us <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And the Beat Goes On: The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher Story</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). This hagiography, produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bono</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, includes the mandatory scene of the downtrodden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> working out his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterpieces</ENAMEX>. Here it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX> (a bland <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Underwood</ENAMEX>), dressed in a fur vest,
plucking out "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Got You</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee Faia</ENAMEX> does a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX> impersonation as good as
any drag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>'s, but her sullen pouting and his whining make it seem like a
long <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCTV</ENAMEX> skit featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Martin</ENAMEX>. (See the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bono</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VH-1</ENAMEX>'s
Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Music</ENAMEX> episode at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX>) True artistry is displayed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bravo</ENAMEX>'s portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Jimmy Scott</ENAMEX>, the
troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> with the angelic voice of a jazz diva (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>). His fans
include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Charles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Reed</ENAMEX>, and you're likely to become one,
too.

            Genuine immigration abuses are the backdrop for the schlocky murder mystery,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Line</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>), which marks the return to
television of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Stringfield</ENAMEX> (formerly of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> ). But the
single-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>-in-peril subplot is so trite it's a wonder she can stay awake, never
mind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>. A better bet for drama is Meltdown at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Three Mile</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>), a tense documentary narrative on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> nuclear
accident.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other docs are worth your attention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Learning Channel</ENAMEX>'s
gritty Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Press Corps</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>); and "RFK
vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>," which offers fake footage of look-alike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> over real audio tape
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> scheming (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). It's competing with a comic take on
politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>), featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd</ENAMEX> as yet another wacky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Fox</ENAMEX>. This time around, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lloyd</ENAMEX>
believes he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messiah</ENAMEX>.

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammys</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX>), expect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX> to be treated like the musical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messiah</ENAMEX> with her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
nominations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX>, a symbol of the blandness that
usually afflicts the awards.

            All the best <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> series ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frasier</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> ) have sweeps- driven episodes, but perhaps the most powerful
program <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> is the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Boy's Life</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>), with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> as an abusive stepdad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tyrannizing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>.

            It's based, of course, on a true story.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Levine</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
