
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            Katha,
Did you write that pre-caffeine?

            I never said or even implied you didn't support equal marriage rights. I
merely protested that it is simply wrong to conflate the cultural arguments for
marriage rights with the political ones. Which seems to me to be the point
you're making in your response. So we agree. But in your previous posting - and
in your piece in my marriage anthology - it is you who equated married life
with certain "conservative" impulses, and (gently) warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> not to
idealize it. You can't have it both ways.

            But you're right, of course, that marriage can be interpreted and lived a
zillion different ways; that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in non-marital bliss can be more
conservative in their way of life than some with church white weddings. But
you're exaggerating surely when you say that the left has completely acceded to
"family values". The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have, but the Left? In lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>? All your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> ? Come off it.

            Speaking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Left</ENAMEX>, I'm glad that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> has clarified itself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> is a liberal interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> designed to advance liberal
policies with regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (if abortion on demand can be described as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX>) and consistently has no truck with abused or harrassed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who might
in other circumstances hold conservative views. Both right and left in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> are like this, of course. (I'm not saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> is worse in the
hypocrisy game than, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> which, bizarrely, supports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>). The ends for all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> always justify the means. How else
to explain the discrepancies between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX>'s positions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Packwood</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>? But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">NOW</TIMEX> at least has the good grace to admit it,
and to get on with the nasty game of political warfare.

            bye for now
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
