
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hundred Years Of Something Or Other</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Library</ENAMEX> raised a ruckus with its "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> best novels
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>" list. It also sold a ton of books--which made a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">non-fiction</ENAMEX> books" list inevitable. It will be released at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BookExpo</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> complaint about the earlier list (aside from the basic crassness
of the enterprise) was that it had been made from a checklist prepared by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> turned out to be not such a bad thing. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to vote, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> novels were by either <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ayn Rand or L. Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbard</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Only Orwell</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolkien</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rings</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Kill a Mockingbird</ENAMEX> cracked the magic circle.)

            A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> complaint: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> was too white and too male. So the new panel
has: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maya Angelou</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Boorstin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.S. Byatt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caleb Carr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Cerf</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Chernow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelby Foote</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Jay Gould</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vartan Gregorian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Karr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Krakauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Pagels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn See</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Styron</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vidal</ENAMEX>.

            It will be hard to make this work. Another problem is that there's vastly
more good non-fiction than fiction.

            And what is "non-fiction"? Does it include science, clearing a path
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas Kuhn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Thomas</ENAMEX>? Philosophy, psychology? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camus</ENAMEX>'s The
Rebel is an automatic. But do you include dazzling prose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigmund Freud</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William James</ENAMEX>? Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nietzsche</ENAMEX>'s posthumous (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX> ) Ecce
Homo get safe passage out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Butler</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX> of All Flesh so bizarrely did on the fiction list?

            Literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reportage</ENAMEX> ought to make up the bulk of the list. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rebecca West</ENAMEX>
should get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half-dozen</NUMEX> listings but will be lucky to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Lamb</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grey Falcon</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditto A.J. Liebling</ENAMEX> (probably for The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Earl</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> ). How fictional can this non-fiction be? Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executioner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Song</ENAMEX> get on? How about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Harris</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Life and</ENAMEX>
Loves ? Prize-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> being present- centered and friendship-bound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McPhee</ENAMEX> could interlope.

            A lot of absolute crap could make it: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frantz Fanon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wretched of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fear and Loathing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> . Good
stuff will be lost. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Feminists</ENAMEX> could shut out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simone de Beauvoir</ENAMEX>'s The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX>
Sex as too tame. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maya Angelou</ENAMEX> doesn't argue for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Jarrell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poetry</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> (and she won't), who will? Someone must argue (it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX>'s job) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Bouton</ENAMEX>'s exquisite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ball Four</ENAMEX> , the first modern
sports book. And what about those journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macdonald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cyril Connolly</ENAMEX>--who never, strictly speaking, wrote a real prose
book?

            Is there an automatic place for the top consciousness-raising tracts of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fifties</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Riesman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lonely Crowd</ENAMEX> ), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman O. Brown</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Body</ENAMEX> ), seventies (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lasch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Culture of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Narcissism</ENAMEX> ), and eighties (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Bloom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Closing of the American</ENAMEX>
Mind )? A tempting (and sensible) option is to split the difference between
influence and style by picking the top books about the major events of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>: Communism (snubbing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker Chambers</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Witness</ENAMEX> would be a
scandal), race and colonialism (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gunnar Myrdal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An American Dilemma</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Octavio Paz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Labyrinth of Solitude</ENAMEX> ); modern art (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s A Room
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Own</ENAMEX> , alas; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Wilson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Axel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle</ENAMEX> , if To the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finland Station</ENAMEX> misses under Communism); and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> (with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s diary likely to top the whole list).

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Caldwell</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
