
   
   
      
         
            Fun for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whole Family</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s hit family series <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Heaven</ENAMEX> has been
celebrated for its uncommon pleasantness and normalcy by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> as
disparate as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> . Now, you
can indulge the show in that fashion if you've seen it once or twice, but after
repeated viewing you can't help suspecting that its niceness is the punch line
to a dark joke. The show revolves around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>: a genial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, his tightly wound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> ( <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?), and a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> bring
home the social diseases of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>--sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, mainly--and the parents
dispel them with the dreamlike reasonableness of a ministerial counseling
session. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is grounded for coming in late? Just when you
expect him to clutch his head and moan, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dean</ENAMEX> in Rebel Without a
Cause , "You're tearing me apart!," he smiles cheerfully at his punishment
and trots off to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. A bottle of over-the-counter speed is discovered in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>? She didn't know it contained the
dangerous but not yet outlawed substance ephedrine. Once she finds out, father
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> join forces in proselytizing against it.

            The dark joke here, of course, is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '60s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '70s</TIMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> disorder we are alleged to have inherited from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>. Set in the
present, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Heaven</ENAMEX> is nonetheless a revisionist view of the
past--what that era of cultural upheaval might have looked like if the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> had had its way with it. (It is not a coincidence that
when the show flagged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its second season</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX> to
flack it to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, or that reruns are shown on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pax TV</ENAMEX>.)  Never has a
show so skillfully exploited contemporary retro-chic to rewrite our visual
image of history. Everything in its universe is '70s revival, from the
sartorial style--tight button-down shirts, clingy pants, long straight hair for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">girls</ENAMEX>, floppy mops for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>--to the lighting design, which is warm and dim in
the manner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family and The Brady Bunch</ENAMEX> , to the static
camerawork, as deftly evocative of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '70s</TIMEX> television as anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarantino</ENAMEX> has filmed. (I hadn't grasped how <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> and stolid the framing was
until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, when, while filming a concert by the pathetic dregs of a
real '70s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, the camera tilted sardonically, just for an instant.)
Even the casting functions as a form of allusion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Watson</ENAMEX> as eldest son
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX> has the soulful eyes, clean-cut yet girlish features, and long dark shag
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Partridge</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Biel</ENAMEX> as eldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> has the center part and
symmetrical eyes and mouth of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Brady</ENAMEX>. The middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>, is the
reincarnation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. And</TIMEX> on it goes, the show doing battle against our dour
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> of those so-called anni horribili with a self-referential
perkiness that would do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> proud.

            The difference between then and now, though, is that while family life in
those real '70s shows was unrealistically goofy, in this fake '70s show it's
strangely isolated and defensive--a little too warm on the inside, a little too
besieged by countercultural horrors on the outside. Consider the absurdly
anachronistic flower-power band that visited its old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, in last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">night</ENAMEX>'s episode, for instance, and how afraid he was that they'd bring
marijuana into his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Or how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are always turning up
with strange addictions, illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, or the need to slice
themselves--cautionary examples of family disintegration for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
steer clear of, or at least try to staunch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camdens</ENAMEX> aren't raising a
family; they're fighting a culture war, no matter how gentle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christianity</ENAMEX> may seem, and underneath the pop-cultural giddiness there's a
missionary zeal that comes off as more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Confidential</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX> 
               Bunch. What do you imagine happens to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s friend
when she ignores the warnings issued by the good reverend to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and the
preaching of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> herself and defiantly keeps popping ephedrine? She nearly
drops dead of a heart attack.

            The most troubling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of all, however, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Annie</ENAMEX>, played
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Hicks</ENAMEX> with a not-quite-comic tension that never seems to achieve
release. Wielding her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windex</ENAMEX> bottle like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>, smashing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleenexes</ENAMEX> into the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-old</TIMEX>'s mouth to retrieve illicit pieces of chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie</ENAMEX> is a
counterfactual from hell--what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX> would probably be like if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Friedan</ENAMEX> had never published <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Feminine Mystique</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mothering</ENAMEX> is loving but grim, and she's prone to irrational outbursts the rest
of the family has to tiptoe around. There's the time her widower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> showed
up with his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie</ENAMEX> refused to speak to her. The theme that
episode was: How can we get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> to behave? Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> couldn't have been more
understanding, but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s emotionalism was so impervious to logic it became
disturbing. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie</ENAMEX> is always slightly more disturbing than any other
character is allowed to be, a sense of inexpressible rage hovering somewhere in
the vicinity of her brightly upturned mouth. She makes you realize with
gratitude that not even the show's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Hampton</ENAMEX>, can force the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> back into its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> without having a little female frustration
leak out.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
