
   
   
      
         
            Partly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>

            Went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Opera</ENAMEX>'s
production of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Abduction</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seraglio</ENAMEX> , which is nearing the end
of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-month</TIMEX> run.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> is something I know zilch about. Whenever I go, I recall an essay I
read in college. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>--either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Shklovsky</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakobson</ENAMEX>--described ostranenie (or "making strange"). Great art, the
critic implied, hews (comfortingly) to the familiar, but cultivates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of
mind that (challengingly) make the familiar fresh. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, we budding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">artistes</ENAMEX> found this doctrine a congenial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, since you could carry it out by
getting drunk before lectures or going to breakfast stoned.

            But the essay's example was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolstoy</ENAMEX>'s use of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Natasha Rostova in War</ENAMEX> and
Peace . At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolstoy</ENAMEX>'s balls, teas, and operas, even jaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> get to see
everything anew--because we see it through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natasha</ENAMEX>'s gushing teeny-bopper
heart. At balls, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natasha</ENAMEX> doesn't understand the music and looks at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s faces.
At teas, she doesn't understand the conversation and concentrates on the cakes.
At operas, she doesn't understand what's going on onstage and just scans at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>.

            It's a good point, but it was lost on us, since we were all more or less
unfamiliar with balls, teas, and operas ourselves. So perhaps I'm just
extrapolating a generalized boobery out of my own specific ignorance. But
whenever I go to the opera I feel like I'm in a roomful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natashas</ENAMEX>.

            The show-stealer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> was the baritone <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunter Missenhardt</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasha</ENAMEX>'s sadistic overseer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osmin</ENAMEX>. He has sung the role in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half dozen</NUMEX> big
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, and seems made for it--burly and snarly, with a gift for
violent gesture.

            But for this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, the delight was more than operatic. At the
end of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act 3, Osmin</ENAMEX> catches the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> trying to escape their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">captivity</ENAMEX>. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasha</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them, he would be within his rights to
hang them. He pardons them, of course, and sends them on their cooing way. But
while he's thinking it over, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osmin</ENAMEX> goes into a paroxysm of bloodthirst,
demanding that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> be <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> decapitated, then hanged, then impaled, then
burnt at the stake, then tied up and drowned, and then flogged:

            
               Erst gekopft, dann gehangen,
dann gespiesst auf heisse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stangen</ENAMEX>,
dann verbrannt, dann gebunden
und getaucht, zuletzt geschunden.
            

            Osmin delivers this tirade while jumping and grunting and flapping his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX>.
In so doing, he shows us that a great deal of sadism, animality, and outright
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lust</ENAMEX> can lurk behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s anodyne professions that they just want to
"uphold the law" or "maintain a level of decency." To fall afoul of the tiniest
law or custom is to issue orgy-invitations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>.

            Washingtonians know this. It's what lawmaking nowadays is all about.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is our leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Osmin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, having nearly lost his office
for conduct that in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> would be considered praiseworthy. But he's
also our leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osminist</ENAMEX>. Look at how deadbeat dads are jailed, how drug-
using small-fry get put away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, how the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who continue
to smoke are gradually being made liable for the entire federal budget.

            So it wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missenhardt</ENAMEX>'s singing--marvelous though that was--that made
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osmin</ENAMEX>'s rantings so thrilling. It was that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natashas</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> had suddenly recognized themselves. And we are all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Osminists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Caldwell</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
