
   
   
      
         
            Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May Day</TIMEX>
            

            Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May Day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Katha</ENAMEX>,

            A big day at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> , I'm sure. Unisex tweeds, seminars on family
values, reminiscences of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX>, sherry all round. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> , all we
got was a large, inflatable menora over <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">19th Street</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s birthday.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Socialists</ENAMEX> have all the fun.

            Some eternal truths in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s papers. The IRA refuses to disarm. And their
intransigence we are supposed to be grateful for. Why is it that, in the press,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> if they enter "peace" negotiations but not blackmailing
murderers if they keep their semtex and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX>? Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX> learned
something from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> continues to reform. Why is it that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
gets such a terrible press, I wonder? What he has achieved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monumental</ENAMEX>, and just when he is dismissed as a buffoon, he tries once again,
against the odds, to keep economic reform on track. His personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unpredictability</ENAMEX> is arguably essential to keep his many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> off balance.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy, for all its woes, is now in recovery. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has
expanded without a revanchist response; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> is still
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just</NUMEX>)intact. What more could we want? Yet it is fashionable to deride this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX> as a drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autocrat</ENAMEX>. I don't get it. Maybe some of the tweedies
are nostalgic for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s press conference was a classic. It reminded me of the only good
scene in Primary Colors when he learns that he may have made a young
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> pregnant. "Can't I ever get a break?" he laments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incapacity</ENAMEX> to take responsibility is fathomless. My favorite quote of the day
is from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webb Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> phone calls to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, saying he'll have to
take the hit for not cooperating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose Law Firm</ENAMEX> inquiry: "I will not
raise those allegations that might open it up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> ... So I need to roll
over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time."

            Just who does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> think he's kidding in all of this? Except most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
