
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Andrew</ENAMEX>,

            You didn't just accuse me of complicity in murder, did you? If we want to
get into evil empires and who supports them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have a great deal to
answer for: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> apartheid and other anti-democratic regimes around
the globe--and don't forget the genocidal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>, supported, not by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, but by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">govt</ENAMEX>! Things are not so simple as us-good, them-bad. And
there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> positions. I didn't defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> while it
existed, so why should I do so now? Soviet-style Communism is not my idea of
"the left."

            I agree with you about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thatcherite</ENAMEX> propensities. Although I
suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't see it that way, or they wouldn't have delivered
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tories</ENAMEX> (your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, as I remember) such a smashing defeat. It strikes me, by
the way, that you have given yourself the heads-I-win-tails-you-lose position.
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tories</ENAMEX> had defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, you would have taken it as their vindication
and the final trouncing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Left</ENAMEX>. Faced with the fact that your side in fact
lost the election, you simply declare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> an honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX>. But what about
the real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tories</ENAMEX>?

            I may be wrong, of course, but I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is on its way to solid
prosperity, more like <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-world extremes of rich and poor. I think what's
going on now is basically the looting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s resources by an elite of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">ex-communists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mafiosi</ENAMEX>. Although maybe, when things get bad
enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> can come in and built some sweatshops there!

            You know, for generations <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> told themselves the sufferings imposed
by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> were temporary, necessary sacrifices--usually to be made by
someone else--on the way to a better world. It seems to me you are making the
same argument on behalf of unbridled market capitalism, and with the same
self-exception: it's always easy to be stoical on other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s behalf! Do you
have a time limit in mind for your experiment?

            Talk to you soon,
Katha

         
      
   
