
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

                   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on welfare: I have no problem with the idea of supporting
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to take care of their own small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But if they are to
be made to work, they should be paid decent wages (for example, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, the wages of the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who did those jobs before workfare). They
should have vacations, benefits, proper clothing, recourse for grievances,
bathroom breaks (and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX>!), and all the other things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> get
that workfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> don't get, or get only sporadically. And their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of other working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> too--should have good child
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>. We <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> profess to be so concerned with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and education, and
early brain development, and on and on, and even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> working moms are subject
to tremendous amounts of disapproval for supposedly compromising their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s whatever, no matter how terrific their child-care arrangements are,
but now we are taking the most vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and saying we don't care what
kind of arrangements you make, just show up for your sub-minimum-wage
street-cleaning job, which will hardly ever lead to a real job, and which you
have to drop out of school to get to. It's very punitive--to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
       From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , this stop-the-presses news on
condoms-in-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> programs: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Condom Access Shows No Effect on Teen Sex</ENAMEX>
Rate," which evoked this response from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gracie Hsu</ENAMEX>: "You are laying down a standard that says teen-age sexual behavior
is fine so long as you use condoms." Well, no--isn't that like saying that
giving your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> vitamin pills means you don't care if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> eat nothing
but junk <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>? Originally sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> claimed to oppose condoms
because they would provoke more sex. If they have no such effect, why continue
to oppose them?
       What do you make of this from the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> perspective? It is as though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gracie Hsu</ENAMEX> cares more about keeping condoms away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> than about keeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. I hate her.
       Talk to you tomorrow,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Katha

            P.S. I would be for condom access in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> even if it did mean
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> would have sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STDs</ENAMEX>, pregnancy--these are much more serious
problems, it seems to me, than virginity. Better <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> rubberized
deflorations than a single dead young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or another unhappy young mom
picking up <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>.
       But have you noticed that the big conservative welfare reform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> never
talk about birth control? You'd think they'd love it, but they don't.

         
      
   
