
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May Day</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May Day</TIMEX>!
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marchers</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CP</ENAMEX>-style demo? Are you sure you weren't wearing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pairs
of glasses? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday my</TIMEX> study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (go ahead, laugh) met to discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henwood</ENAMEX>'s new book Wall Street (I missed this session because I hadn't
read the book) and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX> they went to a demonstration in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union Square</ENAMEX>,
that was supposed to be of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> sweatshop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and came away reeling:
maybe fifteen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, mostly ancient sectarians and a few young ones, all full
of the old rhetoric (a moment of silence followed by a "moment of rage" with
raised fists but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't know how to do it, memories of the black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>' stand at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mexico City Olympics</ENAMEX> having faded). The last demo I went
to (with this same study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, so clearly we are picking up the wrong
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leaflets</ENAMEX>) was the same: tiny, futile gatherings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who, whatever their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ages</ENAMEX>, are living in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">l933</TIMEX>. There are a lot of weirdos on the sectarian left, as
on the right--and as the left collapses, those weirdos get even weirder. I
certainly have never heard anyone say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ukrainians</ENAMEX> killed themselves (in the
collectivizations of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20s and 30s</TIMEX>, I assume you mean). The view I have
heard, not exactly a political program, more like an ethnic slur, is that (fill
in the blank) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern European</ENAMEX> ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> deserved whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>
dished out because they were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic Hitler</ENAMEX>-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>.

            But you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>, there is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Leninist</ENAMEX> left, that believes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX> and other localized forms of ownership, that opposes vanguard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and state power left and right. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> perspectives
here.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Katha

         
      
   
