
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rugrats anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>?

            Last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosh Hashanah</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ran a comic strip
based on the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' TV show <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rugrats</ENAMEX> , in which the main
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Pickles</ENAMEX>, is taken to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX>. He
listens in fascinated befuddlement as all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> around him utter the
Hebrew words to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaddish</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> prayer for the dead. He sits on
the lap of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>, who is very old and has a long nose.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> issued an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note declaring
that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> should have known better than to run the comic strip and
reporting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> had complained to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX>, which produces it,
as well as to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that distributes it.

            What was wrong with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rugrats</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note said "the
depiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worshipers</ENAMEX> and use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaddish</ENAMEX> were
inappropriate." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, interviewed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> newspaper the
Forward , said it had had scores of calls and that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX>
were upset about the inclusion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaddish</ENAMEX>, although a few were incensed by
the length of the nose.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> was faced with a genuine
dilemma but made exactly the wrong call. There is a tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>
caricature featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> with hideous noses, some of which has been used to
justify persecution. (Think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> publication <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Der Stuermer</ENAMEX> .) That
might have been cause for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note pointing out that while some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may have taken offense, none was intended. But there's no excuse for
censoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonists</ENAMEX> (even after the fact) because they've used religion as
their subject matter. That's like saying <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> can't focus on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, or that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Starr</ENAMEX> prays, she can't use language from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prayer</ENAMEX>. Since there was no mockery in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rugrats</ENAMEX> depiction of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaddish</ENAMEX>-- just one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX>'s curiosity -- one can only
conclude the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> deemed the comic strip, as a medium, insufficiently
dignified for serious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. That would be news to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Spiegelman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maus</ENAMEX> --comic-book accounts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> .
            

            As it turns out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rugrats</ENAMEX> TV show is much beloved among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for its helpful and sympathetic depictions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passover Seders</ENAMEX>. So the complainers were not only trying to
abridge freedom of expression, they were wildly off-base. But what's shocking
is that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> gave in to them.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
