
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Are All on Good Morning America</ENAMEX>
            

            Katha,
Sorry to hear about the email. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delete</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delete</ENAMEX>!

            Yes, we're all on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Morning America</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, except me. I've
never been on it, and never seen it (way too early). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX> was absolutely
prescient about that, although surely the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> ideal will pale in
significance as it becomes truer and truer. I had my epiphany when I was asked
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years back</TIMEX> to be an MSNBC whateveritis. Stuck on a set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>,
blathering soundbites about things I know nothing about, watched by a couple of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, morphing into all those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">GenX</ENAMEX> punditclones, who have
subsequently, mercifully, disappeared into the ether. Hell on earth. It's also
a common observation now, first voiced, I think, by our saintly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley, that it only takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about fifteen minutes</TIMEX> for those of us in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media-warp</ENAMEX>, to channel surf before we stumble across someone we know. So much
for the prestige of the box.

            Nevertheless, it still amazes me how powerful TV still is. The response I've
gotten from TV vastly dwarves any feedback I've received from my writing. At
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Correspondents</ENAMEX>' Dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX> (sorry I missed you) I
found myself at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point walking absent-mindedly behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cavett</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> who lined the walls literally screamed and clapped and cheered as he
walked by them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> grabbed him ecstatically and handed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> a
camera. It was truly menacing. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula</ENAMEX>, of course, was made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
surely will be. The complete fusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> of politics by celebrity, was perfectly exemplified by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>.
Anyone's power was related almost perfectly to their media exposure. The sole
exception to this, I suppose, is the equally saintly TV-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>. But
can those of us without her wonderful perch manage to be so pure? I'm not
pretending to be above all this, merely partly horrified at my own
complicity.

            Can you grant absolution?

            best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
