
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crying Wolf</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> girding themselves for the labor of impeaching a
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would have had reason to feel proud if they happened to read
the Wall Street 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's opinion page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>. There, in an
elevated style more common to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> public address than to newspaperese, was
the argument for voting one's conscience rather than one's poll numbers:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greatness</ENAMEX> and transcendence are why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> join political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and why
they go to war. It is why they risk and sacrifice, and engage in political
argument. Ultimately they are moved by principle, and will for its sake throw
aside or forgo the material things that scoundrel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> think they hold
above all else."

            The editorial was written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Helprin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>' answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helprin</ENAMEX> is a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memoir</ENAMEX> from Antproof
Case , A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldier</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great War</ENAMEX> ) whose great theme is the nobility
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> and his worldview. He is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's
editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and a cowriter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> resignation speech.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helprin</ENAMEX> has called for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first days</TIMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair. His arguments have a real resonance (to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, anyway),
since they go to the heart of the matter, at least as high-school English
classes teach us to define it: that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> shapes his actions.
Citing the long record of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s "boldness and mendacity"--not just
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travel Office</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> file coverups, etc.--Helprin
compares the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fibbing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to the model of the self-sacrificing statesman:
"As others move in the light, he will move in the darkness, so that as others
move in darkness, he may move in the light. ... A statesman must have a
temperament that is suited for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Medal of Honor</ENAMEX>, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> that is unafraid
to die."

            Helprin, in short, is a militant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> of political
argument. So what are we to make of the discrepancy between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helprin's</ENAMEX> ideals
and his actions? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helprin</ENAMEX> has an even worse track record than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> when
it comes to stretching the truth so fine it can't be distinguished from a lie.
A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> profile in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> (whose accuracy, it should
be noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helprin</ENAMEX> has challenged) depicted him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who cheerfully admitted
that he couldn't help but spin tall tales, but had learned from hard experience
the downside of doing so: "In my first radio interview, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX> said,
'Tell me about your life.' So I began telling him about how I was a mercenary
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where I became close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. Then there was a
coup and I left with sacks of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX>. I told the story in such a way that it
sounded plausible, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX> kept on saying: 'You're kidding. I can't
believe this. Is this really true?' and I'd say, 'Yes, yes, yes, it's true. Of
course, it's true. . . .' "

            Among stories the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helprin</ENAMEX> fabricated in his
presence , even after making that admission: that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was sold into
slavery; how when he was a teenager he was attacked by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> and received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> stitches without anesthesia. (The fact of the attack is
probably true, but, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> said, the details surrounding it
have changed frequently.) Accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helprin</ENAMEX>'s penchant for amusing or
self-aggrandizing exaggeration are legendary in the literary world. Even his
recent political articles are filled with yarns that make one long for a little
good old-fashioned fact-checking. Take a story he published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes ASAP</ENAMEX> --the tale of how he, a young and lowly private in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> just before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Yom Kippur War</ENAMEX>, understood how unready the army
was for a surprise attack and managed to convey his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golda Meir</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshe Dayan</ENAMEX>. His advice, of course, was tragically ignored.

            It would be naïve to criticize a fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for fabricating fictions;
that's what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> does for a living. But what about when the prevaricator
becomes a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> and tries convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to impeach other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> for prevaricating? As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helprin</ENAMEX> would surely ask, should a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> like
that sit on the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of a major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
