
   
   
      
         
            All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Prot,g</ENAMEX>,s

            Culturebox can't think of a relationship more appalling than the benign bond
alleged to exist between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> and prot,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g,.</ENAMEX> How humiliating for the
supplicant, to grovel before the living proof of his own inadequacy! How
nervewracking for his benefactor, that soon he'll be forced to compete with the
poor resentful bastard! Why, one wonders, don't more prot,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>,s grow up to become
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character assassins</ENAMEX>?

            The short answer is, they do. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the great examples of prot,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ingratitude</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX>, whose <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Torrents of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX> , was a vicious parody of his unusually indulgent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherwood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> dashed it off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX> before submitting it to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>; he was deliberately trying to break his multi-book contract.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>'s portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. I. Lonoff</ENAMEX>, a.k.a. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Malamud</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ghost</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer</ENAMEX> , involves a subtler form of backstabbing: the unkind portrait
masquerading as homage. (See Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> below to see what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>
means.)

            But where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>-murder really thrives is in the somewhat less elevated
genre of literary memoir. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brendan Gill</ENAMEX>'s Here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> is the
most delightful example that comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s mind. Damning with faint
praise and exceptionally witty prose, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gill</ENAMEX> skewers both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ross</ENAMEX> ("As for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> might truly be said not to have had any") and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shawn</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>, by contrast, might be a revenant from some small eighteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX>
court"). Less amusing, but more typical, is an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Atlas</ENAMEX> in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> , in which he offers up the spectacle of himself
cringing at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the feet</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> who helped him with his
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delmore Schwartz</ENAMEX>--and equally nasty portraits of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> themselves. (See Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for a typical exchange between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Kazin</ENAMEX>.)

            Then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Theroux</ENAMEX>, whose book on his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.S. Naipaul</ENAMEX> is
excerpted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> . Never before has Culturebox
encountered such dizzying heights of disingenousness--the prot,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>, pretending to
be taken in by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>, while storing up anecdotes that prove his foulness.
The pinnacle of disingenousness isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theroux's</ENAMEX>, though--it's the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker 's</ENAMEX> headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Enigma of Friendship</ENAMEX>." As if! This is not a nuanced
exploration of the mysterious bonds that form between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. The portrait may
well be accurate--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naipaul</ENAMEX> is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> with a reputation for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warmheartedness</ENAMEX>--but all that can be concluded from the exercise is that, at
best, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one</NUMEX> monster deserved the other. (See Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> for a choice
passage.)

            It was while contemplating further instances of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>-murder in this issue
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> --see the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>"'s paeans to the departing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>'s meditation upon her query, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is</ENAMEX> Housman
hot?" ( Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> )--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> was moved to invent a subgenre,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spiterature</ENAMEX> . It rhymes with literature : literature as spit,
composed in spite. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> are hereby invited to submit suggestions to
culturebox@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> for the most spiteful work of spiterature they've ever
encountered. A warning, however: Should your suggestions turn out to be
superior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox's</ENAMEX>, she might well be forced to write an expose in which
you are roundly damned with her faint praise.

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> : Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Zuckerman</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, who can't stop fussing
with a malfunctioning record-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player arm</ENAMEX>:

            
               This, I realized, is the excruciating scrupulosity, the same
maddening, meticulous attention to every last detail that makes you great, that
keeps you going and got you through and now is dragging you down. Standing with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.I. Lonoff</ENAMEX> over the disobedient arm of his record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, I understood the
celebrated phenomenon for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, his destiny, and his work-all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. What a terrible triumph!
            

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here's Atlas on Kazin:</ENAMEX>

            

               "You know what I don't get about you?" Kazin was studying me intently. "You
don't stand up for yourself. I've read your reviews. You say whatever you want
in print, you take on this big book, and then you sit here like a schoolboy in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>."

               "It's hard," I murmured. "You bully me." The more annoyed he got, the more
unnerved I was. Cowed by his intensity, I was afraid to open my mouth. My way
was to creep up, toss in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">grenade</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delmore</ENAMEX> considered you a serious menace to
criticism"--then melt away before he could get off a shot. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kazin</ENAMEX> liked to
argue; it was a way of working off grievances, improving one's mental
circulation. For him, rudeness was to conversation what polemic was to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>--a style, a genre, an expressive mode.

            

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here's Theroux on Naipaul:</ENAMEX>

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> he had met in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, he said, drank too much. They were
intellectually dead. They were common. They were inferior. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infies</ENAMEX>" was his
name for them. "Listen to the infy," he said while an expatriate held forth in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Common Room</ENAMEX>.

               I had never met anyone so certain, so intense, so observant, so impatient,
so intelligent. He was stimulating and tiring to be with, like a brilliant,
demanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>, exhausting, funny.

            

            
               Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> : Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>:

            
               There were innumerable occasions on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> was right, and
obviously right; but I had a fondness for those times when she was right while
seeming to be wrong, or when she went via wrongness to get to the right stuff.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> claimed to discern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superfluous</ENAMEX> gloss, but what she did was to apply the
invigorating rhetoric of of gloss to the supposedly unglamorous, and thereby
encourage reades to try what they might otherwise disdain; only thus can I
account for her kindly tolerance of my grimmer taste.
            

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
