
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Idiot Box</ENAMEX>

            
               Please note: All times are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Standard</ENAMEX>. Please check local listings
for times in your area.
            

            We're heading into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> home stretch, and you know what joys that
brings--surly department-store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>, brick-like fruitcake, hellish airport
traffic, and reruns on TV. Apparently, even the entertainment industry feels it
deserves a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> break, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to pick through a melange
of series repeats, (mostly mediocre) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movies, and . . . ice
skating.

            What is up with all the ice skating? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holiday Festival</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ice</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:05 PM</TIMEX>) goes head to head with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Boitano Holiday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spectacular</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). Then on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX> brings us Masters of
Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skating</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). I understand the seasonal appeal--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. But please, please, please, bring back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> basketball.

            That said, the TV week doesn't start out too badly. Tapping the surging
Star Wars mania, this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s (non-rerun) Simpsons features
guest voice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Hamill</ENAMEX>, who performs a showstopping rendition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke</ENAMEX>, Be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jedi Tonight</ENAMEX>" in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX> dinner-theatre production of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolls</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). Top- notch chick <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">flick Sense and Sensibility</ENAMEX> is
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX> serves up a smorgasbord of mindless, testosterone-laden
action movies: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:45 PM</TIMEX>) followed by
Marked for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> PM) followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, check out Everybody Loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM). Granted,
you'll miss out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s ritual humiliation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>. But
both shows are airing reruns, and since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX> is kicking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally</ENAMEX>'s scrawny ass
in the ratings, you really should see what the hooplah is about. This episode
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">features Ray</ENAMEX>'s pathetic attempts to get his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in the mood for a holiday
tumble. The concept isn't ground-breaking, but the show's worth watching, if
only for the scene with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> boxers and socks, pushing a floor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sweeper</ENAMEX> around the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> while warbling "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Ghetto</ENAMEX>."

            Come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gotta be Baba</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> proudly presents <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Most Fascinating People</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> . Yes, the queen of celebrity
interviews is a pompous has-been whose primary aim is to reduce her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interviewees</ENAMEX> to tears, but there's a guilty pleasure in seeing just who will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">succumb</ENAMEX> to one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> crying jags. This time around, potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weepers</ENAMEX>
include homerun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sultan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> cum <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geri</ENAMEX>
Halliwell, movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> (and presidential aspirant?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">posterboy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX>, insufferable Titanic director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">King of the World</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calista Flockhart</ENAMEX> (maybe
she'll humiliate herself on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> as well), trash TV god <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>,
and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. As an added teaser, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babs</ENAMEX> is keeping the identity
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s No.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> most fascinating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> under wraps until the show's
close--a shameless marketing ploy, but I'm dying to know which wretched figure
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bimbroglio</ENAMEX> she's chosen. (My money is on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s rerun of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behind the Laughs</ENAMEX> revisits popular sit-coms from TV
history (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed.</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). You don't need to sit through the whole two
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>--particularly when you could be watching figure skating on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>--but flip
over occasionally to see if you can catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> screen test for
the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vinnie Barbarino on Welcome Back, Kotter</ENAMEX> . At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>, music
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> who really care which CDs topped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundscan</ENAMEX> charts this year
may want to turn to a rerun of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">9th Annual Billboard Music Awards</ENAMEX> on
VH1.

            Around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thusday</ENAMEX>, things start to get ugly. Some heartwarming made-for-TV job
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">starring LeAnn Rimes</ENAMEX> is on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), dueling versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Christmas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carol</ENAMEX> are on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:35</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMC</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coneheads</ENAMEX> movie is on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>). . . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> bright spot of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>: At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX> starts its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marathon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Christmas Story</ENAMEX> . This movie captures what being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> is about: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demented</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santas</ENAMEX>, bickering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless</TIMEX> agonizing over whether you'll receive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s hot toy. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>, for my
money,
AGenuineRedRyderCarbineActionTwoHundredShotLightningLoaderRangeModelAirRifle
sounds loads more fun than some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stinkin</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furby</ENAMEX>.) On top of all that, the scene
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralphie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Billingsley</ENAMEX>) pounds the crap out of the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> in a
flurry of profanity and tears is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">finest moments</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, and it is a television wasteland. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>.

            Looking at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s line-up, it's clear the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are betting that, in
your post-holiday stupor, you won't notice the stunning array of box-office
bowsers they're running: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richie Rich</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Medicine Man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8: 05</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poison Ivy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM),
Corrina, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corrina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunston Checks In</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Channel</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). If you've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, they may lobby for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>'s Real
World marathon. Don't do it. Give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>, send them to the movies,
and take refuge in the one decent offering available on the small screen,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM).

            Of course, with airstrikes on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> on alert for terrorist
attacks, and an impeachment vote looming on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, you may just want to keep
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">set</ENAMEX> tuned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>. God forbid you miss the next development in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>
of peace on earth and goodwill toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Cottle</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
