
   
   
      
         
            Headline
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Andrew</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX> marriage gay and straight: of course I can have it both ways. Since there is
marriage, do I think it should be available to all? Yes! Do I think its social
and economic benefits might be better distributed in some other way (health
insurance, for example), are often illusory, come with large helpings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inequality</ENAMEX>, sexism, psychological torment and so on? Yes!

            Is there an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> values "left"? Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> I give you. But I
have to laugh when you talk about my "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> " as
anti-family values types. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Navasky</ENAMEX> -- married forever, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katrina van den Heuvel</ENAMEX>, married, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lingeman</ENAMEX>, another
supersolid family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Winslow</ENAMEX>, ditto. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John and Sue Leonard</ENAMEX>, not only
married but job-sharers, together <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24-7</NUMEX>. Quick mental glance at the rest of the
editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>--usual collection of urban publishing-industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singles</ENAMEX>.
Nobody's even pierced!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Columnists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX>, married (to a stay-at-home
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> no less) with whom he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> (also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by a previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Williams</ENAMEX>, single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Cockburn</ENAMEX>, well okay,
maybe he's a bit of a rogue, I give you him too. But as far as personal conduct
goes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> is probably as conventionally virtuous as any magazine
in the land. Except for 
                  Slate
               , of course.

            As for ideology, I stick to my contention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> values hold sway
partout, except in tiny subcultures. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tagged by the right as
anti-family values <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are actually asserting mainstream ideas, like,
there are many different family forms in contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
are okay, and so forth. But perhaps we should define what we mean by family
values.

            What do those loaded words mean to you?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Katha

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re NOW</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. I always thought, and have written many times,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> was telling some version of the truth, although whether it is
legally actionable, even if she could prove it, which she can't, is another
story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , I seem to remember, took a strong stand that it
was not actionable, because there were no work-related consequences, prompting
a hilarious letter from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> who opined that if the magazine really
believed that it was okay for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> to drop his trousers and ask an employee
for a blowjob, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Republic</ENAMEX> must be a helluva place to work.

            But you know, it isn't just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">NOW</TIMEX> that wants <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> to go away. Just
about everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> feels that way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rutherford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> -- they're very unpopular, even among <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>-of-the-earth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who don't at all condone the sorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shenanigans</ENAMEX> alleged of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Clintonites</ENAMEX> didn't bargain on this, and still don't seem to understand
it.

         
      
   
