
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>: Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May Day</TIMEX>
            

            Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May Day</TIMEX> to you too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>. I must protest the imputation of tweed,
however. In addition to being quietly devoted to family values, without wishing
to force them on others, we <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> are quite modern in our
dress, while agreeing, of course, that others should be able to wear tweed, if
that is their own personal preference.

            Maybe the press portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> as a drunken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autocrat</ENAMEX> because that is what
he is. Are we not talking here about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who shelled his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>?
Who threatened to dissolve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> if they didn't go along with his choice
of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> nobody for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>? Who involved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in the
disastrous <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Chechnya War</ENAMEX>? As for the wonderful new ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> you mention,
I wonder what you make of such facts as the significant decline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
life expectancy (virtually unique in the world), hordes of homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working at jobs who haven't been paid in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>.
The living standard in the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> has risen for the new
entrepreneurial class in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and a few other places. But most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
worse off: something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have significant health
problems.

            The foregoing should not be taken as nostalgia for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> system. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were running the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> are the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are robbing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> blind now.

            More anon,
Katha

         
      
   
