
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Idiot Box: Lemming Chic</ENAMEX>

            Before delving into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming week</TIMEX>'s programming, I have to ask: Why do
they keep letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> appear on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live ?</ENAMEX> I understand
he's a big name in journalism--<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , yadda, yadda,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yadda</ENAMEX>--but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> should not be allowed on television. His performance on
election <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX>, and again after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX>
Address, was painful to behold. He speaks preternaturally slowly, as if
operating underwater, so that watching him in discussion with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>
fast-on- their<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-feet</NUMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> is much like watching a valium addict
trying to communicate with a roomful of meth heads.

            That said, on to less political TV fare. . . First, the bad news: The awards
season continues apace with this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s broadcast of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">56th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe Awards</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). The ad in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> says it all: "As glamorous
and unpredictable as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> themselves!" "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insipid</ENAMEX> and self-absorbed" would
be more accurate. You'd be better entertained watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>'s back-to-back
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">showings of Dirty Dancing</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7 PM & 9 PM</ENAMEX>).

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> scene is equally dismal (unless you happen to care who's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shagging</ENAMEX> whom on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melrose</ENAMEX>). Like a confused lemming, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> is joining the
animation frenzy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dilbert</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), a new series based on the popular
comic strip by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Adams</ENAMEX>. Don't bother. At its best, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>' comic strip
delivers clever, sarcastic, deadpan humor. The series relies too much on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters shrieking</ENAMEX> and running about. Granted, I've thus far seen only the
pilot episode, but the odds are against major improvement: Dilbert the
comic strip relies heavily on its final frame to deliver a hysterical, twisted
punch line--a formula that does not translate well to television narrative.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s most disturbing offering, turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX>
Weddings: In Style (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). A joint presentation with In Style
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour-long</TIMEX> special is media synergy at its most vapid. Meant to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complement</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>) In 
               Style 's annual weddings issue (featuring
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity couples</ENAMEX>!), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s show lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> bask in the warm nuptial-day
radiance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stamos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Romijn-Stamos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Crawford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivica A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Najimy</ENAMEX>, and so on. I'm getting weepy just thinking about it.

            Apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> have designated this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> as "chick <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>," because
hot on the heels of the celebrity-wedding <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">gawking hour</TIMEX> comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFTV</ENAMEX> movie
My <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Love</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> PM). As a general rule, made-for-TV movies stink. It may
have something to do with the fact that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of them are now filmed
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, I don't know. But they tend to fall into one of three dreary
categories: pathetic pseudo-macho western (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlaw Justice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>), cheesy suspense thriller, or nauseatingly gooey romance--which is where
My <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Love comes in. Basic premise: Dying</ENAMEX> from some unspecified form
of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, the fetching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Allen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Travis</ENAMEX>) quits her high-powered law
career and moves home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> with her precocious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carson</ENAMEX>.
There, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> falls madly in love with a yummy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet-waiter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bairstow</ENAMEX>), who makes her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX> worth living. Throw in a couple of well-
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intentioned</ENAMEX>, overbearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>, tearful reminiscing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>-
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waiter</ENAMEX>'s dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, and repeated shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> gazing soulfully out at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>, and you've got the makings of a movie so overwrought it should
only be shown on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Lifetime</TIMEX>.

            The good viewing news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> is harder to come by, in part because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are going heavy on the repeats. There are, however, a number of top-
notch movie options: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driving Miss Daisy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), Star Wars
Special Edition , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20th</NUMEX> anniversary re-edit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> mega
hit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shawshank Redemption</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tue.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM),
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sting</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tue.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stagecoach</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed.</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM), and,
of course, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porky</ENAMEX>'s trilogy on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FX</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porky's</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porky</ENAMEX>'s 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revenge</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> PM).

            Also noteworthy is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files</ENAMEX> conspiracy marathon on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FX</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mon.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fri.</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). It's an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> - phile's dream come true: no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> vampires, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
werewolves, or homicidal inbred hillbillies--<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just 10 nights</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> excluded)
of biological experimentation, government cover-ups, and little green <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
Regrettably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will also be subjected to "behind the scenes interviews"
serving largely to feed the egos of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. But no viewing
experience is perfect.

            Finally, if the media circus surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bimbroglio</ENAMEX> makes you long for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kinder</ENAMEX>, gentler era, check out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Blue</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> PM). Adding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX> to an already silly show, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s episode features former small-screen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stars Erik Estrada</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHiPs</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam West</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Olsen</ENAMEX>
( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady Bunch</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Bonaduce</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Partridge Family</ENAMEX> ).

            Guaranteed groovy.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Cottle</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
