
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Idiot Box: Be Afraid</ENAMEX>. Or Change the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Channel</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week Two</TIMEX> of sweeps features not only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> mini-series but also a
spate of serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, and even a baby-snatching social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>. If that's not scary enough, be warned: The eerily cheerful Tara
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipinksi</ENAMEX> appears on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> twice , including her own TV special
( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>).

            Take shelter from the storm with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimi Hendrix</ENAMEX> (if you can forgive the mixed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical allusion</ENAMEX>) in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bravo documentary, Searching for Jimi</ENAMEX> Hendrix
( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday , Feb. 12.</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 p.m.</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.A. Pennebaker</ENAMEX>, who also
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">made Monterey Pop</ENAMEX>, the film looks at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra Wilson</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie Anderson</ENAMEX> as they record the master's music. "It's taking us <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to do
what he did in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six minutes</TIMEX>," complains <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor Dayne</ENAMEX>--another reminder of
just how innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hendrix</ENAMEX> really was. To learn more about the guitar legend,
start with this bio page, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebsite</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jimi Hendrix</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> is also <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black History Month</ENAMEX>, with more shows on black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and
themes. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> airs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s uneven
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slave</ENAMEX>-revolt drama, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amistad</ENAMEX> , with strong performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morgan Freeman</ENAMEX>, and newcomer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Djimon Hounsou</ENAMEX> as the noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinque</ENAMEX>, who
recently guest-starred on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> as a noble <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> torture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> who
becomes . . . a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX>. Black History <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Month</TIMEX> or not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stereotyping</ENAMEX> still
lives.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This weekend</TIMEX>, you can relive the hunt for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'70s</NUMEX> monsters: a killer shark
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaws</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> ( All the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The History Channel</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>). Here's a
chance to remember what real high crimes and misdemeanors are all
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>.

            There are plenty of pleasingly creepy moments in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockbuster</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Storm of The Century</ENAMEX> , the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> horror
movie written directly for TV ( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>) The
small, isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Tall Island</ENAMEX> finds itself under siege from both a
brutal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> storm and a sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>, a placid-faced killer with
supernatural powers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Linoge</ENAMEX>. With <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours</TIMEX> of screen time to fill, the
townsfolk take quite a long time to realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linoge</ENAMEX> is the force behind a
series of mysterious killings and suicides. (Don't they read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>
novels up there?) All the while, the demonic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linoge</ENAMEX> character, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ably</ENAMEX> played by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colm Feore</ENAMEX>, keeps insisting: "If you give me what I want, I'll go away." While
we wait and wait for him to tell us what he wants, the movie employs stalling
devices such as the search in a darkened house for the elusive bogeyman. "Hell
is repetition," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linoge</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at various points. Well, yes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> is counter-programming by offering refuge for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> heart-tugging
TV films in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> have to give their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> away. Good acting by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bancroft</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep in My Heart</ENAMEX> ( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>), which traces the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">odyssey</ENAMEX> of the mulatto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of a white rape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, but who cares?

            With the hackneyed police mini-series, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Serve and Protect</ENAMEX>
( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> is apparently seeking to bridge
this gender gap in programming. The film mixes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> strife
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> romance and the search for a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> ) gives a confident performance, but it doesn't help this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hodgepodge</ENAMEX>.

            If you want to solve mysteries, turn instead to the conclusion of the
X-Files <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part conspiracy series (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>) when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigarette Smoking Man</ENAMEX> finally explains (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost</NUMEX>) all.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The week</TIMEX>'s most interesting programs may be documentaries. (Exceptions to
this rule: an FX network marathon of 
                  NYPD
                
               Blue episodes,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m to 1:30 a.m.</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX>'s last <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>, and the History
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX> takes a look at the formative traumas in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s life (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>),
followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Matthews</ENAMEX>' documentary on the rivalry between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nova</ENAMEX> is offering lots of bang-'em-up footage in its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part
series , ESCAPE! Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accidents Happen</ENAMEX> , on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8-10 p.m.</TIMEX>) Using the fig leaf of studying "survival
engineering" and safety pointers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> gives us fires, crashes, and sinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> returns to form with a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great Performances</ENAMEX> program on the
late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin Ailey</ENAMEX>, who brought black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> to modern dance ( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX>). The show is a weave of archival footage, interviews, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamison</ENAMEX>'s innovative new dance tribute, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hymn</ENAMEX>," which includes the great
performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Deavere Smith</ENAMEX>.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> sinks to new lows with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confirmation: The Hard</ENAMEX>
Evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aliens Among Us</ENAMEX>? (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m. to 10 p.m.</TIMEX>) The show exploits the
spurious device of "open-minded" questions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX> incident,
alien abductions, and grainy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX> footage. Result: too much credence given to
incidents exposed elsewhere as hoaxes and illusions. For a more skeptical view
of these issues, check out these sensible articles:  What Really
Happened at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell and Abduction</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aliens or Sleep Paralysis</ENAMEX> .

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> offers <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The World's Most Shocking Medical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Videos</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>) and The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Learning Channel</ENAMEX> profiles the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sickos</ENAMEX> who kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shadow of the Assassin</ENAMEX> -- complete with fast-paced footage of
famous assassinations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, and repeated gun-shot sound
effects. All this sure to inspire someone--probably the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirhan Sirhan</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Levine</ENAMEX> 
            

         
      
   
