
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox Rules</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>

            When you read your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday</TIMEX> (or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
if you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>), you will learn about a raging controversy (ok, minor
dispute) in the literary world: Does former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX> fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Lish</ENAMEX>
deserve credit for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Carver</ENAMEX>'s success?

            A quick summary: In the early stages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>'s career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX>--a famous
writing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> in his own right--went far beyond the traditional
role of fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, cutting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as half</NUMEX> the words in a given story,
rewriting entire passages, changing titles, and adding final lines himself. In
short, he carved out of a prolix <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s copy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>'s trademark minimalist
style. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX> never admitted to being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX>'s creation, but he chafed and
finally rebelled, forbidding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX> to edit heavily or rewrite anymore.

            The piece is scrupulously fair, airing all sides and concluding that
collaboration, if that's what it was, may not be such a bad thing, especially
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. However, the article also includes a certain amount of
vituperation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX> is an easy target, since he's
enormously controversial for a number of reasons: his mannered writing style,
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and his interventionist editorial style, for another, which made other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' careers and also earned their enmity.) "I've wondered in my head why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX> did what he did," comments the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Hall</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>'s who
objected strongly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX>'s edit of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bath</ENAMEX>," and republished the
original version as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Small, Good Thing</ENAMEX>." "Was it unconscious jealousy<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            It may be possible that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> claim, he wrote his best pieces
after he ended his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> is here to tell you
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX>'s version of the story <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> republished is infinitely
better--sparser, cleaner, and much more menacing, which just what the story
needs. On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> may be biased, since she is also an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, and had her own moments of sulking at her ungrateful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. So
compare and contrast the opening scene and decide for yourself. (Email
Culturebox at culturebox@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> if you violently disagree).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lish</ENAMEX>'s version:

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> drove to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX> in the shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.
After looking through a loose-leaf binder with photographs of cakes taped onto
the pages, she ordered chocolate, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s favorite. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> she chose was
decorated with a spaceship and a launching pad under a sprinkling of white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. The name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCOTTY</ENAMEX> would be iced in in green as if it were the name of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spaceship</ENAMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> listened thoughtfully when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> told him Scotty would be
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years old</TIMEX>. He was an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX>, and he wore a curious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apron</ENAMEX>,
a heavy thing with loops that went under his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and around his back and then
crossed in front again where they were tied in a very thick knot. He kept
wiping his hands on the front of the apron as he listened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, his wet
eyes examining her lips as she studied the samples and talked.

               He let her take her time. He was in no hurry.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> decided on the spaceship <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>, and then she gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> her
name and telephone number. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> would be ready <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, in plenty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. This was all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> was willing to say.
No pleasantries, just this small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, the barest information, nothing that
was not necessary.

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>'s version:

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> she drove to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX> in the shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. After
looking through a loose-leaf binder with photographs of cakes taped onto the
pages, she ordered chocolate, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s favorite. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> she chose was
decorated with a space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> and launching pad under a sprinkling of white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stars</ENAMEX>, and a planet made of red frosting at the other end. His name, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCOTTY</ENAMEX>,
would be in green letters beneath the planet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX>, who was an older man
with a thick neck, listened without saying anything when she told him the child
would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> olf <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> wore a white apron that looked
like a smock. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straps</ENAMEX> cut under his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, went around in back, and then to the
front again again, where they were secured under his heavy waist. He wiped his
hands on his apron as he listened to her. He kept his eyes down on the
photographs and let her talk. He let her take her time. He'd just come to work
and he'd be there <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>, baking, and he was in no real hurry.

               She gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> her name, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Weiss</ENAMEX>, and her telephone number. The cake
would be ready on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, just out of the oven, in plenty of time for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s party <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that afternoon</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> was not jolly. There were no
pleasantries between them. Just the minimum exchange of words, the necessary
information. He made her feel uncomfortablre, and she didn't like that. When he
was bent over the counter with the pencil in his hand, she studied his coarse
features and wondered if he'd ever done anything with his life besides be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">baker</ENAMEX>. She was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty-three years old</TIMEX>, and it seemed to her that
everyone, especially someone the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX>'s age--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> old enough to be her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>--must have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who'd gone through this special time of cakes and
birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. There must be that between them, she thought. But he was
abrupt with her--not rude, just abrupt. She gave up trying to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with
him. She looked into the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX> and could see a long, heavy, wooden
table with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum pie</ENAMEX> pans stacked at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one end</TIMEX>; and beside the table a metal
container filled with empty racks. There was an enormous oven. A radio was
playing country-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> music.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> finished printing the information on the special order card and
closed up the binder. He looked at her and said, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>." She thanked
him and drove home.

            

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
