
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pompous</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moi</ENAMEX>?

            Apropos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Strauss</ENAMEX>'s interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Corgan</ENAMEX>, the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smashing</ENAMEX>
Pumpkins, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> was moved to ask
several real and self-styled rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> (and who isn't the latter?) the
following question: When did self-important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pomposity</ENAMEX> become an acceptable
cultural style for a pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>?

            The answers:

            

               "I date it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vanilla Fudge recording of 'You Keep Me Hanging On</ENAMEX>.' I
associate this with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaaludes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanilla Fudge</ENAMEX> made a brilliant discovery. They
covered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supremes</ENAMEX> song at half the tempo. My theory is (I have no evidence for
this, of course) that in a drug-addled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, they put the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> on and switched
it to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>. It turns out that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerful</ENAMEX> pop jingle slowed down and its key
lowered by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> sounds important. It's the rhetorical trick of speaking very
slowly when you want to say something important. The wonderful thing about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaaludes</ENAMEX> is they do that for you. I recommend, if anybody still has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45s</TIMEX>, that
they go through the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supremes</ENAMEX> catalogue and play them at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>. It sounds
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanilla Fudge</ENAMEX>. It sounds like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Meaning Songbook</ENAMEX>. You play these
songs at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>, you will believe you have discovered the secret of life. You will
be wrong, of course." -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX>
               

               "I associate this with things like having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> and putting out
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-record sets. The kind of thing that really broke out after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX>,
after the break-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>. You could say in a way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> was
a pathbreaker. There was the whole bed-in thing. It had a humorous quotient to
it, there was something disarming about it, but just think of anyone else doing
it and you realize just how fatuous it was. And then all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">also-ran</ENAMEX> groups
started throwing their weight around. Everybody was making some kind of grand
statement. It was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bee Gees</ENAMEX> could release a record in a red
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">velvet</ENAMEX> jacket. It was called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Odessa</ENAMEX>," by the way, and it wasn't half
bad."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Sante</ENAMEX>
               

               "I would say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody Blues</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Symphony Orchestra</ENAMEX>. That was
pretty seminal." -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX>
               

               "When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy Holly</ENAMEX> started adding strings."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>
               

               "I think it was once rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> starting going to rehab. In rehab you sit
down and think about all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you've screwed over, you've done horrible
things to so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have let you because you're a rock star
and you sell records and they want to do anything that will keep you selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>. You realize you were an asshole, you meet somebody who lives in the
real world, maybe he's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> in rehab, and you realize how far away
you've gotten from all that. Then you become a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> who doesn't live in
the real world who thinks he or she has got a corner on understanding the real
world. That's where the pomposity comes in. Who am I thinking of? Courtney, I
guess."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim France</ENAMEX>
               

               "The classic thing is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> made that statement about how we're
bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> started burning records in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. But
there was always something about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> that was self-deprecating and
charming. The question is, when did things really become so completely without
irony? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late Sixties</TIMEX> you get the concept album, which is what the
Other things that come to mind are The Who with their rock operas, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quadrophenia</ENAMEX> , the way they presented those as overarching allegories
about everything, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Townshend</ENAMEX>, who always seemed so humorless about it
all. There was this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iron Butterfly</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this 18-minute</TIMEX> song called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In A Gadda Da Vita</ENAMEX>" and that just seemed overweening. There was the concert
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Harrison</ENAMEX> organized it in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravi Shankar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> also had a triple-record set called All Things
Must Pass which was pretty pompous. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> other thing: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last</ENAMEX> Waltz
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Band</ENAMEX>. I love <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Band</ENAMEX> deeply but here's this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> already in decline
having a farewell concert and they invite everybody--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muddy Waters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>.
They get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> to orchestrate everything, then they interview
themselves at great length not being that interesting."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex Star</ENAMEX>
               

               "Contrary to conventional wisdom, pretension was introduced into mainstream
pop not by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> but by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stones</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stones</ENAMEX> made a movie with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Luc Godard</ENAMEX>, something you could not imagine even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> doing. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> produced sophomoric concept albums, like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Magical Mystery Tour</ENAMEX>," but
they never made anything as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fake</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Their Satanic Majesties Request</ENAMEX>." And I
have always regarded "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anastasia</ENAMEX> screamed in vain" as the most pretentious line
in rock and roll. Do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Berry</ENAMEX> had even heard of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anastasia?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX>
               

               "It's a combination of groupies and the rock press both serving to inflate
the egos of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. If on the one hand you have somebody telling you you're
a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and on the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> wanting to sleep with you every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>,
it's hard to stay humble. Some of the pomposity is insecurity over the
incredible brutality of the recond business and recording careers. You have to
have a sort of bluster. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> like to complain, of course, but it is so rare
for any recording <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> to put out records over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a three-year</TIMEX> period.
They just chew you up and spit you out. All these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> just have to be
worried."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>
               

               "Actually, self-important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pomposity</ENAMEX> is out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> want flossier
and poppier rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. There's something about [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corgan</ENAMEX>'s] whole
grandiosity that is very <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>. Did you know he is boycotting
Spin because he felt we weren't reverential enough to him? When the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reason</ENAMEX>" album came out he made sure his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> pulled his ad from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>.
It was a full page ad, too. But the high point [of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pomposity</ENAMEX>] might be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELO</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Light Orchestra</ENAMEX>. They performed a very vital function for me. I was
able to convince my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that it was OK to listen to them because it was
sort of classical. This was back when you still had to justify your pop taste
to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, before they started lighting up and handing you joints. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pomposity</ENAMEX> is a perfectly legitimate cultural style. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for music is
very susceptible to pomposity. They haven't developed their sense of self-irony
yet. It's a good mirror to their own puffed-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Hirschorn
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> are of course invited to submit their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pomposity Sweepstakes</ENAMEX> at culturebox@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Winners</ENAMEX> to this and last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spiterature Contest</ENAMEX> to be announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
