
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America Too Democratic</ENAMEX> . . .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> love to condescend to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, but not until <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Vann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> put all the ways they do so into a book-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old World's New</ENAMEX>
World , which came out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>--was it possible to see how inventive they've
been about it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past four centuries</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> they worried about our
environment--our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> were dwarfish and our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> lacked nutrients. Then
they fretted about our intellectual life: Would we ever produce great poets?
Then they waxed romantic about our charming freedom from social hierarchy. Then
they turned against it, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Revolution</ENAMEX> had proved that social
equality could never work. And on it goes, a list of nose-wrinkling quibbles
you can still hear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: We're mercenary, self-centered, impolite, and worst
of all, too bourgeois to understand the geniuses of our age, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Rourke</ENAMEX>.

            The latest outburst of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> condescension comes, sad to say, from an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, albeit one who spends a great deal of time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. Writing last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX> politics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Lilla</ENAMEX> claims to have discovered why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sixties</ENAMEX> still incite
debate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> (under the guise of the culture wars) whereas such matters
have long since been resolved in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> naively make a religion out
of democracy. They just don't understand that politics is politics and culture
culture, and so when they have a political revolution, they're forced to apply
its principles to "every aspect of our lives." Hence feminism, or rather, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilla</ENAMEX>'s kind words, "the joyless militancy of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>";
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multiculturalism</ENAMEX>; gay rights; and all the other movements which subject
personal relations to "the exacting scrutiny of pure democratic
principles."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Undergirding Lilla</ENAMEX>'s hesitations about the spread of democracy into various
corners of life are, of course, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>--the two he credits with first
descrying the worrisome "existential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX> Alexis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Toqueville</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Englishwoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trollope</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> reveals the latter to have been possibly the biggest
snob ever to chronicle <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. She was revolted by "that coarse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">familiarity</ENAMEX>, untampered by any show of respect, which is assumed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grossest</ENAMEX> and the lowest in their intercourse with the highest and most
refined." And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Tocqueville</ENAMEX>, who is worth listening to, concluded his
travels in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> with an endorsement that dismissed all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> made
earlier. To quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granting</ENAMEX> that 'the wishes of democracy are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capricious</ENAMEX>, its instruments rude, its laws imperfect,' granting as well an
appalling list of shortcomings that he abhorred--minds 'so petty, so insipid,
so crowded with paltry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX>'--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tocqueville</ENAMEX> still regarded democracy 'not as
the best, but as the only means of preserving freedom.'"

            
               ...<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Or Do We Just Hate Intellectuals</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX> writes:

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> , it was hard to react in any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> more nuanced than just being nearly flattened by its overwhelming power.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time, though, I detected one false, and creepy, note. That is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">demonization of Upham</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain John Miller</ENAMEX>'s "stick," in the
final extended battle scene. Over and over, we are reminded of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX>'s
cowardice: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX>, in giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trembly sweaty closeup</ENAMEX>, cringes in fear. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX> fails
to come to the aid of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX> has a series of clear shots at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who don't see him, and can't bring himself to pull the trigger. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX> finally does kill, it's too late to do any good, and in clear violation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Geneva Conventions</ENAMEX>. (I saw the movie at a multiplex in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>, and my
appreciation of this point was sharpened by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s yelling "faggot!"
every time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX>'s face filled the screen.) You're clearly meant to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX>
personally responsible for the death of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> at arms,
including, as I read the narrative logic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Miller</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.

            The creepy part is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX> is a sensitive, artistic type who announces early
in the movie that he wants to depict the bonds that form among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in
combat--all of which also applies to the auteur of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> isn't the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> fictionalizer of war to establish
his macho bona fides by humiliating a spun-off, pusillanimous version of
himself. Remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keefer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>-character in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Caine Mutiny</ENAMEX> , who
spends most of his time proclaiming the superiority of moral principle to
personal loyalty (just like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX>) and then gets humiliatingly told off in the
end? The move here is to react to the automatic suspicion of anyone artsy in a
military setting by signing on to it, rather than challenging it. See, I agree
with you! They are all pansies! I'm a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> too! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upham</ENAMEX>
character is a particularly lurid example--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> type (skinny) and his
movements (mincing) are completely different from those of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>,
and seem somehow to be linked to his being more educated. Could his
cartoonishness be an indication of how defensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>, who like nearly all
upper-middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> didn't serve in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, feels
regarding the military and its virtues?

         
      
   
