
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quibbles</ENAMEX> and Corrections

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Culturebox</ENAMEX>:

            I'm not sure why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">booksellers</ENAMEX> don't want the hard numbers, but their
instincts are dead right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundscan</ENAMEX> has done nothing but harm to the creative
end of rock & roll--not because it has made information available, but
because it has made information available too quickly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who, in turn,
overvalue the importance of information gotten too quickly.

            Put another way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundscan</ENAMEX> has killed off word of mouth. It used to be that
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> could get behind an album, or an influential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX>, or a cohort of
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--and bingo, an interesting album becomes a hit album. Now it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">wham-bam</ENAMEX>: An album isn't catching on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or two</TIMEX> (as measured by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundscan</ENAMEX>) and the plug gets pulled on promotion, the CD gets pulled from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">racks</ENAMEX>, etc.

            Further, the industry itself starts pushing albums that will "open
big"--albums with a catchy single (and maybe little else) and (did somebody say
"synergy"?) soundtrack albums. Look at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pop Top 20</ENAMEX> for the results
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundscan</ENAMEX>. If you want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorrie Moore</ENAMEX> to sneak onto the bestseller list
every once in a while, you better hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookscan</ENAMEX> never catches on.-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX>
Marzorati
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Gerry</ENAMEX>:
            

            
               I think there's a risk of such short-sighted thinking, but I don't think
it would prevail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. There just wouldn't be enough blockbusters to keep
the book market going as a blockbuster-only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. If all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">booksellers</ENAMEX> pursued that strategy, in the end some of them would be forced to
re-enter the quality books market, just to get themselves back in the game. I
tend to think that's what's happening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, actually, which is why the
whole indie scene has become so hot.
            

            
               In response to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorrie Moore</ENAMEX> point, I'd think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookscan</ENAMEX> would have the
opposite effect. By allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> target their marketing dollars more
effectively, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookscan</ENAMEX> would help them sell the smaller books. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> could pinpoint exactly where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorrie Moore</ENAMEX> sells, and dispatch her
there on a book tour; could test whether her books were responsive to
advertising and what kind (a test run on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> might also work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Munro</ENAMEX>,
and so on). In short, with real numbers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> would be able to maximize
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for a serious book. --Culturebox

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Culturebox</ENAMEX>:

            With the consumer trade book category exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> in
retail dollars the stakes are now too high not to begin to fine-tune the
marketing mix. For every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> books shipped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 33%</NUMEX> came back to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> for full credit and a one <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> reduction in returns would save the
industry over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX> per year.

            It's important to note, though, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoundScan</ENAMEX>'s launch in the music world
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> was not an easy task. Several of the same issues that you address in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fuzzy Logic</ENAMEX>" existed in the music industry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90</TIMEX>'s.

            Also, the scanning device that you mention has existed for over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>
and has been utilized by package goods manufactures to target market their
products onto the shelves of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> across the world. The system is the UPC
or in the case of books a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EAN/ISBN</ENAMEX> number that when a book is scanned by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> identifies the book, format, suggested price point, genre, etc.
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Fogarty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soundscan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> in charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookscan</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
