
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tale of Two</ENAMEX> Princesses

            The fact that royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX> wrote the stories of both the
late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has made the comparison irresistible,
and it turns out to be apt: They were both childish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> whose
self-involvement nearly brought down their respective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. Disregard
the quasi-coincidental similarities--the paparazzi , the eating
disorders, the overprivileged backgrounds, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' divorces, the
educational failures (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was a finishing-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropout</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> made it
through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> with difficulty). A deeper affinity seems to have drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>
to them, ghostwriting fees aside: Here were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> massively unself-aware
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who had maneuvered themselves into positions of national
awkwardness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who were all but impossible to defend. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX> has met the
challenge with gallant efficiency. From what I've read of his oeuvre
--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, this latest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>--he is our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> of female
self-pity, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for whom no excuse is suspect, no outrage inexplicable, as
long as the explanation is given by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who can claim to have been hurt by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sloane Ranger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> who apparently
threw <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">temper tantrums</ENAMEX> from the moment she entered the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>, who
developed a pathological jealousy of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> that may have
driven him back into her arms. Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, the inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flirt</ENAMEX> who blithely
tried to blackmail the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, who in fact was
something of a stalker, even if the supposedly hateful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> was
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to call her that. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>'s ambition is to make these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
monstrousness pale beside that of their torturers. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s case, that's
easy, because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> happened to be an equally self-involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> who
clearly married her because he thought she would be a docile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeder</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s case is more difficult: Whose pathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> is she, exactly?
Going into the book, we think she's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s. After all, that's the
symbolic valence of the scandal: Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bulimic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s princess
driven to vomit up the monarchy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> seduced and
abandoned by an untrustworthy, poll-driven presidency. She is the sexual
metaphor for all our feelings about political slickness, its uncanny ability to
tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what they want to hear before leaving them high and dry.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> won't have any of that, thank you very much, and that is what
makes her book--and she herself--so much more interesting than the New Age
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">princess</ENAMEX> and her story, more interesting, in fact, than any version of the
scandal narrative so far. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>'s hands, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's</ENAMEX> is the same old tale of
female victimization, but--just as she did before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, thereby helping
to forestall impeachment--she manages to shift the blame. It is not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who traduced the morals of an immature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. It is the prurient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who imposed his Puritanical moralism on a sexually liberated if
somewhat confused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who held her against her will, denied her the
right to call her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, harassed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, flagrantly violated
her constitutional rights.

            To accept this, of course, you have to accept her version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> as
a helpless, goofy romantic, a emotional isolate tormented by the barrenness of
life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. That is a fantasy that is admittedly hard to take. But when
it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, at least, poor crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> has finally got it
right.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
