
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> steps in the web
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Andrew</ENAMEX>,
The story about the Web confession was very disturbing, involving a
particularly mad and grisly crime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Froide</ENAMEX>, A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> with custody of his
small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, still felt pressed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>'s presence in his life. So he
set the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on fire intentionally to kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> (in fact, he went in as
if to rescue her, but instead dropped her closer to the flames!). After Froide
confessed on-line, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the list notified the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">promptly</ENAMEX> flamed by others. Interestingly, one who did not tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> of the list, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotgers</ENAMEX> (of, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX>, where he is director
of the program for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Addiction, Consultation and Treatment</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotgers</ENAMEX> said
after all, "since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was already 'dead,'"--I love those scare quotes --
"no purpose would be served in the form of protecting anyone for rash,
emotional and poorly thought-out action." (I think he meant from such
action.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotgers</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Froide</ENAMEX> private e-mails with referrals for therapy.

            I think you're right about the effect of anonymity on the Web. It's part of
the general lack of reality about the Internet: is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> dead? or only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'dead</ENAMEX>'? I'm not so sure about A.A. though. This particular list wasn't
following a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> step philosophy--it was something called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moderation Management</ENAMEX>;
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> was an AA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>.

            A long time ago I used to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Anon</ENAMEX>, which is a support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX>, and I must say I thought it was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>: people
were very kind, with much life experience and wisdom. And it wasn't so
anonymous either--my "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>" gave me his business card (he ran a lamp <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in
my neighborhood). Unlike on the Net, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> step <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> often get to know
each other outside--they go out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> (for a while AA was
a big date scene, maybe it still is). There's an egalitarianism about the
original <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> step programs I really like, a humble, improvising approach. And
the thing is, it's not like there is some fabulous alternative that works
better.

            In AA, though, the anonymity--well, semi-anonymity--is due to the social
stigma of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. On the Internet, it seems connected with the desire to
lead a fantasy life. Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froide</ENAMEX> was describing real
events--as if they often encountered very detailed and plausible first person
accounts of imaginary crimes. Weird.

            Interesting that we both were taken by stories about evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> in divorce
cases. (Let's not forget the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s horrific story, who injected
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> virus to avoid paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support.) It casts an
interesting, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lurid</ENAMEX> glow on the current obsession with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatherhood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> runs an op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Blankenhorn</ENAMEX> pointing out that if the couples
in these cases had only had covenant marriages, those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would be alive
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Katha

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ps</ENAMEX>. I haven't read Conversations with God. What is it?

         
      
   
