
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turning Japanese</ENAMEX>
            

            Katha,
Sorry to be late up. Crashed out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> and took a long time to emerge. The
joys of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-lancing</ENAMEX>.

            The idea of emulating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> way of life is, well, not exactly one I'm
keen on. The reason no-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gets <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, I bet, is what they eat: all those
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>, and raw <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ugh</ENAMEX>. I've never been there (I think I'd rather go to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siberia</ENAMEX>) but whatever I've seen of it horrifies me. The reason they don't spend
much money on health is the same reason, I'd guess, they don't spend much money
on anything (except inflated property prices). Smacks too much of selfish
pleasure and too little of communal worth. Save me from such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communitarianism</ENAMEX>.

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> left's infatuation with thrifty socialized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> is made
possible by their never having to deal with it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> are a
stoic bunch, suffering in silence, blaming themselves for any illness,
apologizing for any sort of dependence on the health system, probably never
reporting many deadly illnesses for fear of cultural shame. I'll never forget
having my front teeth removed by the wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health Service</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>'s
foot on my chest (I <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you not), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>'s pliers in my mouth, blood
everywhere, no gas, and when I screamed, I was accused of not being a grown-up.
I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>. Still, really cheap. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> of GNP on health in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, and
all those lovely physiques and smiles to show for it.

            I love the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> health system, its waste and all. Without it, I'd
probably weigh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 90 pounds</NUMEX> by now. Yes, managed care is a good way to
squeeze some fat out of the system, but the rising costs are simply a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reflection of America</ENAMEX>'s cultural desire for higher standards of quality of
life, and the astonishing technologies that are making it possible. Let it rip,
say I, even if my premiums (actually <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marty Peretz's</ENAMEX>) go up. And when you need a
serious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, I bet you'll be going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth Israel</ENAMEX>, and not Tokyo
General.

            best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
