
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen Head</ENAMEX>

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> got me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Coen</ENAMEX>'s short-story collection <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> of
Eden for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> because I'm so fond of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>' movies. (At
least I assume that's why he got it for me--what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, after all, wants
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to marry someone with an appetite for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary</ENAMEX> Short
Fiction?)

            This is an extraordinary collection. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Roughly a third</NUMEX> of the stories are
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about mobsters</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> about anomic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>, and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> about growing up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> (which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen</ENAMEX> did). Throughout, it's a book so funny you
should not take it out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> without a change of underpants. The three
best stories:

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have You Ever Been to Electric Ladyland</ENAMEX>," the monologue of a schlock-
rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> trying to figure out who had a motive to break into his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and
castrate his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> (answer: anyone who's ever had to deal with him for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>);

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) "It is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Mariner</ENAMEX>," which has the same kind of
self-incriminating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ring Lardner</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Haircut</ENAMEX>" --and is a better
story;

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX>," which describes the sexual misadventures of a fascistic
operative on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Weights and Measures</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. "Well, that's the
beauty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> female," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>. "We might tag her submissive or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unliberated</ENAMEX> or what have you, but to my mind she has a grace and dignity all
her own, bred by centuries of tradition. Her purpose in life, which she will
ever strive to perfect, is the serving of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>, Jap though he may
be."

            Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> alive have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen</ENAMEX>'s gift for voice. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hector Berlioz</ENAMEX>,
Private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigator</ENAMEX>," says, "I knew a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX> once. Fellow named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Clare</ENAMEX>,
though he spelled it Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Clerk</ENAMEX>. Died of typhus. I did his estate work. Had to
fill out a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> forms. Pain in the neck, but I guess they know what
they're doing." And a mafioso in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Destiny</ENAMEX>" says: "These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, me they would
not fuck."

            Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX> was given to me as a curiosity, I'm ticked off
that the mere handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who've noticed it have reviewed it as a
curiosity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excepting Christopher Lehmann-Haupt</ENAMEX> in the New York

               Times , the attitude has been: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How</ENAMEX> . . . em, sweet that this famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmaker</ENAMEX> should try to apply his gifts to our genre." Here I'm thinking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Lindquist</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> 
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> ("while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Coen</ENAMEX> [qua
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>] isn't quite as stylish with language as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is with a
camera, he does have a distinctive voice and an offbeat worldview") or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ("As with his films, his failures are often
almost as interesting as other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' successes.").

            Which means nothing. Like much deference, it's really a disguised kiss-off.
It's precisely because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen</ENAMEX> is a filmmaker that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contemporary Short Fictionland</ENAMEX> will give this book its due. Contemporary Short
Fiction is shriveled up like a protectionist economy. It is an economy in which
everyone is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buchananite</ENAMEX> and the policy is one of praise-rationing and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fame</ENAMEX>-redistribution. Those who labor in the rusting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fiction mills</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen</ENAMEX> as a recent immigrant to the genre who's taking jobs away
from native <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contemporary Short Fictionites</ENAMEX>. Time to open the borders.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Caldwell</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
