
   
   
      
         
            We <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are All on Good Morning America</ENAMEX>
            

            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Andrew</ENAMEX> --

            I can't retrieve my e-mail at the moment. Could it be because I am
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treasuring</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1275</ENAMEX> messages in my inbox? Anyway, I will just send off into the
blue my thoughts on seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter Kurth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbara Kurth</ENAMEX>, on Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning America</ENAMEX> (I think). You'll remember that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbara Kurth</ENAMEX> is the mother
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> were kidnapped by her ex-husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Fagan</ENAMEX>, who changed
his name and lived in shadowy splendor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Beach Florida</ENAMEX>, raising "the
girls" as they are always called (they're now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 and 23</TIMEX>), having told them
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> died in a car crash. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kurth</ENAMEX> got no help from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> or legal
system in tracking him down, by the way, because the kidnapping took place in
l979, before parental kidnapping was covered by appropriate laws. She spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all</TIMEX>
her money on private eyes, to no avail.

            So of course, since she is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbara Kurth</ENAMEX> has been attacked in
the media, solely on the basis of allegations by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Fagan</ENAMEX>, who says she
was an alcoholic who neglected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, leaving him no choice. (She denies
his charge--which was investigated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, after all, which found them
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">untrue</ENAMEX> and gave her custody.) He doesn't explain why he kept up the deception
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>, long after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> had clearly overcome her problems if
she ever had any, and had gotten a Ph.D. (she is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of cell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biology</ENAMEX>, married--but no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>). His whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was in on it, too--his parents
also moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. It's hard to imagine the cruelty involved here.

            Anyway, I turn on the TV in my hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whittier California</ENAMEX>, which
is--as every single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> I mentioned this place to reminded me--where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>
went to college (why do we all have this little fact so firmly implanted in our
brains?), and there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kurth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, being interviewed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Couric</ENAMEX>. And what amazed me is that here was this ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
who had been suddenly plucked from obscurity by the hand of fate, and he knew
exactly what to do on television! How to sit (not too slumpy, not too stiff),
what to do with his hands (kept them quiet, don't gesticulate or fiddle with
your ear or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> part), how to arrange his expressions (relaxed, alert,
open, affable), how to speak in sound bites (don't digress! don't get mad!
don't talk too long!). It was as though he'd been on TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            Talk to you later,
Katha

         
      
   
