
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idiot Box</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week  Edition</ENAMEX>

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All</NUMEX> times are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>, but check your local listings just in case.
            

            Thanks god it's over. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday</ENAMEX> hell is behind us now,
and things appear to be looking up--at least on TV. The repeats are fewer, the
movies are better, the flood of gooey holiday commercials is drying up--they're
even showing back-to-back <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ally</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mon.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 & 9:00</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX>).

            Leading off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, there's good news for everyone
still in a funk over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s passing: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&E</ENAMEX> has put together a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swingin</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Biography on the Rat Pack (Part 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun.</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 p.m.</TIMEX>). Centered around the rise, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>, and redemption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>, the documentary is chock full of fascinating details about how the
various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Packsters</ENAMEX> were drawn into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s orbit, starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1940s</TIMEX>.
Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP</ENAMEX> aficionados will swoon over the old photos and footage of not only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey</ENAMEX> (who does not make an appearance until hour
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>), but also of such <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>-screen notables as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ava Gardner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humphrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Bacall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana Turner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Gable</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery Clift</ENAMEX>. There
are also terrific vintage clips of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kangaroo boxers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic City</ENAMEX>'s
boardwalk, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lawford-Pat Kennedy</ENAMEX> nuptials, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kefauver Senate</ENAMEX>
hearings on organized crime.

            Attempts to weave the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s stories together
result in some confusing chronological jumps, but the damage isn't serious. One
sour note: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Aiello</ENAMEX>'s voice-over. In theory, he's a logical choice--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">low-key Italian-American</ENAMEX> who sounds like he could have been one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s mob
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chums</ENAMEX>. In practice, he stinks up the joint. Admittedly, the script is no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aiello</ENAMEX> compounds the problem, droning along as if under the influence of
prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s movie scene offers something for
everyone. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bravo</ENAMEX> is running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Award-winning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinema Paradiso</ENAMEX> , while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> goes for mass appeal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleepless</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> . In need of more manly fare? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX> delivers a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint</ENAMEX>
double-header: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">High Plains Drifter</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 p.m.</TIMEX>) followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fistful</ENAMEX> of
Dollars (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:05 p.m.</TIMEX>). And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late in the week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Family Channel</ENAMEX> is showing
What's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eating Gilbert Grape</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fri.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00 p.m.</TIMEX>), in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX> is
annoyingly beautiful, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliette Lewis</ENAMEX> is simply annoying. But the movie is
charming despite itself, and a pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> earned an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX>
nomination for his convincing turn as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depp</ENAMEX>'s mentally retarded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.

            For those not completely overdosed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">on</ENAMEX> reruns, there's
a special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> showing of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Shoot Me</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 p.m.</TIMEX>). This is
the episode in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Spade</ENAMEX>) tries to trick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laura San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giacomo</ENAMEX>) into engaging in "forbidden love" with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--while he
watches. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discovering Finch</ENAMEX>'s plan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> plot revenge, devising a list of
impossible tasks that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finch</ENAMEX> must accomplish in order for the love-fest to take
place. The hysterical part is watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spade</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> actually accomplish
his mission with the aid and encouragement of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>--all men
who are desperate to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finch</ENAMEX> live out "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Every Man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fantasy</ENAMEX>." It's funny
because it's true.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX> also brings the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Franken</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dubious sit-com</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lateline</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed.</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00 p.m.</TIMEX>). Before it was shelved
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the show was populated by weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franken</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Freundlich</ENAMEX>
was a total boob--and riddled with tired gags (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freundlich</ENAMEX>'s shrieking
harpy of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, whom we hear only over the phone.) For the relaunch, I was
hoping the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> had done a major creative overhaul, but the early
signs are not encouraging. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s show--in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchorman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearce McKenzie</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Foxworth</ENAMEX>) starts doing guest spots on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conan O'Brien</ENAMEX> show--is just
plain stupid, relying heavily on dopey sight gags and potty humor. The episode
has some nice moments--mostly involving an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intern</ENAMEX>'s desperate pursuit of a
raise--but overall, it feels like a second-rate <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy Brown</ENAMEX>.

            Other questionable programming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
is showing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">D3</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mighty Ducks</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 p.m.</TIMEX>), in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emilio Estevez</ENAMEX>'s
scrappy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hockey heroes</ENAMEX> face their grimmest challenge yet--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prep Schoolers</ENAMEX>.
In the history of film, there are perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> sequels that deserved to be made.
This is not one of them. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> is premiering <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wrong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girl</ENAMEX> , some bizarre made-for-TV deal starring country-music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
Mandrell as a concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> who suspects that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> is a
dangerous psychotic. And perhaps most disheartening, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> continues to air
episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Boat: The Next Wave</ENAMEX> .

            Where is a giant iceberg when you really need
it?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Cottle</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
