
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furby</ENAMEX> a Must-Buy?

            Here's a brief sordid history of toys-of-the<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisticuffs</ENAMEX> have erupted
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cabbage Patch Kids; Tickle-Me-Elmos</ENAMEX> have been stockpiled and scalped for
bank-breaking prices; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beanie Baby</ENAMEX> counterfeiters have taken rubes to the
cleaners; and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s toy-of-the-year--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furby</ENAMEX>--is already sold out of
several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> and is being auctioned off on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $200</NUMEX> apiece

            I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got suspicious about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Furbys</ENAMEX> when I read their online instructions,
which sounded like an excerpt from a pornographic version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.B. Shaw</ENAMEX>'s
Pygmalion :

            "Before you play with me, please follow these simple steps:

            

               Turn me upside down and open my battery door.

               Insert <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) AA batteries into my battery compartment. PLEASE DO NOT
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CLOSE THE BATTERY COMPARTMENT YET</ENAMEX>.

               While holding me upside down, put your finger in my mouth and hold down my
tongue switch, then hit Reset button

               While holding my tongue switch, please close my battery door and secure the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">screw</ENAMEX>.

               I will now wake up and tell you my name. I am now ready to play!"

            

            The doll looks more like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gremlin</ENAMEX> than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galatea</ENAMEX>--furry, big ears, big
eyes, no neck. The source of its appeal, however, is Galatea-like: You teach,
it learns. It has a motor, internal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, a computer chip, a light sensor,
a sound sensor, and touch sensors, so in addition to old-hat tricks like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blinking</ENAMEX> and "dancing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furby</ENAMEX> knows whether you're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and will talk,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sing</ENAMEX>, and generally act cute. But most importantly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furby</ENAMEX> responds to Pavlovian
conditioning.

            When you first get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furby</ENAMEX>, for instance, you can tickle its stomach and
it may or may not give you a kiss. If it kisses you and you immediately pat it
on the back, you increase the likelihood of it kissing you next time you tickle
its tummy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furbys</ENAMEX> also have their own language, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Furbish</ENAMEX>, "which is heavily
influenced by the languages of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mandarin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>." Over time,
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furby</ENAMEX> will abandon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furbish</ENAMEX> and begin to "learn" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English</ENAMEX> (actually, it
doesn't really learn--it's just programmed to begin speaking more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> words
after a while). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furby</ENAMEX> can even communicate with and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">teach</ENAMEX>" other Furbys
tricks and songs by means of infrared signals similar to the ones in a TV
remote control device. If one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furby</ENAMEX> sings a lullaby, the other will fall asleep
and snore. If you play music, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furbys</ENAMEX> will dance together.

            This is all very cool from an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>'s perspective. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>, though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furby</ENAMEX> has drawbacks, such as:

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carapace Issue</ENAMEX>. In order to protect the various motors, there has to be
a rigid plastic shell under the fur, which makes the thing hard to hug.
Although press materials call it a "cuddly standalone animatronic pet," in my
book, "animatronic" cancels out "cuddly."

            

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Work Issue</ENAMEX>. Who wants to train a toy to kiss you, when every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> knows
that a regular stuffed animal kisses you every time you touch its plastic nose
to your cheek?

            

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breakability Issue</ENAMEX>. The delicate plastic ear bones are just begging to
be snapped, and the toy's many cool functions spark curiosity about how it all
works. In order to satisfy that curiosity, you have to skin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Furby</ENAMEX> and crack
open the internal plastic shell. Another way to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furby</ENAMEX>'s innards is to check
out the exquisite Furby
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autopsy Home Page</ENAMEX> .

            

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Grown-Up vs. Kids Issue</ENAMEX>. As soon as you read that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furby</ENAMEX>'s unique
language is "heavily influenced by the languages of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mandarin</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>," you know that this is a toy that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will like more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
Same goes for all the tricks Furby learns that are cool in concept--but boring
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX>.

            

            Is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> too young for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Furby</ENAMEX>? Will it create more frustration and
heartbreak than happiness? Is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> retail (or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $200</NUMEX> online) too much for
what you get? Do you want a furry animatronic pet that burps (and worse) after
you "feed" it by pushing down on its tongue? These questions are all worth
considering before you join in on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Furby</ENAMEX> auction, break into a cold sweat over
the grim warning on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> pages: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WAL-MART NOW OUT OF FURBYS</ENAMEX>!!!!!," or
smuggle a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">stun-gun</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toys</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-Us to disable the competition.

            -- Eliza Truitt
            

             

         
      
   
