
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>? Come off it.
            

            Katha,

            With all due respect, you keep changing the subject. My point was merely
that our double-standard with regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazism</ENAMEX> and Communism is curious, and
largely because of lingering (and I think mistaken) notions that somehow the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> weren't quite so bad. They were. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> of their liquidation
were different; but the totalitarian structure, police <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and militaristic
expansionism in both systems were uncannily alike. So, of course, were the
crude, domestic economic policies, which harnessed big business interests to
the military <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Both were evil empires; and both were essentially national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">socialist</ENAMEX> experiments. The only difference is that we defeated one in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>; and took another forty-four to defeat the other. And you misunderstand
me when I said that Communism was responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. I didn't blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Left</ENAMEX> for these wars; I blamed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. Could anyone now dispute that? Oh, maybe you do.

            And no, I don't dispute that, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short period of time</TIMEX>, some socialistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impulses</ENAMEX> addressed some real problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and the West and should remain
in place. (What, after all, is workfare, if not a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30s</TIMEX>-style piece of government
intervention?) But I do think that, given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Government</ENAMEX>'s record in providing
public goods over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few decades</TIMEX> (almost universally execrable, wherever
you look), and given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extremely Big Government</ENAMEX>'s record in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX>, we should be a little more concerned about a state that is now
imposing a higher tax burden on ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> than at any time in the
history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>. Those tax-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX>, by the way, are not "big business."
They are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>; and they are being bilked of their own
money.

            And no, I'm not a reactionary. Just because I think we should drastically
cut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s suppression of our economic choices and liberties doesn't mean
I'm against universal suffrage or desegregation. For goodness' sake. I'm a
First <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> absolutist, a solid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in gender and racial equality of
opportunity, etc, etc. And you know it. A truly liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would be
strictly neutral between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, and do as little as possible to rob them of
their civil liberties and worldly goods. Given the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX>'s record
of the alternative, what's so bad about that?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
