
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">From Shangri</ENAMEX>-La

            It's the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>"--again. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> proclaimed the "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>" when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> won
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> celebrated an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years later</TIMEX>. Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is feting the Land of the Snows
with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year of Tibet in Movies</ENAMEX>": <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panegyrics</ENAMEX> will open in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year's end</TIMEX>, and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> is in the works. At the center of the latest round of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adulation</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>, making another triumphal world tour. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> greeted him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, he visits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX>-rights conference, an awards dinner with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX>, and
the kind of gushy press coverage that other world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> fantasize about.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX> is, by all accounts, a true holy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>: humble, devout, warm, funny, as
sweet inside as outside. He casts himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Himalayan Forrest Gump</ENAMEX>--the
accidental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>: "I am just a simple <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX>." But this humility, which
is undoubtedly sincere, also serves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s shrewd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> campaign. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holiness</ENAMEX> is cashing in on the West's romance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> spirituality, using
it to attract international sympathy. Dressed in his maroon robes and beatific
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smile</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean of Wisdom</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Protector</ENAMEX> of the Land of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snows</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Lotus</ENAMEX>--symbolizes all that's right with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and wrong with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>. He is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shangri-La</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emissary</ENAMEX> from a magical, peaceful
land protected by stunning mountains, dotted with magnificent temples, ruled by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wise</ENAMEX> and benevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly 50 years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> conquered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>
and his long-suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> have achieved a victory of sorts: They have
become the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion victims</ENAMEX>. They are, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uma</ENAMEX>) told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , "the baby seals of the
human rights movement." Other trampled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> briefly seize the world's
attention, then disappear. No movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> ever demonstrated for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Estonian</ENAMEX>
independence. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> is already <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s news. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> overran the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Turkestan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> it grabbed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>: Have you ever heard of
it? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>'s "" is cornering the market in human rights.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theocracy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> was (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more or less</NUMEX>) independent for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, mostly
because it was so inhospitable to invaders. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> reasserted an
ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> claim to it, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> stormed the plateau. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>,
then a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, cooperated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> for a while. But in
the midst of a failed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> rebellion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, he fled to northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>,
where he's lived ever since. In the meantime, the occupying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> army
murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> more
starved during a famine caused by demented <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> agricultural policy. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> tried to obliterate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> culture: Celibate nuns and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> were
forced to copulate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>; others were crucified or dragged to death by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>. All but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000-plus</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">monasteries</ENAMEX> were looted and ransacked.
Officially, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> is an "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Autonomous Region</ENAMEX>." In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> controls its
government, economy, and education.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s only tool is moral suasion. He
wields it magnificently. He feeds his Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> a softhearted,
softheaded universalism, a religion without dogma, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ansel Adams</ENAMEX> photograph.
He bathes his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> in kindly aphorisms: "Be a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Be a
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> ." "Happiness produces health. Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> accept
this ." "We should learn together as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> in the great
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> ." (We should.) We should also: protect the environment,
forgive those who abuse us, know that satisfaction does not come from material
things, and escape from hustle and bustle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddhism</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">appealingly</ENAMEX> self-centered: Happiness trumps everything. This is a winning idea
in our therapeutic culture: a religion that's about my satisfaction, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God's</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX> keeps the message cheerful. Who needs some gloomy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gus</ENAMEX> who harangues you
about torture, rape, and murder all the time? (That means you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Wu</ENAMEX>!) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fun Prophet</ENAMEX>. He laughs. He tells jokes--mostly at his own
expense. He even guest-edited an issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogue</ENAMEX> . He pronounces himself
"always optimistic" (though if there's any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whom history should have
taught not to be optimistic, surely it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>, especially those susceptible to
New Age spirituality, find his mixture of exoticism, aphorism, and optimism
irresistible. In the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kundun</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> will present the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX>'s autobiography as hagiography. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven Years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> will tell the
story of an escaped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> POW (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX>) who befriended the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>--call it The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patient</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Seagal</ENAMEX>
movie is also in the works. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrity Buddhist Richard Gere</ENAMEX> is writing op-ed
pieces. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> is bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> at congressional hearings. The Beastie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smashing Pumpkins</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R.E.M.</ENAMEX> are headlining benefit concerts with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX>'s roster of tangible accomplishments has been negligible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
government refuses to negotiate with him. The crackdown on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> religion has
worsened. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> chose a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to be Panchen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-most powerful religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> kidnapped him
and installed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. The original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panchen Lama</ENAMEX> still
languishes under house arrest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> are burying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>
with immigration. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in exile, there are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million Han Chinese</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 6 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> won't be
Tibetan very long.

            In a way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> may
even reinforce <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> authority over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. He insists that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX> abjure
violence, threatening to abdicate if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX> take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>.
But nonviolent resistance tends to succeed when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the world is watching and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
the oppressors care. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> seem indifferent, and the world will only pay
attention as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> is alive. (Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> believe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> won't negotiate with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61-year-old</TIMEX> because they are waiting for him
to die. Then the outside pressure for a peaceful accommodation will vanish.)
Among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX>, frustration with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s placid pacifism is growing.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX>, bombs aimed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> have exploded in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lhasa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Saints</ENAMEX>
never exhaust their patience, but sometimes their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> do.

         
      
   
