
   
   
      
         
            Forgetting the Present

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Santayana</ENAMEX> predicted
an unfortunate fate for those who cannot remember the past. What would he say
about political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who cannot even remember the present?

            Take, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s promise in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Democratic Convention</ENAMEX> speech--repeated more than once
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s debate--that he would offset the harsh effects of the
recently passed welfare rollback by giving "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> a tax credit for every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> hired off welfare and kept employed." What a can't-miss idea. The very
words fairly glow: "tax credit," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>," "off welfare," "employed."

            Trouble
is, we already have such a tax credit--it just got renewed as part of the
minimum-wage bill, and it's a proven failure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Targeted Jobs Tax Credit</ENAMEX> (a k
a the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Work Opportunity Tax Credit</ENAMEX>) has been a ghastly disappointment ever since
it was enacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. Early analysis showed that most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> using it
didn't hire more or different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Instead, they simply got their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> to review personnel records <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at year's end</TIMEX> to see who among recent
hires might qualify for the tax credit.

            Tighter rules have, presumably, curbed that abuse, but far
more damaging findings emerged from a couple of controlled experiments in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>. To their surprise and dismay,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> found that when eligible job <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> (welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and other
categories of "disadvantaged" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>) were sent off to potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
bearing in hand the tax credits or vouchers that labeled them as high-risk
cases, they were less likely--far less likely--to find jobs than if they just
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> on their own. And that was back when the tax credit was considerably
more generous than it is now. From these and other studies, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Burtless</ENAMEX>, who participated in many of them, "we can safely
conclude that sending someone out in the market saying, 'Hire me, I'm for
sale,' is a bad idea."

            For that
matter, so are all the efforts to engineer social and economic behavior through
the tax code of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is so enamored--the embellished tax preferences
for buying and selling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in day care,
sending the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to college or going back yourself, saving up for a nursing
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, and so on. There's so much evidence on this point that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> agreed that tax subsidies are, at best, an inefficient way
to promote desired behavior, since most of the money goes to pay for things
that are going to happen anyway. At worst, they are a complete rip-off, since
they are almost impossible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> to monitor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> gave the tax code a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">much-needed</ENAMEX> cleanup job, with lower rates as the reward, and everyone promised
they wouldn't junk it up again.

            
But that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 long years ago</TIMEX>, and no one
would expect a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> to remember that far back. Let's return to the
forgotten present.

            
Attention-deficit disorder is also afflicting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. On the campaign
trail, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> was still calling for the misbegotten Homemaker IRA a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> after it had passed into law. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has apparently not forgotten his own
past record on taxes--he correctly, if ineffectually, pointed out during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s debate that his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> tax bill was not a true tax hike, as normally
understood, but primarily a canceling of corporate tax breaks not yet in place
and crackdowns on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cheaters</ENAMEX> to collect taxes already owed. (He did fail to note
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> bailout of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>, about which he also bragged
repeatedly, included a large tax increase.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s grasp of specifics
seemed a lot less secure when it came to defending his current plan to
cut taxes by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $550 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next six years</TIMEX> while still balancing
the budget. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also managed to forget the incredible elements in his own
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> budget-balancing plan, as he touted it repeatedly during the
debate.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s tax plan argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have
paid far too much attention to the relatively modest "supply-side" feedback
effects counted on to pump up tax collections by promoting growth and reducing
tax avoidance. The real guts, they contend, lie in the promised budget cuts,
which, since they amount to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a mere nickel</NUMEX> out of every dollar of cut-able
programs over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six-year</TIMEX> period, are surely an easily achievable target.

            A mere <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nickel</ENAMEX>? Piece o' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>.
Or at least you might think so if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> escaped your
attention. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> indulged in a round of mutual
self-congratulation over their agreement on an appropriations package for the
new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>. "You <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> did such a great job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> as they finished up on their work, "You should really be
proud."

            Gee, and
they didn't have to close down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> even once. Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> small detail
that might have given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and his illustrious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> a moment's pause: The
appropriations measures, while restrained by recent standards, nonetheless
weigh in at probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 billion</NUMEX> over the target the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> set for
domestic discretionary spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a year ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will argue the
shortfall isn't that big, because they are going to cover some of it by onetime
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX>: dipping into the bank insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funds</ENAMEX>--never mind the S&L
collapse, that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eons ago</TIMEX>--and, of course, selling off part of the broadcast
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectrum</ENAMEX>-- the most oversold commodity since the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brooklyn Bridge</ENAMEX>. Didn't anyone
remind them that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> had already reserved the spectrum sale to help pay for
his tax-cut plan?

            
A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 billion</NUMEX> discrepancy may not seem much
when measured against the total budget, with all its sacrosanct or unavoidable
obligations. But it's a significant shortfall if you are sufficiently
present-minded to recall that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>) have separately
committed themselves to mammoth--and almost entirely unspecified--cuts in the
magical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year of 2002</TIMEX>, when the budget is to alight, if only for a moment, on
balance. And it is on top of these cuts--before the first small step of which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> just blinked--that the additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> cuts are
to be made, an amount totaling close to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of the vulnerable part of
the budget. Assuming the bare-bones basic functions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are to be
maintained, where then will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for any border-control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> or
anti-terrorism measures, or <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Head Start</ENAMEX> or education grants or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX> subsidies
or national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, or disaster relief--let alone the enhancements that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
deemed so necessary this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>?

            No
doubt--as former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Reischauer</ENAMEX> points
out--with all the election-year pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to show they really
aren't so bad and the temptation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to show his newfound muscle, the
final appropriations package isn't bad. That is, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reischauer</ENAMEX> quickly adds,
"if budget balance is your prime desire and you believe that cuts in
discretionary spending are the way to go."

            But that, of course, is the real and present issue that
neither congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> addressed, transfixed as they and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are by
the fantasy budgets offered on the campaign trail by their respective
standard-bearers. A budget is not a mere political prop: Whether by design or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inadvertence</ENAMEX>, it's the end product of politics, the actual blueprint for
government's role in society.

            This budget makes some
big--if dubious--choices, if only implicitly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an extra $9.4</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">billion this year</TIMEX> (with more to come) for weapons systems and other sundries it
doesn't want, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few weeks</TIMEX> after another set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> decided to cut
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21.2 billion</NUMEX> from programs for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX> over this and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two years</TIMEX>. But
most important choices were not made. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s problems won't be
manifest until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>, but it would be both easier and kinder to
start making modest reforms now. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is exploding
right now. So, for that matter, is the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. But overseas
family-planning programs, despite minor restoration, were left at a funding
level <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a third</NUMEX> below that of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>.

            Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are often
faulted for living in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> or ignoring the future.

            We'd be lucky if ours simply
got a firm hold on the here and now.

         
      
   
