
   
   
      
         
            The Old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Carolinians</ENAMEX>

            If you stick around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> long enough, anything can happen. And during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>, it did.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>--the villainous, superannuated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carolinians</ENAMEX>--became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Statesmen</ENAMEX>.

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> was feted for breaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> longevity
record (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41 years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 months</TIMEX>, if you're counting). There was an outpouring of
bipartisan piffle, the gist of which was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> miracle,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Carolinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, a model for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> everywhere. His career was
much applauded. He won <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election 18 years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> was born! He
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">challenged Truman</ENAMEX> for the presidency! Why, he's old enough to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, too, is now flirting with respectability. As
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> to kiss his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>, waxes fondly about her new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> commend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> for his good sense, flexibility,
and bipartisanship (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>!). When he struck a deal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to repay some but not
all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> debts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> on both sides hailed his
compromise. Even his latest act of spite, the attempt to derail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX>'s
nomination as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, is being interpreted charitably by
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> as a sign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' commitment to a tough anti-drug
policy.

            The
rehabilitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom</ENAMEX> and Jesse is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politesse</ENAMEX> of the worst sort, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twisted Inside-the-Beltway</ENAMEX> version of ancestor worship. Call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Old</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man Theory</ENAMEX>: Anyone who's served as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom or Jesse</ENAMEX> has can't be all bad.
Here's a reminder: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> are all bad. They have done as
much to despoil <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics as any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> living, and they're an
embarrassment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> has
compiled a perfect record: He has done nothing that can be called an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>. His career is an unblemished <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half century</TIMEX> of efforts to impede
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progress</ENAMEX>, inflame race relations, and squelch good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. So what has he
done? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> on what is politely called a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>'
rights" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> or accurately called a "segregationist" platform. He conducted
the longest filibuster in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> history in a vain attempt to stop a
civil-rights bill (one of many civil-rights laws he opposed). He
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concocted Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Strategy</ENAMEX>"--the tacit appeal to white
racism that became the blueprint for future <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>, incidentally, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Atwater</ENAMEX>, the nastiest political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> in recent memory. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atwater</ENAMEX> had to die to get rehabilitated. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Thurmond</ENAMEX>
just had to get very old.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX> insist that he has mellowed. And he has, sort of. He
abandoned segregationism when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> became a powerful voting
bloc, throwing his support behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>, hiring
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>, and recommending a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for appointment as a federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. But his racial politics can scarcely be described as up-to-date. A few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, I interviewed him about a black ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> who had won fame as a
talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> told me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>'s success showed what "those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" could do. This is considered great progress--when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> advances
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Neanderthal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX>.

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> has been a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. He doesn't have
a significant bill to his name. He does, however, have other things to his
name, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Center</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond Dam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>
Highway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soldier Service Center</ENAMEX>, etc. In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> spent
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of his political life as an ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">segregationist</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork-barreler</ENAMEX>, and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last quarter</TIMEX> merely as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>-barreler. Is that a record
to honor?

            There's
even less to admire about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> has contributed as much
as any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> to the corruption of the election process. He pioneered the
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ab</ENAMEX>)use of direct mail, sending inflammatory fund-raising letters to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. He's notorious for massive campaign spending: He set a record
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> by spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 million</NUMEX> to win re-election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> has perfected the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>: He relies almost exclusively on television ads, eschewing
rallies, public appearances, press conferences, debates, and the other niceties
of traditional politics. (In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> campaign, for example, he would respond
only to faxed questions.) He has been equally destructive as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX>: A
fervent anti-Communist, he championed right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">despots</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
(including death-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad leaders</ENAMEX>). He was also the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>'s apartheid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. And his anti-gay, anti-abortion, anti-NEA rhetoric
has lowered standards for political civility.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are trying to present
him as a moderate, accommodating figure, but that image won't stick. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> is
an absolutist, and he doesn't stop till he gets his way. He only knows the
politics of the truncheon, a quality that's tolerable in a backbencher but
terrifying in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> can barely stomach the democratic process. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, for example, he held up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 ambassadorial</NUMEX> nominations to force the
administration to consider his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> reform package. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This spring</TIMEX>, he
attempted to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> from voting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chemical Weapons Convention</ENAMEX>.
And rather than persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> doesn't deserve to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> is trying to spike the nomination by not scheduling a confirmation
hearing.

            So why are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> getting a free pass? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> is so old that it's considered bad form
to criticize his sorry record or dredge up his racist past. (Or to comment on
his current incompetence--it's an open secret on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> has
lost it. His staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shepherds</ENAMEX> him from meeting to meeting, writes his public
statements, and cleans up after his many gaffes, such as his attempted pass at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> benefits from a more curious phenomenon: the vagary
of the news cycle. He's been mean-spirited and vicious for so long that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are tired of hearing about it. They need a new story about him.
So, voilà !--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> has matured into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> each won
re-election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, but this is likely to be the last term for both. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Thurmond</ENAMEX>
announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> that he won't run again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>, who will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81</TIMEX> when
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX> ends, is increasingly frail. He too may retire. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>--that's when we should celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>, because that's when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will finally be rid of both of them.

         
      
   
