
   
   
      
         
            Content Is King

            After the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Jr.</ENAMEX>'s assassination, a host of civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> made a grab for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mantle</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lowery</ENAMEX> laid claim to it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> waved
the bloody shirt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Widow Coretta Scott King</ENAMEX> established the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jr. Center for Nonviolent Social Change</ENAMEX> Inc. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin King III</ENAMEX> made a brief stab
at a political career. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who has capitalized most on the legacy is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dexter King</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> emerged as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1995</TIMEX>, when he succeeded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coretta</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Center</ENAMEX>. He inaugurated his tenure with a call to arms: "My father
delivered political freedom, and I would like to deliver economic freedom. ...
I'm calling home all those freedom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> who marched with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. Dexter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott King</ENAMEX> is going to be there with you this time, and we will make it to the
promised land."

            The promised land, as it
turned out, looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graceland</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX>'s first acts as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was
to meet the caretakers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>' image to learn how to market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> like the
King. He hasn't let up since. In the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX> alone, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> family
has:

            signed a contract with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>, who plans a movie about the assassination (just imagine the scene
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX>, dolled up in tutu and lip gloss, orders the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
hit);

            made a gigantic deal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> to market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX>'s speeches and writings; and

            sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>,
alleging that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> had violated copyright laws by excerpting the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Have</ENAMEX>
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream</ENAMEX>" speech in a documentary.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> also made headlines by announcing
that it supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX>'s motion for a trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>, who pleaded guilty
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s assassination without trial, is dying of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">liver disease</ENAMEX>. He claims he
was a patsy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> hint at a grand and sinister conspiracy.

            Dexter, it
seems, has revived the dream. Not that dream, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dream
that anyone can make a fortune. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> version, all it takes is a catalog
of marketable data, vigorous application of copyright law, the financial muscle
of a multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media conglomerate</ENAMEX>, a few good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and frequent
talk-show appearances.

            
Talking with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter King</ENAMEX> is a disconcerting,
demoralizing experience. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disconcerting</ENAMEX> because his voice has the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intonation</ENAMEX>, the same accent, the same creamy richness as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demoralizing</ENAMEX> because his message is so distant from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> spoke
the language of protest, sacrifice, spirituality. Beneath <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX>'s stentorian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tones</ENAMEX> and rhythmic tide one hears only managementese. "It makes logical
sense to align ourselves with a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the industry. " "We are
moving from the hardware side of the business to the software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX>. " His
"vision," he assures me, is "holistic."

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> took over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Center</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonprofit</ENAMEX> needed help.
Coretta was a reliable liberal mascot, but she foundered as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> had become a hodgepodge of unconnected programs--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">day-care center</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>, a nonviolence training <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. It alienated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and
overshot its budget, amassing a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> deficit by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>. "The
programmatic impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Center</ENAMEX> across the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last decade</TIMEX> has been
somewhere between small and nonexistent," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Garrow</ENAMEX>, who won the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> biography, Bearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> .

            Dexter, who had spent most of his professional career as a
music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>, was the one who realized that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was
sitting on a valuable asset: the collected works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>
These were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24-carat</NUMEX> golden oldies.

            If content is king, Dexter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reasoned</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> should be content. Consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> licensing deal,
which will generate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $10 million</NUMEX> a year for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> estate. It
covers every angle a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">media entrepreneur</ENAMEX> could dream of: highbrow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nonfiction</ENAMEX> (the first comprehensive collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s sermons); innovative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nonfiction (a King</ENAMEX> "autobiography" cobbled together from his writings);
audiotapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX> speeches; high-tech (a fancy civil-rights Web site); and
even a little snack for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX>'s ego (the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s memoirs, which are to
include his thoughts on health and nutrition). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> partner
and college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Jones</ENAMEX> have also accelerated licensing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> products: You can now buy "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keep the Dream Alive</ENAMEX>" checks and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tasteful King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">statuettes</ENAMEX>. (Countering a question about tackiness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dexter</ENAMEX> says,
"You should see what we turned down--'I <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have a Dream</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> pocketknives.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> are also seeking financing for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pièce de résistance</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Dream Center</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50-million</NUMEX> interactive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> complete with virtual-reality games. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Journal-Constitution</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Tucker</ENAMEX> has dubbed it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Have a Dreamland</ENAMEX>."

            The family
has also tightened its grip on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s work. Besides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> suit, it won <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,700</NUMEX>
plus legal fees from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> after the newspaper reprinted the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Have</ENAMEX>
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream</ENAMEX>" speech without permission. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> demand stiff payments from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> who want to republish or air <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s speeches.

            
Not surprisingly, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King fans</ENAMEX> see something
grotesque in milking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s immortal words for cash. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garrow</ENAMEX> and fellow
King biographer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor Branch</ENAMEX> have criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for its tight-fisted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control of King</ENAMEX>'s papers. Civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Bond</ENAMEX>, who reprinted three
King speeches in a textbook, has denounced the exorbitant rates charged by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> estate. Bond estimated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX> fees alone added <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $10 and $15</NUMEX>
to the price of his book. "It is a travesty in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> legacy. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">belong to Mary?</ENAMEX>" asks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hosea Williams</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>
lieutenant.

            Dexter
does have copyright law on his side, a point that he makes with numbing
regularity. "It has always been our legal right [to control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s works]," he
says. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> may claim <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> as its civic saint and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Have a Dream</ENAMEX>" as a
national manifesto, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s words belong to his estate. In fact, the words
are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s only inheritance, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> left no material legacy. Dexter
also scoffs at the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> would be appalled. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>
himself copyrighted the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Have a Dream</ENAMEX>" speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> after he delivered it,
and he sued a record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to enforce the copyright. (Not that King
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">père</ENAMEX> was always so scrupulous about copyright. He did, after all, commit
plagiarism when writing his dissertation.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> also preaches free-market moralism. Marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLK</ENAMEX> is
not merely good business--it's good, period. The real purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX>,
he says, is to revive his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s image, to spread "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kingian</ENAMEX>" thought in the
most effective way possible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publicizing King</ENAMEX> will make him live: "His media
was marching. We are substituting the means of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--CD-ROMs, the Internet,
books--to get the message out. ... Our intentions were not for profit. The
profit happens to be a byproduct of doing the right thing."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, after all, can
reach the entire world. A small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> press can't. "The end result of what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> is doing now will be to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s ideas far more publicly accessible
than they ever have been before," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> Clayborne
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carson</ENAMEX>, who is editing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s papers for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Center</ENAMEX>.

            It's an
argument that would go down easier if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> were promoting anything
besides commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>. After all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Center</ENAMEX> has
eliminated (or, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dexter</ENAMEX>'s words, "divested") the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX>'s social-welfare and
educational programs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dexter</ENAMEX> rarely takes public positions on subjects that
don't concern the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King family</ENAMEX>'s bottom line.

            
Which brings us to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case
where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> has taken a position on a public issue. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coretta</ENAMEX> testified at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee</ENAMEX> hearing in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s request for a trial.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> has requested (and been denied) a trial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> family
has never backed his petitions before. But this time is different, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dexter</ENAMEX>,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> is dying, and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> family has asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> to speak
out. (More cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> say this time is different because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>'
deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dexter</ENAMEX> says the family has always doubted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>, and he cites "compelling new evidence" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s innocence collected
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Pepper</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biographer Garrow</ENAMEX>, himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of the
assassination, calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX>'s evidence "complete, utter, hilarious bullshit.
... The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dexter</ENAMEX> and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX> seriously is sad."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>, calling for ballistics tests to determine if a gun with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fingerprint</ENAMEX> fired the lethal bullet. But this decision is a long, long way from
a trial. If an appeals court sustains the ruling (which is considered
unlikely), and if subsequent ballistics tests indicate that the gun did not
fire the deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX>, then there could be a new trial.

            Not that the delay has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deterred Dexter</ENAMEX>. He's planning to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. And he's
taking his case to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> book- and audiotape- and
movie-ticket-buying public. He did <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> . He did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie Cochran</ENAMEX>'s
show. He did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>'s show. He did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montel</ENAMEX> . That's what a King
does in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
