
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>, a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Percy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>, reigns as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of rap. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28-year-old</TIMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> albums in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billboard</ENAMEX> 's Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>. Rappers on his No Limit record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
more, and he has just signed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snoop Dogg</ENAMEX>, hip-hop's biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, to a recording
contract. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>'s new movie, a blaxploitation comedy titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Got the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hook-Up</ENAMEX> , which he wrote, produced, and stars in, has already grossed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, far more than the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX> he spent to make it. His No Limit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">empire</ENAMEX> has been valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>. Hip-hop's leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vibe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Source</ENAMEX> , have run adoring cover stories about him,
and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> has anointed him rap's savviest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> phenomenon is an object lesson in how far rap hasn't come as an art
and how far it has come as a business. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX>: how far it hasn't come. The hype
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> has overlooked the banality of his music. He is unapologetically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ghetto</ENAMEX>. He was a teen-age hood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>--his (terrible) autobiographical
movie, I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bout It</ENAMEX> , hints that he was a major crack-house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>--and
he likes to say that his music is "authentic." Namely: It celebrates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX>
life of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, violence, and general sociopathic idiocy.

            Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is a "nigga," every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> a "bitch," and all and
sundry are "motherfuckas." The title track of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> triple platinum album,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ghetto</TIMEX> D , is a recipe for making crack from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> hits all
the clichés of gangster rap: the elegy honoring murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeboys</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chronicle</ENAMEX> of his rise through the drug-dealing ranks, the tribute to marijuana,
the paean to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>. The rhymes are <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, though the beats are potent, as in
this clip of his trademark groan, "unghh." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kane</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fiend, Silkk the Shocker, C-Murder, Mac, Mia X</ENAMEX>, etc.--hew to the same
gangster themes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>'s marketing does too: No Limit album covers are heavy
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, bikinied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, gold jewelry, wads of cash, and No Limit's logo: a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamond</ENAMEX>-encrusted tank.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>,
in short, promotes and produces the same socially appalling (if aurally
appealing) kind of rap that had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> predicting the end
of civilization <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>. Back then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> would have sparked public
outcry and condemnation. Why doesn't he <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? Why is there no hue and cry
about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>?

            
Gangster rap was supposed to be a minor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perversion</ENAMEX>, a sick dead end. It was supposed to have been killed by now,
murdered by public backlash, or by the resurgence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> & B, or by its own
fratricidal strife. But instead of dying, gangster rap has been
institutionalized, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> (as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tupac Shakur</ENAMEX> and others). It
has become cliché. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Familiarity</ENAMEX> has bred indifference. No Limit's music does not
outrage because it does not surprise.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>
is, and I mean this in the best possible way, a hack. He sticks to the
conventions of the genre and produces derivative, competent music. Even his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> admit he breaks no new ground and is essentially a skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">imitator</ENAMEX> of
more innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. But hackdom, I would argue, may be the proof of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX>'s maturity. Motown spawned zillions of copycat acts, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grunge</ENAMEX> joined
the mainstream when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nirvana rip-offs</ENAMEX> began winning gold records. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>, too,
represents the mainstreaming of a once-outrageous art.

            There is another reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> doesn't prompt any
outrage: the glorification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>. No one pays attention to what
he sells because everyone is so fascinated by how he sells it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rap</ENAMEX> has always
been a commercial affair, and there is a long history of hip-hop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Def Jam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Simmons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Rubin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row</ENAMEX>'s Suge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knight; Bad Boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Puff Daddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, to name a few--but there
may not have been anyone with better business instincts than Master P.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, he has turned a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> into a multimedia <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>.
The No. 1 lesson of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> school of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>: ownership. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Musicians</ENAMEX>
have been getting ripped off by their record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> as long as there have
been record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> wouldn't permit that to happen to him. He is
the most independent of the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>. He started selling records
out of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and he hasn't relinquished control of anything yet. He owns
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> recordings, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, his label. By paying the production costs of
I Got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hook-Up</ENAMEX> out of his own pocket and retaining ownership of it,
he stands to make at least twice as much as he would have if he had taken
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> offer to buy it outright. "This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> where
everyone has a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX>-an-hour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> negotiating for them. You have to admire P
for doing all this on his own, putting the records and movies out himself and
turning it into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> figure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>," says rap legend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Stephney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">StepSun Music</ENAMEX>.

            
The other guiding principles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>
operation are volume and speed. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Corman</ENAMEX> is to movies, he is to rap.
No Limit CDs usually include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> songs--nearly twice as many as other hip-hop
CDs. He sells double albums at single album prices. He works fast, producing
his latest straight-to-video movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Da Last Don</ENAMEX> , in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX>, and he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> albums in even less time. Everything is branded and tied together: All
No Limit albums advertise coming albums by other No Limit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. He makes
movies in order to sell soundtracks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cross-marketing works</ENAMEX>: No Limit CDs,
advertised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> in advance inside other No Limit CDs, sell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of copies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their first week</TIMEX> in record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. No single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>
product is phenomenally successful, but there are lots of them, and all are
profitable. It adds up. (He has taken his vast fortune and diversified: He runs
a sports-management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, a shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, a gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, a clothing line, and
a phone-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.)

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">do-it-yourself</ENAMEX>, bootstrapping ethos is admirable, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> also represents
something more atavistic. He sometimes refers to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> as the "No
Limit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." If it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, it's more like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corleones</ENAMEX> than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleavers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> was a hood and a hustler, and even as a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, he
behaves like a hood and a hustler. He models No Limit on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>, not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fortune 500</ENAMEX>. He calls his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Limit Soldiers</ENAMEX>." Some of them are named
after mobsters: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gambino Family, Goodfellas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li'l Gotti</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> values loyalty
and friendship above all: Most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> or homeboys. The
hip-hop industry is concentrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, but he and the No
Limit posse occupy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baton Rouge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La.</ENAMEX> They are well armed and wear
bulletproof <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vests</ENAMEX>. And they don't welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>.

            This may not be the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> for a durable business
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">empire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simmons</ENAMEX>, probably rap's greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>, lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>;
schmoozes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>, fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, and record <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>; and cuts deals
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>. He is sophisticated, urbane, wise to
capital flows and big business.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>, by contrast, seems
to be following in the footsteps of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row Records</ENAMEX>. In
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '90s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX> built <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row</ENAMEX> into a phenomenally profitable rap
label, even bigger than No Limit is now. Suge, too, imitated mob style, valuing
loyalty and insularity over all, surrounding himself with thuggish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX>.
Death Row was run more like a criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> than a real business, with
huge, suspicious cash payments; shoddy accounting; and management by
intimidation. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row</ENAMEX> collapsed. Star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakur</ENAMEX> was murdered,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX> went to jail.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX> has avoided such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chaos</ENAMEX>, so far. But can he forever? If he abandons his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> pose and posse he
abandons the image and the "authenticity" that made him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>. If he
doesn't he could end up like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master P</ENAMEX>, neither is an appealing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
