
   
   
      
         
            Ideas! Optimism! Compassion!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of ideas.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> is compassionate, a self-described "bleeding-heart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> is optimistic. These are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> great strengths <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> is said to
bring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ticket. And the downside? Judging from the media
coverage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s only problem is that he may be too good for the job: too
reasonable for his extreme-conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, too idealistic to get along with
the world-weary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, too boyishly bumptious to sit quietly in second
place.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> is neither a phony nor
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX>. He is sincere, well-meaning, and impossible not to like. But he has
gotten an amazing free pass, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> chose him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, on his three
alleged strengths.

            Take his
so-called ideas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> does, indeed, love ideas. But he loves them the way a
rare-book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX> loves his leather volumes. He loves to acquire them, own
them, fondle them, display them--everything but open them up and read them.
Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> adds "ideas" to his collection--supply-side economics, the gold
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard</ENAMEX>, enterprise zones, school vouchers--then immediately puts them behind
glass. A real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of ideas loves to play with ideas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> just loves to repeat
them.

            It's laughably easy to get a reputation as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. At least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>, unlike the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of ideas in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX>, does not posture as the chin-pulling philosopher. Indeed his
self-deprecating I'm-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just</NUMEX>-a-dumb-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> routine inoculates him against charges of
intellectual pretension. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> will, for example, ostentatiously throw out
the full name of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Baptiste</ENAMEX>
Say"--as a way of implying, incorrectly, that he has more than the vaguest
notion of what <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Say's Law</ENAMEX> ("supply creates its own demand") is about--other than
knowing that it includes the magic word "supply." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> are impressed. And
if they aren't completely buffaloed, they still give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> points for effort and
obvious sincerity. Even an empty enthusiasm for ideas is appealing in a party
whose other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>) claim
not to have read their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>.

            Like the first names of dead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, the blizzard of statistics that blows through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s oeuvre
of op-eds gives an impression of learning. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> is a propagandist, not
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> small example. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last February</TIMEX>,
arguing (surprise, surprise) that tax cuts will increase tax revenues, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>
wrote: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the 1980s</ENAMEX>, taxes were lowered from a top marginal rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28 percent</NUMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s real gross domestic product
surged by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX>." A little math reveals that this "surge" implies average
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> GDP growth of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.8 percent</NUMEX>--not too different from the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5 percent</NUMEX> growth
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> claims is woefully inadequate. (And the difference,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Allen</ENAMEX> pointed out in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> a while
back can be fully accounted for by the ironic fact that government
spending--which is part of GDP--grew in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'80s</ENAMEX> and is shrinking in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'90s</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s writings have no more inaccuracies, misleading
statistics, and fallacious arguments than those of most other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. But
a glaring internal contradiction is especially telling for a would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of
ideas: It suggests that you are not subjecting your own "ideas" to even the
minimal test of logical consistency.

            What's
usually missing from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s "ideas" is the intellectual discipline of
acknowledging that more of this means less of that. Regarding abortion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>
says, "My premise is that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>--the
unborn--should have constitutional protections for life and freedom." It would
be lovely if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s freedom to choose didn't conflict with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>' claim on
life. But the notion that this can be arranged is a magic wish, not an
idea.

            
The same defect mars <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s "compassion."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> seem to regard "bleeding-heart conservative" as a charming anomaly,
or a welcome melding of extremes into moderation, rather than as a mathematical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conundrum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> is in favor of expensive programs for the poor. He also favors
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX> tax cuts for the rich. And he opposes any cuts in middle-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entitlements</ENAMEX>. It is a remarkable coincidence that none of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s "ideas" for
helping the poor--which get him so much credit for being
"compassionate"--involves any effort or sacrifice by the affluent and the
middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. Quite the contrary: They almost invariably involve tax breaks for
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. No doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> sincerely believes in the supply-side <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alchemy</ENAMEX>. And
no doubt his personal compassion for society's downtrodden is real. But as
public policy, cost-free compassion is worth about what it costs.

            Which
brings us to "optimism." I, too, would be optimistic if I thought most of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> problems could be solved by lower taxes for everyone, even lower taxes
for rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, no taxes at all for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> (yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>
has proposed a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> tax rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K Street</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> socialites),
and that the more you cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s taxes, the more money will flood into the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX>. But believing that requires more than a leap of faith: It
requires a leap of reason.

            It's easy to be optimistic if you believe in the tooth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fairy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> seems to think that those who refuse to leap with him actually
prefer pain, sacrifice, and "root-canal economics." And it's probably
true that psychological predisposition, as much as reason and intellect, leads
dour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX> (and--until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>) to be
preachers of sacrifice, while sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX>
for alchemy. But it's silly to prize optimism for its own sake in a public
figure, irrespective of whether that optimism is justified. Indeed, unjustified
optimism is more dangerous than unjustified pessimism. Unless that is just a
dour predisposition talking.

            The main reason the media
have greeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> so rapturously isn't his ideas, his optimism, or his
compassion. It is simple, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>-like gratitude for a reason to declare the
presidential race more interesting. And credit for that compassionate,
optimistic idea goes to cruel, brain-dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sourpuss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>. So, credit given.
Now, let's give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> the going-over he deserves.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
