
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flytrap Goes for Baroque</ENAMEX>

            It is a popular view among
pundits that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> has entered what they like to call its "endgame." But I
think the scandal has moved into a very different phase: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baroque</ENAMEX>.

            Here's
what I mean. Flytrap as a journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> is in a holding pattern.
Everyone is waiting--for leaks about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s testimony, for the DNA
tests, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s grand jury day. There is a vacuum of genuinely new
information.

            Punditry abhors a vacuum. So, in the absence of news,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> are concocting ever more ornate theories to explain
what could be happening, sculpting the long available info into gaudy new
patterns. Some of these theories are based on intelligent guesswork. Some
belong to the "I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who talked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who
said ..." school. Some are malicious rumor. Some are wishful thinking. Some may
even have a tenuous relationship to an actual fact. But, at bottom, all are
founded on essentially the same knowledge base: none.

            The result: spectacular
theories, tales decorated with filigree and gilded rosettes and stucco clouds.
Since these may be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final few days</TIMEX> before real new facts about Flytrap
emerge, let's take a last chance to revel in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baroque</ENAMEX>. Having spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the past</TIMEX>
few days collecting theories from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, and other scandalholics,
I offer you a few of the best (divided into appropriate categories).

            
               The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">She Still Loves Him</ENAMEX>"
Theories
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The main source of leaks
about the dress, the answering machine messages, the talking points, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s testimony is none other than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> herself (through her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>). Why
would she leak? Because she still adores him, and she wants to signal him about
how he can protect himself when he testifies.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is testifying only
because she wants to force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to admit their love affair to the world.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The dress is a sham.
There are no stains. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> gave it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to discredit his investigation and
save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               Other
Theories <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About the Dress Not Contingent on Monica Loving Him</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, ever imaginative,
bragged about the dress to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> even though it was just an ordinary
dress. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> negotiated with her, he asked about it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> then used the
dress as a bargaining chip to guarantee her full immunity, even though she knew
there was nothing on it. Since she has full immunity, it doesn't hurt her if
it's bogus.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) There is semen on the
dress, but it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, in her usual mendacious way, lied to
Tripp about it.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> leaked the
existence of the dress as a favor to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. They wanted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> that there is plenty of damning evidence of an affair, so
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> would know not to lie to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wag</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dog Theories</ENAMEX>
            

            There are, believe it or
not, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> separate scenarios suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may use a war abroad to
distract attention from his war at home. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> (thanks to artfully timed
obstinacy by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of the widest
speculation. My favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX> target is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Kitts</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX> where a local <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charles "Little Nut</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>) has threatened
to murder <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s veterinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> tries to extradite him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Kitts</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grenada</ENAMEX>.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Theories</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants to apologize
but is afraid to because he never told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. (She did not mind
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> affair, because she knew about it.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fears she will
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hate/divorce/abandon/</ENAMEX>kill him if he admits the affair.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Very similar to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Theory 1</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> won't let him apologize because she has spent so much of her
own credibility defending him ("vast right-wing conspiracy," etc.). She refuses
to be made to look like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible fool</ENAMEX>.

            
               The
Right-Wing Conspiracy Theory
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> belonged to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">devious</ENAMEX>, long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> conspiracy with, as one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of the theory
puts it, "instructions to orally seduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in order to assure
positive transfer of his semen (positive proof of sexual acts) on an article of
her clothing." Thus she kept the dress, knowing that her affair was going to be
made public by her good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX>, and she would have a
chance to produce the dress as evidence.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Non-Right-Wing Conspiracy Theory</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last fall</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> before her
existence was revealed to the public), a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>
to avoid a neighbor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had had an affair and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> should take
special care not to be seen or photographed with her, because it would lend
credence to theories that the affair is a right-wing conspiracy and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
was a bimbo <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mea Culpa Theories</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has
already contacted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> to reserve television time (on either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16</TIMEX> or
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>) for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apology.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erskine Bowles</ENAMEX>, are contacting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to
see how they would react to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mea culpa</ENAMEX> .

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Dissent Theories</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) A corollary to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mea</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Culpa 2</ENAMEX>" above. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> are not contacting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mea culpa</ENAMEX> , but they are leaking the story that they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contacting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. They are doing this to pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to apologize. They
must use the media and rumor to communicate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, because they
are not allowed to talk to him about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> directly.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> is about to turn on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to save himself. Or, more plausibly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> just had back surgery in order to delay his testimony. Now he won't
testify till after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> a chance to mold his story to
support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
Some of the conspiracies are so peculiar, so
much the product of an alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> that they can't be categorized. These come
untouched from the inky void of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, both courtesy of 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigation
is not focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and obstruction of justice. It is really concerned
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> testified for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX>, because she was
providing evidence about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is not planning
either to apologize or to fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> allegations. In fact, having
implemented his entire political agenda and revived the economy, he is
preparing to resign.

            Remember what comes after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baroque era: the Enlightenment</ENAMEX>.

            A final note on another
subject. During her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> press briefing (that's a briefing!) last night,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Smith</ENAMEX> offered this absurd bit of one-upmanship.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, testified "truthfully, completely, and honestly."

            Why is this significant?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, you see, promised only to testify "completely and truthfully." What
about "honestly," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
