
   
   
      
         
            The New Courtney

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Love</ENAMEX> used to say
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alanis Morissette</ENAMEX> had killed alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> with her carefully crafted
brand of faux angry-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> rock. I'd argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> put the nail in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coffin</ENAMEX> herself <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar night</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Cobain</ENAMEX> and "Queen
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grunge</ENAMEX>" threw a post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in a yellowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX>-store gown and tiara,
the embodiment of rock-star glamour. This time, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The People</ENAMEX>
vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> , she'd had her famously scraggly hair blown out into a
variation on the straight little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Wintour bob</ENAMEX>. Her face, applied by
celebrity makeup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Aucoin</ENAMEX>, had lost that jolie laide quality that
used to make her so compelling. And she was wearing a tasteful dress by Gianni
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Versace</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Versace</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who built his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> dressing the very same
past-their-prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Bon Jovi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX>) in opposition to whom
alternative rock arose. She presented the award for best makeup, of all things,
and played it completely straight, talking in the measured mid-Atlantic accent
that her new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> seems to adopt when she wants to sound
cultivated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sulky Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX>--who refused to sing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar-</ENAMEX>nominated
song because she herself hadn't been nominated for anything--came off as a
bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.

            There are
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">rock</ENAMEX>-world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> who never considered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX>, who dismissed her
as a marginally talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX> who married well and whose stock rose
precipitously after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> committed suicide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of
long-divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who is a New Age therapist and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful Dead</ENAMEX> hanger-on--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney</ENAMEX> left home while in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and blew a
meager trust fund traveling the world. She lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, and always managed to hook up with powerful figures such
as film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Cox</ENAMEX>. She worked as a stripper. She pursued Cobain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relentlessly</ENAMEX>, convincing a record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> that was wooing her to fly her to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nirvana</ENAMEX> show so she could meet him. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>, before anyone in the
mainstream knew who she was, she was already such a legendary social climber on
the indie-rock scene that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> called itself "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courtney Love</ENAMEX>"
just to get on her nerves.

            All this deepened the luster of her image. In an age in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and publicists once again monitor a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>'s movements as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">religiously</ENAMEX> as they did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>--when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock Hudson</ENAMEX> was forced to marry his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to forestall rumors that he was gay--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney</ENAMEX> was an imperious and
slightly unhinged anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, physically incapable of keeping her mouth
shut. Once, at a concert in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, she turned to the industry-heavy VIP
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> and threatened anyone who "fucked with" her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Billig, who had just been named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Records</ENAMEX>. She punched
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Hanna</ENAMEX> of the riot grrrl <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">band Bikini Kill backstage at Lollapalooza</ENAMEX>,
and referred to her as "ratface." She was kicked off <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX> for making
remarks that were too unladylike. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, she chased another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer/songwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Lou Lord</ENAMEX>, down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunset Boulevard</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> showed up
uninvited at the after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for one of her shows.

            But her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>--the primarily female, vaguely cerebral, post-boomer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> like me who
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">made her band Hole's album Live Through This</ENAMEX> go <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">platinum</ENAMEX> (that is, sell
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> copies)--admired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> in the face of evidence that she was
something of a trial. She was a less-than-fit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> with a drug habit,
which was unfortunate (she has since stopped using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>). The backlash against
her on that score still seemed misogynous. How many drug-addled male rock stars
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have been taken to task for the same behavior? Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richards</ENAMEX>; not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX>; not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aerosmith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Tyler</ENAMEX>, who didn't even
acknowledge his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX> until she was in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>. Leaving behind a
trail of babies conceived with groupies has long been a key to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>-rock
mystique.

            
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> had a brain and was not
afraid to use it. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney</ENAMEX> seemed much more real and more pertinent than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, whose strength and sexuality appear, by comparison, cold and
calculating--a power-suited '80s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, with little range for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradiction</ENAMEX>. "I want to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> with the most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney</ENAMEX> sang on
Live Through This . It was a perfect expression of the kind of
cut-and-paste feminism young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> I know practice, which makes room for
self-destructiveness and fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Perla</ENAMEX> lingerie and fury.
Onstage she'd prop her leg up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> and wail into the microphone like
any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. Offstage, she'd announce that she had got a nose job, lost weight, and
dyed her hair blond because she knew that that was what it was going to take to
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay attention to her. It wasn't just idolatry we felt; it was
anxiety, memories of the times when she was so strung out at a show that she
had to be carried offstage by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> shouted "slut" and
"whore." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hole</ENAMEX> played its first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> show after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cobain</ENAMEX>'s death, every rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> showed up to see if she'd pull it
off. (She did.)

            In order
for The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> to qualify for insurance coverage during
the shoot, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> had to prove her sobriety by peeing into a cup once a week.
One can understand her desire, then, to continue proving to the world that
she's no longer a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loose cannon</ENAMEX>. And a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is certainly entitled to make
herself over. In fact, now that mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Sheryl Crow</ENAMEX> have
adopted the trashed-out slutty look, it was probably canny of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> to
rethink her style. And there may not be a lot of room for subversion at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuba Gooding Jr.</ENAMEX> gets a standing ovation just for
gleefully evading the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> acceptance-speech rule.

            Afriend of mine who knows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney</ENAMEX> says she's still the
same old feisty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cuss</ENAMEX> once the cameras are off, but that just means she's
getting good at separating her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private personas, at being the kind
of slick movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> whose opinions stay within well-demarcated boundaries.
Under this new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Courtney</ENAMEX> who, amazingly, has nothing she wants
to share with us about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Steinem</ENAMEX>'s old-school-feminist attack on the movie
and on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>, with whom she has become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Courtney</ENAMEX> who told
Premiere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>: "The welcome that I get from grown-ups in the film
industry is so nice. I'm used to going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> and having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in black
lipstick scream at me, 'I love you! I didn't kill myself because of you!' Or,
'You suck!' But a grown-up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 50s</TIMEX>, in a suit, being nice? I melt."

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hole</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> it would be a shame, but not a tragedy--she's a good
actress too. It's not as if she's sold out, because any major-label rock star
who claims to have managed not to is self-deluded. But while she's obviously
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> on the order of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pablo Picasso</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>, she does have an
outsize, nasty personality, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aren't offered that spectacle very often.
It's odd to watch a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who named her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> for the notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
rule-breaker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Farmer</ENAMEX> purring at a pat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
phonies she would formerly have laughed at. But as she herself once sang, "I
fake it so real I am beyond fake." It may be that the artificial construction
that is the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> is the realest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Courtney</ENAMEX> yet.

         
      
   
