
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifty-Seven Ways</ENAMEX> to Say

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the weirdest and most
pernicious side effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> has been the relocation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
to an alternative universe, a place where up is down and down is up and
everything is the opposite of what it should be.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> universe,
there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Ruff</ENAMEX>) who can't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, a presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confidant</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>) whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can't confide in, a presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who acts like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who acts like a criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>,
and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intern</ENAMEX> who has more power than any of them.

            The most
public manifestation of the bizarro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX>. He has become
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spinner</ENAMEX> who can't spin, a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> who can't talk to the
press or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> about the only issue they care about.

            Here, as evidence, are the notes I managed to scrawl during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> press briefing. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> unless
otherwise indicated, and the subject is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>.)

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has answered
all questions.
            

            
               It's clear there is
nothing more to say.
            

            
               I am not going to add
anything.
            

            
               I don't have anything to
add. [twice]

            
               You played a semantic game
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. I am not playing that game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
            

            
               You played a semantic
game.
            

            
               That has been asked and
answered.
            

            
               I just said I was not
prepared with any information.
            

            
               The same questions were
asked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.
            

            
               The answer is the same
answer. It is the same answer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> gave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31</TIMEX>.
            

            
               We don't know.
            

            
               I obviously don't have any
information.
            

            
               I don't have any
information.
            

            
               I just don't have an
answer.
            

            
               I don't have an answer to
that.
            

            
               That was asked and
answered.
            

            
               That was asked and I don't
have the answer.
            

            
               I don't have any
answers.
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have not
passed on any answers to us. We have passed on the questions, and they have
said they would take them under advisement.
            

            
               I am not making any news
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I made that clear.
            

            
               I don't have any
information.
            

            
               I don't know.
            

            
               We don't have anything to
talk about. (To which tart <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Thomas</ENAMEX> responds: "We do have something to
talk about, but you're not talking about it.")

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>, we have been through
that.
            

            
               I have not said
anything.
            

            
               I have not talked to him
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about this</TIMEX>.
            

            
               I have not talked to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> about it.
            

            
               I have
made it clear I have nothing to say on that subject <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quizzing McCurry</ENAMEX> is like playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> against
a mattress. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> of questions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> manage to glean
nothing--not a single picayune detail--except the obvious fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have barred any public discussion. Among the subjects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> has no
answers about: whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will address the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>, whether
any of the logistics of his testimony will be revealed, whether he will answer
all questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> has talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> has talked to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, whether "completely and truthfully" means the same thing it did at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s press briefing, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Thomason</ENAMEX> is prepping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomason</ENAMEX> is staying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Throughout McCurry</ENAMEX>'s litany of refusal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> seethes, periodically
interrupting with shouts of "Why are you denigrating us?" and "It's not a
game!")

            Ican't decide whom I feel sorrier for, the reporters
without stories or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> without answers. The assembled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> have to
ask questions, but they know he can't answer them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> has nothing. For
fear of subpoenas and legal bills, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> simply can't talk to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. He is in the impossible position of interpreting and
reinterpreting exactly the same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> public statements <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has made on the
subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> ("that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> and "completely and truthfully" in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>). He is otherwise a blank. The result: a farce, a mockery of discourse, an
embarrassment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> and the press corps.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX>
may be obliged by ignorance to stiff-arm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, but that doesn't mean the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is inattentive to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> report <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> are busy testing
how the press and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> would respond to a limited mea culpa .) (For
more on the utter cynicism of this latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House PR</ENAMEX> ploy, see <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FRAME GAME</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
Flag.)

            
When everyone eventually tires of this thrust
and parry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> adjourns the briefing and disappears into the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Wing</ENAMEX>.
Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Press Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX>, who will succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> as press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>, remains behind. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockhart</ENAMEX>, I had noticed, spent the
entire briefing doodling red squares on his pad.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockhart</ENAMEX> has learned well
from his departing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>. I eavesdrop as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> corner the deputy
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>. I can just hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockhart</ENAMEX>'s soft, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> voice. "We get asked
the same questions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. You know as well as I do why we can't answer. ...
Of course I haven't spoken to him. If I had discussed it with him I would be
running up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> a day in legal fees and be in front of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>."

            As I
leave <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> later I still hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockhart</ENAMEX>, now pinned by another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>: "I don't know. ... I don't know."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flytrap Today": The complete chronicles</ENAMEX>.

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
