
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX>

            Of all the stupid things the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX> has done during its disastrous fling with
commercialism, choosing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX> as its business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> has to be
the most stupid. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s nicknames-- preferred nicknames--are "Chainsaw
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pinstripes</ENAMEX>," so you can scarcely imagine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more
antithetical worldviews than his and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX>'s. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> pitches itself as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s selfless medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>, indifferent to the demands of the
marketplace. Dunlap, by contrast, is the marketplace. The most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">coldblooded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> around, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> personifies the relentless logic of Wall
Street. He champions efficiency and ruthlessness, and follows no higher
principle than the value of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock. If the market is controlled by
an invisible hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> is its iron fist.

            The AMA
hoped the would help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s bottom line, and not cause it embarrassment.
But since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its Aug. 12</TIMEX> announcement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> has been teaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> a
painful lesson in the realities of the market. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> tried to soft-pedal the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> deal as a consumer-education project, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> exploded that notion
by touting its commercialism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>, he declared, would eagerly advertise its
exclusive AMA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>. When public outrage prompted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> to wriggle free
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> deal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> threatened to sue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> to
enforce the contract. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> haven't settled their dispute, but
everyone knows who won and who lost. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has received a vast
amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. Its little-known home-health-care product line got a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
boost. Its stock price jumped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> points. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, will spend the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next few months</TIMEX> (or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) trying to repair its image. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> has been
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlapped</ENAMEX>."

            Aholy terror of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> has emerged as the mascot of
a new kind of capitalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlapism</ENAMEX> begins and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ends</ENAMEX> at Wall Street. Its
sole credo is: "How can we make our stock worth more?" Nothing that is
valued by less steely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>--loyalty to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, responsibility to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, relationships with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, generosity in corporate
philanthropy--matters to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>. Business ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> tout "stakeholder
capitalism." Dunlap sneers at the phrase. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlapism</ENAMEX> is the perfect religion for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutual Fund Age</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> discovered, everyone who deals with Dunlap
loses--except his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>.

            Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> share his creed, but none matches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s methods. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> has run <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. He served as right-hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>/enforcer for both
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry Packer</ENAMEX> and recently deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>
Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Goldsmith</ENAMEX>. In the process, he has earned a reputation as the most
merciless turnaround <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> in the world. To wit: As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of struggling cup
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer Lily Tulip Corp.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> fired most of the senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, sold the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>, closed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>,
dumped half the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> staff, and laid off a bunch of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The
stock price rose from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.77 to $18.55</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his two-and-a-half-year</TIMEX> tenure. At
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott Paper</ENAMEX>--his pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> tour of duty--he fired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> (including
half the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>), eliminated
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3-million</NUMEX> philanthropy budget, slashed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R&D</ENAMEX> spending, and
closed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>'s market value stood at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $3 billion</NUMEX> when Dunlap
arrived in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1994</TIMEX>. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, he sold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kimberly-Clark</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, pocketing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> for himself--a modest payoff, he says, for the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> in increased shareholder value.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlapping</ENAMEX> continues at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>, a stagnant
consumer-products <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> has fired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> since
taking over in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1996</TIMEX>; sold off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX> employing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 3,000</NUMEX>;
eliminated corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>; and shuttered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>. The payoff:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>'s stock has climbed from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 to $44</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">barely a year</TIMEX>.

            What
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distinguishes Dunlap</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> is that he takes pride in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">toughness</ENAMEX>, expressing only cursory regret for having cashiered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ran a cover story about corporate layoffs, Dunlap
contributed a gleeful column about how wonderful such firings are for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>. Then he savaged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Allen</ENAMEX> publicly for not
sacking enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. He posed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX> on the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . And
he titled his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> best seller <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mean Business: How I Save Bad Companies and</ENAMEX>
Make <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Companies Great</ENAMEX> . (In it, he likens himself to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX>, fellow "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstars</ENAMEX>.")

            It's easy to hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> for the wrong reason, which is
that he is a brutal, heartless, arrogant bastard. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> skipped the funerals of both his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, failed to support
(or even pay attention to) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> from his first marriage, and refused to
help pay for his niece's <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> treatments. But to criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cruelty</ENAMEX> is akin to scolding a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> for killing an antelope. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Dunlap</ENAMEX> lacks
conscience? Well, so does the market. If Wall Street were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, it would skip
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' funerals, too. And there is logic to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s cruelty.
Struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do need to shed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in order to recover. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumping</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
percent of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> did at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott</ENAMEX>, may save the jobs of the
other <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX>. Stockholder profits should not necessarily be squandered on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>.

            But there is a right reason
to hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX>, which is this: He's not as good as he looks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> does not
know how to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. If capitalism is "creative destruction," Dunlapism
is simply destruction. He prettifies struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for Wall Street, but
undermines them in the long term. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barron's and Business Week</ENAMEX>
have chronicled how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> has built his "turnarounds" on cosmetic measures
designed to pump up stock prices. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>, he has sold assets to
raise quick cash, cut prices to artificially boost sales, and squeezed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> for short-term savings at the price of long-term reliability. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX> cuts have come at a time when other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are investing in
new technology. He uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> brilliantly: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knowlton</ENAMEX> tout him relentlessly
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, winning him an adulatory profile that serves him
well. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> he was hired, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> stock jumped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59 percent</NUMEX> on his
reputation alone. (Another example: Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> of my call to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam HQ</ENAMEX> for
information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>, I received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> voice mail messages from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> Sunbeam
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flacks</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, too, rely heavily on short-term marketing
campaigns and advertising. What he does not do is spend time developing new
products, nurturing talent, and cultivating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Why? Because he never
sticks around a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> long enough for that to matter.

            Sooner or later--almost
certainly sooner--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> will quit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>, liquidate his stock options, clear
a profit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $100 million</NUMEX>, and move on to another high-profile job.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> will be worth a lot more than it was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> arrived. It may not be
a better <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
