
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>

            Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX>, perhaps
the greatest of all self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX>, couldn't fault the hype job being done for
him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. The biopic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> opened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Judas Kiss</ENAMEX> , a play about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed</ENAMEX> love affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Douglas</ENAMEX>, debuted on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>.

            This is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildean</ENAMEX> moment. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> have been glutted with
mass-market issue: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar Wilde's Guide to Modern Living ; Wilde the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irishman ; The Oscar Wilde Reader ; Andre and Oscar ; Oscar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> (by his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vyvyan Holland</ENAMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wilde Album</ENAMEX> (by his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grandson Merlin Holland</ENAMEX>). Besides <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Judas Kiss</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s life is the
subject of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other major new plays, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several one</NUMEX>-man shows, and an opera. As
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s own work, there is the usual spate of theatrical productions, as
well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> planned films of his plays and novel.

            Normally this kind of wretched historical excess (e.g.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wretched Titanic Excess</ENAMEX>) should be deplored and stifled. But in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> culture has finally found a subject worthy of this
superfluity, someone complicated and challenging enough to endure the excess
and more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> once wrote, "I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who stood in symbolic relation to the
art and culture of my age." He is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who stands in symbolic relation to
the art and culture of our age.

            For most
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> was simply a cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, a bon-moting smart aleck.
"I can resist everything except temptation." <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Ha ha ha</NUMEX>! "There is only one thing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>." How droll, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>, how very droll! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> said that he "summed up ... all
existence in an epigram." And that is exactly how he has been perceived--as the
cool, cruel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of aphorism. His plays were produced and his quips were
plagiarized, but he himself remained a one-dimensional figure in the popular
culture.

            
That has changed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX> and
especially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>. The revival ignores the art for the sake of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, recognizing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> himself is at least as interesting as his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">one-liners</ENAMEX>. Requisite quote: "I put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> into my life. I have put only my
talent into my works."

            So why is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> suddenly so popular? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason is that this is an age of memoirs:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>, who self-consciously made his own life a work of art, is an evocative
symbol for self-involved literature. Literary nostalgia also explains the
obsession with him. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1895 and 1900</TIMEX>, he endured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> trials, was jailed
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, published his most famous poem, and died: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
anniversary of each event has been (or will be) much commemorated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s
combination of stylishness and tragedy lends itself perfectly to overcostumed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overwrought Merchant</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>-style drama.

            But there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more important reasons why this is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde time</ENAMEX>: homosexuality and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>. The rise of gay studies and increasing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX> of gay themes in popular culture have made a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> resurgence
inevitable. (This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, not his, is the gay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'90s</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s homosexuality was
ignored for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, then glossed over. When he was first claimed as a gay icon
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generation ago</TIMEX>, he was explained too simply as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>: A vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> destroyed him because it was too intolerant to accept
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX>.

            The 1990s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> provokes because he is not simple at all. In an era obsessed by identity,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexuality</ENAMEX>, and ambiguity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> is one of the most puzzling cases. His life
raises very modern questions about what homosexuality is and how much sexuality
should define identity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> is the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ur-homosexual</ENAMEX>," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> put it, yet
he never saw himself as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX>. In fact, it is only after his trials--and
partly because of his trials--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> began to be classified as
"homosexual" and "heterosexual." (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s enduring role in shaping
gay identity, click .) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> was not only not explicitly gay, he was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infrequently</ENAMEX>, and only late in life. To appreciate the complexity of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexuality</ENAMEX>, consider the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wilde plays: The Judas Kiss</ENAMEX>
focuses on his love affair with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross Indecency</ENAMEX> focuses on his
denials of his love affairs with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Secret Fall of Constance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> focuses on his love affair with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.

            
Often called the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> famous for being
famous, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> foreshadowed our modern celebrity obsession. At a time when
realism and authenticity were in vogue, his life was a stylized performance
designed to grab attention. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1880s</TIMEX>, before he had written anything
worth mentioning, he made his name as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s great young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aesthete</ENAMEX>. He mooned
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, and threw himself at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the feet</NUMEX> of actresses.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> parodied him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patience</ENAMEX> . He then got himself sent
on an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lecture tour to drum up publicity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patience</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
production. He wore outrageous clothes and quipped his way across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.
(On arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>: "I have nothing to declare except my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>.") His
lectures about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior decorating</ENAMEX> were mobbed. He also milked his fame
brilliantly after he'd achieved commercial success. He is undoubtedly the only
canonical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to endorse "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Madame Fontaine's Bosom Beautifier</ENAMEX>," a
breast-enlarging <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX>.

            Just as
his rise prefigured modern ideas about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, so also did his fall. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wilde</ENAMEX>
was the first mass-media celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> gutter press, which
was just developing a wide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, whipped up public hatred toward him over
his sex crimes and made him a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wilde scholars</ENAMEX> note his sex scandal is
curiously evocative of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s: A spectacular public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> denies sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indiscretion</ENAMEX> (in the face of overwhelming evidence) rather than risk
challenging conventional morality.

            One thing is missing from the revival: subversiveness.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> himself was endlessly transgressive, always finding a new way to jab
Victorian complacency. He made vicious fun of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> bourgeoisie in plays
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Importance of Being Earnest</ENAMEX> . The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bourgeoisie</ENAMEX> packed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and made him a fortune without realizing the joke was on them.
It's impossible <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to realize how shocking <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Picture</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorian Gray</ENAMEX>
was to 1890s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. And even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s decision to endure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> rather than
flee was a rebuke to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s inhumanity.

            But there is very little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wildness</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>. The books, plays, and movie are extremely couth,
extremely respectable. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>, a movie about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> and his gay
affair would have been considered remarkable: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, it's a cliché. At the end
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, "gross indecency" could not even be described
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Today, you can throw it on the screen and no one even notices. The
challenge for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 20 th century</TIMEX> is this:
Find a way to appall.

         
      
   
