
   
   
      
         
            NAFTA Math

            When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration releases its analysis of the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Free</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Agreement</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> will seize on the data. They'll point
to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> "certified" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Labor</ENAMEX> as
having lost their jobs because of the agreement as evidence of the treaty's
dangers. They will be pointing in the wrong direction.

            A Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> recently examined some of these job-loss cases and
found that most had little or nothing to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>. Like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> unionized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pabst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">brewery</ENAMEX> that moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> to a non-unionized plant
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Crosse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisc</ENAMEX>. Or the unionized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> toilet tissue mill
that sold out to a non-union <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which reopened the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> on the same
spot.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> responds that it is not to blame for
the sloppy way in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, seeking to soften union opposition to NAFTA
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, drafted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> monitoring rules. The law, for example, does not say
that the closing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">brewery</ENAMEX> (or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plant</ENAMEX>) has to be directly attributable
to NAFTA-induced trade in order for the displaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to be eligible for an
extra year of unemployment benefits and other "adjustment" assistance. It
requires only that imports of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> (or whatever) from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
increased during the relevant period. Nor does it matter whether, as in the
case of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith-Corona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> had already planned to move the
operation to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>; all that counts is that the move was made and that it cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> jobs at some time after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> became law.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX>
also point out that many of the certified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>" drew little or no
benefits. Instead they retired, found other jobs--or applied for regular Trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adjustment Assistance</ENAMEX>, a larger, older, and also much-abused program. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> (who have traditionally been resistant to government efforts to
"adjust" them) prefer regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAA</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> aid because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAA</ENAMEX> rules, which require
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to sign up for retraining in order to get cash, are more laxly
enforced. (In fact, the only advantage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> benefits have is that they may be
claimed when jobs are lost to plant relocations, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAA</ENAMEX> is restricted to
job losses related to higher imports.)

            
As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> benefits program, while
growing, still costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $30 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cautions</ENAMEX>, the low usage level doesn't mean that harm hasn't occurred. Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> injured by trade are likely to be employed by small, non-unionized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and either unaware of the trade benefits, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> actively
peddle to their laid-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, or in service jobs that are not covered.
Still, while these exclusions may bolster the job-loss claims of the NAFTA
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attackers</ENAMEX>, they are hardly an advertisement for the equity of the "adjustment"
they embrace.

            Even if
it were possible to find and help every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> directly or indirectly hurt by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> pacts, why should they have a larger claim for public help than those
whose jobs are lost to technological change? Or to shifts in consumer taste,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lousy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, an overpriced dollar, or domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX>? Government did
not create trade. It created trade barriers. When it removes them, should it
incur a special obligation to the formerly protected?

            In any case, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> can make no credible job-loss case
on the basis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> certifications. They may find some comfort,
however, in the aggregate trade statistics. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> ran a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21 billion</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> surplus with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, once a net <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">importer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
products, chalked up a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17.5 billion</NUMEX> export surplus with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
(while running a roughly equivalent trade deficit with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, from
which it imports large quantities of machinery and partially processed goods
for final manufacture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the numbers are projected to be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> the same, though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> surplus is expected to shrink
somewhat.

            But the
net <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> deficits are only a small part of a larger picture of growing
hemispheric integration. Since the pact, the total volume of trade among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> has grown substantially, with partially fabricated goods and
parts moving back and forth across borders before reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. In
addition to efficiency gains, these flows have helped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> recover from its
near-death experience in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1995</TIMEX>, when an orgy of import buying led to the
collapse of the peso and the flight of investor capital. Since then, austerity
has curbed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> buying of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> luxuries, and higher tariffs have helped
stem the influx of cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> textiles and footwear that threatened its
low-end industries. However, the primary engine of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> recovery, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis de la Calle</ENAMEX>, stresses--and the main
hope for spreading internal prosperity, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has a large
stake--has been export growth, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>.

            
Even for trade-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worriers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> must be rated a
small-potato <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> trade surpluses are piddling
compared to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $200 billion</NUMEX> total trade deficit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will
likely incur <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Or even compared to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$54 billion</NUMEX> surplus projected
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> (which, despite its poor-mouthing, continues to enjoy much higher
growth and lower inflation and unemployment than the prideful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>).
Still more striking is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--which buys only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-sixth</NUMEX> as much from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> does--is expected to ring up its own <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$54 billion</NUMEX> trade surplus
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer should, of course, be grateful for
the opportunity to buy all these fine goods on the credit thus extended. And
trust that our foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> will remain willing to invest their surplus
dollars in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> securities and other assets and to reinvest the proceeds from
those investments within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our</TIMEX> borders in a kindly fashion. But should that
willingness ever falter, one thing is sure: No "worker adjustment" program will
be able to measure the harm, much less assuage it.

         
      
   
