
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Groping Toward a New Liberalism</ENAMEX>

            With our reaction to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> episode, we <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have turned the concept of hypocrisy on
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">François La Rochefoucauld</ENAMEX> famously praised
hypocrisy as the socially useful "homage that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> pays to virtue." That, of
course, is very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, however, it seems that virtue
pays homage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>. Have we thought through the implications?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
in large numbers tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> that we disapprove of adultery, regularly
attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, and would like to see the return of prayer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. We claim
nostalgia for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> moral standards and propel the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of</ENAMEX>
Virtues to the top of the best-seller list. Yet <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 60 percent</NUMEX> of us,
according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times /CBS</ENAMEX> poll <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, not only don't think
it's our business whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> but
also "would understand" if he had lied about it, even under oath.

            Until now, it has been assumed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">egalitarian</ENAMEX> society should, at least in aspiration, be better--not just smarter
and braver, but more noble--than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Now we seem to be engaged in a
rapid rewind of the morality tape, zipping right through the age of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX> to
the time when the rules of droit du seigneur held sway. Then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> and bourgeoisie were expected to live lives of probity, while the king
and his court whored and plundered as they pleased.

            Can this
really be us, tugging our forelocks and mumbling, "That's OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, you go
ahead and have a good time, we'll just wait out here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> and say a few
prayers"? No, that's not us. Far more likely is that we still regard the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as a role model--it's just that, like him, we prefer his new role. We
wish we had the protective coterie of government-paid procurers and concealers
that would let us get away with it.

            
That being so, serious rethinking is in order
before we invest further in public activities incongruent with the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dispensation</ENAMEX>. Some corrections are easy and obvious. Send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> off
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepperdine</ENAMEX> and let him take all his pokings into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S & L</ENAMEX> swindles and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
file invasions and election-fund finagling with him. Nobody cares about that
other stuff, either. For a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, that's just doin' what comes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">natcherly</ENAMEX>.

            And let's
quit picking on poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Sgt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Maj.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene McKinney</ENAMEX>. If it's OK for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> to hit on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, why should we prosecute a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> so much
farther down the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>? Sure, his satisfied-customer ratio
seems to have been lower than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s, but is that any reason to put a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at
risk of a lifetime in jail? Let <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">copulation</ENAMEX> thrive, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lear</ENAMEX> would say. And
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> ends, let us grope our way toward a new liberalism.

            Other changes in federal policy are needed urgently to
support the implicit goals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Awakening</ENAMEX>. For example, we must obviously
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restore Welfare</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Knew It</ENAMEX>. Here, after all, was a program (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Families</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dependent Children</ENAMEX>) that, judged by current lights, must be rated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
the most successful social experiments of all time. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> rolls began
climbing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 10 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were
born out of wedlock. By the time the welfare rolls peaked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, that figure
had risen to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a gratifying 31 percent</NUMEX>!

            To be
sure, illegitimacy is not a perfect proxy for indiscriminate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promiscuity</ENAMEX>--although other indicators (venereal-disease incidence, divorce
rates, etc.) track well with it. Nor can AFDC take all the credit. Other
programs--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Stamps</ENAMEX>, housing aid, special feeding and educational
programs for unwed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>, and so on--certainly provided additional inducements
for unguarded sexuality. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (e.g., our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>) manage to
promiscuate pretty indiscriminately without the incentive of food stamps--just
as some minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> manage to get ahead without affirmative action. But
an extra incentive from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> surely helps.

            
And yet even now, in a misguided appeal to a
public that misunderstands its own core beliefs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is presiding
over the dismantling of this forward-looking program. Welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are being
pushed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX>, whence they will stagger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each night</TIMEX> lacking
the energy for romantic exploration. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are being told to take
responsibility for their sexual behavior and, should they slip, pay up on child
support. This threatens to undermine all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s good work in
sending the message that one should get it whenever and however one can.

            Oh, and let's cut out all
this huffing and puffing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. He's got oil to sell, and we've
got gas guzzlers to keep rolling. Anyway, by now he has surely squirreled away
all that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anthrax</ENAMEX> and poison <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> where we'll never find it with bombs or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>. Keeping all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> on alert is expensive.
It uses up money that would be much better spent on--well, tax cuts for all of
us. And while we're at it, isn't it time to jettison all this anal-retentive
preoccupation with a balanced budget? Is paying for what we get really the
essential us ? Listen instead to the subtext of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s recent,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acclaimed State of the Union</ENAMEX> message. More spending! More tax cuts! This,
surely, is where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex policy and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> social policy combine.
He wants us to feel his pleasure. And we do.

         
      
   
