
   
   
      
         
            Major League <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Soccer</ENAMEX>

            Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soccer League</ENAMEX> disintegrated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has been plagued by its soccer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bores</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, who are the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Tsongas wasn't elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, are perpetually lathered at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
indifference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of sports. But it's the most popular sport in the
world! But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> play it! But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love it! But there ought
to be a pro league! But ... but ... but ... (Full disclosure: I, too, am
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> bore.)

            Finally,
the bores have shut up. Professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, a sport whose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history is
an unbroken record of , has, at long last, found a happy home here. Major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League Soccer</ENAMEX> opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its third season</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> is drawing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> per game--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NASL</ENAMEX> averaged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 15,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its best season</TIMEX>. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>'s championship game sold out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57,000</NUMEX>-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFK</ENAMEX>
stadium.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> has TV contracts: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> will broadcast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> games this
season, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> will air <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> more. It has endorsement deals: Corporations
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> will spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 million</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> over the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. It has expansion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> just added <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchises</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>, in short, looks very much like a real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sport.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> is a
weird experiment, a test of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Soccer</ENAMEX> has always been
perceived as vaguely un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>: It's too low-scoring, there's too much
cooperation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are too small and too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX>, it looks bad on
television. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>, in fact, is un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, but not for those (wrong)
reasons. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> is un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> because it marks the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
pro sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> hasn't tried to be the best in the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> is perhaps the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 th best</TIMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> in the world, a shout and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> divisions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. (According to soccer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> could compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraguay</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraguay</ENAMEX>? )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> are a spoiled lot. It is the
philosophy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> sports that if you can't be the best, buy the best.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Americans</ENAMEX> invented <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and dominate them
by divine right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has used dollar power to make itself the
world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of other, non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHL</ENAMEX> buys the best hockey
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> from eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGA</ENAMEX> tour buys the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. Huge purses bring the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> figure skaters here.
Foreign boxers travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> for title fights. In every sport in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> stages pro competitions, those competitions are the world's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">finest</ENAMEX> (except, perhaps, for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>).

            And that
was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASL</ENAMEX>'s strategy in its glory days. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid- and late-'70s</TIMEX>, NASL
lured some of the very best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the world to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pele</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz</ENAMEX>
Beckenbauer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Best</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johan Cruyff</ENAMEX>--and flirted with being one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX>.

            But that's not the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> was designed. In an age of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly</NUMEX> universal free agency and vicious competition among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> is a
command economy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> of pro sports. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> hosted
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1994 World Cup</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">impresario</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Rothenberg</ENAMEX> recruited a bunch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX> to invest in a new pro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rothenberg</ENAMEX> believed, should avoid
the mistakes that killed NASL: too much expansion, too much spending, too many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>.

            Rothenberg devised a crafty
mechanism to lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s costs. He constituted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> as a "single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>."
Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has an "owner-operator," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> itself owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. It
negotiates all contracts and assigns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. (In other pro leagues,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> sign contracts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> can't auction themselves to the
highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>.

            Though
soccer salaries are soaring worldwide, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> has gone cut-rate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASL</ENAMEX> paid stars
more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s maximum salary is only
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$236,750</NUMEX>--less than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>'s minimum salary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s minimum is only
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24,000</NUMEX>. The payroll for an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is capped at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 million</NUMEX>--less
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of what a top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> earns. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> allows only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>
on its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-man <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rosters</ENAMEX>, a move that cuts costs while guaranteeing playing time
for home-grown players. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> also recruits most of its foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, largely because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are cheaper than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> also appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. Latinos are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spectators</ENAMEX>, and certainly the most fervent of them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> relies heavily on ,
assigning foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> where they'll be most popular.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s calculated efforts have created a lovely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX>, one that preserves the intimacy that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, have lost. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">major-league</ENAMEX> sport with minor-league charm. The average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> ticket costs a mere
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> the price of an NHL or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> ticket. The relatively small crowds
mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> sit close to the action. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> encourages fan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>. At every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> game, a section called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barra Brava</ENAMEX>" is jammed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvadorans</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bolivians</ENAMEX> wielding noisemakers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> may not feature world-class <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, but its
"toque toque " style of play, which requires lots of short, accurate
passes, is more elegant and entertaining than the kick-and-run game many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are accustomed to. The best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C. United</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wizards</ENAMEX>--pass beautifully and score lots of goals. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco</ENAMEX>
Etcheverry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Valderrama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Moreno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Preki</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Wynalda</ENAMEX> would be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thrilling</ENAMEX> in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>.

            But this
may not be enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> is losing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of money--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $30 million</NUMEX> in its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two seasons</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> will distract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and remove the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months in the middle of the season</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> have filed a lawsuit to end the single-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity league</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>
launched, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> were so grateful to get work that they accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s
terms of employment. Now they argue that the single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> suppresses salaries
and violates antitrust laws. The lawsuit goes to trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s major obstacles, however, are its ambivalence about
itself and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s ambivalence about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> to grow, it needs to
fill <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Sports Fans</ENAMEX>, the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> bores
but will attend a few games a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>. And for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> to make itself a top-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX>, it needs to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions of dollars</NUMEX> to steal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> players
and protect its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is already grabbing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s best: Goalkeeper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Friedel</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liverpool</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX>, and more top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> may follow
him.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s dilemma is this: If it
doesn't pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, it will certainly remain a minor league. But even if it
does pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, no one knows whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> will come. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>
doesn't know whether it wants to be a very expensive world-class soccer league
or a very charming second-class one. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> doesn't know if it cares.

            
               If you missed the link to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>'s ethnic marketing strategy, click .
            

         
      
   
