
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Knows</ENAMEX>

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Thomason</ENAMEX> is back in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>. The First <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friend</ENAMEX> testified to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s grand jury <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but that's
probably not the most important reason he has returned. If news reports are
correct, the sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> is also here to advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> appearance. That is, to stage-manage him.

            (Bit of advice for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> hasn't had a hit for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. How 'bout calling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>?)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> no doubt negotiated endlessly about the nuts and bolts of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s testimony, but you can be sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomason</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Co.</ENAMEX> are doing
everything they can to tilt the arrangements in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s favor: What
should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wear? How should he sit? Where should the camera be? What should
be in the background? How should he be lighted? These may not be questions
on which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidency</ENAMEX> hangs, but they're undoubtedly ones that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
is obsessing about. It's political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, and they'll treat it like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomason</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> aren't talking, so I consulted
my own image <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Bain</ENAMEX>. He runs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Assoc.</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Virginia</ENAMEX>, and he specializes in prepping corporate honchos for scary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> appearances. What would Bain do if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> were his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First of</ENAMEX>
all, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must look as presidential as possible," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should
wear his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soberest Leader</ENAMEX>-of-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free-World</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>: dark blue suit, white shirt,
dark tie. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> would be the ideal setting, but it appears <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
will testify in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Map Room</ENAMEX>, a private meeting chamber, where he has testified
twice before. It's filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chippendale</ENAMEX> furniture and--surprise--maps, but
they should be out of the picture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> should place an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag and a photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea</ENAMEX> behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must sit behind a desk, and the camera
should see only his head and shoulders. "Not to be crude, but I don't want
anything below <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> button showing, and I want the desk between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s
private parts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bain</ENAMEX>. "I don't want anything on his
desk, and I don't want to see his hands.

            "I want a nice tight shot,
as tight as possible. Get those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> blues right down the throats of the people
watching in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. I want to give the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> a sense that they
really are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with him."

            That also
means great sound--the "best stereo microphone money can buy. And great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> in the grand jury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. If I could sneak a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub-woofer</ENAMEX> in there, I
would."

            No one but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should appear in the camera shot. This
is of paramount importance. "If I am running a show to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> off, I want
the grand jury totally focused on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s face, his honesty, his sadness of
having to do this. I want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s total concentration on his guiltless,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guileless</ENAMEX> face. I want them to see his eyebrows go up and down. He is the only
person the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> wants or needs to see."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>,
not at the camera, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> himself should not be visible. "If I were on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s side, I would not let them show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bain</ENAMEX>. "They should
have him be just a disembodied voice. Having another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in the picture is a
distraction. And if you do have to show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, just show the back of his ear,
not his face. There is nothing less attractive than the back of someone's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>."

            (Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> be able to
watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>'s reaction on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX>? "No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s total
concentration should be on the eyeballs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendall</ENAMEX> should be invisible, too: You don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to look like a puppet
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. And as for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, forget it. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> cannot be there! No,
no, no! It is too awkward. Just one quick nanosecond glance at her, just one
moment of discomfort, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> will see it. You don't want
that! Keep her out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Wing</ENAMEX>. Keep her out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. Some time
later they can go on some benign morning talk show together and talk about
this."

            
And what if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bain</ENAMEX> were advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>?

            "I would make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> look
as small as possible. I would show the desk. I would show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fidgeting
with his hands. And I would show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has been well trained to smile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">benignly</ENAMEX>. He has learned to smile sweetly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, because he realizes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> does not like him that much. He has developed this beatific smile,
and I would want to show that.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Behind Starr</ENAMEX> I would put a
neutral or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX>-brown background--but not black--so his flesh tones look
good. He is a pale-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>. You really have to warm him up."

            
               Movies
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dress, Part 2</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> I suggested
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> watch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> movies for inspiration about how to escape the dress:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primary Colors</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumed Innocent</ENAMEX> , and There's Something About
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reader Jason Furman</ENAMEX> reminds me of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> film: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gattaca</ENAMEX> , a
sci-fi thriller in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> hides small packets of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in his fingertip
and urine in his bladder (don't ask how) in order to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool DNA</ENAMEX> tests. Does the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> have such technology, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>?

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
