
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Ni</ENAMEX>

            Perhaps every era gets the
weather it deserves. Drought and dust storms coincided with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s weather was unusually tranquil during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the tranquil '50s</TIMEX>,
unusually chaotic during the chaotic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'70s</TIMEX>. So it's fitting that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> should
return <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>, its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> visit of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> is weather for the
'90s, weather for an age of conspiracy theories.

            As anyone
who's tuned in a weather forecast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> knows, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>"--"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>," as
in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Christ child"</ENAMEX>--was so named by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> who noticed the
warming of the waters of the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Christmastime</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>, officially known as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> Oscillation
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ENSO</ENAMEX>), works like this: Every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>, for some inexplicable
reason, the trade winds that usually blow west from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subside</ENAMEX>. As a result, the warm waters of the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>--a pool the size
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>--drift east toward <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>. The result: worldwide weather
chaos. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX> is part of a larger cycle. Periodically, the conditions that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">produce El Niño</ENAMEX> act in reverse. This produces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Niña</ENAMEX>, which causes different,
but equally freaky, global weather conditions.)

holding emergency hearings about the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are covering it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obsessively</ENAMEX>. There is good reason to worry. The eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> has heated
faster <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> than at any time in recorded history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño '97</ENAMEX> promises to
be the most brutal climatic event of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, surpassing even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'82-'83</ENAMEX>, which killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> and caused <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 billion</NUMEX> in damage.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trilateral Commission</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> science, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilderberg Group of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">climatology</ENAMEX>. It explains everything. The difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> and the
Trilats: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX> really does explain everything. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s
disaster-movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dante's Peak</ENAMEX>, the twisters, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> iceberg--are
pikers next to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>. Here is a partial list of events that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> can be
blamed for (at least partially): the ongoing drought in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX>; forest fires in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>; famine in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>; the appearance of hurricanes along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> coast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>; the disappearance of hurricanes along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Coast</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>; a mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>, a harsh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX>, the
failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> harvest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> seems to determine the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> production of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> production of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumatra</ENAMEX>, and the cocoa
production of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory Coast</ENAMEX>. It appears to spark of encephalitis, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cholera</ENAMEX>,
hantavirus, bubonic plague, rattlesnake attacks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX> attacks. It could
even influence immigration patterns in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern United States</ENAMEX>. (How?
Most migration to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> has occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20 years</TIMEX>, a period of
frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niños</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niños</ENAMEX> bring lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> to the region, and if they
subside, there may be too little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to sustain the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun Belt</ENAMEX>.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>, in fact, is a conspiracy so immense
that it even explains the other weather conspiracy--namely, the jet stream. The
warm, moist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> air causes the jet stream to split as it flows eastward
over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>. One arm dips south, giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coast</ENAMEX> a wet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>. The
other stays in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> is thus spared the jet stream's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blasts</ENAMEX>, and enjoys a lovely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>.

            Despite implicating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El Niño</ENAMEX>
in all these varied weather crimes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> know surprisingly little about
it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> is the first major <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to have been . Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX>
was identified, weather consisted of a series of little mysteries: Why is there
a thunderstorm? Why a drought? Those mysteries have been solved (sort of), but
they have been supplanted by a much bigger one: What is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>? Weather mavens
don't understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX> begins. They don't know why it is occurring more
frequently: It used to arrive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every five to eight years</TIMEX>; recently it's been
coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every three to five years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> are befuddled about its
relationship (if any) to global warming: Some say global warming is making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
Niño more severe; others say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX> is making global warming more severe. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niño</ENAMEX> is a darling of greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> because it shows how mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> is compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>, a natural phenomenon we don't
understand and can't control, can shift worldwide temperatures and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rainfall</ENAMEX>
dramatically, we should hesitate before blaming our own carbon dioxide
emissions for the world's ills.)

            There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other reason
why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> is a fitting weather pattern for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age</TIMEX>: On balance, it rewards
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> at the expense of the rest of the world. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> parches land, devastates <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>, and causes famine.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX> are starving because of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'97</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niño</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> destroys the fishing industry: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>'s economy
shrank <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> during the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'82</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'83</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>. It's true that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX> afflicts
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coasts</ENAMEX> with nasty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX>, and that it decimates the salmon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. But fewer hurricanes will strike the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>,
fewer tornadoes will touch down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, and more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> will fall on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>. Mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North and East</ENAMEX> will save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> on heating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX>. Thanks to the northward migration of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">marlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> sport
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> will have an annus 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mirabilis</ENAMEX> . And as for the surfing,
it will be awesome.

         
      
   
