
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertie Wooster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party Tricks</ENAMEX>

            Anyone whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>
brands as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> is instantly sympathetic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> says he will use his powers
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Foreign Relations Committee</ENAMEX> to derail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX>'s
nomination to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> supports the
decriminalization of marijuana for medical use. But unlike other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> who have given up when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> opposed them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> has girded for battle.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this week</TIMEX>, he resigned his position as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">combat Helms</ENAMEX>' "ideological extortion" full time.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>
wants his fight with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> to be a "battle over the soul of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party." And where does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Weld</ENAMEX> think the soul of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> should
lie? He declares himself a philosophical libertarian who discovered <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hayek</ENAMEX> in
law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. But his alleged libertarianism is inconsistent, and may be no more
than a convenient, fancy formulation for the combination of policies--fiscally
conservative, socially liberal--needed to get elected as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> certainly did not advertise himself as a libertarian
when he worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Division of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s popular appeal is based less on the perception that
he's a libertarian than the perception he's that even rarer <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, a moderate
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. With the crusty, rural, reactionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> seems a
moderate, cosmopolitan thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, above petty politics. He is even willing
to accept a job in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s moderation, his
"independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>," like his libertarianism, may actually reflect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> less
admirable qualities: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clintonesque</ENAMEX> political slipperiness; and, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>,
a lack of seriousness. He's a flake.

            He's a
flake because he's an aristocrat. And he brilliantly fuses these two
politically disadvantageous conditions into a political plus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> comes from
wealthy, pure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASP</ENAMEX> stock and married a great granddaughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>. Far from playing this down, he revels in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brahmin</ENAMEX> shtick, incessantly
gabbing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> about his prep-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school days</TIMEX>, publicly proclaiming the
sacrosanctity of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice-weekly</TIMEX> squash games, and cracking jokes like "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welds</ENAMEX> arrived in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1630</TIMEX> with only the shirts on their backs and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 pounds</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>."

            
More successfully than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s demeanor plays on the ancient myth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cincinnatus</ENAMEX>--the
notion that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of wealth makes the best statesman, because he will never be
tempted to act in his own self-interest and will work solely for the common
good. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> never seems to be straining to garner the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>'s approval. An obsequious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> profile
put it this way: "In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> has restored a tradition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aristocratic Yankee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lordship</ENAMEX>, he has made governing look easy and WASP
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ascendancy</ENAMEX> seem an expression of natural law, if not of divine right." He can
drink a martini while balancing a budget.

            But all
is not aristocratic ease and devil-may-care frankness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> came to national
prominence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, when he resigned as head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Division</ENAMEX>, allegedly in protest over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Meese</ENAMEX>'s
interference in the investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meese</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Robert Wallach</ENAMEX>, accused
of using his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wedtech</ENAMEX> to abuse government contracts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> later conceded
that he had planned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> before to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>. He didn't
mention this when he struck his headline-grabbing stance.

            And then there's his claim that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> he restored the
health of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> economy. Remember back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>
presidential run. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid</ENAMEX>-campaign, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s economy, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> was
referring to as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> miracle," sank, creating a huge government
budget deficit and threatening the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s financial solvency. To stave off
collapse during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX> in office, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> stewarded over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>
in tax increases through the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>
campaigned for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
Silber, he vociferously supported a ballot measure that would have reversed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> tax increases. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silber</ENAMEX> argued (correctly) that repealing the tax
increases would ruin the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s bond rating, and result in irresponsibly large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX>-spending cuts. Silber was too persuasive for his own good. As it became
clear that the disastrous tax cut would not pass, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>--disliking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silber</ENAMEX> for his cranky hard-line views on social
issues--felt it was safe to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> won by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 3</NUMEX>
percent.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s combination of positions on issues plays
to the great weakness in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s liberalism: its obsession with social issues
and relative indifference to economics. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> is pro-gay, pro-choice,
and pro-affirmative action, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> overlooked his strident economic
conservatism. As promised in the campaign, he slashed social spending and
welfare rolls. However, taxes remain at nearly the same levels as when he
entered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and government spending has increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 percent</NUMEX>
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his six-year</TIMEX> tenure. If he had got his way about repealing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>
tax increases, he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would be up <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shit creek</ENAMEX>. He has the unpopular
stands taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Silber</ENAMEX> to thank for creating the
conditions for solid growth that have buoyed his popularity.

            The pose
of the post-partisan suits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> because he can change his positions on a dime.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years</TIMEX> into his term he dropped his strident opposition to gun control
when the position began hurting his poll numbers. Though he describes himself
as being "to the right of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attila</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun</ENAMEX> on crime," he authorized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie</ENAMEX>
Hortenesque early parole of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 700</NUMEX> sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Despite twice
campaigning actively against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, he has begged for a post in his
administration.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s capriciousness is key to his success. Even when it
would seem blatantly self-serving, his unpredictability jibes with the public's
expectation that his personal wealth will allow him to do whatever he thinks is
right. His whimsy can be downright charming. During a signing ceremony for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>, he dove headfirst fully clothed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Charles River</ENAMEX>. And he once sent
pictures to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> of himself with a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">boar</ENAMEX> he claims to have hunted
down--though it turned out to be in captivity.

            His decision to resign and
run for the ambassadorship few expect him to win should be treated like these
other nutty episodes. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who describe the move as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quixotic</ENAMEX> express
admiration for his audacity. He has already demonstrated his acumen at milking
the confrontation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> for its maximum theatrical and political value.
And since he clearly has further political ambitions--he has talked about
becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>, and no doubt thinks of even
higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--the spotlight will serve him well. He can indulge in the
self-serving grandstanding and self-effacing silliness that only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX>
could possibly pull off.

         
      
   
