
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX>

            The release of the movie
Fear <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Loathing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> and its attendant publicity have revealed
what may be a surprising fact to some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX> is
alive.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>
so belongs to a bygone era that he probably should have had the good sense to
die along with it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX> of self-destructive living have taken their toll, but
he remains with us--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years old</TIMEX>, mumbling, shambling, drunk, stoned, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">addled</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> is a useful icon to have around: For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>, he's a
visible casualty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'60s</ENAMEX> sybaritic excess; for rebellious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, he's a
token--or is that toke?--of nostalgia for more exciting times.

            The implied question in most criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fear and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loathing</ENAMEX> movie is: Why on earth did we ever think this crap mattered? The
book and movie chronicle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s drug-fueled invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have admired the film technically but have deplored
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s vision. Fear <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Loathing</ENAMEX> 's psychopharmacological obsession
is dated and dull, further proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are not only destructive but banal.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are vicious, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, solipsistic, and adolescent. All in
all, it's a bad memory of a silly time in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history, a relic of a
national embarrassment.

            But the
criticism does injustice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>. Now is the worst possible moment for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> revival. This is a tranquil era, and considered in tranquility,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> is indeed a horror. His writing seems archaic and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, and its
self-indulgence seems stunning even in an age of memoirs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> is often
compared, unfavorably, with his New Journalism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> is
undoubtedly a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>, but he's also an easier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> has worn well because his detached irony suits us. His cool style is
ours. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> responded to his lunatic age with bemusement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> responded to
it with ferocity, and ferocity is not comfortable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1967 and 1973</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> was , he
wrote with crazed, out-of-control, phantasmagoric violence. But he was living
in crazed, out-of-control, phantasmagoric, violent times. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that had
been placid suddenly raged with race riots and assassinations, manipulated by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crooked</ENAMEX>, villainous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and trapped in a terrible war. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">idealist</ENAMEX>, was appalled. He reacted to madness by writing (and behaving) madly.
A quarter-century later, the prose looks deranged, and it is. But it came by
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">derangement</ENAMEX> honestly.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> gonzo piece--the mishmash of raw notes and vitriol that became
his trademark--was a feral account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Derby</ENAMEX>. It was not intended
to run in raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">form</ENAMEX>, but--according to the most appealing account--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> was
so horrified by the Kent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> massacre, which occurred while he was writing,
that he was unable to make his notes into a coherent piece.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s notoriety has also overshadowed his fine early
style. Hell's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX> and the two <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fear and Loathing</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> and On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Campaign Trail '72</ENAMEX> ) books seethe. His words club
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s screeds and ad hominem attacks are worthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mencken</ENAMEX>. As much as any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> shook <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
political writing from the coma of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>. His savage, profane descriptions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, his mockery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hubert Humphrey</ENAMEX>, his
characterization of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nazi" or "the fourth Reich</ENAMEX>" or "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>" enlivened (and, yes, debased) political debate. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a couple of
examples.) When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a "scumbag," he owes a tip of the cap
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>.

            But if the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> is
being rejected too easily, the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> is being welcomed too kindly. In
a certain segment of lefty society, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> has become a much revered elder.
The current image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> is that of a hilarious, endearing old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goat</ENAMEX> who's
coasting out his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> score and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>. He doesn't merit such niceness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>
has more than just squandered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> (what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigy</ENAMEX> doesn't?), he has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">betrayed</ENAMEX> himself. He's a romantic who has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX>. He was once filled
with passion. Now he fakes it for money.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>,
of course, is not the only '60s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> who is disillusioned. But he gave no
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> to anyone who disappointed him, so he certainly doesn't deserve any
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> from us now.)

            
Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> is part <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beavis</ENAMEX>, part whore. He
still behaves like an adolescent moron. He's a freakish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pan</ENAMEX>--the juvenile
delinquent who wouldn't grow up. He ignites kegs of dynamite in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aspen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, backyard. To ring in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, he reportedly blew up a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX>. He gropes female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>, watches porn, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks monstrously</ENAMEX>, smokes
more, and uses <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. There's something unbearably sad about a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-year-old</TIMEX> man
who still takes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s real problem isn't that he indulges himself, it's that he's lazy.
(He once called himself, with a flash of perfect insight, a "mean, lazy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hillbilly</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> used to be a fabulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. He reported masterfully
on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'72</NUMEX> campaign and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hell's Angels</ENAMEX>. He exaggerated and lied, but he was
there --he befriended weirdos and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX>, made common cause with the
dregs of society, stirred trouble, listened. At some point in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> realized he didn't need to bother. He was a celebrity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s
writing retreated from the outside world. He hasn't had a new thought for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. A shocking number of his recent articles are based on something he saw
on television.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> is no longer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX>: He performs a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX> routine. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doonesbury</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke character</ENAMEX> is not the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> cartoon. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> himself is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> cartoon.) He works himself
into a fake froth; does some calculated, halfhearted gonzo writing; then
collects a fat check. He has become as repetitious, pontificating, and slothful
as the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> pundit--as ridiculous as the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> he mocked in
Fear <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Loathing</ENAMEX>: On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Campaign Trail '72</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> poured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> because he honestly believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was a devil. He pours <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
because, well, that's what someone pays him to do.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>--though fewer and fewer of them--still shell out top dollar for this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX> routine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Colleges</ENAMEX> still pay for his slurred, mangled
"speeches." His books are still, astonishingly, best sellers (even his wretched
new ones). Apparently there are enough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> in the first
flush of marijuana to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX> in tequila and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> for the rest of his
life.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> a fan
letter saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX> had inspired him to join a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>. An alarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> replied by telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to do his own thing, not
imitate others, and warning him about what was wrong with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX>: "The best
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you might want to sit down and talk to--have almost all
played that game for a while and then quit for something better. The ones who
are left are almost all the kind who can't do anything else, and they're not
much fun to talk to. They're not smart, or funny, or brave, or even original.
They're just <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Punks</ENAMEX>, and that's a lot worse than being a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Young Punk</ENAMEX>. They're
not even happy; most of them hate the lives they lead, but they can't afford to
admit it because they don't know where else to go, or what else to do. That's
what makes them mean."

            That is
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Punk</ENAMEX>; not smart or funny or brave or even
original. And he sure doesn't know what else to do.

            
               Click to
read about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s glory days and for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of his political profiles.
            

         
      
   
