
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget True</ENAMEX> and False

             

            You can't believe everything
you hear about the balanced-budget deal. You can't, because so many of the
claims are contradictory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enemies</ENAMEX> agree, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> disagree. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> calls the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> plan a historic breakthrough. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> agree. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX> calls
it "a budget of many deficits--a deficit of principle, a deficit of fairness, a
deficit of tax justice and, worst of all, a deficit of dollars." Writing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brooks</ENAMEX> hails it as a triumph for
conservative values; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> condemns it as
a betrayal of conservative values. And so on. Who's right?

            
               
                  A
Deficit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Dollars</NUMEX>?
                The overarching purpose of a balanced-budget
agreement is, presumably, to balance the budget. Yet the deal rests on various
assumptions, and the likelihood that all of them will work out is small.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The deal presumes an
economic scenario more roseate than any envisaged since the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
administration. Now, unlike then, we have already enjoyed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than six years</TIMEX>
of uninterrupted growth. Unemployment and inflation together are lower than
they've been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>. Some say this shows the economy has reached a
new plateau of long-term prosperity. Others say this suggests the good times
can't last much longer. The deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> contend that the budget deal itself
will promote growth and so create additional savings. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five more years</TIMEX>? Over
that period, your guess is as good as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Even if the good times
keep on rolling, the promised retreat of red ink depends on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> devising--and sticking with--a tax-cut package that includes both
sides' favorite giveaways but still costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $85 billion</NUMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. (According to a "side agreement," it must also cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $165</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX> after that.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) On top of this, someone
must find <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $300 billion</NUMEX> in spending cuts and other deficit reducers,
most of them now suggested in only the broadest outlines. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 80 percent</NUMEX>
of the cuts in non-defense programs are to come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX>. Indeed,
total spending cuts are supposed to jump by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> of the
plan--which also happens to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election year</TIMEX>. By contrast, in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two years</TIMEX> this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> control--the
budget deficit will actually increase as a result of the deal.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Miscellaneous
implausibilities: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Labor Statistics</ENAMEX> is supposed to recalculate the
Consumer Price Index to save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $15 billion</NUMEX> in inflation adjustments over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three years</TIMEX> of the plan. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of nature are supposed to avoid
any <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multibillion-dollar</NUMEX> calamities such as the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Forks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.D.</ENAMEX>, flood.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> serving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are supposed to
absorb <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130 billion</NUMEX> in payment cuts (without fundamentally altering the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>). Someone must be found to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $26 billion</NUMEX> for the unused part
of the broadcast spectrum. And, of course, lots of fraud, waste, and abuse is
to be rooted out on all sides.

            
               
                  A
Deficit of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Principle or a Principled Conservatism</ENAMEX>?
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> charge that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sold out his core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> by agreeing to deep cuts in
domestic spending. True? This depends on which you think is more important: the
spending increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacts now--or the spending cuts it
promises to enact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years from now</TIMEX>. By the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> measure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did quite
well, securing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> agreement to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $30 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> in new
spending for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. (That's in addition to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in subsidies for college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> disguises these as "tax
cuts.") Domestic non-entitlement spending over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX> will be just
about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> requested in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> budget--though that budget won him
scant applause within his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            But the deal promises a huge
whack at "unprotected" domestic spending in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001 and 2002</TIMEX>--everything from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>, housing, and the weather <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>. This
is what excites the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>. By leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>,
and other entitlements unreformed, he argues, when a recession hits, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
will be forced to all but dismantle the remaining part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--"all the
things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> love." Of course, this assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> won't just forget
about balancing the budget instead.

            
               
                  A
Deficit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Justice</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deficiency of Tax Cuts</ENAMEX>?
                Part of the side
deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> obliges him to sign a bill cutting capital
gains and estate taxes "even if it is not the bill I would write." It is not
yet clear how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can squeeze all the tax goodies each
insists upon into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$135 billion</NUMEX> bag (and come up with an honest <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> in
new revenues to bring the net price down to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85 billion</NUMEX>). So there is no way
yet to know for sure who wins and loses. But capital-gains and estate-tax cuts
of almost any sort will surely favor the well-to-do in the long run. (In the
short run, higher-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> may pay more taxes, not less, if a capgains
rate cut leads them to sell more assets than they otherwise would have done.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s college breaks will be of primary benefit to middle- and upper-middle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class taxpayers</ENAMEX>. The "per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>" credit will be broadly distributed--though not
to the poor (who pay no taxes, so can't use the credit). However it all shakes
out, those who benefit most from the tax breaks almost surely will lose least
from the spending cuts.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> seem
fairly content with the tax package, since it includes their cherished
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>-per-child credit. But "supply-side" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> dismiss the tax cuts as
"minuscule." The net <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85 billion</NUMEX> cut, they note, is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1 percent</NUMEX> of the
taxes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> expects to collect over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>. And, if the
inflation-adjustment rules are changed, that will raise taxes as well as trim
spending.

            
               
                  A
Drain on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>?
                Under the budget deal, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, national defense will
consume <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $273 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$267 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. Inflation,
however, would turn that into a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9 percent</NUMEX> cut in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> purchasing power. This
doesn't seem unreasonable when you consider that our political and military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have shown themselves increasingly reluctant to put either our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
or our expensive weaponry at risk. On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> feels it
must buy ever more elaborate and costly weapon systems--in part to counter the
weapons we sell so freely to others. Hard-line <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> argue, moreover,
that the real measure of lost resolve is to be found in the fact that military
spending will fall to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 3 percent</NUMEX> of gross domestic product by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. At
the peak of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reagan Cold War</ENAMEX> buildup in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> claimed about
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> of GDP.

            Of course, the magnitude of
the threats faced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> bears no fixed relation to the size of
our economy. Today, our GDP, adjusted for inflation, is twice as big as it was
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. Have the threats to our security doubled since then?

            Looked at another way,
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 40 years</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX> defense experts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">calculate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $320 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> on defense,
measured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s dollars. Under the budget agreement, it will spend the
equivalent of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> less. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> has disintegrated, and its former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minions</ENAMEX> are queuing up to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>.
That ought to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> on the dollar.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bottom Line</ENAMEX> . Is the budget agreement, on balance, more likely to reduce
the deficit--or to increase it? The answer depends on which you count as more
important: the tax cuts and spending increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is pledged to enact
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this very year</TIMEX>, or the spending cuts it vows it will embrace in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come.
You might want to keep in mind that back in the budget deal of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
voted to cap spending through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. As part of the so-called balanced-budget
deal that passed both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> canceled those caps.

         
      
   
