
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare Scare</ENAMEX>

            You have a reasonably soft
heart. You wouldn't feel comfortable seeing little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> begging in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>,
or stepping over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> gasping in the gutters. Maybe you read
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Edelman</ENAMEX>, a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, who called the welfare-reform law signed last
fall by his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> "terrible legislation." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelman</ENAMEX> says the result will be
"more <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malnutrition</ENAMEX> and more crime, increased infant mortality, and increased
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and alcohol abuse." You don't defend the previous welfare system--who
could?--but you wonder: Are the scaremongers right?

            How
worried should you be? Here's a quick review of what is--and isn't--likely to
be truly troublesome as the great welfare-reform experiment begins.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> that are too "kind." Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>' worries are the opposite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelman</ENAMEX>'s. They fear that the welfare system
won't change enough.

            The new welfare law abolishes
the current federal welfare-entitlement program, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aid to Families With Dependent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>, and replaces it with block grants to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> have to
create replacement programs that set limits (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>) on how long most (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> can get welfare, and ensure that half the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> still
on the rolls in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> (part- or full-time) working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> also have to contribute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of the money that they used to spend
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Temporary Assistance to Needy Families</ENAMEX> (TANF) program--the
so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Maintenance of Effort</ENAMEX> (MOE) requirement.

            Beyond
that (and a bunch of other eye-glazing rules and exceptions to exceptions that
will keep federal regulation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> off the dole), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are basically free
to offer whatever combination of cash and services they think is best.

            
So what are states likely to do? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> option
is--nothing much. If a state really wants to maintain the status quo, it can
probably get away with it. Welfare law has long been loaded with requirements
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> must cut fraud on the rolls, move <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">recipients</ENAMEX> into jobs, provide
necessary service, blah, blah, blah. The requirements go unmet. The governor
makes a few calls to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. Eyes are averted.

            Moreover, the new law, for
all its seeming toughness, allows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> plenty of leeway if they want to be
generous. And welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> are already showing the way. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> are free,
for example, to redirect the money that they used to spend on matching federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> grants (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 45 percent</NUMEX> of the total) to provide help for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who
have lost their "temporary assistance" coverage. The new law also provides an
incentive for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to use their own money to continue grants to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that
exhaust their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> eligibility.

            Not so
long ago, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> might have
brazened it out. But times have changed. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have already toughened
their welfare programs under waivers granted under the old <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pre-reform</TIMEX> rules.
Some of these waivers are for more generous programs, but others are just as
tough as the new law.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> that are too mean. So how nasty might states
get? Some were pretty mean already. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> tend to forget that under the old
rules, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> got to set the key parameter--the benefit level. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> payments
ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> of the official poverty line in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 65</NUMEX>
percent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Suffolk County</ENAMEX>. (This doesn't count food stamps,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>, and federal aid for housing, home
heating, child care, and so forth, which will still be available.) At least in
theory, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> now could replace even its small cash contribution with the
proverbial "bus ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>." Not likely, perhaps, but worth watching out
for.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> A shortage of money. Under the old rules, the federal
government would match the money states spent, according to a formula that took
account of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> need and benefit levels. The new rules cap federal welfare
payments at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> level (with some allowances for rising unemployment and
other contingencies). For now that's a windfall for all but a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
since welfare caseloads have dropped by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 10 percent</NUMEX> nationally since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. But what if times get tough and caps start to pinch? Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Stamp</ENAMEX>
program has long been capped--supposedly--yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has never failed to
provide extra funds when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> needed them.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> A lack of "suitable" jobs. Welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are
already complaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> will be pushed into "dead-end" jobs. But
successful job-program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> have learned a key lesson since the last time
we had this argument (back in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>): Most jobs in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy are</ENAMEX> "dead end." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who work hard and build a good record move on to
better jobs. And the labor-market success of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of unskilled immigrants
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> makes it hard to sustain the case that only highly trained or
educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are in demand--at least for the moment.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5 Incapable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. What about welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who, in practice, just cannot hold jobs (or perform other "work
activities") as the new law requires they do after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> on the rolls?
Maybe they have low mental or physical abilities. Maybe they are <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol addicts</ENAMEX> or have multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or behavioral problems--or maybe they
simply have a bad attitude. Nobody really knows how big a problem this is, and
the extent will surely differ from area to area. But we won't know till we push
the limits.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are already
finding that a simple shove can have surprising results. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>'s ambitious
(and relatively expensive) welfare reform has cut its caseload by more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> put in a tough program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1995</TIMEX> and has seen its
welfare rolls drop to the lowest level in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>'s welfare rolls
have dropped by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>, even though it has only talked
about tougher rules.

            Healthy
job markets surely helped, but the economy has boomed at other times with
little effect on welfare. State <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> think many potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>
simply got the message that times have changed, and found jobs on their own.
Moreover, credible studies have shown that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have hidden income. A
recent study from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Policy Institute</ENAMEX>, for example, found that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> teen-age welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> have income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> other
than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> who have set out looking for early
horror stories have returned with articles that are, on the whole, remarkably
upbeat.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> Not enough training and supportive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The new law is pretty tough on training. Only short-term
job-readiness or search assistance, on-the-job training, or a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of vocational training count as "work activities"--though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> who
are working part time can take other classes in their spare <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. But training
programs have a dismal record. Some have even been shown to impede movement
into jobs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles County</ENAMEX>, for example, was having no luck with its
basic-education GAIN (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Greater Avenues</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX>) program until, two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, it shifted the focus to getting jobs. The result: a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">160 percent</NUMEX>
increase in job placements and big benefit savings.

            As for
"supportive services," in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, at least, most of the special jobs set
aside for welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> have gone unfilled, and there has been no
increased demand for medical help or child-care assistance.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> things you really should be alarmed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> (both of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> now proposes to remedy):

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 and 50</TIMEX> who have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> lose food stamps after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> if they aren't
working or in training. That might not sound so tough. Street-level trafficking
in food stamps has got out of hand, and it's time for another round of cleanup
and streamlining. And many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in question are real
deadbeats--drunks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>, and the like. But that's just the point. Food
stamps are the last resort, the pittance that a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> doles out to even
its least "deserving" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Of course, this new requirement, like many
others, is "waivable," and many big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have already got--or applied
for--dispensation.

            Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> who are not
yet naturalized (unless they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, seeking asylum, have worked here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, or are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> or in the military) lose both food stamps and benefits
they might be receiving from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Security Income</ENAMEX> (SSI) program for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> and disabled. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> are supposed to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> who stand
ready to make sure they do not become public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX>. Yet the number on SSI,
especially, has soared. Putting some teeth into sponsorship requirements for
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX>, as the new law will do, is reasonable. But pulling the rug out
from under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who may have no practical recourse is unfair. And unlike the
cutoff for childless food stampers, this requirement can't be "waived"
away.

         
      
   
