
   
   
      
         
            The New <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>

            The traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shawl</ENAMEX> is still wrapped around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>'s neck, but the hair is grayer and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sparser</ENAMEX> and the round face is lined with wrinkles. He needs a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX> to walk and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> to breathe. He is nearly blind in the left eye, and he can't stand the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquitoes</ENAMEX> that swarm around his hut. He is older now, and he is wiser.

            The man
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> once maligned as a genocidal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maniac</ENAMEX> is living quietly--dying
quietly--in the jungles of his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>. With age has come
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">introspection</ENAMEX>; with introspection has come regret. "Our movement made
mistakes," he admits softly, sincerely, in his first interview in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 long</TIMEX>, hard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> has made peace with himself.

            Once upon a time, way back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> was
the fieriest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brother No. 1</ENAMEX>," "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Original Cambodian</ENAMEX>." He
was enthusiastic--too enthusiastic, he realizes now--to bring glorious Marxism
to his suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, to free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> from the yoke of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> invaders,
to abolish the twin evils of Western materialism and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> privilege. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>
dreamed of a society of equals, a grand new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>. And so he made
errors--the errors that young, eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> everywhere make.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'70s</NUMEX>,
of course, were a difficult <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>. We all did things we have come to regret,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is no exception. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A million or two</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> lost their
lives because of his mistakes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starvation</ENAMEX> was epidemic. Cannibalism was common.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> abolished religion, education, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, commerce, money. He drove city
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwellers</ENAMEX> into the countryside, and he forced them to farm. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Tens of thousands</NUMEX> of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> were tortured and murdered at his behest. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> said he
returned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark Ages</TIMEX>. Others called him names: "bloodthirsty,"
"barbaric," "cruel" ...

            
To hear those words today pains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>. "I
came to carry out the struggle, not to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," he says, a look of
melancholy shadowing his face. "Even now, and you can look at me, am I a savage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>?" The plaintive question echoes in the moist, warm air of the
jungle.

            Several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> sentenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> to life under house arrest--hut
arrest, really--for the murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son Sen</ENAMEX>, an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> who
plotted a coup against him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son Sen</ENAMEX>'s family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant grandchildren</ENAMEX>, also were killed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> regrets the murders.
They, too, were a "mistake," he says, his voice filled with pain. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>
can accept his arrest. What he can't accept is his betrayal at the hands of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who tried and sentenced him are his oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> he led through good times and bad.

            Who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>? He is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has always had difficulty
telling others about himself. "I'm quite modest. I don't want to tell people
I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>," he says. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX> have courted the press: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castro</ENAMEX>
practically lives for sound bites, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zapatistas</ENAMEX> are better at planning
press conferences than battles. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> has never had the gift of the gab,
especially around the camera, and he has never learned how to play to the
press. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> saw him only as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cold-blooded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>; they missed his pensive
side. The adulation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> showered on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Assad</ENAMEX> passed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot by</ENAMEX>. So, too, did the personal wealth that other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> amassed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> has never believed in greed. Not for him the
diamonds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>, the snazzy clothes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duvalier</ENAMEX>, the shoes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> bank accounts of them all. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> fell from power, he walked into
the jungle with nothing but the clothes on his back.

            But that's all in the past.
The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is about the future. He wants to make the most of his golden
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. His politics have mellowed. Today, the elder statesman advises
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to seek rapprochement with the West. "When I die, my only
wish is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> remain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> and belong to the West," he says. "It is
over for communism, and I want to stress that."

            The old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> worked tirelessly on the revolution, neglecting his health, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and their
charming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>--the apple of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX>--share his captivity. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pol</ENAMEX>
Pot rests quietly during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> goes to school and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
hoes the vegetable patch. In the evenings, they share a modest meal, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX> asks his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> about what she learned that day. In captivity, he has
fulfilled a lifelong dream. He has found the very thing he sought to give his
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodians</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>: a quiet life on a country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>. To see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol</ENAMEX>
Pot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is to be reminded of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voltaire</ENAMEX>: "We must cultivate our ..."

            
OK, OK, I give up. It won't work, not even as
parody. The re-emergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is a landmark moment in celebrity culture:
At last, someone who cannot be forgiven.

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cooper</ENAMEX> wrote in the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , there is a standard
forgiveness ritual for sinning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. After they're caught, they
disappear for awhile, then re-emerge, apologize for their venality (usually to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>), and retake their place in the pantheon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> managed this
in a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Milken</ENAMEX> got sick and became a beloved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philanthropist</ENAMEX>. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Superb</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> served <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a decade</TIMEX> in exile before returning triumphantly as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statesman</ENAMEX>.

            So the rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is heartening. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--exists in the world whose evil is so great
that it cannot be neutered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">captivity</TIMEX>; he is sick; and he is
(mildly) apologetic. Yet not a single word has been murmured on his behalf. Any
other infamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>--could rescue a
damaged reputation. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is irredeemable. Can you imagine a ?

            There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> irony in the
rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>. In making him a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX>, the world is legitimizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who
are almost as awful. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who imprisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-legged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>
general named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ta Mok</ENAMEX>. His nickname is "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butcher</ENAMEX>," and he carried out many of
the brutal massacres ordered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ta Mok</ENAMEX> is being feted for having
captured his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>. He has received favorable press coverage for opening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and permitting markets in his remote northern stronghold. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ta Mok</ENAMEX> has
even been given credit for putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> on trial and sentencing him to life
under house arrest--as opposed to summarily shooting him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, which is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>'s usual idea of justice. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> hint that the only reason
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ta Mok</ENAMEX> bothered with the trial and the life sentence is to burnish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rouge</ENAMEX>'s bloody image. If so, it seems to have worked.

            As for the supreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villain</ENAMEX>,
he is unlikely to appear again in public. The remarkable interview <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> gave
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nate Thayer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Far Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Review</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> was his first
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX>, and it will undoubtedly be his last. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thayer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>
is very near death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Survivors</ENAMEX> of his terror can take some satisfaction in this:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> is bound for the death that you would wish on a tyrant, the death that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> managed to duck. He is going to die slowly, a captive who is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impoverished</ENAMEX>, in great pain, betrayed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and unredeemed by a world
that would redeem anyone else.

         
      
   
