
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>

            
               Schadenfreude being
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> religion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> world, this has been a particularly
satisfying week for glossy mag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker Editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>--who essentially invented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> "buzz," perfected buzz, made buzz
high art (and made high art buzz)--is becoming buzz's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>.

            This is the moment that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">loyalists</ENAMEX> to the Old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> have been eagerly anticipating for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX> brings new evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> is no longer--to use a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinaism</ENAMEX>--hot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Condé Nast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Florio</ENAMEX> just removed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
from his position as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, then appointed a
replacement without consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Florio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.I. Newhouse Jr.</ENAMEX> also declined to name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, a job she reportedly coveted. Recent articles have exposed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s sorry financial shape: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> promised
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> to make profitable by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, and its ad
sales are stagnating during an economic boom. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> dropped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Evans</ENAMEX>, the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s most formidable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, as head of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>, raising speculation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evans</ENAMEX>
are out of favor with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si</ENAMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are speculating (without
evidence) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> may not renew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s contract when it expires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.

            (Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">non-Tina</ENAMEX> news is being turned against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new books
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shawn</ENAMEX> has inspired another round of pompous elegies
for the grand old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> .)

            Who would have thought it--the queen of spin is losing a
spin war. "You live by buzz, you die by buzz," says an ex- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, with malicious glee. It's not that anything has actually changed
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>, but there is a perception that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> are stumbling. And as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> knows as well as anyone,
perception matters.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>,
after all, is print media's greatest showman. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of a film producer
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX>, she packages her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> like movies and promotes them like
a flack. Her formula: She overpays star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, gives them top billing, and
relies on striking covers to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. As the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tatler , Brown</ENAMEX> transformed a stodgy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> society <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sassy</ENAMEX>, nasty, attention-getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say she revived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> simply by publishing slobbering celebrity stories. That's not fair to
her: Everyone published slobbering celebrity stories in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genius</ENAMEX> was to combine them with superb investigative, political, and feature
writing, then wrap it all in a salacious cover that you just had to
open.

            
She brought that gift for spectacle to The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Her re-creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is a familiar tale: She
inherited from Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>--by way of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gottlieb</ENAMEX>--a tired, unread <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Requisite</ENAMEX> example of dreariness: the multipart series on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX>.) In no time
flat, she turned it into the most talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. She
supplemented the already prodigiously talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with her own snazzy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires</ENAMEX>.
Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> pandered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> and petted moguls, but it also ran the
best-written, best-edited features in the industry. Topicality reigned: In the
old days, you couldn't tell what year an issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> was
published; now you could tell what day it was published. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, which
had been self-effacing to the point of reclusiveness, suddenly was brilliantly
packaged and promoted. The chattering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> began chattering about it and
haven't stopped since.

            What is
the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s methods? A civil, slow-moving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> became a chaotic,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ill</ENAMEX>-tempered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> is capricious. She charms the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> she needs but frosts underlings. Her buzz production is endless.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , as well as
several full-time event <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> relies on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, conferences,
and stunts--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest editor</ENAMEX>--to generate heat. It's not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s
uninterested in beautiful or ambitious writing--she publishes plenty of it--but
she cares most about attention-getting.

            The old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> was whimsical, often fatally so:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writers</ENAMEX> were expected to indulge their own peculiar interest and damn public
opinion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> seems poll-tested. If you are writing about
what's hot, then you are writing about what everyone is writing about.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is predictable and getting more so the longer she is there: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Of</ENAMEX>
course it devoted "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> when he died. Of course it
wrote a suck-up about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> playoffs, a suck-up about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX> for the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Horse Whisperer</ENAMEX> , a suck-up about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for another reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> favors
celebrity.) A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that was once entirely, and bizarrely, different from
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>--often to its detriment--is now much the same as them. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
for another important way in which sameness has affected <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> .)

            Despite
her current woes, no one really expects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> can't afford not to renew her contract. To dump <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> now, amid all
the bad financial news, would be an acknowledgment that he picked wrong in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            
Nor is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> likely to quit. She was reportedly
offered a job producing a weeknight version of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> , but there are
no signs that she's interested. She has too much pride to surrender in the
middle of the battle. As an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of hers puts it, "She would only quit if
she could quit in triumph, with everyone acknowledging that it is the best
magazine in the world and that she is the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in
the black."

            "In the
black"--that is the real key to understanding what's going on at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>'s
magazine. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> bought in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> was profitable.
But having shelled out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$168 million</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> was not
satisfied with the measly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> it was earning. He set out to
impose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> : expand circulation and
raise ad rates.

            The move to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nastify</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> worked, sort of.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> began offering . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> did her job: producing buzz to
fuel circulation. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> soared from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 450,000</NUMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'80s</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 800,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> hiked ad rates accordingly, pricing
quirky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in favor of big national ones. Ad
revenue increased but not enough to cover enormous new costs: Recruiting new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> by direct mail, printing more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, and mailing more magazines
are tremendously expensive operations.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> is squeezed between newsweeklies and glossy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monthlies</ENAMEX>. The market for general-interest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> has long since
dried up: Look and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday Evening Post</ENAMEX> are dead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> has
tried to remake The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> as an upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsweekly</ENAMEX>, but its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX>
paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> can't match the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 million</NUMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> offers its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> can't compete with monthlies either. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> and its advertisements have a full <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> to be seen by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> has a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> window.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> has fought back with special
issues--massive tomes about race or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> or the future. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
double issues and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other special issues accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s advertising pages, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising Age</ENAMEX> . The double
issues save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> postage and printing costs, and their
advertisements have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 days</TIMEX> to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is still
losing money, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> seems trapped. She has staked her career on
profitability. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> could probably make money as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">bimonthly</TIMEX>
or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> (ideas that have reportedly been floated within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX>). But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> probably would not accept that tarnish on their reputations:
They don't want to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cretins</ENAMEX> who killed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s last great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>. The
magazine could also break even by raising subscription prices and shrinking the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>. That too would look terrible on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CV</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> has
always had an outsized ambition, and now she is imprisoned by it. She and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> have traded a small, weird, profitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> for a big, flashy,
unprofitable one. And now they don't seem to know what to do with it.

            
               Click to
read why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> likes celebrity stories. If you missed the sidebar about The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, it is. And is an anecdote about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s cheap subscriptions.
            

         
      
   
