
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln Bedroom</ENAMEX>?

            Your task today is to study
the adjacent photograph carefully, then to locate the notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bedroom</ENAMEX>. This is neither a trick question nor an implausible request: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Bedroom</ENAMEX> (this is a hint) is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and that's just what
you are looking at--a photograph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> interior taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbie Rowe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Abe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> has, of course, become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s most infamous place to sleep
in under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, surpassing in moral infamy even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at the nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson Hotel</ENAMEX>. Many unworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been
allowed to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX>'s memory, fat-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> among them. It has become a case of History
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defiled</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Bode</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> round-table,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> , spelled out the case for defilement right
after the story broke that big-time campaign money would get you booked
overnight with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honest Abe</ENAMEX>. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bode</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>
planned the strategy that won the war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s fleeing crowned
heads found refuge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bode</ENAMEX>'s implication--and it underlies all the countless
portentous references by the press corps to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>'s classless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>--was
clear: This is political sleaze at its lowest, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> putting a price tag
on the presidency and auctioning off our national integrity and memory in the
process.

            Now, back
to the photograph, and to our search for that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. You will, by now, have
noticed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> interior is filled with a mesh of steel girders
holding up the exterior, and that the sorts of things that are usually said to
make up a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>--a floor, a ceiling, doors, a complete set of walls--are
missing.

            
Where are they? Well, by the time this photo
was taken, most of these things were probably in a landfill in northern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>; that's where much--though not quite all--of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interior</ENAMEX> went around midcentury. The fact is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s guts barely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>. This doesn't get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> off the hook, but that's not our
text. More interesting are the rules of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> memory game. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>'s pictures of a totally gutted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> have become a kind of
forbidden imagery, evidence of something that none of us seems to want to
remember happened, because it seems to snap--by our own hand--a rare link to
glory. Some pictures are allowed to speak their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> words because we like
what they have to say; some pictures are silenced. This is one.

            It is
hardly a secret that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> interior became a structural replica under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>: It was about to collapse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Truman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> had
actually broken under the weight of her piano, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> himself was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> to sleep in the comparatively sound <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln Bedroom</ENAMEX> (if indeed it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>; he may have used it only as a study), lest he find himself
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Room</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">downstairs</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> was closed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half</TIMEX>. Work
there was widely reported, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of pieces of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>--old bricks and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of wood--were openly sold as souvenirs. There are
some significant cues to remembering all this, especially the attempt on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>'s life by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> that occurred at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair House</ENAMEX>--where
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trumans</ENAMEX> had to live during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconstruction</ENAMEX>--and cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
man his life: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> memorial plaques are affixed to the fence in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> telling this story to anyone who hasn't heard it.

            Nor are
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Service</ENAMEX> pictures documenting the work all that rare. Our own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photograph</ENAMEX>--featuring a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> bulldozing new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basements</ENAMEX> that will house, among
other things, the executive atomic-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bomb shelter</ENAMEX>--was reproduced full-page in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David McCullough</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> best seller, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> , which came out in an
election year in which both major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> were doing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">impressions</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thorough McCullough</ENAMEX> devotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> pages to the details of the renovation, down to
the number of old bricks (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">95,000</NUMEX>) trucked to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> for reuse there.

            
Yet, the myth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> continuity keeps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resurfacing</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacqueline Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s famous television tour doubtless played a
role in establishing it. When it was revealed a while back that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> had installed listening devices in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workman</ENAMEX> from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> told reporters how he'd drilled the necessary holes in the floor
under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s desk, adding, in a phrase that was reported without comment, that
those holes were "probably still there." Of course, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> line up to see where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> hung the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laundry</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> lay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> slept--not to see
restorations of those locales.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCullough</ENAMEX> writes that "by the standards of latter-day preservation," the
dumping of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> interior represents "a needless and tragic loss."
Still, it is obviously a historic place, and not just because the famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exterior</ENAMEX> remains (as do the mantelpieces, chandeliers, and paneling that were
later reinstalled). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom</ENAMEX>, for example, contains none other than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s own ornate bed (if indeed he ever slept in it; questions have been
raised about that, too), the one for which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Coolidge</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> labored two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to make a sufficiently large quilt. On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s
Box at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Theatre</ENAMEX> contains the chair in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> was sitting when
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Booth</ENAMEX> shot him, and no one would argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s is anything but a replica.
(For that matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New York Avenue</ENAMEX> was rebuilt itself as a
near-replica <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years ago</TIMEX>, too; rather a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">architectural Potemkinism</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beds</ENAMEX>, chairs, and pews are where history rests its aging
bottom in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> has been having a continuing debate
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about its past</TIMEX>--what to revere and what to demolish--for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> now, and has
destroyed a good many places with real claims to historical value, places as
old as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, with bricks from the same brickyard. The deciding
factor in what stays and goes, apart from "charm," is often the same: Who is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with it? Where does it rank in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Great Man</ENAMEX> Theory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tour Bus</ENAMEX>
History? Indeed, as the capital ages, its history is increasingly becoming
whatever associative past you can conjure up as ornament, reward, or
weapon.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s association with
the idea of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> historic, even if there's not much there.
So, secondarily, does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>'s. But in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> was reportedly ill at
ease in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom</ENAMEX>; he is said to have often moved himself across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hall</ENAMEX> in the course of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>. Why? Because while there was an unrenovated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Bedroom</ENAMEX>, there was also said to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ghost</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> himself
encountered him, he wrote, in the form of mysterious knocks on the door and
receding footfalls. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch Queen Wilhelmina</ENAMEX>, one of wartime <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s refugee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crowned</ENAMEX> heads, fainted upon meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX>, or so she said. But then she is also
reported to have heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX>'s ribald laughter coming from her bed in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Bedroom</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX>'s spirit has been pretty
quiet since the midcentury restoration. But no matter. By now, we've turned the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> itself into a kind of clanking ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> past, its very
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms suffused</ENAMEX> with the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirits</ENAMEX> of those who slept there. Once conjured,
it throws its looming shadow over the unworthy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">undeserving</ENAMEX> who dare
trespass. Well might they tremble.

         
      
   
