
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Welby</ENAMEX> Wasn't So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>

            Not long ago, I was
listening to an NPR talk show on which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> bemoaned the
passing of the well-beloved family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, whose kindly manner and personalized
attention once graced the healing arts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Anders</ENAMEX>, author of a
new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Against Wealth</ENAMEX> , described the ways in which
health-maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and other forms of penny-pinching managed care
are causing the "breakdown of medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anders</ENAMEX> offered upsetting
details: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s mysterious life-threatening disease misdiagnosed; terminal
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> denied last-ditch bone-marrow transplants; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who watch
bottom lines instead of blood pressures; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> who scan spreadsheets instead
of bedsheets ...

            When suddenly, there leapt
to mind the memory of a holiday party <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation ago</TIMEX> in a fashionable
neighborhood of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital:

            A kindly
white-haired gentleman sidles up to an ample hostess. "Come on, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kitty</ENAMEX>," he says
in his soft <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> drawl, "A little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddy</ENAMEX>'s not going to hurt you."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in question was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alcoholism</ENAMEX> was then in remission. The prescribing gentleman was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, a
practitioner much in vogue in old-time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> society.

            An
atypical example of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage practitioners</ENAMEX> of yore, you say. And indeed, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I spurned the courtly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generalist</ENAMEX> for an up-to-date internist,
highly recommended by a more senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> at the top <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> law firm my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had joined. And our switch came not a moment too soon. My thyroid, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> advised, was dangerously low. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Medication</ENAMEX> and frequent check-ups (covered
by our insurance, as routine physicals were not) were advised.

            
This struck me as slightly odd. I didn't fit
the sluggish, overweight profile of the low-thyroid sufferer. But I paid the
visits and took the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> and ignored the occasional heart palpitations that
troubled my sleep. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> was most attentive--he even visited me at home
when I came down with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken pox</ENAMEX>--though more out of curiosity than
solicitude, he admitted, adult chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pox</ENAMEX> being so rare.

            As time
went on, I met more and more fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> of my internist. A striking
number, usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, turned out to share my low thyroid. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, the favored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagnosis</ENAMEX> seemed to be gout. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gout</ENAMEX>? In a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20ish</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who never frequented a club
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pall Mall</ENAMEX>, drank no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brandy</ENAMEX>, squired no acres, rode to no hounds? Well, who
were we to judge?

            Of course, we, with our fine educations and scholarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">honors</ENAMEX>, were a lot better equipped to judge than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer.
And I will warrant that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>--keenly attuned to the income-enhancing
potential of well-insured diagnoses as he was--was probably far better trained
than the average practitioner in his cohort. He probably did us no lasting
harm. When I finally fled to the excellent, still younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">internist</ENAMEX> who remains
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, he took me off the thyroid pills immediately, and the palpitations
vanished.

            Which
brings me to the "to be sure" paragraph, as they call it in our trade. Most
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> were--and still are--impeccably honest, devoted to
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and incredibly hardworking. And many of them, my doctor
included, are chafing under the book-keeping requirements and restrictions on
their professional discretion that are prominent features of the new medical
regime. Adjustments in managed care need to be made--and under pressure from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, they are already being
made.

            
Nevertheless--the "nevertheless" paragraph
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ineluctably</ENAMEX> follows the "to be sure" one--it would be a mistake to try to turn
back the clock. Remember that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> before my remembered holiday
party, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't have health insurance at all. If they got sick, they
scrounged up the few dollars the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> requested and received care that, while
sympathetically tendered, probably wasn't worth much more than they paid for
it. If <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granny</ENAMEX> needed an operation, there went the tuition for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>'s college.
Then employer-provided health insurance proliferated, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> waded
in with generous coverage for the elderly through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">last</NUMEX>-dollar coverage for the poor through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>. More and more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> demanded more and more care and, thanks to science and technology, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> was far more likely to be efficacious.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
having failed to include conforming amendments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare/Medicaid</ENAMEX>
legislation to repeal the laws of supply and demand, medical prices soared.
Nobody minded much as long as somebody else was paying the bill (true, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> warned in their dreary way that costly benefits get shifted back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the form of lower wages, but who listens to them?). As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
found themselves increasingly squeezed between the demands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>, however, they started pressuring their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>, who passed that
pressure on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only a few years ago</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to be exact--managed care was
the prescription of liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> for an over-stressed health care
system. By standardizing practice, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> argued, wasteful care would be
curtailed without sacrificing--perhaps even while improving--quality. Indeed,
managed care was the primary engine relied upon by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' health-reform
plan to generate the savings that would finance universal coverage at no net
cost. Now, as the movement toward managed care has accelerated to a full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gallop</ENAMEX>--and health-care costs, once thought unreinable, have slowed to a
walk--managed care has become the bugbear of liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. "Don't let the
philosophy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> ... push your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> into the gas ovens of managed
health care," warned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> especially overwrought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> challenger in the
fall elections.

            How dire
is the threat? A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> review of various evaluations of managed care, in its
several variants, found no large differences in the average quality of such
care as compared with that provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in typical fee-for-service
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indemnity</ENAMEX> plans. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, for example, tended to get somewhat better
preventative care (including early <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer detection</ENAMEX>) and somewhat less
satisfactory care for complicated illnesses where methods of treatment are not
well defined. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> were especially satisfied with the lower premiums
they typically paid.

            
No doubt an energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> can dig up
horrible cases (though most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anders</ENAMEX>' don't pass the outrage threshold since,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> got the care they sought). But what about all the
horrible cases that flourished under the old system? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anders</ENAMEX> devotes a whole
chapter to examples of "shoddy care" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, that have
steered their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> clients into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anders</ENAMEX> had wanted to find a
carload of cases that move well beyond the shoddy into the truly horrific, he
need only have consulted the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid Fraud Reports</ENAMEX> put out by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys General</ENAMEX>. These I have perused with sick
fascination for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX>. The mildest of the reported cases--most of
them the products of our traditional system of loving care--involve the simple
theft by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX>, nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, chiropractors, and the like of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, often <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> (or sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>) from federal and
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. The more colorful cases involve the infliction of torments
on helpless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> that would excite the envy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>.

            Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> passed into law with scant attention, a few brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> dared to
suggest that the poor might be better served at far lower cost if the money
were spent on developing well-staffed, multidisciplinary health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> in
chronically underserved inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and rural areas--sort of like, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>.
Good heavens, snorted the conventional wisdom: That would be to create two
classes of care in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, one for the well-off and one for the poor! And
so we consigned many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX> to care that would be flattered to be called
second-class: to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid Mills</ENAMEX>" or to poorly trained solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>
or to wait in long lines at hospital emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> till the harried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> can
find time to treat their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' runny noses.

            Nor, to
return to the start of our story, is it only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> who were often ill-served
by the kindly and not-so-kindly vagaries of our old-time health system. So, as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX> of complaints about "managed care" swells to cathedral-filling
volume, it's worth remembering that much of what we like to remember never
was.

            

               References
            

            Anders, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>).
Health against wealth: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> and the breakdown of medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin Co.</ENAMEX>

            Congressional Budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>). The effects of managed care and managed
competition . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO Memorandum</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R.H., Luft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.S.</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18</TIMEX>). Managed care performance since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>: A literature
analysis . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">271, 19, 1512-1519</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 7</TIMEX>). Access to care in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> managed care: Results
from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> survey of enrollees and disenrollees . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mathematica Policy</ENAMEX>
Research.

         
      
   
