
   
   
      
         
            Polar Politics

            The bark beetle is eating
the spruce forests of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>. Clump by clump, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">acre by acre</NUMEX>, the tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> turn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brown</ENAMEX> and drop their needles. Already whole swatches of the lush Kenai
Peninsula look drought-struck. Soon, it is expected, the beetle will masticate
its way north into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denali</ENAMEX> and onward to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic Circle</ENAMEX>.

            No one
knows why the bark beetle has suddenly proliferated. Everyone agrees that the
bugs must have their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>. Spraying the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">roughly 150-million-plus acres</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s last great wilderness preserves is simply impractical.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loggers</ENAMEX> see opportunity in this. Why not clear-cut the
threatened stands before the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> is pitted? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> see peril.
The young spruce <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> clinging to their dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' skirts are seemingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beetle</ENAMEX>'s incursions. In not too many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, they, and the aspen
and other sprinkled hardwoods, will restore the forest's verdure. Lumber cut
many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> bears witness to earlier infestations. (The door to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sauna</ENAMEX>
cabin at the lodge where I stayed during a recent visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kachemak Bay</ENAMEX> is
etched with beetle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>.) Yet the wilderness restored itself. Clear-cutting
will destroy healthy and unhealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> alike, allow grass to take root, and
impede reforestation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> to come.

            It is
scarcely worth asking where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> stands on the
issue. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>--strategically seated on
key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>--unambiguously represent the corporate interests that, absent
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>, would log, mine, and drill every corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
largest land trust. They know that they can rely on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>'
reflexive resistance to any form of federal intervention, save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. That sole
exception to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarian orthodoxy</ENAMEX> is made in the case of federal
money.

            
Oil money and federal largess--funds available
either in full or at the most favorable matching rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, military
bases, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, refuges, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX> affairs, and the full gamut of
social-welfare benefits--allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to eschew both an income tax and a
sales tax. (According to a new report, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> ranks <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in
total federal spending per inhabitant, receiving <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX> more than
the average <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. So much for rugged individualism.) Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> can
reserve the proceeds of its vast <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Slope</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>-revenue trust fund to be doled
out per capita to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person resident</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>. (If
you have a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, an aversion to work, and a tolerance for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>
darkness, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> may be the place for you. Indeed, while welfare rolls are
plummeting in the contiguous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>, they are still on the rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>.)

            This is
not to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> are indifferent to the natural values
of their inheritance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s growing eco-tourism industry harbors many
"enviros" who regard the fragile bounty of their land with a quiet pride that
has less to do with ownership than with stewardship. The enviros, in their
well-cured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX> blues and olives, are an outwardly cheerful bunch. They
are never cold or tired or just plain out of sorts. They would rise before
dawn--if the sun, which lingers obscenely above the horizon during the summer
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>--would only set. Their vices are few--they enjoy an occasional glass of
wine or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, and now and then one may overindulge in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX>-spiked trail
mix. But they would prefer to be trekking across the wildflower-pocked tundra,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wading</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>-degree glacial muck, spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> -looking, or exploring
tidal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> for sunflower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and brittle stars, spiny sea urchins, mussel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX>, anemones, and blennies, as curious and brightly colored as any on a
tropical coral reef.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of the sourdoughs (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of whom, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early this</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount McKinley</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two 20,000-foot</NUMEX> peaks, dragging with
them a pine pole, an oversized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag, and a bag of stale doughnuts)
are, of course, less refined in their sensibilities. So, too, are many of the
adventurers, loners, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> who have migrated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in their
footsteps. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> has its seamy side. A story making the local papers
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> concerned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 2-year-old</TIMEX> who was asphyxiated when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> tried
to force oral sex on him. You may wonder why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> had been left in the
care of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> who was on probation for having broken the leg of another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had fled north, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>--also on probation for an unnamed
offense--was otherwise occupied. Oh well, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have their
troubles.)

            Yet, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Smith</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wilderness Society</ENAMEX>'s regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, points out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
rejected by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">to-2</NUMEX> margin the "sport" of aerial wolf shooting in a
referendum, overturning a vote in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX>. When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the
expected number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sockeye salmon</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bristol Bay</ENAMEX> to spawn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>,
more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alaskans</ENAMEX> began wondering if unrestrained exploitation might, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>,
destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that lay the golden <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. Farther south, angry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> blockaded an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> ferry to protest their low catch of sockeye,
which, they say, have been impelled northward to the colder <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> waters by
unknown factors (global warming?).

            
But because they have no direct financial stake
in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are relatively indifferent to
its pursuits. This leaves the political field wide open for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>,
their politically active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anchorage</ENAMEX> (where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 40 percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> resides), and their dogged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juneau</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

            And when money is at issue,
there is no contest. While <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> consistently tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX>
they oppose extending oil and gas drilling and other development in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic</ENAMEX>
National <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wildlife Refuge</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alaskans</ENAMEX> favor it. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native population</ENAMEX>, many of whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> still subsist by hunting and fishing,
is divided according to the traditional interests and financial stakes in the
potential revenues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwich'in</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">caribou</ENAMEX>," oppose
development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic</ENAMEX> coastal plain, to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">caribou</ENAMEX> migrate to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX>.
But since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwich'in</ENAMEX> opted out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1971 Alaska Native Claims Settlement</ENAMEX>
Act, they stand to make no profit from new drilling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Inupiat Inuit</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hunt whale</ENAMEX>, seal, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, favor development on the coastal plain--but not
offshore continental shelf drilling.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convoys</ENAMEX> with
their vigilant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wolf</ENAMEX> escorts migrate north <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each spring</TIMEX>, the grizzlies flourish
along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">salmon rivers</ENAMEX>, and the moose munch in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anchorage</ENAMEX>'s suburban backyards.
Along with the red <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX>, marmots, otters, beavers, ground squirrels, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dall sheep</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whales</ENAMEX>, sea <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>, bald and golden <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">eagles</ENAMEX>, tufted and horned puffins, and
myriad lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fauna</ENAMEX>, they participate with quiet dignity in the great cycle of
eat and be eaten. The enviros watch them with mixed pleasure and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. They
know that while the bark beetle is self-limiting, humankind is not.

         
      
   
