
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX>, is the
id of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the rage beneath its tense smiles. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders cower</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s poll numbers, too fearful even to whisper what they
call "the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>word." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, is furiously pushing impeachment. For the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-term representative has been shouting out loud what many
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> only think: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has betrayed the public trust,
that he has corrupted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, that he's deeply sleazy, and that he
should go.

            In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, long before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> introduced a resolution to open a
congressional impeachment inquiry: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, reads its text, "has engaged in a
systemic effort to obstruct, undermine, and compromise ... the executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branch</ENAMEX>." And since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinterngate</ENAMEX> broke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> has been in a state of high gloat.
He's now preparing articles of impeachment and happily adding obstruction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> and perjury to his list of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintonian</ENAMEX> high crimes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> has become what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrich Congress</ENAMEX> was supposed to
be. After the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican revolution</ENAMEX>, tough tactics and rabid conservatism
were expected to replace give-and-take and moderation. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
outflanked them and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s ethics problems embarrassed them, even the
party's most intransigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX> learned the necessity of compromise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the legendary "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman class</ENAMEX>" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, seized the
opening. He had campaigned as a run-of-the-mill anti-tax, pro-family,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">rock</ENAMEX>-solid conservative. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> crew weakened, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> repositioned
himself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> leaned left toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> went right. He advanced
himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the abandoned conservative fringes, as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> of right-wing anger.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> can
afford it. He has one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' safest seats. His west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district</ENAMEX> used
to be represented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Birch Society</ENAMEX>, and it voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. You can't be too conservative for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Seventh District</ENAMEX>,
though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> is giving it a good try. He has attached himself to the usual list
of silly far-right causes: no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> command, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX>
majority to raise taxes, a flag-burning amendment, etc. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>'s real genius
has been igniting nasty fires over issues that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> would rather
ignore. He is more than willing to embarrass party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> over matters of
principle. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, for example, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>-divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> drafted the so-called
Defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marriage Act</ENAMEX> banning gay marriage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> forced a reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> to move the bill by whipping up support among conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>. With his usual light touch he blasted "homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>" and
their "deviant way of life." ("The flames of hedonism, the flames of
narcissism, the flames of self-centered morality are licking at the very
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> of society.") The bill passed.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> whose
fondness for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> exceeds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX>'s, also led the
attempt to repeal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s assault-weapons ban. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> wanted to leave
the ban alone: There is little upside to endorsing semiautomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>'s grandstanding threatened to mobilize the gun nuts against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> let the bill go to a floor vote.

            On impeachment, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> is
happy to buck his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and speak for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-haters. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Philosophy: Extremism in</ENAMEX>
pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>.) Besides introducing his resolution, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>
published a law-review article on the history of impeachment and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
fitness for it, and wrote a glowing foreword to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Emmett Tyrrell</ENAMEX>'s The
Impeachment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX> . Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinterngate</ENAMEX> broke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>
has been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>'s hottest interview. All this has played brilliantly
among those irked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s silence on impeachment. "He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who have felt abandoned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. He's almost the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> who is thought of kindly," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Klayman, chairman</ENAMEX>
of the conservative legal-rights group <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Watch</ENAMEX> and fellow
impeachment-phile.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>,
like many cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, is flummoxed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s continued affection
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>: "If the poll results are true and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> really don't
want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to be held personally accountable, then we are in pretty sad
shape as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," he says.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> has the temperament of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Inquisitor</ENAMEX>--a moralist
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rationalist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, and his prosecutorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zeal</ENAMEX> is notorious. He interrogates hostile (read "liberal") <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> with a
chilliness that astonishes congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>. He never smiles when a frown
will do, never skips a chance to seize the moral high ground. At a recent
hearing on partial-birth abortion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> told a pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> that she and
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> were "very hardened, very cold, very callous ...[and] have
developed, I'm sad to say, a moral blind spot."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> say exactly the
same thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> himself. The family-values <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> is not only
twice-divorced but has also been sued for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support. He was also once
photographed licking whipped <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> off a buxom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s breasts. It was at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity fund raiser</ENAMEX>, he says, and he did it to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>
research.

            Part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' dislike of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> undoubtedly stems from annoyance with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persistence</ENAMEX> and effectiveness. But part of it is personal. Even his admirers
admit he's "dour" and "humorless." (His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> use words like "mean" and
"heartless.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> can't recall a single occasion
on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> cooperated with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX>
address, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>, rose repeatedly
to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> standing ovations. Except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>: He sat, glaring and silent,
through the entire speech.

            
It would be a mistake to confuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>'s skill
at setting fires with real power. He has gathered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-sponsors</ENAMEX> for his
impeachment resolution, almost all of them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>-nuts. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, has suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> be court-martialed for his
treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-sponsor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Chenoweth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>,
belongs to the black-helicopter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who hold
real power keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> at a distance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Rules Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, has so far refused to schedule a hearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>'s resolution.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> scoffs at the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> will
introduce articles of impeachment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
Armey, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, has compared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> to former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, the nuttiest,
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obsessive Democrat</ENAMEX> of the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. If impeachment hearings do
occur, it will be because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX> favor them, not because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> does.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, who's a champion
publicity hound, has national ambitions. During <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinterngate</ENAMEX>, some admirers
have begun comparing him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Barr</ENAMEX>
throws <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Molotov cocktails</ENAMEX> from the back benches, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> once did.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> rose to fame by destroying a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> is making his name by trying to topple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> rejected
the timidity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and held himself out as the true
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>; so does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> too may hope to ride right-wing
indignation to national power, but don't count on it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> may have been a
vicious partisan, but he is also sunny of temperament, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cooperative</ENAMEX>, optimistic.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> is none of these: You can't rule <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> with a glower.

         
      
   
