
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>

            Talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
Springer, the ringmaster of a lumpenproletariat circus, is enjoying a
wonderful month. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jerry Springer Show</ENAMEX> just evicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> from
the top spot in nationwide talk show ratings: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> is now watched by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 12 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, more than twice as many as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too Hot for TV</ENAMEX> , a video compilation of the show's worst
moments, has won a cult following and sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> copies by mail order. Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX>'s bad news is good news: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Coats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, demanded the feds stop funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> 's
closed captioning, calling the show the "closest thing to pornography on
broadcast television." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Activists</ENAMEX> for free speech and the deaf rose to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX>'s defense: It's always good business to be censored.

            This is
an era of aggressively nice talk shows. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> has abandoned sleaze for
self-esteem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX> has never met a guest she could not drown in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slobber</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jerry Springer Show</ENAMEX> is unrepentantly vicious. It's
dedicated to strife and misery, to the principles that human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frailty</ENAMEX> should be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ridiculed</ENAMEX>, that the weak and the stupid should be humiliated, and that there is
no better cure for your problems than the sorrows of others. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX>'s
show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> learn their girlfriends are actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> learn their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>
are sleeping with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> or ex-wives or both; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> learn that their
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> are strippers or their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are whores;
fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are poked and prodded and berated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> is an endless
parade of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>, perverts, and exhibitionists.

            What makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Springer</ENAMEX> a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landmark</ENAMEX> is not its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>-- though they are the saddest rabble in the medium's history--but its
violence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> seeks out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> who are too confused and too angry to address
their problems rationally and too inarticulate to address them verbally. Other
shows excise fighting and profanity: Springer promotes it. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>--mostly well-groomed, college-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--screams for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. When one
episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Geraldo</ENAMEX> erupted in a brawl in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, it made national news:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> has brawls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and more real-life violence than any show
on television. On the episode I watched last night, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tell Her It's Over</ENAMEX>," there
were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> separate fights. There was also so much cursing that entire segments
were incomprehensible (they're bleeped out). Most talk shows maintain at least
the pretense of reasoned discussion: not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springer</ENAMEX> . The closest it gets
to "debate" is a robed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX> moron assaulting a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>, as in this clip from
Too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot for TV</ENAMEX> .

            Springer
himself presides, oleaginously, over this spectacle. He's sometimes funny,
often smarmy, and always condescending. He brings the dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tinder</ENAMEX> and lights the
match, but he's always shocked, shocked , when a fire breaks out. If
guests swear, he tut-tuts them. If they fight--which is exactly what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> want them to do, exactly why they have burly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bouncers</ENAMEX> at
the ready, exactly what ratings depend on--he admonishes them to control
themselves. A lecture from the devil.

            
It's no mystery why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springer</ENAMEX> is on
television. A talk show is cheap to produce--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fourth</NUMEX> the cost of a news
show, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-tenth</NUMEX> the cost of a drama--and immensely profitable. As for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> 's grotesque content--well, someone will always push the
envelope of good taste. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> is riveting, excruciating
television. It is unbearable to watch but impossible to turn off. You know, I
know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> knows, he knows: No good can come of exposing these horrible
problems to the world, yet it's impossible not to watch it happen. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Carter</ENAMEX> put it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> does not have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, he has "rubberneckers."

            So the
question is not "Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springer</ENAMEX> on television?" It is "Why is Springer
on television?" How did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springer</ENAMEX>, with his do-gooding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">résumé</ENAMEX>, end up here? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>, he earned a law degree at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, then became a campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>, lost a race for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, and was
elected to the city council <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>. He was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 27</NUMEX>. He became a popular,
outspoken, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lefty leader</ENAMEX>--his first action was to propose a ban on the drafting
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>. He resigned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> when he was
fingered in a vice investigation--he had paid a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> with a check (duh).
But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX> he ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> again and won. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> he was elected
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. Springer was an old-fashioned tax-and-spend liberal. He was
a beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, the smart young thing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> politics. (He even
read the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> !)

            After a failed run for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> jumped to
television. He delivered short commentaries at the end of local news
broadcasts. He was brilliant: The minieditorials were concise, witty, and warm.
He took over the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> and soon became <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>'s most popular anchor. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, he launched his own talk show. It was responsible and dull. As ratings
sagged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> had a change of heart. Backed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> who'd
worked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly World News</ENAMEX> , he went tabloid. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> Jenny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones Show</ENAMEX> -related chagrined the rest of the talk show world, but Springer
filled the sleaze vacuum. He's descended the moral food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, TV talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>--and climbed the income
ladder.

            During his slide into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hades</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX>'s liberalism has degenerated into a kind of nihilism. (If a
conservative is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> who has been mugged, a nihilist is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> who is
paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to do something revolting.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> makes several tepid
attempts to justify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> :

            It gives voice to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disenfranchised</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who would be ignored otherwise.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guests</ENAMEX> are not exploited
because they are .

            The show shouldn't be
criticized for presenting disgusting behavior, because television doesn't
create values, it only reflects them. Click below for his unctuous commentary
on this.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> actually teaches moral lessons. Bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>--e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beaters</ENAMEX>--are booed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springer</ENAMEX> himself closes each episode with a "Final
Thought," a sermonette that makes it clear how little he thinks of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX>'s excuses are halfhearted (not to
mention contradictory--it's not consistent to say that television doesn't
create values, then lecture your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> about values).

            But
mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Springer</ENAMEX> doesn't bother with justifications: He smiles and admits the
truth about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jerry Springer Show</ENAMEX> . It's "stupid human tricks." "It's
all stupid. We're all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX>." "It's bubble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>." He has said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
shouldn't watch it and that he himself has never watched it.

            Most articles about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> describe this bad-mouthing as
"self-effacement." But it's not. It's more like self-loathing. Once upon a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springer</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX>: He hoped to change the world through politics,
to lead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> out of a recession. He cast himself as on-air <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a
million <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>. Now he is the ringleader of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> of morons,
the host of a TV show he doesn't like and doesn't believe in.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> hopes to redeem
himself, but it's a lost cause. He wants to be a political science professor
when his contract runs out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. Imagine that: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of
political theory and teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hookers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jerry</ENAMEX> attempted a return to the
straight world. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> hired him to deliver the kind of
commentary that made him so beloved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX>'s anchor and chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> chose to resign rather than share air
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX>. He delivered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> commentaries--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a bitter rant
against "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elitists</ENAMEX>" who condemned him--before the public outcry drove him to
quit. He slunk back to his rabble--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>, pervs, and exhibitionists--the
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who might still listen to his advice.

         
      
   
