
   
   
      
         
            Winnie-the-Pooh

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, whose two
principal hobbies seem to be slobbering over small <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and waxing nostalgic
about their past, found a way to do both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. They demanded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repatriation of Winnie</ENAMEX>-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pooh</ENAMEX>.

            The
sideshow to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> summit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pooh</ENAMEX> flap was
touched off when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Dunwoody</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pol of Very Little Brain</ENAMEX>,
visited the displayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>. Dunwoody beseeched the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> to liberate the "Pooh Five" from their "glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>" and send
them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. The dolls, she said, were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elgin</ENAMEX> marbles, a cultural
treasure stolen from overseas.

            Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> had made the front page of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Post</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> had told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunwoody</ENAMEX> to buzz off; Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nita Lowey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, had introduced a congressional resolution declaring that
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brits</ENAMEX> have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in a honey jar if they think they are taking Pooh
out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> had brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> a jar of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX> and
praised him as "the very best in immigration"; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> had called the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX>'s repatriation "un bear able." (This
was, believe it or not, one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s better puns.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>, recognizing that
discretion is the better part of absurdity, relented and withdrew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunwoody</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> was saved.

            There's no
doubt that the law favors the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> side in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pooh</ENAMEX> flap. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
have been here since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.A. Milne</ENAMEX> loaned them to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.P. Dutton</ENAMEX>, for a publicity tour. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milne</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, Dutton
bought the dolls from his estate for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX>. Pooh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milne</ENAMEX> son
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Robin Milne</ENAMEX> expressed his satisfaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> home
before his own death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.

            
The law favors the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, but does justice?
To whom does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie</ENAMEX>-the-Pooh belong? Who is Winnie-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pooh</ENAMEX>, really?

            There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> feud: nativist and internationalist. The nativist
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunwoody</ENAMEX>) logic: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.A. Milne</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Robin</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, he was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hundred Acre Wood</ENAMEX>, and he played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poohsticks</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river</ENAMEX>. Ergo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> is
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englishbear</ENAMEX>, whatever). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> counter with an
internationalist view: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> is a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the world," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> put it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hundred Acre Wood</ENAMEX> is not identifiably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. What kind of English forest has
a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">kangaroo</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger</ENAMEX>? Besides, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">internationalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milne</ENAMEX>'s
language is universally charming (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"a Wedged Bear in Great Tightness"</ENAMEX>), and his
moral lessons are universally applicable (if you visit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and gorge
yourself on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, you are likely to end up stuck in his doorway for a week
while he uses your legs as a towel rack--how true!).

            But there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX>: that he is neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> nor global. He is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>. If you could summarize what an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> is
(or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit</ENAMEX>'s idea of what an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> is), it would be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX>. He is a Very
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sort of Bear</ENAMEX>, a bear without a single English quality. Like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old West</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> is endlessly greedy, and he is cunning in
pursuit of that greed. Winnie-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> is, at bottom, the story of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX>'s quest for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX> = money?). His appetite cannot be sated. He eats
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbit</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>; he eats the honey meant for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heffalump</ENAMEX> trap; he eats the
honey that is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eeyore</ENAMEX>'s birthday present; he tries to eat a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beehive</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> is naive and ignorant: He spells poorly ("honey" is "hunny"), and he is
impressed by the pretentious wisdom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Owl</ENAMEX>. But when it comes to avarice, Pooh
has a native intelligence. He can't reach a beehive by climbing, so he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>-rigs a balloon to raid the hive from the air. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Owl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eeyore</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most
obviously <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> characters, are talkers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> is a doer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX>'s
greed is tempered by an all-American friendliness. Of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s most memorable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s-book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toad and Badger in The Wind in the Willows</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aslan</ENAMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Narnia</ENAMEX>" books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad Hatter in Alice's Adventures</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wonderland</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> is by far the sunniest. There is no dark side to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX>,
no complicated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> is guileless, blithe, good-natured,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX>. He is the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to all. (There is also a brash
self-confidence to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX>: He composes to himself that would have done <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman</ENAMEX>
proud.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX>'s world, too, is far more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hundred Acre Wood</ENAMEX> resembles an idealized vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s pioneer
past, a wild, empty land populated by a few hardy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> who band together
when danger threatens (Heffalumps!).

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
for economic reasons as well as literary ones. Where would he be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> without
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> commercial know-how? For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 50 years</TIMEX> of his life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> was a
modest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>--a pair of books that sold fairly well to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> rescued him from minor cult status and gave him to the world
(at a not-insignificant profit). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> has now sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20 million</NUMEX> books,
most of them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Penguin, which holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> copyright on
the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> books, has published black-and-white <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> books, color Pooh
books, miniature Pooh "storybooks," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnie ille Pu</ENAMEX> ), Pooh
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Agers</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tao of Pooh</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> volume, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Te of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piglet</ENAMEX> ), and even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, which owns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX>'s
merchandising rights, has done even more to spread his gospel. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> has
produced <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX> short animated features, one of which won an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Academy Award</ENAMEX>. It
has also aired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 80</NUMEX> episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Adventures of Winnie the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Pooh</ENAMEX>" horrifies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pooh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalists</ENAMEX> ("abhorrent," says one
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> I know). He wears a red jacket ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classic Pooh</ENAMEX>" was naked) and
speaks with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> accent. He fights movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monsters</ENAMEX>, sings in a musical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX>, and celebrates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> ( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>? ). But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> Pooh
reaches the world. Pooh videos from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> have sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 20 million</NUMEX> copies,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Pooh</ENAMEX> decorates books, blankets, albums, bedding, slippers,
calendars, backpacks, and cookie jars sold to impressionable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
everywhere. There are even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Pooh</ENAMEX> CD-ROMs. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> is on CD-ROM, you
know he really has it made. And you know he really is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
