
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> omens of apocalypse: A
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>--respectable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>--ran the following headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Geri Loses a Nail</ENAMEX>." Geri was Geri
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Halliwell</ENAMEX> (a k a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ginger Spice"</ENAMEX>), one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>. The nail was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fingernail</ENAMEX>.

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> performed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>
was there. He said, "These are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>. This is one of the greatest moments
of my life."

            Even if you're not a pre-adolescent or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>'s
living saint--and 
                  Slate
               's demographic surveys strongly suggest
you're neither--you have probably heard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> ("Tell me what you
want, what you really really want"). And you have undoubtedly heard of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>, who are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the you could ever hope to meet. Their song
"Wannabe" went to No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> album,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> , has sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 million</NUMEX> copies, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 million</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s release of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s new CD, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spiceworld</ENAMEX> , was the
biggest album launch in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> history (though sales were not as brisk as
expected). The album's first single, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spice Up Your Life</ENAMEX>," has already
performed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herculean</ENAMEX> feat: It knocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Candle in the Wind</ENAMEX>" off
the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> charts. Spiceworld the movie opens worldwide at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>.

            It is hard
to overstate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>' influence on popular culture, especially in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. Cabinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tory MPs</ENAMEX> voted for their favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spice Girl</ENAMEX> (not surprisingly, Posh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> won). A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> has proposed
teaching a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> course. They have spawned a dozen imitation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spiced Girls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpicE Girls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nice 'n' Spicey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five Spice Girls</ENAMEX>, among
others--who do nothing but perform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> songs while wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>
clothes. This is, in short, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> moment, the apogee between launch
and crash.

            
It is the time to cash in. There have, of
course, been plenty of teeny-bopper idols--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">New Kids</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take That</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanilla Ice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menudo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s byways are littered with their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corpses</ENAMEX>)--but none has ever been as well marketed as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>. They are,
essentially, a poll-tested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> picked them from an open
audition based on their looks and spunkiness. None of them is a professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">singer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX>--unless you count strip-club experience. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel B.</ENAMEX>, who once
played drums, has ever been a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>. Their music, too, is
poll-tested. The radio-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singles</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spiceworld</ENAMEX> are watered-down
versions of popular pop genres--disco, funk, world beat, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Motown</ENAMEX>, etc. They are
to pop music what <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are to ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spice Up Your Life</ENAMEX>,"
for example, is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> pop, while "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lady Is a Vamp</ENAMEX>" is a big-band tune.

            But the
music is an afterthought. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> represent the Jurassic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> ification of pop. In the movie industry, spinoff products now account
for a huge percentage of profits. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> bring the same spinoff
sensibility to music. Sure, there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> lunch boxes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>
gloves. But they were peripheral to the music. Life is different in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spiceworld</ENAMEX>.
If there is a product that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-olds</TIMEX> use, there will be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>
version of it in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>. Look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> backpacks,
trading cards, action figures, duvets, perfumes, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato chips</ENAMEX>, lollipops.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> will buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>-shaped chocolates, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid Spicecams</ENAMEX> plastered
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> stickers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> deodorant--in one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different
Spice scents. A toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> when it won the license to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">distribute Spice Girl</ENAMEX> action figures. A clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>'s stock fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>
when it underestimated the demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX>.

            The high point--or, depending on your view, the low
point--of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> promotion is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> deal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> wrote a
commercial jingle for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Generation Next</ENAMEX>" ad campaign. Then they included
the jingle on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spiceworld</ENAMEX> . You hear the jingle, you buy the album. You
buy the album, you hear the jingle. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> sells more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spiceworld</ENAMEX> . This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businesspeople</ENAMEX> call synergy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> call prostitution. Whatever it is, it pays. According to some
estimates, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> stand to earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>,
naturally, are appalled. The marketing juggernaut, derivative music, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moronic</ENAMEX> lyrics annoy music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>, according to reviews, are
"awful" and "extraordinarily untalented." During their rise to fame, the girls
wisely avoided giving concerts; when they finally performed live (on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> panned them. They "can neither sing nor
dance."

            
And yet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are not as bad as all that.
No matter how they are, no matter how pushily they are marketed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls</ENAMEX> are truly winning. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> has a voice, it is
theirs--optimistic, cheerful, arrogant. Along with bands like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls</ENAMEX> have helped vanquish the doleful grunge music that dominated the early
'90s. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> songs are derivative, but they are also catchy as hell, great
big pink bubbles of chewing<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-gum</ENAMEX> pop. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> themselves are cheeky: Geri
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patted Prince Charles</ENAMEX> on the butt and told him he was sexy (probably the first
time he's heard that). They mock <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> monetary union and embrace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> as "the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>." Their self-proclaimed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> power"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feminism</ENAMEX> is simple-minded--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> power seems to be the right to wear short
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skirts</ENAMEX> and still be taken seriously--but it's no more dumb than anything
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> ever preached.

            The most endearing quality
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> is their very crassness. They are products of this ironic,
shrugging age. They are more than happy to sell out and more than happy to make
fun of themselves for doing it. History tells us that the life of the average
pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> is a mere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX>: a meteoric rise to a brief and spectacular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reign</ENAMEX>, followed by flameout. (Just ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">New Kids</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>. All that remains
of them is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Wahlberg</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band members</ENAMEX>.)

            What does this calendar tell
us about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>? They arrived in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1996</TIMEX>. So they'll be
gone by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX>--just as soon as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas shopping season</TIMEX> is over.

         
      
   
