
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creed</ENAMEX>

            The devil can cite scripture
for his purpose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX> generally prefers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph Waldo Emerson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>, our secular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>'s executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> makes an exception for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> biblical passage, a verse from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>. It
appears in his book Active <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> , in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">op-eds</ENAMEX>, in interviews: "I have
become all things to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that I may by all means win some." It is an apt
motto for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>, a thoroughly political statement that defines a thoroughly
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> on the left blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> for infecting politics with
religious fanaticism. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s achievement is exactly the opposite: He's
turned religious fanaticism into mere politics.

            So it's
fitting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> is embarking on a career as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, a
profession where everything is mere politics. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> announced his
resignation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> has built into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>'s most powerful interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. When he steps down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX>,
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> will move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Strategies</ENAMEX>, which
will advise "pro-family, pro-life, and pro-free-enterprise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> is that he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot in chief</ENAMEX>, a devil with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cherub</ENAMEX>'s face. This is a misreading. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> faith is undoubtedly sincere, but his real creed is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
politics. He's a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkie</ENAMEX> who models himself after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Atwater</ENAMEX>. As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, he ran a direct-mail campaign for student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>. As an
undergraduate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>, he became the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' master
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX>. (According to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-tax Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> once instructed young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> about
the correct way to burn a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> flag during a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity</ENAMEX> protest.) His
tactical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ruthlessness</ENAMEX> has defined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>. "I paint my face and
travel <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at night</TIMEX>," he once said of his work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>. "You don't know
it's over until you're in a body bag. You don't know until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>." His
books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Active Faith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After the Revolution</ENAMEX> , read as much like
primers on power politics as religious-right manifestos. The strategy, not the
scripture, thrills him.

            And his
strategy, not his scripture, revived the religious right. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robertson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invited Reed</ENAMEX> to start an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to expand the grassroots network from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> presidential campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> was an inspired choice: He had
enough principles to win religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>, but not enough to
scare everyone else. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> recognized that the religious right had staggered in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'80s</TIMEX> because it had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) depended too much on national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alienated America</ENAMEX> with its red-hot rhetoric. To remedy the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> problem, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>
established <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>. Slowly, that network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> took
over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school boards</ENAMEX>, county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commissions</ENAMEX>, and state political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s more important contribution was to
abandon the clear, if ferocious, principles that defined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'80s Moral</ENAMEX>
Majority and replace them with a comforting fog of "family values." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>
hardly ever calls the movement "religious." He labels it "pro-family"--as if
anyone is "anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.") He dumped the "sodomite" rhetoric and distanced
himself from the religious right's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loonies</ENAMEX> (including his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>,
prone to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> ravings and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-world-government <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>). He presented
himself as the religious right's new face--smiling, civil, conciliatory. He
ripped off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s manifesto idea, preparing a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Family</ENAMEX>" whose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> points were poll-tested to draw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>-percent-plus
approval ratings.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> continued to push the
old standbys--defunding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX> and stopping gay
marriage. But he added a classic right-wing economic agenda: an endorsement of
free enterprise (God's own economic policy, apparently), opposition to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> stimulus package, and fervent support for tax cuts. He
even tried to quell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s abortion controversy, seeking to moderate (if
only a tiny bit) the language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1996 GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>. In short, he's
flattened the evangelical crusade of the old religious right into mainstream
conservative politics.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> has
also made overtures toward black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most committed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750,000</NUMEX> to rebuild burned black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">churches</ENAMEX> and is hosting a conference on racial reconciliation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> feels passionately that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelicals</ENAMEX> must atone for their
opposition to the civil-rights movement.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s political tactics occasionally annoy the ideologues
of the religious right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Schlafly</ENAMEX> criticized him when he suggested softening the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
platform. Some evangelicals view <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compromiser</ENAMEX> who'll bend a principle
for a tactical victory. Which, of course, he is.

            Not that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX> have cause to complain. Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX> now claims <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.9 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> nationwide, and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million</NUMEX>-a-year budget. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 million</NUMEX> "nonpartisan" voter guides the coalition
distributed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> are credited with electing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of the freshman <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, securing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s congressional
majority. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> distributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">45 million</NUMEX> guides in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>-right
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> now exercise significant control over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>;
they are estimated to comprise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fourth to one-third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> primary vote
and to swing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5-10</NUMEX> points to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in general elections.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s departure will diminish the movement's
influence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Committee</ENAMEX> investigation of allegations of
partisan campaigning by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> endangers its tax-exempt status.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>, who has kept in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX>, may emerge to embarrass the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coalition</ENAMEX>. (He's well on his way: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> bought by his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Operation Blessing</ENAMEX>" to fly aid to impoverished
Zairians were used instead to service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robertson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zairian</ENAMEX> diamond <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> seems most likely to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> as the
religious right's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX>. But he's much less politically savvy, much less
telegenic, and much more ideological--qualities that won't help the movement's
reputation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>, on the other hand,
will see his credibility increase. He no longer has to answer for the erratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>. He can drop the pretense that he's nonpartisan. He stands to become
the right's hottest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> agree that conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rocky Mountains</ENAMEX> will beg for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s talents and connections. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>
will make a killing. He earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $200,000</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>. His
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> estimate that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, he'll earn <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least half</NUMEX> a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $3 million</NUMEX>.

            But consulting is a
self-effacing business, and self-effacement is one thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX> has
shown no aptitude for. (He quotes himself in his books, the sure sign of a
towering ego.) He is relocating to his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>. He's got plenty
of name recognition. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Cleland</ENAMEX> barely won his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election.
Don't be surprised if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> takes his place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. God knows he's
prepared for it.

         
      
   
