
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poll Sitters</ENAMEX>

            Here is
my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap nugget</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>'s papers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post writes:

            Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>), at home in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>), in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> for a vacation, commented on the speech. Also unavailable
was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry J. Hyde</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>), the pivotal figure in an
impeachment inquiry. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas A. Daschle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.D.</ENAMEX>) was
traveling in rural areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> and unreachable throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard A. Gephardt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-Mo.)
was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            Now even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are entitled to a private life, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> noted last
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, and (as he didn't note) that includes the right to vacation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.
But does anyone else find it suspicious that on what will undoubtedly be one of
the most important political days of their lives, so many of them were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unreachable</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>'s "rural areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>"--that's a good one! Don't
they have phones in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>? Didn't the New Deal take care of
that?)

            Contrast this with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, who set new records
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> for quantity and speedy delivery of blather. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spoke for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> after he finished, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> had already rendered judgment
on the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are paid to be interesting, not to be
right. All they make is opinions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX>, by contrast, make decisions--in
this case, their opinion on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may turn into a decision about impeachment.
So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s silence from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> al. reflected an admirable
desire to think through the weighty issues that ...

            No, I
don't believe that. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> reticence can be partly attributed to the
ancient rule of politics: Don't kill your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> when he's committing suicide.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> even warned his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underlings</ENAMEX> to keep quiet.) But the main reason
for silence from congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of both parties was the modern political
practice of poll sitting. Don't express an opinion until you're sure it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 51 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallup</ENAMEX>'s random samples.

            
Until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:06 p.m. last night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> was a
complicated issue. The most basic facts were in dispute, and a political leader
could plausibly decline to express an opinion. Now the basic facts are clear,
and there are very few opinions to choose from. You believe that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) adultery
with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intern</ENAMEX> and lying both publicly and under oath about it are
sufficient grounds for impeachment; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) these are insufficient, but evidence
yet to come out about obstruction of justice might be sufficient; or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the
whole thing should go away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>. You are permitted to weave variations on
a few side issues--for example, was his apology groveling enough? But you are
no longer permitted to say the basic question is unclear or you need more time
to think. You've had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> to think.

            Say what
you want about an impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX>, but at least
he had the courage to go on national television <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> and argue for
continuing investigation. A few bold <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> also rose quickly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s defense <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. But among
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, it seems, there was no reason to get ahead of the polls.

            Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> broke their
silence with some of the most mealy-mouthed statements you could ever hope to
hear. But suppose that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or a month from now it becomes clear that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> have turned against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and impeachment is a salable
proposition. At that point you can expect to hear ringing moral judgments from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>, which they could just as easily assert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> if they 1)
really believed this stuff and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) had the guts. And if it becomes clear that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> side with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> and the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will turn up
the self-righteous anger.

            And if the polls are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambiguous</ENAMEX>, the assertion of timeless values by both sides will just have to
wait.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Web site's theme of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supporting America's Families</ENAMEX> in
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distress</ENAMEX>."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flytrap Today": The complete chronicles</ENAMEX>.

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
