
   
   
      
         
            Domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goddess Dethroned</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> 's final
episode will air <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> press machine, which
operates on the principle that no one who earns <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> can be all
bad, is cheerfully toasting its star's bright future. The theme: We haven't
heard the last from her. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX>, it is said, will become a serious movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">actress</ENAMEX>, a best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, a standard-bearer of feminist populism. Her
current role--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wicked Witch</ENAMEX> in a theatrical production of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wizard of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oz</ENAMEX> --will make her a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.

            Well, here's an alternative
prediction: We have heard the last from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX>. And if we haven't,
we'll soon wish that we had.

            TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, at least the political-minded ones, opine gravely that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> 's cancellation proves that a complacent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has lost its
appetite for "real-life," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"blue-collar"</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, that all TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> want
now are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 rd Rock</ENAMEX> 
               From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> and
Seinfeld <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX>. This is wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> 's cancellation proves
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has lost its appetite for a "real-life," "blue-collar" character
played by a spoiled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> brat. By making it, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> destroyed the very
thing that defined her: not making it.

            Once upon a time, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne mattered</ENAMEX>. She understood what it
meant to be lumpenproletariat , and made it her life's project to explain
this outsiderness to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. She did it brilliantly. Between its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> launch
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> ranked among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> highest-rated shows on
television. It transcended demographics. The working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> whose lives
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> claimed to depict tuned in. So did wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, to whom the show
represented blue-collar chic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> was not only television's most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX> sitcom; it was also its best (except, perhaps, for The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> ). As <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne Conner, Roseanne</ENAMEX> turned the pain of poverty into
comedy, exposed the absurdities of family life, and punctured the egos of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All in the Family</ENAMEX> --and no show
since-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> gave life and warmth to the ugly, the fat, the poor. It
was social criticism of the best sort, a tonic to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Family Ties/The Cosby</ENAMEX>
Show pablum of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan-Bush</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne Conner</ENAMEX> became a genuine
populist icon, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-June Cleaver</ENAMEX> for a downsized era.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Roseanne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> became an icon, too. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, she made more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> covers than anyone in
history. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years later</TIMEX>, The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> invited her to guest
edit its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s issue. But her celebrity depended on a fiction: that the TV
character was in fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>. For a while, she was. Like her TV namesake,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> was trailer trash. She was a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> who had
lived in squalid poverty with a ne'er-do-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. She had
street credibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> assured her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> could not change
her. She and her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Arnold</ENAMEX>, himself a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meatpacker</ENAMEX>, built
themselves a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> to escape the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> phonies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX> proudly
described the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> as: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s worst nightmare--white trash with money." You
could take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> out of the trailer, but you couldn't take the trailer out
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.

            
But of course everything changed, though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> herself did not seem to recognize it. She went <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> in the worst
possible way. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domestic Goddess</ENAMEX> became just another prima donna. She and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX> divorced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>. She tyrannized her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>, throwing fits,
firing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> at will, terrorizing her underlings ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> is
notorious as the worst workplace in television). She publicly accused her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of abusing her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> (they denied it). She followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>'s
lead by dropping her last name. She married her security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> (perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s hoariest cliché). She underwent repeated plastic surgeries in order
to reduce her breasts, smooth her wrinkles, slim her face (alarmingly, she
looks younger in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> than she did in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>). She stopped telling interviewers about anal sex and started talking
about her deep spiritualism and her study of mystical Judaism. In short, she
became a parody of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, indulging in every whim of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overclass</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX> did
more than make <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne grotesque</ENAMEX>; it also untethered her from the Domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddess</ENAMEX>, the one idea that made the show great, "the only good idea she's ever
had," as one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquaintance</ENAMEX> puts it. She could no longer portray a convincing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne Conner</ENAMEX>, largely because she no longer had any connection to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conner</ENAMEX>'s world. In its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few seasons</TIMEX>, the show lost its grounding in
reality. Plastic surgery made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roseanne Conner</ENAMEX> look less like a haggard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> than
like, well, a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> who's had a lot of plastic surgery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> used
to tackle issues like homosexuality or race relations with grace (e.g.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX>'s lesbian kiss with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariel Hemingway</ENAMEX>). But recently the show has
succumbed to ludicrous ratings-pandering gimmicks (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s
emergence from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>).

            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this final season</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> attempted the most
desperate plot device of them all: She had her TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> win <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$108 million</NUMEX> in
the lottery, replicating her own rags-to-riches story. What few shreds of
real-life credibility remained after that plot twist were destroyed by cameos
from C-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tammy Faye Messner</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlo Thomas</ENAMEX>? Moon <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unit Zappa?</ENAMEX>!)
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame parodies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xena</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warrior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseambo</ENAMEX>,"
the episode was titled), and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Dream of Jeannie</ENAMEX> . TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodman</ENAMEX>, who'd grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sick</ENAMEX> of the show and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX>, was all but written out of
the plot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> melted away. Once a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">top-10 regular</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> fell
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 th</NUMEX> place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 32</TIMEX> nd in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. It may finish as
low <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as 40 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>.

            What may be saddest about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> 's decline is that the show won't leave the legacy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX>
intended for it. It didn't usher in a golden age of real-life sitcoms.
It didn't open the airwaves to blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. Its single
accomplishment--if it can be called such--is that it legitimized the stand-up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comedian</ENAMEX> as sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>: from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne to Seinfeld to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> .

            Not that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> needs your
sympathy. She's earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX>, making her the
second-highest-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in show business, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>. Syndication revenues
will guarantee her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. She is about to launch her own TV talk
show. Don't be surprised when it flops. She's spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last nine years</TIMEX> talking
on television. She seems to have nothing left to say.

         
      
   
