
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man Who Should Be King</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               It is this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, this
right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">torturers</ENAMEX> worked over for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> in a hellhole
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plantation</ENAMEX>, till it was broken and bruised and lacerated. It is this
arm, this right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, that is still stiff, still scarred, still bent. And it is
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, this right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, that the avaricious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, who sell death
and call it commerce, think they can twist, think they can break, think they
can make reach out to them, open-palmed.
            

            
               But, you see, they don't
understand that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> attached to it. And they don't understand
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, who is allergic to their blandishments and
threats, just as he is allergic to the cozy, sleazy compromises of this dark
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, just as he is allergic to the mendacious hypocrisies of politics as it is
practiced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-20 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> is the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last _____</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of honor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, honest man, saint ...) in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics.
And perhaps, if we are very lucky, he is our next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ...
            

            Political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, like all professions, depends on the formula--the ritual "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> is
doomed" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will survive anything" stories. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, there
has been a significant addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> media formulary: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> profile. It can be boiled down to this: He was our bravest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of war. Now he's the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> courageous enough to tell the truth.
He is battling evil cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> money-grubbers. He may lose,
but he won't quit. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, he'll run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. We don't deserve someone
this honorable. Vote for him.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , and countless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have sanctified the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> in this way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX> has said he would consider quitting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> to aid a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign. As far as the national media are
concerned, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> can do no wrong. When his tobacco bill was shot down, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> declared the defeat would only burnish his reputation.
When he got caught telling a dumb, nasty about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX>--the kind of
crack that might cripple the career of someone else in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--he apologized
immediately, was forgiven by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and the love-in continued. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
for a brief sidebar on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> uses apology as a career strategy.)

            It's easy
to understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has been anointed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s favorite presidential
hopeful. He is irresistible. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> populated by grasping automatons, he
behaves like an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>. Probably because of his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five and a half</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> imprisonment, he is impatient with the euphemisms and lies of politics.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> once said of him, "You spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> in a box and you're entitled
to speak your mind.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> cracks jokes, dishes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>, and generally mocks the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypocrisies</ENAMEX> and failings of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> (and himself). The more his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> spin and position themselves, the better he looks.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> also has the appeal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX>. The
press loves <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s willingness to buck his party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> on campaign finance and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> makes great copy. (If he were a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>
leading the fight against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> and campaign corruption, no one would care.)
There is something heroic about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who seems to act against his
immediate self-interest.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> benefits, too, from
the general swoon about his history. He is an awesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. He doesn't need to
talk about the war: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX>, most of whom never served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, are
paralyzed by him. His indisputable bravery and honor inoculate him against
charges of base motives.

            And he
makes himself phenomenally accessible. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, he's
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ill</ENAMEX>-tempered and vindictive toward the local press; but he charms the socks off
national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. He interrupts family vacations to appear on cable news and
rises at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ungodly hours</TIMEX> on foreign trips to do TV interviews. He has a knack for
flattering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> obviously stage-manage media
encounters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, by contrast, is transparent. He confides in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. He
holds conversations with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in front of them. He asks them for
advice. (Tip to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX> way to ensure a favorable article is to ask the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for advice.)

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> hagiography is not harmless. It misleads the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and it will disserve him if he does run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He
isn't just an honorable, truth-seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, a selfless iconoclast. He's a
schemer, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, a calculating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> who has built his career on sexy,
attention-getting issues. He is opportunistic. He arrived at a convenient time
in the tobacco fight: He had no strong feelings about the evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weed</ENAMEX>, and he
became the tobacco scourge only when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> asked him to shepherd
the bill through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. He adopted campaign finance reform only after he
was tarred in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX> Five scandal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX>. Others who've devoted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to campaign finance and tobacco have watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> get credit as the
heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron saint</ENAMEX> of lost causes.

            What's
more pernicious about the coverage is that it confuses the qualities of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">crusader</ENAMEX> with those of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is often praised as an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX>, but no one ever points out that he's a rather ineffective <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. He
is unpopular in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> dislike him for
selfish reasons--they envy his popularity and resent his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> stances.
("His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> feel he's a showboat and a camera <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Sabato</ENAMEX>.) But they also dislike him for good
reasons. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> resists the political horse trading that underlies legislating:
He has said he has no plans to modify the tobacco bill to get it passed. (Well,
why not?) Similarly, he infuriates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> with grandstanding attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>,
being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> at publicizing and eliminating other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>' sweetheart
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>. He does not recognize quid pro quo politics.

            
This naked, righteous populism makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> a
superb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> on campaign finance and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. And there is certainly
something romantic in the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> needs an honorable, truth-telling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> like him. But there is also something foolish in it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contrarian</ENAMEX>, someone whose life is defined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely opposition</ENAMEX>. He was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>,
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon leader</ENAMEX>. He resisted his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captors</ENAMEX> alone and endured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in
solitary confinement. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Academy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was nicknamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punk</ENAMEX>," and
that's what he is. He suspects authority and challenges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>. It's why
he's a great story and a great troublemaker.

            It's also
why he would make a lousy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is not about bucking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>, it's about being authority. It's not about resisting coercion, it's
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about coercing</TIMEX>, and bargaining, and sucking up, and twisting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, and telling
little lies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> thinks that's beneath him. So he should stay in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and continue to make trouble.

            
               If you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">missed McCain</ENAMEX>'s awful joke, . This describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s penchant for
apologies.
            

         
      
   
