
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venture Capitalist</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Carnegie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>
embodied the democratic confidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilded Age</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> enshrined the scientific meliorism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Era</ENAMEX>. But the
defining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX> of our time is not a university <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX> or an art
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collector</ENAMEX> or a chair endower. It is Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Marks Templeton</ENAMEX>, religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philanthropist</ENAMEX>, investment wizard, amateur philosopher, and full-bore
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crank</ENAMEX>.

            A
do-gooder for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the millennium</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> pays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> to promote
conservative values, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> to build <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to
investigate the connections between faith and science. He believes he can
reconcile the irreconcilable contradictions of contemporary society: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
conservatism and New Age loopiness, capitalist greed and sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>,
old-time religion and modern technology.

            Before he started giving away his fortune, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the world's greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moneymakers</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>, he
began investing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '40s</TIMEX> and soon proved a natural. He established the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> mutual fund in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>. He was the first great global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investor</ENAMEX>, buying
international equities long before other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stock pickers</ENAMEX> noticed them.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Templeton Fund</ENAMEX> grew an astonishing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year between 1954</TIMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 retirement</TIMEX>--a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> stake in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> would have grown to more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> developed a cult following: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> thronged to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> meetings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> and obeyed his every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pronouncement</ENAMEX>. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> after retiring, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> can move the
market. When he hinted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock market was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overvalued</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> dropped briefly. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, he sold his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, pocketed
more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400 million</NUMEX>, and turned full time to good works. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, he gave
away <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> through his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Templeton Foundation</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">octogenarian Templeton</ENAMEX> has always been a devout <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>. (His own faith
marries the strict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presbyterianism</ENAMEX> of his childhood with a sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Vincent</ENAMEX>
Peale-y optimism.) But his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX> is secular: He brings
capitalist hucksterism to religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> has transformed
philanthropy into marketing, his own name into a brand. His earliest venture
set the tone. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, he inaugurated the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Templeton Prize</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX> to remedy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel Foundation</ENAMEX>'s omission of religion. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">brilliant stroke</ENAMEX> was to brag that his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> would be worth more than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>, thus ensuring lavish press coverage. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> award went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> before her <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>. He has raised the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prize</ENAMEX>'s profile by awarding it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Solzhenitsyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">burglar</NUMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Colson</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Templeton Prize</ENAMEX> helped
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> win a knighthood in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> had moved to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>--a tax haven--abandoned his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>, and become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
subject.)

            
Post retirement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> demonstrated a knack
for tapping into popular culture. He has, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> himself as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guardian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> morals and a bulwark against political correctness. The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton Honor Roll</ENAMEX>," announced with much fanfare <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, celebrated 126
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, and even textbooks that uphold
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traditional</ENAMEX> (i.e., conservative) educational values. Professional moralist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Himmelfarb</ENAMEX> and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Friedman</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>
lifetime-achievement awards. Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Lefkowitz</ENAMEX> also made the roll. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton Honor Roll</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Character Building Colleges</ENAMEX>" rewards <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that "promote
character development." The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Templeton Honor Rolls for Education</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>" boosts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> that promote market economics. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton Laws</ENAMEX> of
Life <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Essay Contest</ENAMEX>" awards <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> who write essays about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spirituality</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Templeton Prize for Inspiring Movies and TV</ENAMEX>" (now renamed
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Epiphany Prize</ENAMEX>") gives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> to movies and TV shows that acclaim faith.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Favorite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s Touched by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angel</ENAMEX> .) He's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> with a
bankroll.

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> is more than just a conservative sugar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>. His moralism is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sidelight</ENAMEX> to his much more ambitious goal: the reunification of science and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropists</ENAMEX> endow chairs and build <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> is
trying to refashion the world's intellectual fabric. He is, if this is not an
oxymoron, a religious technocrat. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>, science has
outstripped faith, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> views this as a great tragedy. He believes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX> must match science's advance with spiritual research, and
attempt to rejoin the soul and the brain. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX> should harness the tools of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> to make "progress." "Progress" is his favorite word, though no one, not
even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> himself, seems to know what "progress" in religion would
mean.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> has, almost single-handedly, revived the field of
religious science. He gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to teach courses in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> and religion. He offers the same amount to medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for classes
on "healing and spirituality." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Templeton Lectures</ENAMEX> send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> to campuses
to opine on faith and science. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> may appeal to New Age softheadedness,
but he's much more rigorous than the crystal-and-shaman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. He believes in
hard science. Favorite projects include a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX> study on the
relationship between prayer and longevity, and research at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins</ENAMEX> into
how meditation alters brain activity. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> he awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Templeton Prize</ENAMEX>
to a respected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cosmologist</ENAMEX> who argues that the structure of the
universe reflects intelligent design. Even so, the entire enterprise reflects a
mad obsessiveness: What to make, for example, of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Templeton Prizes</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exemplary Papers in Humility Theology"</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX>'s magnificent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crankhood</ENAMEX> reaches its apotheosis in his own writings. His new book (published
by, naturally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Templeton Foundation</ENAMEX>--a true vanity press) is Worldwide
Laws of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> . As ambitious as its title, it lists 200 "eternal"
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">spiritual/</ENAMEX>ethical laws that purportedly apply to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, in all times, in
all places. No kidding. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> unvarnished, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">didactic</TIMEX>, optimistic,
scientific, grandiose beyond imagination: "Behind this book is my belief that
the basic principles for leading a 'sublime life' can be examined and tested
just as science examines and tests natural laws of the universe." Worldwide
Laws of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> is an incredible volume--a weird combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomist canon</ENAMEX>
law, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Seven Habits of Highly Effective People , and Successories</ENAMEX>. Some
of the laws are biblical aphorisms: "As you give, so shall you receive." Most
are platitudes of high banality: "Every ending is a new beginning." "What the
mind can conceive, it may achieve." (Of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> laws, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph Waldo Emerson</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> himself.)

            And yet, even at his most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peculiar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Templeton</ENAMEX> stays true to his scientific and capitalistic principles:
If you send him a new law and he adds it to the next edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>
Laws , he'll pay you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>. If you teach a course about Worldwide
Laws , he'll pay you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>. And if you want to scientifically "prove" or
"disprove" one of the worldwide laws, he'll fund the experiment.

         
      
   
