
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loneliest Liberal</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Messinger</ENAMEX>, the favorite
to become the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, is being treated here
as a kind of anthropological curiosity. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> gave a major address a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> back, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> sardonically endorsed her as the "Mayor
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>," observing with a characteristically light touch that her speech had
furnished evidence of life on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Red Planet</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> hasn't just lost the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who read, or at least edit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>. A recent poll
found <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> beating her by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> points. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, bearers of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> tradition that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> represents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> leads by the
staggering ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79-to-21</NUMEX>.

            You have
to pity <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX>--first because the brand of liberalism she is identified with
was the universal philosophy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> because nobody's listening to the second thoughts she's been having
about it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> gave a speech before a business
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, in which she proposed to reduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s budget by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>, to
force work-rule changes on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, to permit private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> to compete
with city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>--the kinds of innovations common in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-dominated
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>. She even said, in what passes in politics
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mea culpa</ENAMEX> , "You learn a lot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>, and I have." The
New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               Times editorial page applauded, but nothing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> does will remove the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">scarlet</ENAMEX> L from her brow. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Koch</ENAMEX>, the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, says, "I believe in epiphanies," but adds that when he looks at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX>, he sees a younger version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bella Abzug</ENAMEX>, the hat-wearing,
megaphonic incarnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Left</ENAMEX> of the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>.

            That's fatal, and a bit unfair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> is actually not
that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>--she can keep her hands in her lap when she
talks. She's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of the middle class who attended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brearley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s most
rarefied girls' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radcliffe</ENAMEX>, from which she graduated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>. She
has a master's in social work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> is widely respected for her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>, her studiousness, her belief in the fine distinction. But there's
something of the killjoy in her. She's brisk, and pinched, and a bit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">censorious</ENAMEX>--you have the feeling that she has a moral position on, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
food.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> claim that she's been typecast based on her milieu--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">predominantly Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX>--rather than her beliefs. The problem with
this is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> has a history of beliefs that look rather embarrassing
in retrospect. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, while a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>, she hosted a
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">coming-out-of-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> cocktail party for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John R. Hill</ENAMEX>, who had murdered a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corrections officer</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attica</ENAMEX> riots. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, she returned
from a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinista</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> to assert that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> there
"participated in everything" and were "ready to die for this freedom."

            
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> was generally
considered a staunch voice for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, for the homeless and the
poor. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, she proposed extending rent control from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, a suggestion very few real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> have forgotten. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, she endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Barbaro</ENAMEX>, about the closest thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has recently
had to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic Socialist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. She consistently argued for
more spending, even as it was becoming clear that the Wall Street boom of the
'80s was flattening out.

            Of
course, practically everyone, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX>, wanted to spend more than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> had--that's what it meant to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Future</ENAMEX> Once
Happened Here , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and polemicist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Siegel</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX>, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, as saying, "I do not propose to let our fiscal problems set
the limit of our commitments to meet the essential needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>." The problem, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> notes, is that the definition of "essential
needs" grew exponentially, forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> not only to raise
taxes but to scant such traditional services as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and sanitation in favor
of a whole new range of social services.

            By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Dinkins</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, this kind
of spending had made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ungovernable. The economy was dead, the budget
was in perpetual crisis, and crime was shooting through the roof. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> did
nothing to reverse the trend, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wagner Jr.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>), abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> in
favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, and his election
had been heralded, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> among others, as the dawn of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainbow</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>. It turned out to be the last gasp of traditional liberalism.

            Crime, and
a broad sense of civic disorder, probably had more to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX>' defeat
than spending did. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX>, cannot find a way of sounding
convincing when she deplores crime--she has spent too many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> thinking about
it as a civil-rights and civil-liberties issue. Nor can she bring herself to
say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> was right about the merits of arresting low-level offenders
and cracking down on "quality-of-life" violations.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> points.
Now it appears that many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> who had stuck with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> are going to decamp in favor of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> with the personal appeal of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torquemada</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> victory by more
than, say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> points is bound to be seen as a repudiation not merely of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> but of everything she stands for. But the truth is that urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liberalism</ENAMEX> is not as bankrupt as the election is making it appear. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reformers</ENAMEX>
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Robins</ENAMEX>, a former top <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinkins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Horton</ENAMEX>, an
independent budget monitor, have been arguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> could save billions
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> by targeting long-standing perquisites--such as the endless array of
paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> for city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> or large amounts of down time for cops and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>--then investing the savings in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> and in restoring
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s neglected neighborhoods. They have made plausible arguments for
raising some taxes and lowering others.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> has at least been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alluding</ENAMEX> to the new reformist thinking, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> merely mocks
good-government proposals as so much eyewash. In fact, in a truly remarkable
public-relations coup, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> has managed to gain a reputation as a pitiless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> without reforming anything except the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX>. He has
disappointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> by treating rent control as part of natural law, and
by making no serious inroads on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s bloated labor costs. To hack away at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s reputation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> has recently taken to issuing press releases
with headlines like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">He Just Keeps Lying ... And Lying ... And Lying ...</ENAMEX>" But
it doesn't seem to matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messinger</ENAMEX> can't break <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s stereotype, or
break out of her own.

         
      
   
