
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>

            By my reckoning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> has played: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> prophets (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>, twice, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thomas More</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John the Baptist</ENAMEX>), an admiral, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>
(as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> captains and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richelieu</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macbeth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s voice).

            So the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX>, which elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, can be
forgiven for mistaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> for a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> believe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patriarchal Heston</ENAMEX> will polish the gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>'s lousy public image while
galvanizing its red-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>-and-gunpowder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> is on our side,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gloats NRA</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne LaPierre</ENAMEX>.

            At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> does remain an awesome presence--tall,
grandfatherly, astonishingly handsome, his voice as magnificent as ever.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> has already employed that godly bass to great effect. His NRA
speech produced a that's being played and replayed on newscasts.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ascendance</ENAMEX> seems to be filling some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> with what-if regret. Why
didn't he run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> when he was in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> are falling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrity Identification Disorder</ENAMEX>, the same malady that causes people
to write letters to soap opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> periodically says, "I am not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>," but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> don't quite believe it. He's been associated with
extraordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for so long that they assume he must be one.

            In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> embodies a very different, more mundane, but still admirable ethos. The
defining quality of his career is competence, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. He was never a
romantic lead, but he was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> during the epic's brief heyday.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '50s</TIMEX>, however, he has enjoyed the most workmanlike career of any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. He has made a prosperous living by playing, with slight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variation</ENAMEX>, the same role for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> with a stick up his rear
end.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>: never
brilliant, never awful, always reliable. He has appeared in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 80</NUMEX>
movies, countless TV films, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of plays. He is always first on the set.
He's unfailingly polite to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> and respectful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>. He never
misses work because of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>. Appropriately modest, he credits his success to
his "physical equipment" rather than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>: his height and good health, as
well as that voice, that jaw, and that nose. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Heston</ENAMEX>
researches his roles assiduously, memorizing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament passages</ENAMEX> to play
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> and reading all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s letters to play him.

            Unlike
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> has cheerfully adjusted to senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizenship</ENAMEX>. He accepts lesser parts in bad movies ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Call of the Wild</ENAMEX> )
and worse television ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Colbys</ENAMEX> , a short-lived, dreadful <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dynasty</ENAMEX>
spinoff). He has become a hired-gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you buy when you need
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God</ENAMEX>'s voice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>'s signature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Hur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Cid</ENAMEX>) always took
themselves seriously, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> doesn't. He has played self-mocking parts in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World 2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Light</ENAMEX> ads. He is a pro, a hack, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> whose
highest value is that he gets the job done.

            Off-screen, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> leads an unremarkable life. He has
been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54 years</TIMEX> and is extremely close to his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. He lives
quietly on a (well-armed) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">estate</ENAMEX>, eschewing parties for history
books and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> memoirs, he is an excellent, funny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">writer</ENAMEX>).

            And his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activism</ENAMEX> is a steady hobby rather than an obsession. He's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX>, but
also a dilettante. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '60s</TIMEX>, he was a staunch civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>, he advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX>. He has condemned the nuclear freeze movement, obscene rap music, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overpopulation</ENAMEX>. In every case <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> has been effective without being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monomaniacal</ENAMEX>. (His rhetoric, admittedly, is not always restrained. He denounces
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correctness</ENAMEX> with froth-at-the-mouth language that would be hilarious
if it weren't so nasty. Click for a couple of examples.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> has even had moderate instincts about
gun rights. Until recently, he hasn't spent much time pushing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX>
Amendment. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s assassination in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, he endorsed strong gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> legislation, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as last year</TIMEX> he declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AK-47s</ENAMEX> are
"inappropriate for private use." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>'s "softness" on gun rights was an
issue in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> election, but he has quieted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> by backing off his
earlier statements and hewing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>'s official line. He recently said that
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state initiative to require trigger locks was "written by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>.")

            All this
is to say: Those who liken him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misunderstand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>. It is an easy
comparison. Both are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who converted to conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republicanism</ENAMEX>.
Both are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> who involved themselves in politics. Both served as president
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Screen Actors Guild</ENAMEX>. Both are marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>.

            But here is the critical point about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>: He never
grabbed the ring. He declined invitations from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to run
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and resisted efforts to draft him into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>
presidential race. He was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, and will always be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>.
His life is comfortable, and he sees no reason to change it.

            It's true
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> has accomplished more than most private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> ever
hope to. But he has never done what his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> would have. The
extraordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who believes he can change the world, hungers for
the power to do it and pursues that power relentlessly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> had that hunger
and changed the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> has all the "physical equipment"--brain, voice,
good looks--but not the hunger.

            That's why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> presidency is the perfect job for him.
It's a ceremonial position, a grand title with few responsibilities attached.
He will not actually run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>. His job is to give speeches, to be a symbol,
to act presidential. And there's no one who acts presidential better than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>.

            
               If you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">missed Heston</ENAMEX>'s NRA sound bite, click . You can read some of his ornery
comments about political correctness .
            

         
      
   
