
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> enjoys nothing so
much as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> fight between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s spat between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> was a doozy. In his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>--usually a highly unmemorable document--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief justice</ENAMEX> criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> for stonewalling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judicial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>. Noting that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judgeships</ENAMEX> are vacant and
caseloads are rising, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> warned that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> should act within a
reasonable time to confirm or reject [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>]. Some current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> have
been waiting a considerable time for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> vote or a
final floor vote." By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> standards, those were fighting words.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> tried to shift the blame to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for nominating "liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>," but he was too late. The spin had
been spun. Editorial pages and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> agreed: If a conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologue</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is crippling the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>,
then <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Something Must Be Done</ENAMEX>.

            The reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s comments highlights a common
misunderstanding about the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> is popularly viewed as a
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and last, a partisan in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> revolution. But what really defines <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> in his role as chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> is not conservatism--though he's certainly very conservative--it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylorism</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Winslow Taylor</ENAMEX>, the apostle of "scientific
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> champions rationality and efficiency above all.

            Once upon
a time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> was a real bomb thrower. The chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> to his bones. Raised in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> home in an all-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> eventually settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, where he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allied</ENAMEX> early and avidly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX> in
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> as an assistant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> appointed him associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>.

            
From an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> believed
passionately in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' rights. (This principle has haunted him. Click to read
why.) He was appalled by the way federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> were intervening in state and
local governance, coddling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, and expanding individual rights. He was
an early convert to judicial restraint, concluding that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> should
butt out and let elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> do their job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX>
court's outlier, writing lonely, sclerotic dissents and preaching a
conservative legal philosophy long before it became popular. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supreme</ENAMEX> rationalist, and even his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> admired the analytical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of his
dissents.)

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> slowly began to catch up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
elevated him to chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. But after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX>, it's still hard to
characterize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. There isn't a consistent conservative
majority, and philosophically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is a muddle--"a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pudding</ENAMEX> without a
theme," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akhil Reed Amar</ENAMEX>, quoting the old saw. It's more
conservative than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> (especially on race and crime), but most of
its major decisions (on abortion, gay rights, Internet free speech) have been
moderate or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>. Instead, what seems to define the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s style. His success on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is a success of process: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>
has made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> do less and do it more rationally. He has not grown
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. He has shrunk in it.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s proudest achievements as chief justice
has been to pare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s docket. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX> court heard oral arguments in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX> or more cases every term. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> hear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as many
cases. The result, wonderfully satisfying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>, is less judicial
meddling. "His great contribution as chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> is that the role of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is smaller than it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>," says a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rehnquist clerk</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> has pushed to minimize federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurisprudence</ENAMEX> at
every level. He may have requested more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, but only because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clogged</ENAMEX> and slow. He has urged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> repeatedly to stop federalizing crimes.
Fundamentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> doesn't want more federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>; he wants fewer
federal laws.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of law that matter most to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> are habeas corpus reform and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX>-procedure reform. He campaigned vigorously and successfully to
restrict the number of habeas appeals for death row <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>. This has limited
federal involvement in state cases and, more importantly, sped up the judicial
process. "He has intense anger about convicts who after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX> are on their
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> appeal. He thinks that things should not be chewed on endlessly," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emory University</ENAMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Garrow</ENAMEX>. In criminal procedure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s
decisions have weakened the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Miranda rights</ENAMEX>, nibbled away at the exclusionary
rule, and granted cops more leeway to conduct warrantless searches. These
procedural reforms remove the "technicalities" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> believes clutter
and pollute the legal system.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s decisions, too, are becoming
increasingly streamlined. Associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> was famed for his witty,
explosive writing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> leaves the verbal pyrotechnics to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX>. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s opinions are skeletal: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> complain
that his reasoning is almost nonexistent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s pithiness is the
pithiness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two decades ago</TIMEX>, he wrote extensively because he had
to explain his unfamiliar views to a liberal world. Now, his views are
mainstream law. He doesn't need to elaborate on them.

            Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s operations
are evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s efficiency. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX>, the conference--the
meeting where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> discuss cases--was a notoriously windy affair.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s conferences are no-nonsense. He permits little discussion--he
doesn't think it changes anyone's mind--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> through votes. He prods
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> to turn in draft decisions promptly and penalizes tardy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> by withholding new assignments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> who disagree with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> politically love him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>: He's fair, agreeable, and
fast.

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, it was
ritual among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> to speculate that "this term" would be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s last. He was too old, his back hurt too much, he had too many
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> ... But recently, the speculation has subsided. There are two
explanations for why the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> is staying put. One is
political: He's enough of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> not to quit until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. I favor the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> explanation. Why would he bother to retire? Every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> he has less work to do. He's made sure of that. The efficient justice
arrives at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> and leaves by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>--what other job in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has
such sweet <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>?

         
      
   
