
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every few years</TIMEX>, like
clockwork, the pop-music industry presents to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> for its
delectation a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> so base, so vile, so offensive to common decency, that
he must be stifled. Once upon a time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ozzy Osbourne</ENAMEX>, bat eater.
More recently, it has been <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Twisted Sister, 2 Live Crew, Snoop Doggy Dog</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inch Nails</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>'s designated villain outdoes them all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX>, who lends his adopted name to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of</ENAMEX>
Satan, the self-proclaimed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antichrist Superstar</ENAMEX>," and the perfect cartoon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fiend</ENAMEX>. Already <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> have canceled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> shows, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> has paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> not to play. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> has had to threaten a
lawsuit in order to perform in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, and has filed a lawsuit in order
to perform in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> has blacklisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> because he once shredded
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mormon Bible</ENAMEX> onstage, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> picket outside every venue he
plays.

            They have
picked an easy target. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX> plays music that is called, depending on
who's doing the calling, "death metal," "industrial," "gothic," "glam <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX>,"
"shock rock," or "sleazy industro-crunch." Or, perhaps most accurately:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-Year-Old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Boy</ENAMEX> music--the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sonic pollution</ENAMEX> that no one but a boy
high on testosterone could enjoy. What this means is huge, distorted guitar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noise</ENAMEX>, a thumping backbeat, lots of screechy fuzz, and vocals that are usually
droned, occasionally screamed or hissed. It also means ferocious lyrics:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX>'s songs are a foul <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stew</ENAMEX> of obscenity, violence, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Satanism</ENAMEX>, scatology,
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> invective, sadomasochism, and suicide. For example:

            I am
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">god of Fuck ...Cash</ENAMEX> in hand and dick on screen, who said god was ever
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX>? Bible-belt round <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-waste [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ], putting sinners in their
place. Yeah, right, great. If you're so good explain the shit stains on your
face.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX>'s public image is as creepy as his
music. He and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band members</ENAMEX> have adopted female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop icons</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>' last names (my favorite: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna Wayne Gacy</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX>, whose
given name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>, cakes his face with alabaster makeup and wears
androgynous, ragged leather clothes. He looks like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grim Reaper</ENAMEX> after a
nasty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> accident. His concerts are frenzied: He lacerates his chest
with broken bottles, rips <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bibles</ENAMEX> apart, and uses an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag as toilet
paper. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s videos are filled with freakish images of medical oddities.
Its T-shirts are decorated with pentagrams and slogans like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kill God</ENAMEX>, Kill
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kill Yourself</ENAMEX>." Needless to say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> eat this up. The most
recent album, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antichrist Superstar</ENAMEX> , debuted at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 3</NUMEX> on the Billboard
charts and has sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1 million</NUMEX> copies. (The album was released by--of
course--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interscope Records</ENAMEX>, the label that brought you <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snoop Doggy Dog</ENAMEX>, Tupac
Shakur, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nine Inch Nails</ENAMEX>.) Any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 40</TIMEX> knows, of course, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> isn't the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> to combine horror-movie imagery, crude
theatricality, and anti-social lyrics--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Sabbath</ENAMEX> did it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mötley Crüe</ENAMEX> did it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> is more horrible, more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>,
more theatrical, and more anti-social than any of its antecedents.

            And more
ridiculous. You wouldn't think that anyone could take this kind of rock
grandiosity seriously after seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Is Spinal Tap</ENAMEX> , but they do.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> champions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> as the conscience of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> music:
"Never has there been a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> quite as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX>." Never?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> is lionized for speaking the "truths" that no one wants to hear: that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christianity</ENAMEX> is false, that conventional morality is stifling, and so on. No
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX>'s philosophizing more seriously than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> himself. "Rock 'n'
roll was dangerously close to becoming completely boring until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX>
came along," he said in a recent interview.

            
Unlike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee Snider</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Twisted Sister</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Simmons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> isn't a jokester. He honestly
believes himself to be "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX>," the embodiment of the world's great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opposites</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, icon and villain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>. He believes, too,
that his music has deep social significance. He cites his intellectual
influences to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nietzsche</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roald Dahl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seuss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anton LeVay</ENAMEX>--and delivers the kind of muddled rants that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> mistake
for wisdom. In his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX>, for example, he writes: "We are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s shit
and they should be ashamed of what they have eaten. Fortunately you have
received this in time to escape the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">encroaching HOLOCAUST</ENAMEX> of fascist christian
[ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] morality."

            Not
surprisingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Association</ENAMEX> have taken up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX>. The silly, juvenile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rocker</ENAMEX> vs. the prudish, humorless censors. You want both sides to lose.

            Earlier battles over offensive music were fought on
television and in print. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> fight is shaping up as one of the
Internet's first great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kulturkampfs</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the AFA
posted "affidavits" about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> concerts on its Web site. The affidavits
claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> passes out bags of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>, that he raped a
dog onstage, had anal and oral sex onstage, threw <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> and kittens into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> to be torn apart, and led Satanic services that included a "virgin
sacrifice." The affidavits also attest that he watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> stab a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to
death and bathe in her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. E-mailed around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the affidavits
galvanized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to organize protests and
demand concert cancellations.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> have retaliated in kind. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> is threatening to sue the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX> for libel and defamation. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">AFA</ENAMEX> has yanked the affidavits off
its site.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> have parodied the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> and organized their
own online "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Family Association</ENAMEX>," which takes its name
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manson album</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POAAFA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> Web sites, some of
which counteract the false affidavits by publishing concert-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goers</ENAMEX>' accounts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> shows (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass laceration</ENAMEX>, no sex).

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> fight is a morality play in which
everyone wins. The decency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> get to make headlines, shock consciences, and
stop concerts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> gets to paint himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> and
keep selling records. The good times won't last. The shelf life of preteen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bands</ENAMEX> is measured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. When the censors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> stop complaining, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will stop listening, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> will fade away.

            But there may be some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consolation for Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX> himself. Here it is instructive to remember
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Cooper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> to whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> owes most. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A quarter century ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> sold the same kind of horror show to his teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> does now: a
gender-bending female name, pancake makeup, raucous music, an onstage
guillotine, and preposterous gross-out legends. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> allegedly filled
balloons with live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX>, released them above the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, then popped them,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">showering</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> crawlers.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> was condemned, reviled and, for a
brief time, incredibly popular. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> he's made a revival. He played
himself, campily, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> . He draws <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to his
goofy, self-consciously bombastic concerts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX> is darker, more
serious, and more vicious than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Cooper</ENAMEX> was. Even so, you can imagine a
comeback in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2017</TIMEX>: shredding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bibles</ENAMEX> to a laugh track.

         
      
   
