
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Scheck</ENAMEX>

            If there is a special corner
of hell reserved for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>--and I'm sure there is--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last week</TIMEX> roasting in it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> had conducted a
magnificent defense of accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby killer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX>, complete with his
trademark sneering speeches, windmilling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, and devastating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-examinations. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX> watched, stunned, as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> was convicted
of second-degree murder and sentenced to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>.

            What does
this have to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>? Well, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternate juror</ENAMEX> hinted that one factor in
the verdict might be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> backlash. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternate</ENAMEX> says he heard other panel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> talk about getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX>--about punishing him for his courtroom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">histrionics (à la the Simpson</ENAMEX> trial), his sarcastic attacks on prosecution
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> (à la the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> trial), his "hocus pocus" medical evidence (à la
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> trial).

            This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Scheck</ENAMEX>'s torture: to be forever yoked to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> case. Not just yoked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> case, but yoked to the worst
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> case. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">O.J. attorneys</ENAMEX> did the impossible: They
managed to lower the public's estimation of criminal defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Cochran race</ENAMEX>-baited and spun wild conspiracies. Scheck badgered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and
split hairs. His destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>'s heralded DNA evidence was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meticulous</ENAMEX>, obnoxious, and unforgettable. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-day</TIMEX> evisceration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Fung</ENAMEX> ("Where is it, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fung</ENAMEX>?")
the greatest cross-examination since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scopes</ENAMEX> trial. The verbs "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">to Scheck</ENAMEX>"
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">to Schecktify</ENAMEX>" entered the legal vocabulary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> came to personify the
grotesque defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, bullying, self-righteous, melodramatic. (In a
priceless moment during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> himself phoned Court TV to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">defend Scheck</ENAMEX> against charges of obnoxiousness. For more on this, click .)

            And yet,
of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> is the one who least deserves public disapproval.
He is, in fact, the very model of what a celebrity defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> should be.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> has spent his entire professional life in pursuit of (usually) worthy
causes. His motto could be: always righteous, often right. As an undergraduate
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s</TIMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX> was a fervent anti-war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protestor</ENAMEX>. Big deal--so was everyone else. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX>'s protest was inspired
and brave. He fought to abolish all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> deferments, figuring that the war
would end only when white, middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> saw their white, middle-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> (like him) die in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.

            
The same creative skepticism toward authority
defines his legal career. After law school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX> worked for several years
trying to expose grand jury abuse, and then spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX>'s vigor and intelligence landed him a
job as a clinical law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardozo Law School</ENAMEX>. The job gave
him the freedom to pursue cases that interested him. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, Scheck
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">represented Hedda Nussbaum</ENAMEX>, adoptive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of the murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Steinberg</ENAMEX>.
Paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $25</NUMEX> an hour, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nussbaum</ENAMEX> escape prosecution for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa</ENAMEX>'s
death, and shifted blame to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Steinberg</ENAMEX>, who had battered and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abused Nussbaum</ENAMEX>.

            Scheck
found his forte in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>. He and his law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, an equally pugnacious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Neufeld</ENAMEX>, handled a case where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> carelessly used
DNA evidence to railroad a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>. He and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neufeld</ENAMEX> made themselves the
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> testing. It became a cause for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX>: He was convinced
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> would overstate their DNA evidence to secure conviction. So
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neufeld</ENAMEX> launched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Innocence Project</ENAMEX>. You would be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hard-pressed</ENAMEX> to find a more admirable enterprise. Scheck, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neufeld</ENAMEX>, and their
law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> use DNA evidence to spring wrongly convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>--frequently
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>." So far, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Innocence Project</ENAMEX> has cleared more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> on death row. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> is not perfectly consistent
about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>: He uses genetic fingerprinting when it exonerates his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and
criticizes the technique when it implicates them. But defense lawyering is a
rough trade.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> case was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faustian</ENAMEX> bargain. It gave him
useful fame, but it tarnished him as someone who had helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> get away with
murder. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> doesn't see it that way. For him, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> case was as much
about the misuse of medical evidence as about murder. His devotion to his
cause--scientific evidence--allowed him to avoid larger questions (such as,
say, "Did he kill 'em<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"). Within that narrowed framework, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX> could
construct an intellectually honest defense: There was reasonable doubt because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> forensic work was shameful.

            Scheck
began the case on the periphery of the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and ended it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.
There are very good reasons for this: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX> was probably the smartest of the
defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and he was certainly the hardest-working; he spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>
poring over complex evidence that other defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> didn't bother with. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Toobin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Run of His Life</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> is titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Best Trial Lawyer</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scheck</ENAMEX> one of the most famous lawyers
in the world, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to mind. He writes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
and comments for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> on big trials. (He did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> civil case, and was
surprisingly evenhanded.) But mostly, he has used his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> to advance his
causes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX> is constantly in court for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Innocence</ENAMEX>. He has spoken out
against the new restrictions on federal habeas corpus. He serves on the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York State Commission on Forensic Science</ENAMEX> and he lectures to police departments
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> about proper use of genetic fingerprinting.
He is representing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abner Louima</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Haitian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> who allegedly was
sodomized with a toilet plunger by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> cops. The defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> is
even advising <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>!) on the medical evidence in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX> case.

            Estimates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX>'s fee in
the nanny trial range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000 to $300,000</NUMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> case--his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> Trial of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Decade</TIMEX>--reflects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX>'s high-mindedness as much as his
greed. (After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX> earns a pittance compared with what he could if he
were a full-time criminal defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>.) The nanny case jibes perfectly
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX>'s obsession. The case turns on questionable medical testimony about
injuries to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-month-old victim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Eappen</ENAMEX>. Scheck, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> agree,
poked huge holes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> shook the baby and
then dashed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> against a hard object. If the wound to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eappen</ENAMEX>'s skull was
new, asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX>, why had scar tissue formed around it? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> had shaken
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, why did his neck show no signs of damage? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheck</ENAMEX>'s questions didn't
convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>, but they may well persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to toss out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s
conviction or reduce her conviction to manslaughter. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will not make
that decision until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10</TIMEX> at the earliest.)

            During the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> trial,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie Cochran</ENAMEX> has occasionally devoted his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> TV show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochran</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Company</ENAMEX> , to the case. He has interviewed other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, alternate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX> himself was billed as a guest, but he
never appeared. There was something fitting about this. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochran</ENAMEX> pontificated
windily for the camera. Scheck was too busy being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, too busy trying to
redeem a (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">possibly</NUMEX>) innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, to join him.

         
      
   
