
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX>

            To understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX>
matters, ignore what he says and listen to how he says it. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
acceptable accents for a contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sincere Southern</ENAMEX>
(favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and every other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX> who's ever lived south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flat Corporate</ENAMEX> (preferred by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> speaks neither. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> delivers speeches and strike ultimatums in an accent best
described as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens Bray</ENAMEX>. Hearing him on the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was a shock: How
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX> has it been since such a broad, brassy voice has been broadcast to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>? Or, to pose the question another way, how long has it been since anyone
outside a union hall paid attention to a union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>?

            But while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> is the first union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> to intrude on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
public consciousness, and while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike is the most important and
disruptive walkout since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> busted the air-traffic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, the
Carey backlash is already under way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s difficulties began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>, when
he narrowly defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hoffa</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the Late <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Unlamented</ENAMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>
presidential election. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffa</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> of campaign-finance irregularities.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> began probing whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> had
laundered union dues into his campaign chest. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> has already
pleaded guilty to a conspiracy count.) Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> is
investigating allegations that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Teamsters PAC</ENAMEX> engaged in a dirty quid pro
quo with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> steered funds to state
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> campaign.
Meanwhile, a federal election monitor is refusing to certify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s victory
because of the investigations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> are stepping up attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>. And now, most
damningly, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are contending that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> instigated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>
strike in order to distract attention from his own troubles.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> does not deserve the mud. In an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> infected
by crime, cowardice, and greed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> has been a beacon of honesty, courage,
and restraint for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>. To appreciate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>, you must understand the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>'s depravity. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From the early '50s</TIMEX> until a federal takeover in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">racketeers</ENAMEX> dominated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> who preceded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> went to jail (including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffa</ENAMEX>), and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> died while under indictment.
The union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czars</ENAMEX> lived fat on union dues: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
Presser squandered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$650,000</NUMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> where he costumed himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> and entered on a litter borne aloft by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> muscled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> were no better: The "barons" padded their payrolls with family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, paid themselves enormous salaries (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $500,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>), took
bribes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweetheart</ENAMEX> contracts, siphoned pension
funds into mob-run operations, and generally screwed their rank and file.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Carey</ENAMEX>
didn't. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> was first elected chief
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">local</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX>, and he has run it cleanly
since then. He took an extremely modest salary--less, famously, than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> took his
local to the pickets against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>, and won huge concessions. When national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> negotiated weak contracts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>
opposed them. When mobsters threatened him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> defied them. Again and again,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> returned him to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> with huge majorities.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> had a small moment of national fame in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'70s</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Teamsters</ENAMEX> depicted him as one of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s only incorruptible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>. But it was a surprise when he upset two
old-guard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX> to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s first fair, open presidential election in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> has continued his upright ways. He has slashed his
own salary by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, sold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s fleet of private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>, and canceled the
conferences at five-star <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>. Backed by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX>, he
stripped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> of their autonomy, placed them in trusteeship, and
purged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> for consorting with mobsters. In just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> have almost banished corruption from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> that
was filthy to its bones. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> re-election over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hoffa</ENAMEX>, an unabashed champion
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX>, may have been the final nail in the coffin of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> has
also fought to restore labor's national credibility: He spearheaded the
campaign to oust longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> chief <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lane Kirkland</ENAMEX> and replace him with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dynamic John Sweeney</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> membership rose for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s history is a bulwark against the recent charges. There's
little doubt that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> broke election laws and no doubt that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffa</ENAMEX>, but that certainly doesn't mean
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carey</ENAMEX> licensed or even knew about campaign hanky-panky. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's spent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> refusing opportunities to corrupt himself: Why would he start now?

            Which brings us to the charge that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike is a
Carey smokescreen. One can debate endlessly about the merits and demerits of
the walkout (and that is exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Oi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Geoghegan</ENAMEX> are doing
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" titled "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>
Strike"), but it's hard to claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> trumped up the strike. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Carey</ENAMEX>
has long objected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>' employment of part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and its widely
disparate pay scales, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concessions</ENAMEX> that the old, corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> leaders
granted, and which are at the heart of the current strike. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> has spent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> rallying the rank and file behind the strike and, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>' protestations to
the contrary, he seems to enjoy overwhelming support from the picketers. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> special credit for picking an opportune moment to strike:
The booming economy means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> is losing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX> a day during the
strike, and the tight labor market will make it difficult for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to
find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement workers</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> is, deservedly, a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hero of New Labor</ENAMEX>, yet a certain pathos clouds his achievements. What exactly
has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> accomplished? He has not been indicted. He has sacked some crooked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. He barely eked out a victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hoffa</ENAMEX>, a mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>. And he
has led a strike whose aims are embarrassingly modest by the standards of old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX>: a piddling raise, a few more full-time jobs, and a small change in the
pension plan. But this is organized labor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, where even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> must
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aim</ENAMEX> low.

         
      
   
