
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humanitarian</ENAMEX>?

acknowledged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> is scum. The media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> has built his global
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">empire</ENAMEX> on schlock and sleaze, used heavy-handed tactics and legal chicanery to
evade laws and taxes, toppled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to expand his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">domain</ENAMEX>, all but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bribed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> with sweetheart book
deals, made mockery of the grand traditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian/British/American</ENAMEX>
journalism. He is perhaps the world's most sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ernst</ENAMEX>
Blofeld of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Age</ENAMEX>. Even his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s name, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>, has an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ominous</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX> ring to it.

            So it's
no wonder that the press--at least that fraction of the press he does not
own--is gloating about his recent troubles. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX> has been an unpleasant month
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>. He abandoned a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> satellite-TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>, provoking a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>
billion lawsuit from his jilted business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and inviting speculation that
he'll be shut out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> market. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> threw out most of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s own lawsuit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> had refused to carry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Channel</ENAMEX> on its cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, prompting a
spectacular squabble between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>.) He horrified the
publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX> by shutting down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Books</ENAMEX>. Even his lone May
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">triumph</ENAMEX>, the planned purchase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Dodgers</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350 million</NUMEX>, has
been dismissed as an expensive folly.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>, as usual, is getting a raw deal. You may not
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>--it's nearly impossible to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>--but you should probably
admire him. He has done more to help the great mass of media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> than
anyone in the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> is the global capitalist par excellence, the very
model of free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> and entrepreneurship. Almost single-handedly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>
has modernized the world's media, forcing competition on stagnant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>,
cracking open monopolies and oligopolies, vanquishing "traditions" that were
often an excuse for laziness, unleashing the creative destruction of capitalism
on an industry that thought itself exempt from it.

            Everywhere
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> has gone, competition, efficiency, and consumer choice (and profit)
have followed. In his launching pad, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> bought weak papers,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outworked</ENAMEX> established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>, and became the market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX>,
he dragged the newspaper industry into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> he
broke the press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. He won the eternal enmity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> lefties,
but he was right: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> were lazy and intransigent. By sloughing
off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of make-work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and ditching absurd union rules (which had
banned computerization, for example), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> made his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> cheaper for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and more profitable for him. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> rarely acknowledge that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX> all over the world--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal saint</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX>--have
crushed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press unions</ENAMEX> to stay afloat.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s British satellite-TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSkyB</ENAMEX>, shattered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>'s near monopoly on programming. British terrestrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> had limited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to only a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s
satellites give them nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX>.

            
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> has greased
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> of capitalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> savaged his tabloids--the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Herald</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> (he no longer
owns the latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>)--as grotesque conservative rags. Which they were. But they
also grabbed market share from big complacent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> and awakened the sleepy
local news trade. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> brought the same fierce energy to the self-satisfied
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> TV industry. He broke up a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> oligopoly by starting a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
network, a feat that no one, least of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, thought possible.
(At the time he bought his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX>,
industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> said he'd paid too much for them. They don't say that
anymore.) While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> has certainly splashed its share of garbage on the screen
(e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Studs</ENAMEX> ), it has also given <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> some of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>'s most
remarkable shows ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Simpsons , The X-Files</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s Most
Wanted ). Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s aborted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> deal would have
benefited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. If it had succeeded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> would have offered the first
serious competition to the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX>--the very choice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
and consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> have been pleading for.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hatred of Murdoch</ENAMEX> is, at its core, aesthetic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s in-your-face
conservatism is alienating. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and TV shows exaggerate and
distort for the sake of sensationalism. They deny the very existence of good
taste and propriety.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> is immune to such criticism. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>. He
was also born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, which makes him, almost by definition,
disrespectful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>. He derides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> and respectable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> as
"unpopular" media subsidized by a condescending, out-of-touch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentry</ENAMEX>.
("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular</ENAMEX>" is the highest praise in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> lexicon.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> may be a
modernist in his pursuit of a global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">techno-empire</ENAMEX>, but he's also an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anachronism</ENAMEX>, a throwback to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
journalism used to be competitive, sensational, overtly political, and
populist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> believes that the snobs have crippled the profession with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">respectability</ENAMEX>, making journalism irrelevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> has done
all he could to restore that scrappiness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> is, in some sense, the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrat</ENAMEX> of all: He prints <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to read and produces TV
shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to watch. His <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> has the
largest circulation of any English-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Populism</ENAMEX> is
popular.

            Sadly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> the robber
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baron</ENAMEX> may not be with us much longer. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66-year-old</TIMEX> is not showing signs of
age, but he is showing signs of respectability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> has always had his
yearning-for-respect side. But as he gets older, it seems to be getting worse
(or, if you prefer, better). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> he bought the money-losing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
Times . Characteristically, he both vulgarized it and turned it around
financially, thus chalking up another business triumph but losing much of the
cachet he sought. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, he championed the effort to give presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> free air time on network TV. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> also produces far more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
programming than the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. What a shocking notion: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>
who cares more about his legacy than his bottom line.

         
      
   
