
   
   
      
         
            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>

            Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> scandal
broke, armchair shrinks have been psychologizing round-the-clock about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s libido. His indulgent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is to blame. Or is it his no-goodnik
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stepfather</ENAMEX>? Or his impulsive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>? Or his "anti-social personality disorder"?
Lost in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinternalia</ENAMEX> is an essential question about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">womanizing</ENAMEX>: How does he pick them?

            If
allegations are true, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has slept with (or tried to sleep with) lawyers
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> and groupies, interns and beauty
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">queens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blondes</ENAMEX> and brunettes. What on earth do they all
have in common? 
                  Slate
                has compiled a list of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> most
frequently linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (click for the list and bios) and tried to figure
it out: Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> have a type? Who is his ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>? If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is a "sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX>," as some would have us believe, who is his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite prey</ENAMEX>?

            

               Looks
            

            
               Above all: She's big in
the face. She has big lips; full, fleshy cheeks; and enormous, showy teeth.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, who has chipmunk cheeks and a whopper of a grin, may be his
model here. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
also fit the type. They have huge teeth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>'s-office teeth, the kind of
choppers that can tear flesh from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>. Of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> I've
seen pictures of, only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> has an average-size mouth. (In a recent,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cruel Salon</ENAMEX> column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camille Paglia</ENAMEX> pondered the significance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s big mouths. She called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' features a "walking,
talking advertisement for oral sex." I leave such speculation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>.)

            
               She has big hair. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cliché</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but a true one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Flowers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McDougal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, Dolly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle Browning</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Ward</ENAMEX> all wore big, fluffy manes at the time of
their alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> encounters. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> used to prefer the fright-wig
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdos</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. Lately he's gone for a more sober look.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> have long, but controlled, hair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> has had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> or
more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair incarnations</ENAMEX>, but her locks have always been shorter than those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> likes brunettes plenty (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobbie Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>) but seems to prefer blondes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Perdue</ENAMEX>). He doesn't mind
if the color is from a bottle (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>). Bangs are fine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>), but so are no bangs (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perdue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curly</ENAMEX>, wavy, straight--it
doesn't seem to matter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               She has blue or green
eyes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are uncommon in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton pantheon</ENAMEX>. Though we hate
to say this in a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, she has large breasts . (Evidence:
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s-magazine photo spreads. More on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this later</TIMEX>.)

             

            
               And
she's a beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s been linked to--count 'em--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Arkansas</ENAMEX> title: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1958</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Perdue</ENAMEX>, who has admitted an affair;
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1980</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lencola Sullivan</ENAMEX>, who has denied an affair; and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1982</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> and
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America Elizabeth Ward</ENAMEX>, who has denied an affair. Most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s other
alleged paramours have been lovely, too.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX>
            

            
               She's
in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youth</ENAMEX> may be wasted on the young, but it's not wasted on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20s</NUMEX> at the time of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> encounter; he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade or three older</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> at the time
of his alleged affair with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX>. He was nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is no ageist. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perdue</ENAMEX> is almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> older than he is.
And his longest relationships have been with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is his
age, as is high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweetheart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX>.

            

               Clothes
            

            
               She
wears either revealing clothes or professional clothes (or perhaps both).
The best way to catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s eye seems to be to show skin. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> picked up rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groupie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie Hamzy</ENAMEX> when she was sunbathing in a bikini
by a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> reportedly wore a provocative dress to attract the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s attention, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDougal</ENAMEX> did a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Guaranty</ENAMEX> TV commercial in hot
pants. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> enjoys the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> look, too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is buttoned up.
Willey, allegedly propositioned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, was dressed professionally
(at least till <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "untucked" her blouse). And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, is neat
as a pin in her publicity photos.

            

               Job
            

            

               Ideally, she's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Arkansas</ENAMEX>. Otherwise, she works under him. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> intern. Willey was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susie Whitacre</ENAMEX> worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> was an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelia Lawrence</ENAMEX> on the federal
payroll. Besides beauty queens and underlings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s taste is eclectic.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>,
Hamzy a groupie, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businesswoman</ENAMEX>.

            

               Loyalty
            

            
               She's loyal to him even
when he doesn't deserve it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> has endured philandering for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX> has served time rather than rat on him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> may have lied under
oath for him. (Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> may be loyal because he gave them favors.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> simplified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s job search. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> found federal jobs for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> got to be in charge of health-care
reform.)

            Loyalty
may be his ideal, but he doesn't always get it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX> wrote a novel about
her romance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamzy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perdue</ENAMEX> have blabbed extensively about their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> sold her story to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> and wrote a tell-all memoir.
The tabs paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> for her story. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' suit landed him in the
mess he's in.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shared</ENAMEX>
Interests
            

            No relationship can flourish
without shared interests, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s are no exception. Like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> loves music. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> was a cabaret
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">singer</ENAMEX>. Perdue claims she used to croon "He's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just My Bill</ENAMEX>" to him; he
serenaded her with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Long Tall Sally</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX> sang "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After You've Gone</ENAMEX>" at the Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Pageant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamzy</ENAMEX> is a professional rock groupie. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> dated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie</ENAMEX>
Wonder.

            
               And,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, his ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> may be a shameless exhibitionist. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
reportedly talked dirty to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and sent him an explicit tape. Hamzy, who
claims to have slept with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>, sold her sex story to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX>. (She said, "I may be a slut, but I'm no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perdue</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>) stripped for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>)
did the same for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> .

            .

         
      
   
