
   
   
      
         
            Geraldine Ferraro

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> won't wait for
much, but they apparently will wait for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geraldine Ferraro</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 12</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has been mulling over the idea of
quitting her <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> job to run for office. She's about to make her
decision: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> will announce in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two weeks</TIMEX> whether she's entering
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> senatorial primary--also known as the race to decide
who gets to mud wrestle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonse D'Amato</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godot</ENAMEX> act has
overshadowed the campaigns of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> declared primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Public Advocate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Green</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>
and big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> are biding their time waiting for her announcement. The
fund-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMILY</ENAMEX>'s List, which could steer <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> to its chosen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, has encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to withhold contributions till <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro</ENAMEX> makes
her decision.

            The
latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quinnipiac College</ENAMEX> Poll, a respected independent survey, shows Ferraro
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">massacring Schumer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> in the primary and routing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> points in
the general election. This enthusiasm is a little mystifying. After all, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62-year-old</TIMEX> has served a grand total of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> (all in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>), has not won an election since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, was brutalized
in her last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> campaigns (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>presidential and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> senatorial), and has
been tangled in more ethics scandals than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> except, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>. A little ethnic arithmetic explains some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> excitement.
She's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> beats any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, and he
loses to any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>," says a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> political operative.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro</ENAMEX> owes her popularity to something else: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro Aura</ENAMEX> (try saying that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times quickly). To this day, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> is
defined by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months 13 years ago</TIMEX> when she was the most famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, especially middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, remember her at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Convention</ENAMEX>, remember her white dress, remember her
introduction, which brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down, "My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Ferraro</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale-Ferraro</ENAMEX> campaign degenerated into a wretched, embarrassing spectacle,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ferraro</ENAMEX> proved that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> could be just as good--and just as bad--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>-presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> as any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Ferraro, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> wrote, came to
embody "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella</ENAMEX> myth, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dream and the feminine mystique"
rolled into one. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> stopped seeing her as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. She became an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">icon</ENAMEX>, an unreal, idealized symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s achievement.

            But this
image distorts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX>. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, rather than a symbol, she's
wonderfully engaging--charming, tough, smart, funny, thoughtful. But she is
also very much a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>: self-aggrandizing, ambitious, and acutely
sensitive to political wind shifts. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>, let alone few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
remember her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and with good reason. She was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork-barreler</ENAMEX> and a more-or-less willing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cog</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens Democratic</ENAMEX> machine.
(Her path to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> was cleared by the fact that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>
Ferraro was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX> and a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> had
enough principles to stand on, not enough to get in her way. Despite her
lionization by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro</ENAMEX> was not terribly progressive on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s issues. She was pro-choice, but not emphatically so. She supported the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Equal Rights Amendment</ENAMEX>, but then maneuvered to keep it out of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> platform. Her skills as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> served her own career: When she
arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, she quickly inserted herself under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tip O'Neill</ENAMEX>. His sponsorship was critical to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>-presidential nomination.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> seems to favor retail politics over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideology</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>). She has never attached herself to any particular set
of ideas, never had any consuming passion. It's notable that none of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> I talked to could describe her ideology or name
her pet causes. ("She's sort of moderate, I think," said one.) When I asked
Ferraro about her key issues, her answer was boilerplate: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>," the
struggling economy of upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>'s "horrendous" record.

            Even her
responses to ethics charges reflect her political instincts. Confronted with
allegations about campaign-finance irregularities or with questions about her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s business dealings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> has bobbed and weaved with Clintonian
deftness: Hand out a few documents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hedge</ENAMEX>, cavil, deny, admit with
explanation.

            All of which is to say: Of course she'll run. She's a
natural-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, and she can't stay away from the race. She sounds
thrilled when she considers the prospect. "If you look at the time of my life
that was the happiest, it was the time as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,"
she says. "I am <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> points ahead in the primary. And I am the only one who beats
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> has always wanted to take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pothole</ENAMEX>. She reluctantly
skipped the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> campaign because of ethics problems. Scandal dogged her again
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, when she lost a vicious <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-way primary. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> is her last chance
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>: "It's either do it now, or don't do it at all."

            It's not
likely to be an easy primary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> and is a relentless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">campaigner</ENAMEX>. Green has a loyal following among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who vote in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primaries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro</ENAMEX> says she needs to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.5 million</NUMEX> to win the
primary. It will be a fratricidal, exhausting race.

            
And if she wins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> will be no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushover</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> are filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> in the polls a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>. He always polls low, he has <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> to spend in
the general election, and he solidified his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> with lots of . And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>
will not underestimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro</ENAMEX>, whom he fears most of all his potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. He has already fired a shot across her bow. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, he ran TV
ads--between segments of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> , no less--slamming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro</ENAMEX> as a
pro-tax-and-welfare liberal. The ads mimicked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> 's format: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On</ENAMEX>
the left, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geraldine Ferraro</ENAMEX>. And on our side, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>." An icon
would have ignored the attack, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro</ENAMEX> harpooned right back, calling the ad
a "sign of panic." When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> to drop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossfire</ENAMEX> , complaining that she was using the program to advance her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">candidacy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro</ENAMEX> countered that "[i]t's almost unbecoming to see grown men
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whine</ENAMEX>."

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> are lucky,
this sniping is a preview of a delightful fall campaign: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather-skinned</ENAMEX>,
fast-talking, old-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> whaling the bejesus out of each other. That's the
kind of politics everyone enjoys, not least <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geraldine Ferraro</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
