
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>
the capable hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> wants it back. His <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> Pacers
face the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Conference Finals</ENAMEX> in what could be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s final season. Basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> think that the tough, wily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pacers</ENAMEX> are
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that can dethrone the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-time champion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>, a
thing of beauty and a joy forever as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, is turning out to be a fabulous
coach, too. When lured out of retirement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>--he was "bored to death" of
fishing and golfing--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacers</ENAMEX> had just finished a miserable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39-43</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, had
missed the playoffs, and were led by a core of aging, disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, with a virtually identical roster, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> has coached <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58-24</NUMEX>
record--the best in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s history. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> was
named--deservedly--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> of the Year. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> finished off
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX> to advance to the conference finals.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Legend</ENAMEX>'s emergence as a coaching phenom is
surprising. In part it's so because when he played for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX>, he used to
say he would never coach in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>. It's also surprising because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> the
Coach is not much like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bird the Player</ENAMEX>, at least not in the ways you might
expect.

            At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX> and during his early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> gulled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, opposing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. He played the rube. He had grown up in the small, poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Lick</ENAMEX>, and he dubbed himself the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Lick."
His redneck accent and reinforced the impression that he was a dim good ol'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. So did his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doughy</ENAMEX> face, blond <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feathered hair</ENAMEX>, and beaky nose. (The
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-foot-9-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> looks, appropriately, very much like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bird</ENAMEX>.)

            
But behind that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bumpkin</ENAMEX>'s exterior lurked a man
of endless guile and will. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> may have been slow, but he was an astounding
passer, an elegant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>, a vicious rebounder, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>'s toughest
competitor. He was always busy on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>: If he didn't make the assist, he
made the basket; if he didn't make the basket, he grabbed the rebound; if he
didn't grab the rebound, he made the steal. He was also a relentless
psychological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>. So taciturn in public, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>'s most notorious
trash talker, mocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>' attempts to guard him. (Once, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>
rushed over to stop him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> stared at him, said, "You know you're too late,"
and buried a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> goaded and inspired his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>, and they
heeded him: If he told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammate</ENAMEX> to do something, he did it. Thanks in large
part to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> were a , single-minded and selfless.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> and
Magic are permanently yoked in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> legend. They entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> together, rose
together, retired together. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the greatest achievements of each is that he
destroyed the stereotype about himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>, the black, mouthy, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guard</ENAMEX>, won over basketball fogies with his sound fundamentals and court
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>, the solid white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, won over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> with his
creative shooting and flashy passing.

            So why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>'s coaching career taking off when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>'s
flopped? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>-game stint coaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Lakers</ENAMEX> was a disaster.
He failed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> for the reason that other great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> have failed as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>: He thought about himself too much. He complained his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> didn't
care about the game the way he did. He felt he still belonged on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. But
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> has a cranky back, and he's accomplished everything any
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> could ever dream of. He doesn't want to play anymore, and he
doesn't need to show off.

            As a
result, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> is a very effective, very unobtrusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> who used
to be involved in every play has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> who is hardly involved in any
of them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Player Bird</ENAMEX> was a maximalist; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> is a minimalist. His
predecessor as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Brown</ENAMEX>, hectored and nit-picked in practices
and games. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> is quiet, has short meetings, and never chews out his players
publicly. He doesn't criticize them when they make turnovers or commit fouls,
and he doesn't tell them how to play. He treats them as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, just as
he liked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> to treat him.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>'s coaching philosophy, which he repeats
over and over, is "It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>'s game." He laid down a few commandments: Thou
shalt be well conditioned; thou shalt be ; thou shalt not hot-dog. Then he let
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> do their jobs.

            Pacers
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guard Mark Jackson</ENAMEX> explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>'s hands-off style this way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : "You don't have to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Mullin</ENAMEX> how to come off a pick. You
don't have to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reggie Miller</ENAMEX> what to do when he catches the ball in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>. You don't have to teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rik Smits</ENAMEX> how to make post moves."

            The laissez-faire philosophy has worked wonders on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, they were spooked. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This season</TIMEX>, they sense <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>.
They play confidently, hustle, and never choke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth quarter</TIMEX>. They're
selfless: They have the most balanced scoring of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. It's true that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pacers</ENAMEX> don't play beautiful or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acrobatic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>. They play something
much rarer in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>. The greatest tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>
is that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> now play as he used to.

            With
typical canniness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> chose to coach a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that would listen to him. The
Pacers are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>. The average age in the starting lineup is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>, and the
roster is filled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> workhorses such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mullin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Davis</ENAMEX>.
They have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>, and no prima donnas.

            
Could <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> manage a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>?
It's a full-time job just controlling the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hotheads</ENAMEX> on some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squads</ENAMEX>.
Like many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">old-timers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> deplores the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTVification</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. He
doesn't like its glitz and disapproves of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>' greed. And he has said
he wouldn't want to coach a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> might not want to coach
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, but he surely could. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pacer</ENAMEX> who has made the most improvement under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jalen Rose</ENAMEX>. Rose used to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> case par excellence. When he
entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, he was supposed to be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>, a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-foot-8-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> who could do everything. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX> struggled, pouted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mightily</ENAMEX>, feuded with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>, and generally demoralized himself and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> around him. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>, he has settled in happily as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pacers</ENAMEX> role
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. He's playing a little more, scoring a little more, and cooperating a
lot more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> gave him respect, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX> reciprocated.

            It would
be a fitting reward for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> if his mature, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calvinist</ENAMEX> style did catch on around
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. Maybe, just as he helped revive pro basketball as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '80s</TIMEX>, he can revive the game as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '90s</TIMEX>, saving it for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who never saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry Legend play</ENAMEX>.

            
               If you
missed the sidebar on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>'s clothes, click . This lists the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celtics</ENAMEX> now
coaching in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>. And you can read about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>'s punctuality fetish .
            

         
      
   
