
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>

            You better not try to
stand in my way as I'm walkin' out the door Take this job and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">shove itI</ENAMEX> ain't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workin</ENAMEX>' here no more.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Paycheck</ENAMEX>

            What
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> enjoyed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Fourth of July holiday</TIMEX> more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>? While his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> were out hustling for campaign dollars and marching in sticky-hot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parades</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> was casting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX> on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Corps of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Engineers</ENAMEX> lake just northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>, humming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX> tune.

            At least, that's what we've come to expect, given the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persona Armey</ENAMEX> has cultivated: a plain-speaking, country-music-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who
would (to quote the bumper sticker) "rather be fishing" than putting up with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">BS</ENAMEX>. This "I-ain't-much-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speechifyin</ENAMEX>' " image has
served <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Armey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> in his surprising rise through the ranks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, setting him apart from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and making him
seem personable. But it has cost him respect.

            Is Armey
just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step away from the speakership? Or is he the only thing keeping the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">debilitated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> in power? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caucus</ENAMEX> (such as
they are) find <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armey</ENAMEX> too conservative and outspoken to serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hard-liners</ENAMEX> say he's too ineffective a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>.
Having already paid too high a political price for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s failings,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> don't want another headache leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            
Hence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> are taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> down a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pegs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX>, bicoastal proprietress of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">salon</ENAMEX>, took a break from her endless campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> to attack his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> apparent in one of her recent op-eds. Calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s best
insurance policy," she accused him of duplicity in defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> when
simply everyone knows, dahling, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> needs new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. "It is high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huffington</ENAMEX> wrote, "for some young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> to recognize that there are
moments when appeasement is more destructive than war--and to strike."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> has
been dismissed before--beginning with his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>. A
geeky economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> accent challenging an entrenched
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX> was given no chance of winning. Soon after capturing what
would become a safe seat, he fathered one of the unlikeliest pieces of
legislation to emerge from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>: a bill creating an apolitical process for
closing obsolete military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, he surprised fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> by
challenging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP Conference</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, a party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> and
known conciliator, and took his job from him. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, asked whether he would
run for the minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> post in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX> told
everyone (including an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incredulous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>, in a limousine ride back from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>) that he expected to be the next majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. He may have
been grinning, but he wasn't joking.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX>'s refusal to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> game--to dine
with media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> or golf with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>--makes him an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>. And he pays for
this lack of political refinement, as the political oddsmakers portray him as a
boorish ideologue and rhetorical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bumbler</ENAMEX> prone to such "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Armey Axioms</ENAMEX>" as "You
can't put your finger on a problem when you've got it to the wind."

            Damaging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> further is his contemptuous relationship with the press. He rarely gives
direct answers to unfriendly questions, although he's always good for a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bizarre Dan Rather Texasisms</ENAMEX>. Instead of giving artful non-answers to tough
questions--a prerequisite talent for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX> usually lets fly a
smart-aleck comment that gets him in trouble: Soon after becoming majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, he referred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Fag</ENAMEX>." But after a
shaky <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first few months</TIMEX> in charge, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> settled in as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s relatively
effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief operating officer</ENAMEX>.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>, a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
legislative misplays has increased skepticism about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. Most of the fault lies with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> has been considered
politically dead for so long that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> talk about him as a quaint memory.
But, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huffington</ENAMEX> noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> has not acquitted himself well with his effort
to keep up appearances.

            Still, suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX> were
passed over for the job. Consider the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>:

            Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>,
another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX>'s opposite--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Wright</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rank-and-file</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> fear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> and respect his political abilities, but they don't like
him or trust him as much as they do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Boehner</ENAMEX>, a slick but
likable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ohioan</ENAMEX> who chairs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX>, is as adept at
playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> game as is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>--befriending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, making goo-goo
eyes at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, passing around campaign contributions on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor,
etc. But he's more comfortable behind the scenes; pencil him in as the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising and spending apparatus that helped win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, is enthusiastic and smart but doesn't seem tough enough to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. The classic sidekick (even to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Molinari</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX> is
being talked about as the next majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. Call him Armey's good-cop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>.

            Which leaves us with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX>. Knowing that he's close to
getting the job, he's started to cultivate a more conciliatory image. But a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">softer Dick Armey</ENAMEX> is a tall order, and it's resulted in more verbal gaffes and
more unseemly backpedaling. On a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Dick</ENAMEX>
agonized over the question of human rights in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, but then reached the
conclusion that free trade is a basic human right, and voted as usual for MFN
status.

            What to
expect from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX>? He doesn't waffle. Throughout his political career,
he has focused on free-market economic principles: unrestricted trade, low
taxes, less government regulation. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, another
former economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> has avoided budget hypocrisy by eschewing the
pork barrel--some of the military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> he closed were in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. He took on
farm subsidies. He was pro-flat tax before flat tax was cool. And his advocacy
of the flat tax isn't just some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gingrichian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual dalliance</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gephardtian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> pose, or even a Forbesian attempt to pocket <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few million</NUMEX>
more bucks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            
Holding fast to one's beliefs has never been a
desirable trait in congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Yet it would be unwise to count Armey
out. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalists</ENAMEX> would agree that anybody is better than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, whose image-softening efforts consist of photo ops with furry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Armey</ENAMEX> prefers his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX> flailing at the end of a baited hook. Those
who worry about how the ruffian image will play should Armey become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> can
rest easy: As both angler and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> admirer told me, "He's
catch-and-release."

         
      
   
