
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>

            Back when there was more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> treated little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> as playthings, dolls to dress up and knock down. But these days the
besieged tyrant of an ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> look mousy.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> ignored the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
when it commanded him to halt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
Throwing a bone to the outraged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> repeated his meaningless
promise to consider negotiating with moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, he courted
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s support for his escapades, raising the specter of a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>-style
standoff.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has played the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for a patsy. His pattern: He
behaves in his most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hitlerian</ENAMEX> way, then promises to improve and weasels away
unscathed. By some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> accounts, he even emerges as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. He is
applauded for helping to cobble together the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dayton Peace Accords</ENAMEX> that ended
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bosnian War</ENAMEX>. In his memoir To End a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador nominee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> intelligent and downright affable. Newspaper
profiles add the requisite charming details: Sure, he murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, but he loves cigarillos and insists that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> join him for fancy meals and drinking bouts.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butcher</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> is his chilly
pragmatism. He has a sensitive political ear: If he needs to compromise, he
compromises. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1996</TIMEX>, for example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> took to the
street calling for his resignation. Instead of rolling out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
caved in to all their demands--short of handing them his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. Soon after
his concessions, the movement splintered. Later, he retracted most of his
concessions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machiavelli</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotsky</ENAMEX> could not have scripted it better. (For a
quick backgrounder on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s cynical orchestration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bosnian War</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">click</ENAMEX> .)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
applies this same savvy to his diplomatic dealings. Unbelievably, he has
convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Foggy Bottom</ENAMEX> that he's indispensable to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> peace and
stability. The reason: The alternatives to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> are considered even more
monstrous. This is a perception that he created himself. Quietly, he bolsters
his most radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, giving them air time to grandstand on state-run
television. He carefully calculated the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vojislav Seselj</ENAMEX>, who calls for
the ethnic cleansing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> and has written tomes paying homage to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">militarism</ENAMEX> and fascism. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s genocidal record, he does appear to
be tame in comparison--the housebroken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>.

            
How did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> come by this cold pragmatism?
He is a product of the hellish post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>, a place where
betrayal was a much better career strategy than principle. His rise to power is
a tale of back-stabbing and machinations. An ambitious law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
hitched his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> to the rapidly advancing career of his older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolmate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stambolic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> served as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stambolic</ENAMEX>'s right-hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> as the latter rose to
top positions in the state energy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>, the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> seemed destined to die a hatchet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            Then, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, he got lucky. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stambolic</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> as his proxy to a party meeting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> were grouching about their oppression by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
majority. It was a standard apparatchik affair, ending with a predictable
affirmation of the old Titoist line that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> must crush nascent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
nationalism. But departing from the meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> encountered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> who were being restrained by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and filmed by live television
cameras. As the camera turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, he hesitated, bumbled, and then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">yelled</ENAMEX>, "Nobody has the right to beat these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>!" His remarks electrified
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, which spontaneously broke into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> national anthem. The
incident made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> an overnight symbol of rising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX> sentiment,
and he milked his accidental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> to the fullest. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Months</TIMEX> after his
pronouncement, he ousted and replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stambolic</ENAMEX> as head of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party, accusing him of not being supportive enough of downtrodden <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has carried the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX> mindset into the
post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> era. He refuses to allow the liberalization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> economy,
letting corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX> run state monopolies and pillage the state coffers.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly every year</TIMEX> he reorganizes his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>, deposing old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and allowing
no one to accumulate significant power.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>
doesn't care about the trappings of power. He doesn't put his name on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>
or collect seaside villas or bed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Although he has a gift for oratory, he
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recluse</ENAMEX> who hates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>. Quite simply, he has an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apparatchik</ENAMEX>'s attitude:
He will hang onto power at all costs. He has a paranoid fear (well, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paranoid</ENAMEX>, because it's true) that if he doesn't ruthlessly boost himself, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> will do him in.

            
There's something darker at work as well.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was born in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montenegrin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteachers</ENAMEX>. Both
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> committed suicide. Those who regularly deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> say he
suffers from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than</NUMEX> a touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> himself. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> march
against him, he grows despondent and doesn't leave his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. It is
said that he hasn't a lick of genuine humor and rarely displays empathy. Unlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, whose inner circle adored him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> humiliates his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and keeps
no confidants.

            In the
pursuit of power, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has run <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> into the ground. The war he
instigated provoked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> sanctions that wrecked the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> economy. Although
many of the sanctions have been lifted, inflation remains sky high.
Unemployment hovers near <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s manufacturing output has
been reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> during his tenure. His popularity is said to be at an
all-time low.

            To prevent any of his discontented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> from revolting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> has reverted to the nastiest of his old apparatchik instincts. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, he has temporarily closed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and
television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> because they griped too loudly about him. He has also
expanded the secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, which now totals <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 80,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. One
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> is said to be specially trained to quash riots. Another
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> is said to be devoted to preventing army coups.

            The current tumult in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
completes a circle for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>. He launched his career there and it seems
fitting that he return. His <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> seem to be doing their best to
provoke war. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to cross the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> border. If war does erupt, it may not be contained as it was in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> could be drawn into
the conflict. How much of the world would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> sacrifice for the sake of
his power? As much as it takes.

            
               If you
missed the sidebar on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bosnian war</ENAMEX>, click .
            

         
      
   
