
   
   
      
         
            A Brief History of Taxes

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>, it has been
an article of faith, at least within one potent sector of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>,
that tax cuts are ipso facto good (and tax hikes are ipso facto
bad) for the economy, for the financial markets and thus, for all of us. For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>, as well, taxes have gone up and down, and so have the economy and
the financial markets. So how do theory and reality compare?

            Other things being equal, a
tax cut, by stimulating consumption and investment, can help the economy. But
many things besides taxes affect the level of economic activity. And then
there's the little problem of paying for the nice tax cut. As long as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
is unwilling to offset revenue losses with real spending cuts (not the vague
promises of future rectitude that have been the mainstay of every "historic
balanced budget" package since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>), a cut in taxes means a bigger federal
budget deficit. And that, in turn, can drain investment capital, alarm an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inflation-wary Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX>, raise interest rates, and unnerve
financial markets.

            So, are tax cuts good for
the economy and tax hikes bad? Take a look at the record, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> tax cut through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> tax hike, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for
yourself.

            Of
course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has since repented his tax-boosting ways. Only last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, he signed off on another big tax cut. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh-oh</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
