
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>--and
who's not one--have been saying for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, is like a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>--squalid, dangerous, and corrupt. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> has never
seemed more like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mini-Suharto</ENAMEX>, has dragged it into an embarrassing, protracted drama: It is in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rack</ENAMEX> and ruin, he had overstayed his welcome, everyone wanted him to leave, and
he wasn't sure he wanted to oblige.

            From the
beginning of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> toyed with his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> about whether
to seek re-election to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term this fall</TIMEX>. Largely ignored during his
current term, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> was at the center of attention again. His <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hamlet act</ENAMEX> had
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> on edge, and he loved it. His press conferences were packed. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> launched a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Barry Watch"</ENAMEX> column. National media
were calling. His every hint--and he dropped lots of them--was parsed for
significance. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each week</TIMEX> was supposed to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> he announced his decision
but, having the time of his life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> kept putting it off.

            Now, with his usual excruciating/exquisite sense of timing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> has followed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s retirement announcement with
his own. The inevitable comparisons to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> probably
picked the right moment to bow out: He's on top again--briefly. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> poll found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary, attracting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, nearly twice as many as
his closest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>.

            For those
who still can't believe the ex-crackhead was re-elected once, this survey was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unfathomable</ENAMEX>. How could he be ahead? (I won't begin to justify all the bad
reasons for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>'s popularity--race resentment, patronage, etc.--but will try
to explain one good one .) Even for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtonians</ENAMEX> who had forgiven <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry</ENAMEX> his
crimes, the prospect of another campaign appalled. The post-comeback <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry</ENAMEX>
hasn't much changed his ways: He still favors racial rhetoric and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>-bashing. (And he may not have shaken his worst old habits<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: The Last</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Emperors: The Hollow Comeback</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX> in a New Age of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Leaders</ENAMEX> , a new biography by longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonetta Rose</ENAMEX>
Barras, alleges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> may have bought <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> during his current term. It also
alleges he made sexual advances toward male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> has called the book
"garbage.") The same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> poll that found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> would win the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary also found that the vast majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtonians</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX>--preferred he not run.

            
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> is a political creature: Why would he
skip a race he thought he could win? The answer is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. There is no good professional reason for him to
hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. He's scarcely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of anything. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> returned to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> power structure has devoted itself to
emasculating him. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> of his inauguration, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>-loathing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> installed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Board</ENAMEX> to oversee the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s shaky
finances. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Board</ENAMEX> soon stripped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of authority
to issue contracts or manage budgets. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, they usurped his control of
the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>, removing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> of public safety, welfare, health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, public works, and basically everything else that matters from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supervision</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> was left with the dregs: recreation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
of Aging. (The transfer of power has been good news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, which has
erased a huge deficit and begun to stem the exodus of middle-class
residents.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> does still get to
revel in the trappings of mayorhood. He continues to flounce around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> he once was. He has a limo at his beck and call. His personal
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> included an incredible <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> forced
him to halve it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of flunkies and yes-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> surrounds him.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> still issues self-aggrandizing statements in which he takes credit for
things he didn't do and announces "initiatives" that will never be initiated.
And he still takes grand foreign tours on which he behaves as if he is visiting
royalty. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>.)

            "Losing
the actual power bothers him, but I don't think it's as big a deal as the aura
of power," says a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. "It's not just the limo, because anyone can
have a limo. He is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> . He really enjoys being <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man</ENAMEX>."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry</ENAMEX> recognized that the trappings of power were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tenuous</ENAMEX>, too. If he had been re-elected, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would have probably punished
him by cutting his salary; eliminating the security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> who remain; and
stripping him of the few, pathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> he does control.

            Not having
lost his sharpness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> understood the emptiness of his position. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">re-elected</ENAMEX>, he would be a nonentity, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX> cannot stand to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nonentity</ENAMEX>. So why not hand the job off? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will be more likely to return
home rule and rearm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> is gone. Besides, he has nothing left to
prove. He already has made the greatest political comeback in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history. The
Post poll predicting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> primary win allows him to quit with a bang,
not a whimper: "He can go out saying, 'See, they still love me. I told you I
would win. Bye ,y'all,' " says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barras</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and local business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have
been trying for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to find a way to let him exit with honor--to give him a
gracious payoff in exchange for his decision to step down. It's a good idea.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> has been a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX>--of a sort--and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> traditionally finds
respectable retirements for its former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Pols spend their dotage as
think tank "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>" or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> or part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> (see: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>) and
are trotted out periodically for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX> commentary. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> doesn't quite
deserve the same, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> deserves not to have its ex-mayor disgraced.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>'s retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has talked to local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and historically black
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> about a position for him. He is also planning lecture tours and
shopping a memoir.

            And there
is even talk that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> will be hired as a top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> by a local business.
Given his track record as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, you might want to sell your
stock in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            
               If you
missed the sidebar about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good reason to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>, click .
            

         
      
   
