
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shooting Pool With Joe Camel</ENAMEX>

            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Camel</ENAMEX>, the
cartoon tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mascot</ENAMEX>, is currently facing charges by the feds that he has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knowingly</ENAMEX> and with profit aforethought enticed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to smoke cigarettes. He
is not accused of hooking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the manner of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground pusher</ENAMEX>,
however--he's never directly addressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or been seen in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
Rather, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camel</ENAMEX>, himself a habitual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> of nicotine, has been accused of
being way too cool, in much the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph K.</ENAMEX> was once accused by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> of being way too guilty. The very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
has put the case in these terms--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX>, declares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>
that "smoking is cool."

            Now, this
is a charge of considerable interest. For it to stick, "cool" must be perceived
to be good, or else associating it with smoking wouldn't be so dangerous that
the ads have to be banned. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX> must make smoking seem cool because of
the life he leads, as suggested in the ads that feature him. So what does he do
in these ads? Among other things, he plays in a blues <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, shoots pool with
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy camels</ENAMEX>, rides a big hoggish <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> (without a helmet), drives a
flashy convertible (without fastening his seat belt), and otherwise does a
whole lot of hanging out in graphically interesting settings. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camel</ENAMEX> is
never seen doing any productive work of any kind, is never portrayed wearing
bourgeois clothing of even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Casual</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">variety</TIMEX> (he usually wears a
leather jacket), and is never seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camels</ENAMEX> who
have to work for a living.

            In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX> is not respectable. He is--to use the
language of cultural authoritarians--an unproductive social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parasite</ENAMEX> who lives
for his own pleasure. He stays up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> in unwholesome places, indulges in
risky behavior that threatens to make decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camels</ENAMEX>' insurance premiums go up,
and surely hasn't phoned his aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. And that isn't the worst of
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> is also a sexually charged throwback with predatory sensibilities,
notorious for his lack of sensitivity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>. It is obvious that he would
be unwilling to negotiate the stages of a sexual encounter as an equal. Even
his face has a phallic quality. Indeed, given the ubiquitous social messages of
what now constitutes enlightened masculinity (a nurturing, sensitive,
cholesterol-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, etc.), it would be interesting to know why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camel</ENAMEX> is not perceived by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> as a criminal rather than, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade</ENAMEX>
Commission's would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">censors</ENAMEX> insist is the case, as a model.

            But,
advertising being in large measure fantasy anyway, let's you and I make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
over. Let's say we subject him to behavior modification of the Clockwork
Orange sort, putting him through some Pavlovian ordeal that takes the devil
out of him. (Or is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> we're taking out of him? Or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brando</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild One</ENAMEX>?
Or Kerouac? Or the dromedary version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailer's</ENAMEX> beat-era <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Negro</ENAMEX>?) Let's
give <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Joe</ENAMEX> a job, a sense of responsibility, a life of achievement, and a
capacity for being a loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and a sacrificing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. And, oh yeah,
let's put a smoke in his mouth.

            
You don't think a pitch like this will sell
cigarettes? Think again. It sells more cigarettes than a lowlife like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX>
does (including to juveniles). An association with respectability has been the
central image of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and tobacco advertising for much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. From
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dewar's Profiles</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller Time</ENAMEX>, a drink or a smoke has more often than not
been portrayed as a reward for hard work, an indulgence that the achieving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bourgeoisie</ENAMEX> earns the right to allow itself.

            For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> and maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> in cigarette ads have been
lighting up at picnics, on hiking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX>, or on horseback. Yet the first
commercial smoker to get hauled into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to have stepped
into a pool <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>, to have shrugged off respectability. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX> is not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consciously</ENAMEX> playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prude</ENAMEX> here, there is a logic to cultural control to
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> probably doesn't appeal to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>," but it may well appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> by exploiting their sexual
and social insecurities. The campaign allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> to appropriate some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inexpensive American Cool</ENAMEX>, an emotional style that developed in the wake of
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> along with mass cigarette smoking. In fact, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nine years</TIMEX> that
the campaign has been running, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camel</ENAMEX>'s share of the underage smoking market has
gone up.

            But the
majority of underage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> don't smoke <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camels</ENAMEX>--they reportedly smoke
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlboros</ENAMEX>. And if the only issue involved in attempting to ban a
cigarette-advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> were its effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, then the obvious culprit
to focus on would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlboro</ENAMEX> cowboy. But he's not sitting in court; he's
out riding the range, perhaps roping in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when they really are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
(Perhaps not: What any ads have to do with the decision to start smoking is not
known.)

            
Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX> is a "cartoon" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> and,
to a certain set of mind, ipso facto directed at little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. In fact,
the campaign's graphic style, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, and situations are directed at an
older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, whereas the appeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> to little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is too well known
to argue about.

            You
couldn't invent a more striking contrast of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> than exists between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camel</ENAMEX>'s downtown urban punk and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlboro</ENAMEX>'s mythically respectable horseman.
This long-running campaign (which has helped the brand become the world's most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX>) portrays a disciplined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of experience who seems to embody a cowboy
code of honor, a traditional regard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and the offer of a
self-sacrificing friendship with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> who can meet his standards of what
it is to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. (Want his respect? Buy a pack.) Perhaps he's next on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX>'s hit list. That he'd be in line behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX> is a lesson in cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptability</ENAMEX>.

            Anyway, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX> hasn't much in common with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlboro</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne West</ENAMEX>, he has plenty in common with a literary creation who is
becoming more relevant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. That figure is the protagonist of the
once-famous play, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Bedbug</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Mayakovsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s great
futurist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bolshevik</ENAMEX> propagandist. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>, disillusioned by the
revolution, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayakovsky</ENAMEX> wrote a protest play about the growing repressiveness of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. He imagined himself frozen through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> of authoritarianism,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">awakening</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> into a risk-free world where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of his temperament were
no longer allowed to exist.

            What he
emphasized about himself were his bad habits: his desire to carouse <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>
away, to run around with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, to sing loudly and drunkenly, and to smoke his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> off. The sum of these unholy things, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayakovsky</ENAMEX> suggests, is the feeding
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, the making of his poetry. "Why did we shed our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>," he asks an
uncomprehending scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX>, "if I can't dance to my heart's
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">content?</ENAMEX>"

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayakovsky</ENAMEX> is stuck in a kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zoo</ENAMEX>, where curious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come to watch him do unhealthy things. "Look," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, "it's now going to have what they called 'a smoke.' " Comes
a voice from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>: "Oh! How horrible!" And another cry, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>!
Remove the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>!"

            It would be culturally
blasphemous to draw too close a parallel between an advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camel</ENAMEX> and a tragic figure like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayakovsky</ENAMEX>, who shot himself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> after he
wrote his drama about the interplay of freedom, pleasure, and risk. On the
other hand, the horrified cries of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayakovsky</ENAMEX>'s authoritarians will be ringing
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Camel</ENAMEX>'s ears as he roars out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for the last time on his big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motorcycle</ENAMEX>. Because he still won't be wearing a helmet.

             

         
      
   
