
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker Snooker</ENAMEX>

            
               The 
               God of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small</ENAMEX>
Things has been good to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arundhati Roy</ENAMEX>. The past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> has brought many blessings: the fairy-tale arrival at her door of the
eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> with the fat check (a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6-million</NUMEX> advance--unheard of for a
debut novel); landmark sales (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600,000</NUMEX> copies in hardcover); multiple
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">translations</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> languages); much feting and fanfare (global book tours,
interviews, pride of place in "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">specials in Granta and The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ); and finally, the announcement, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Tuesday</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> had won the
, which is awarded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX> and
brings with it a cash prize of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $30,000</NUMEX>.

            Though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>'s victory seems to validate the ubiquitous comparisons to the ubiquitous ,
there is cause for pause. Sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The God of Small Things</ENAMEX> is a cozy read.
But so are many of those books that go straight to the remainder pile. So why
did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX> win the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker</ENAMEX>? Why all the hype?

            The answer is simple: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> was ripe for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX> for it. Her book hit an English-speaking market that craves all things
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tandoori food</ENAMEX>, yoga, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deepak Chopra</ENAMEX>, the altie-hip-hop of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornershop</ENAMEX>,
chai , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homi Bhabha</ENAMEX>. And while it would be ridiculous to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
incubated this book for the better part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> and then released it to
capitalize on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> chic just as it crested, it is also true that she has
played to that market in terms it understands and swallows whole.

            Nothing
wrong with that--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> is strenuous in her denials. She claims that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) she
doesn't want "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownie</ENAMEX> points because I'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>" and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) her book "doesn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> on the currency of cultural specificity." But of course <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) she does and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) it does. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>'s book--a humid tale of a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> whose divorced mother
has an affair with an untouchable--is the sum of its othernesses. The
family at the center of the novel belongs to a small, insular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> whose
inner workings are foreign even to most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>. Their family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ayemenem</ENAMEX>,
is located in the comparatively remote southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerala</ENAMEX>, a region that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX> who might know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rushdie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naipaul</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX> from reading
their fiction might not recognize. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>'s descriptions, therefore, can be safely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lush</ENAMEX>, richly runny: "The river shrinks and black crows gorge on bright mangoes
in still, dustgreen <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. Red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas ripen</ENAMEX>. Jackfruits burst. Dissolute
bluebottles hum ... and die, fatly baffled in the sun."

            
No one cares that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>'s prose is a
breath-defying crush of run-together words and run-on sentences; strategically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> capitalization and italicization; numbered lists; reversed words;
adjectival clusters; acronyms; quotations from songs and poems; repeated
images; and abrupt endings. The sensory overload--the weight and range of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">devices</ENAMEX>, some more clunky than clever--fragments the narrative more than it
enhances it, forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to keep pace. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a sample.)

            But
nowhere is the self-indulgent circling as pointed--or annoying--as in the image
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rahel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>-woman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> who is a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ringer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>: "jeans and
white T-shirt ... wild hair tied back to look straight, though it wasn't ...
tiny diamond in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> nostril ... absurdly beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">collarbones</ENAMEX> and a nice
athletic run." It is this image of the exotic-familiar, the combination of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diamond</ENAMEX> stud and bluejeans, that has made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> go light on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>. She's
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babe</ENAMEX> who led that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Religions</ENAMEX> seminar you took: different
enough to charm, similar enough not to intimidate. And the fact that she's
clearly smart and literate makes everyone feel good--and safe--about gushing.
How glossy, therefore, is the praise, how insubstantial the contact, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> reviews I've read. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> gives us a richly pictorial sense of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> routines and habits," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , "and she delineates their emotional lives with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> and
panache, revealing the fatal confluence of jealousy, cruelty and naivete that
shapes their destinies forever." No mention of the flabby plot with its
contrived deaths, no taking to task for the overworked prose--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayemenem</ENAMEX> is just
too far away.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> rode the wave here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Book clubs
met and raved, and timorous, tingling questions ("How deep did you have to
reach to release those wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>?") were asked during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tours</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> invited magnificent pronouncements from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>, a sense, somehow, that
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> felt things more deeply, more creatively, more spiritually. And she
responded. Asked about her language, she said it is "the skin on my thoughts,"
traceable only to private rhythms. So deeply felt, so minutely realized were
these rhythms, it seems, that she rewrote nary a word of her book (remarkable,
given its length--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">321</NUMEX> pages--and the fact that a word processor is quick to
forgive errors). The narrative <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> was "crafted and designed ...
obsessively for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four-and-</NUMEX>a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>." The story, too, was mine, mine ,
so what if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX>'s latest was also set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kerala</ENAMEX>: "I grew up in that village
in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s pickle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX> didn't invent that."

            Some of
her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> would agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX> indeed have little in
common. Only in the "fantasies of publicists," moaned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , can
such comparisons be made. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brits</ENAMEX> feel they know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and several members
of the press, at least, appear unimpressed. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arundhati Roy</ENAMEX>'s victory left me
close to despair," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Robson</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> . "If
this is the novel of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, then the novel is dead." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmen Callil</ENAMEX>, who
chaired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s prize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The God</ENAMEX> "execrable" and said
it shouldn't have made the list.

            
Does the skepticism mean that The God
got a more thorough going-over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>? Not really. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> think of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Protectors of the Literary Flame</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker</ENAMEX>
politics are no less clubby and sordid than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> politics. Prize and process
are widely reviled by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. By giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> the prize, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> has confirmed the darkest suspicions of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: Yes, it's sold
out quality literature for pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">accessibility</ENAMEX>. Also: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>'s recent visit to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> put the spotlight back on the issue of colonial guilt. Her refusal to
apologize publicly for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX> massacre was badly received; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>'s win has been
spun as a compensatory gesture from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonialists</ENAMEX> to the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> herself was predictably
modest about The God 's success--"not the best novel, the luckiest," she
said. The win brought tears to her eyes, of course, and prompted a phone call
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. The God of Small Things is dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Roy</ENAMEX>, who,
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, married outside her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> before returning divorced
and in disgrace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> were estranged for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, if the
stories circulating here are to be believed. Kicked out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> when she
was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only 16</NUMEX> (she was called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Suzie</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> and then
to architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, supporting herself by selling empty milk bottles (some
say beer bottles). She bummed around the beaches of western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> (some say a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>) before settling down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>'s comfy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press Enclave</ENAMEX>,
where all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsies</ENAMEX> live (one review claims a "cottage ... deep in the jungle
in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>"). The stuff of a novel, but don't expect the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>
to write it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker</ENAMEX>, and all the laurels, are "about my past, not my
future," says this ace of the apothegm. "I will only write another novel if I
have another novel to write. I don't believe in professions."

            At a book reading in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> told her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that she'd allowed The God to be
published on the condition that it never be optioned. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX> had finished recording an audio
version of the novel, using the voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Quick</ENAMEX>, who,
though she had been chosen because her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> accent would not "distract"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>, was "directed to imitate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> accents for some dialogue." Earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX> confessed that she'd stuffed some "movie-related" faxes into
books, saving them for a calmer time ... perhaps for when she repairs to that
quiet cottage in the central <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian</ENAMEX> jungle.

         
      
   
