
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Coz</ENAMEX>

            Once upon a time--before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>, that is--supermarket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> were journalism's shame. Respectable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers sneered</ENAMEX> at the tabs for their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of lumpen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>; their
fabricated or (worse) purchased stories; and their raffish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, who
behaved more like blackmailers than like scions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth Estate</ENAMEX>.

            But now
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Coz</ENAMEX>, has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> degree
( cum laude , no less!) and mainstream cachet. In an age when
celebrity-worship is religion and populism is the dominant political ideology,
the tabs are pariahs no longer. Since taking over as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coz</ENAMEX> has become the tab industry's first star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> as
well as its first respected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> named him one of
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">25 Most Influential People</ENAMEX>" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> profiled him
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">admiringly</ENAMEX> soon after. And until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coz</ENAMEX> was considered the
leading candidate for the editorship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> , one of
the most venerated of daily mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> has flourished since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
Winchell, and the tabs have been thriving since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>--but it's only
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have taken the supermarket rags
seriously. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coz</ENAMEX> deserves as much credit (or blame) for this as anyone. Before
becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX> directed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's massive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> coverage. (At
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> case made the cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 weeks</TIMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> far outclassed other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. Thanks to lots
of spadework and liberal payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> tracked down the
famous pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruno Magli</ENAMEX> shoes, the harrowing diary of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Brown Simpson</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who sold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> a knife right before the
murder. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ran a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>-word paean to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's "feminist" coverage, and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">credited Coz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with breaking open the story.

            The paper
has been equally enterprising during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX>'s tenure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. In the midst of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> presidential campaign, it revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> had had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>.
After the murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ennis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> posted a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> reward, opened a phone tip line, and fielded the call that led to a
suspect's arrest. It has covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX> murder doggedly, too.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX> vogue owes as much to his public
posturing as it does to his investigative reporting. Coz casts himself as the
conscience of tabloid journalism (if that's not an oxymoron). When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer 's</ENAMEX> , hired an airline stewardess to seduce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX> on hidden camera, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coz</ENAMEX> was shocked, shocked . He penned an
op-ed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> condemning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> for making news
rather than covering it. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coz</ENAMEX> made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>-TV
rounds to denounce the paparazzi ("stalkarazzi") and tout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's refusal to buy crash-scene photos: "We call on the rest of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> to join our ban on the photos." If he gets any more high-minded, he's
going to bang his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on the ceiling.

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">righteousness</ENAMEX> lies at the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX>'s business strategy: to make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Enquirer</ENAMEX> respectable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX> is trying to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> is more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> than it is like other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , he says, abjures paparazzi photos, inflammatory and
misleading headlines, and fabricated stories. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX> is more likely to appear on a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talk-show round table than on a tabloid TV show. He also gets a lot of
mileage out of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> degree and his preppy good looks, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> commodities
that old-school tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> lacked. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> shtick is largely that:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX> has spent his entire working life at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> .)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX>'s grandstanding does reek of hypocrisy. He denounced
the stalking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's own cover story at the time of
her death was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Di Goes Sex Mad</ENAMEX>," complete with snapshots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and Dodi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coz</ENAMEX> criticizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX> trap yet defends the similar way the
Star , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, treated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>. The
Star paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Rowlands</ENAMEX> to lure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> to a place where a hidden
camera could film them. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX>'s distinction: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> was carrying on with
Rowlands before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> took pictures, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzen Johnson</ENAMEX> didn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">approach Gifford</ENAMEX> until after she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> contract.)

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> also pays for stories and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>--an absolute no-no in
mainstream journalism--and relies on gossip that would never make it past a
regular newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz's Enquirer</ENAMEX> still depends on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sucker</ENAMEX>-punch journalism. It is far crueler than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ever would be.
Celebrities scoff at the claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> is kinder and gentler.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz's Enquirer</ENAMEX> has been sued frequently for defamation and invasion of
privacy. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>'s death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coz</ENAMEX> personally for encouraging
celebrity-stalking. And, according to gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Smith</ENAMEX>, three
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstars</ENAMEX> have hired private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> to gather dirt on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>.

            
The misfortune of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX>'s career may be that he
is gunning for journalistic respectability at a time when journalistic
respectability doesn't pay. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are starving for tabloid-style news, and
everyone wants to feed them. Tabloid TV shows such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Current Affair</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Copy</ENAMEX> have stolen tab <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' market share. So have reputable TV
shows and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, which now cover celebrity news with as much vigor as the
tabs. The best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX> story ran in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> worship stars, fad diets, and medical
miracles almost as avidly as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> does. These mainstream media
are eating the tabs' lunch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> circulation has fallen
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 million</NUMEX> copies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.7 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coz</ENAMEX> believes he'll reverse
this decline by taking (or at least talking about) the high <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. Don't count
on it. Consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> : As the respectable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have become sleazy,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> has become sleazier. While Coz preaches decorum, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> has added more sensationalism, more gore, more nasty gossip. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's circulation is stagnant. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's circulation is
rising fast.

         
      
   
