
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mea Culpa</ENAMEX>

            
               A
proposal to lure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> by slashing federal income tax rates
for city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> got its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> big boost in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as many days yesterday</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> in
endorsing it.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1996</TIMEX>

            Forgive me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, for I
have sinned. I confess that I harbor a belief that contradicts much that I have
held dear over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, that leads me to reject well-established economic
theory and practice, that has earned me the understandable scorn of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. I confess: I favor a substantial federal income-tax break for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>.

            So strongly, moreover, do I
cling to this heretical belief, that when one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> suggested I
write a column attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX>'s tax remission on well-accepted economic
grounds, I objected (devotion to a free and fair airing of contrary opinions be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">damned</ENAMEX>). Such narrow-minded accountancy, I argued, would destroy the fragile
political consensus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> that might actually produce a timely
rescue. (Yes, yes, I stole the central theme of this column from a subordinate.
Another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 days</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Purgatory.</ENAMEX>) And finally, oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Inquisitor</ENAMEX>, it will not have escaped your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>-piercing gaze
that, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>, I stand personally to benefit
should the tax cut be enacted.

            And yet I
do not repent.

            Of course I know most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> believe that local tax
breaks do nothing to stimulate overall economic growth. My files are as full as
any policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wonk</ENAMEX>'s with scholarly studies demonstrating that using tax lures to
attract jobs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> often ends up robbing not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> as
well. Obviously, much of the "growth" generated by such a break is merely
stolen from other jurisdictions--leading them to offer breaks of their own in
an ultimately futile "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX> to the bottom." Less obviously, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> may be a bad deal. Meeting their needs may require, for example, new
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, without the extra tax revenues needed to pay for them.

            Nor does
my heresy blind me to the inefficiency of tax transfers in affecting behavior,
economic or otherwise. I will not deny that it has been shown that as much as
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of a tax "incentive" often goes to pay for activity that would
have taken place anyway. As for the pious hope that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX>
Service will be able to police the new tax breaks--to assure that all claimants
are truly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the district and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital has not
become a flagrant tax haven--well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has a better chance here than in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cayman Islands</ENAMEX>.

            
Surely you know, argue my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could just give as much money directly to the district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as
the area would gain from a federal tax break--at a fraction of the cost to the
rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Well, this is where I start falling off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>. We're
talking, after all, about a city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that--with an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $5 billion</NUMEX> and a shrinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>--runs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that cannot shelter,
much less educate its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; cannot mend its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> or keep its drinking
water potable; cannot police its own police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, let alone its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jails;</ENAMEX> cannot care for the sick, or elderly, or homeless. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that
cannot resist the importuning of any special interest or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, that lacks both
the will and the talent to reform itself. What would make anyone think that
giving more money to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would fix anything?

            The only thing that will
save the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> is more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and more businesses able not only to pay
more taxes, but to take a lively interest in how they are governed. And only
tax benefits, big ones, will persuade them to move into an ill-governed,
crumbling capital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Yes, they will come initially at the expense of other,
especially neighboring, jurisdictions. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> have
long prospered at the expense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commuters</ENAMEX> benefit mightily
from the services provided by the district, yet pay no taxes to support those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The surrounding areas cannot ultimately flourish without a vibrant
core. Moreover, the district, unlike other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and because of its unique
constitutional origins, cannot annex its fleeing middle class. Nor can it claim
the voting representation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s historical tradition,
has been considered the essential trade-off for taxation.

            That is
why there is grumbling, but little organized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> to the tax grant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX>--worth perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700 million</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>--that is gathering bipartisan support in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Still, you may ask, why
should the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East St. Louis</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> provide tax breaks to the
district when they have so many problems of their own? Why should they allow
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> to enjoy a federal tax rate of, say, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>, when
they themselves may face rates close to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>? Because it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
capital, and because it's a good investment.

            No, I do not profess that the tax breaks will pay for
themselves in no time at all. How could I, when I have so often written that
they will not? But the "supply-siders" are quite right when they say that
economies are not a zero-sum game. Is it too large a leap of faith to believe
that the right incentives, ones that capitalize on the comparative advantages
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or locations, can reap positive returns not just for the direct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>, but for the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>?

            Here is a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, one
that ought to make any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> proud. Its well-tended (by the federal
government) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, monuments, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> can compare with
those of any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> it is not, but its downtown
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> have a polyglot vitality they lacked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few decades ago</TIMEX>. Its
neighborhoods are filled with solid housing and well-kept gardens--and not just
in the wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enclaves</ENAMEX>. You can have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in your backyard (as I do) and
still make it to work in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> (if you keep a sharp eye out for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">potholes</ENAMEX>). It would be nice if more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, artisans,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, I'll stack
up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s intellectual capital against any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>'s. A timely
expenditure of tax revenues might just work wonders. And even if the costs were
a dead economic loss to other jurisdictions, surely there are gains in national
pride for recompense.

            I confess that I cannot prove
I am right in my belief. Costly error or painful recriminations lie on either
side of my position. The money might, after all, be wasted on windfalls. On the
other hand, it's also possible that the tax incentives would miraculously repay
the federal coffers many fold. In either case, my knees are ready. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> is
worth a mass, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> .

         
      
   
