
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>

            It's a terrible time to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father Christmas dying</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Santa Clause</ENAMEX> ),
killing ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silent Night, Deadly Night</ENAMEX> ), and being kidnapped ( The
Nightmare Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> ). On television, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most visible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> ads portray him as an old lech (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Secret</ENAMEX>) and a clumsy oaf (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depot</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, who suspect all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>, see a pedophile lurking
under that bushy white beard. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mall Santas</ENAMEX> now must keep their hands visible and
touch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> only in "safe" zones. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> has banned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> from
touching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at all: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tots</ENAMEX> did get to hand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> their wish lists--but
through a mail slot. It doesn't help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Kringle</ENAMEX>'s cause that a 71-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">mall Santa Claus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> recently pleaded guilty to raping and
molesting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of 1 and 7</TIMEX>. The mall <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>'s real name
is--no joke--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald McDonald</ENAMEX>.

            
Animal-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> want to get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>'s reindeer: Pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethical Treatment of Animals</ENAMEX> forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Park Service</ENAMEX> to remove
reindeer from their annual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> pageant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fundamentalist Christians</ENAMEX>
want to get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> himself: He overshadows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and profanes a sacred
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Nick</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, he's been assaulted
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and denounced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, a department
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">store</ENAMEX> recently stumbled into the yuletide spirit by displaying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claus</ENAMEX>--nailed to a crucifix. Why, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall Santas</ENAMEX> can't even say "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ho ho ho</ENAMEX>"
anymore: It frightens <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>, in short, is in trouble. Any day you
can expect to hear that fringe-right conspiracists have implicated him in the
New World Order. "Look, he sees you when you're sleeping. He knows when
you're awake. He knows when you've been bad or good. And he's got a list with
the name of every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the world! Tell me that's not suspicious ." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
needs a makeover.

            It wouldn't be his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> is one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s grandest fabrications. He is, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Nissenbaum</ENAMEX> puts it in his
excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Battle for Christmas</ENAMEX> , an "invented tradition." In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> was a rowdy affair: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s poor and
working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> ran wild through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and invaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> of the
wealthy. So in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 19 th century</TIMEX>, a group of rich <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>
took it upon themselves to domesticate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. Their chief accomplishment:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clement Moore</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Visit</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>," the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1822</TIMEX> poem that introduced
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> (of course you know it: " 'Twas <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> ...").

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> took
an arcane <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> tradition and neatly transformed it into an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> one.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX> was a real saint, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia Minor</ENAMEX>
famed for his generosity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 6</TIMEX>. On that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, he visited <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and left gifts for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by the fireplace. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX> was an ambivalent figure: He was lean and solemn, and he gave bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> birch rods. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> moved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>'s visits to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX>; equipped
him with a beer belly, a sleigh, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight reindeer</TIMEX>; and dropped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinter Klaas</ENAMEX>'
darker side. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s poem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nissenbaum</ENAMEX> writes, was intended to help turn
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to a private <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>, to make it an event that rich
and poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> would celebrate around their fireplaces.

            
And it worked. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> and the domestic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> were embedded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">psyche</ENAMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> myth grew by accretion, adding layer after
layer of sweet detail. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19 th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas Nast</ENAMEX>'s
drawings defined <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> as fat, jolly, bearded, and red-suited. At the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>'s home moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Pole</ENAMEX>. Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claus</ENAMEX> appeared in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>, a copywriter for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery Ward</ENAMEX> added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> to the reindeer
pack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> distributed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4 million</NUMEX> copies of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Red</ENAMEX>-Nosed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reindeer</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, and another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.5 million</NUMEX> when it reissued the story seven
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>, of course, was a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> from the beginning.
Store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> appropriated his picture for ads and posters.)

            
Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX> and for most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> was
both beloved and respected. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> repelled every effort to knock him off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pantheon</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX>, for example, a girl named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia O'Hanlon</ENAMEX> wrote a letter
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Sun</ENAMEX> : Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> had told her that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> didn't
exist. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> replied with one of the most famous editorials in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, your little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are wrong. They have been
affected by the skepticism of a skeptical age. ... Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, there is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>. He exists as certainly as love and generosity and devotion exist."
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> marks the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centennial</TIMEX> of "Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>," and the editorial has been
much reprinted.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '20s and '30s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> even issued court rulings
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">affirming Santa Claus</ENAMEX>' existence.

            But we have been affected by the skepticism of a skeptical
age. Or perhaps it's the irony of an ironical age. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> hasn't disappeared,
but he's been made ridiculous. The assault by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, and
paranoid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> has taken its toll. His public image has degraded. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
is unappetizing, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall pedophile</ENAMEX> or a fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">buffoon</ENAMEX>.

            There should and can be
another kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. In an age that valorizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
capitalism, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> should be recognized as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of both. He has been
married to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">98 years</TIMEX>. He operates a fabulously successful toy
factory. It has a package delivery system that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Express</ENAMEX> look like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pony Express</ENAMEX>. Long before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Americans with Disabilities Act</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
staffed his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> with undersized elves.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> is a role model for our
ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the perfect benevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round,
then gives away everything he made. This should be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> for our time: a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soros</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Pole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
