
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Eszterhas</ENAMEX>

            No profession embraces the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brash</ENAMEX> and talentless more warmly than the movie industry, and no one is better
evidence of this than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Eszterhas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most famous--or
rather, notorious--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>. His career is dedicated to the principle that
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> has something to say. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, the eminence greasy of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>.

            Most film
types get the chance to create <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> disastrous flop in a lifetime. After
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to his credit. Eszterhas, you may remember, is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genius behind Showgirls</ENAMEX> . The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> lap-dancing epic is arguably the worst
movie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> and inarguably the worst- written movie of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>' dialogue, delivered by bimbos painted and injected to a
fare-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thee</NUMEX>-well, is an (unintentionally) hilarious parody of porn.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>' latest movie, a much-anticipated, much-hyped
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> satire called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Alan Smithee Film: Burn Hollywood Burn</ENAMEX> ,
opened--and closed--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. The film's conceit (always a good word to use
around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>) is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> steals his own terrible movie to prevent
its release. If only the same fate had befallen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Burn Hollywood Burn</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have called it "bilious," "ham-handed," "a hapless display ... of
groundless vanity," a "wretched fiasco." Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Idle</ENAMEX>, the movie's
star , dismissed the film as "not funny." Burn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> Burn cost
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> and grossed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately</TIMEX> ... nothing.

            Apart from his two
megafailures, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> has devoted his career to the artful composition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smut</ENAMEX> and violence. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> has been churning out more or
less identical genre pictures: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jagged Edge</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Betrayed</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Instinct</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sliver</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), Jade
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>) . Basic plot: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hero/heroine</ENAMEX> falls for weirdo. Many sweaty breasts
and bloody <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weirdo</ENAMEX> turns out to be--surprise!--a raving,
homicidal nut job. Eszterhas not only recycles plot, he recycles dialogue. He
even recycles his sex obsessions: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sliver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Instinct</ENAMEX> both
devote inordinate amounts of attention to the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> is not
wearing any underwear. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>' sex fixation is legendary and comical: His
original draft of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Night Stand</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>] opened with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>-page
description of a marathon sex session.)

            Eszterhas
is not a hit-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, at least not anymore. Several of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> movies, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flashdance</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jagged Edge</ENAMEX> , were <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moneymakers</ENAMEX>. But his last
real success was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Instinct</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Since then he's written
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> flops in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> isn't deterred: He's now being paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 million</NUMEX>
to script a movie about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobsters</ENAMEX>.

            
This raises a question: Why? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> is
probably not the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jagged Edge</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Basic Instinct</ENAMEX> are quite fun. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> is an object lesson in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perils of the Brand Name Economy</ENAMEX>. By tradition, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> are
anonymous. They're supposed to be heard but not seen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stars</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX>, cinematographers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>--settle for a credit
line and a chubby paycheck. There have been only a handful of famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screenwriters</ENAMEX>, all of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of magnificent movies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> essentially
invented the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity screenwriter</ENAMEX>. "He's a run of the mill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> who
created a myth that he was an idiosyncratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>.

            Eszterhas
has always been a masterful self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hungarian World War II</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, he started his career as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Plain</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dealer</ENAMEX> . He won fame by obtaining photographs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Lai</ENAMEX> massacre, then
caught the eye of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> with his bold crime stories. The
magazine was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its days</TIMEX> of high gonzo, but even by that standard, Eszterhas
stood out. At editorial meetings he would brandish a knife.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beckoned</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movie
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F.I.S.T.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>), a labor drama starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> took credit for the script, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> challenged him to a fistfight.
It was a sign of things to come. Ever since, he has used belligerence, bravado,
and a gift for charming the media to make himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flashdance</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> suggested rewriting the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, Eszterhas
bullied him out of the idea. He did the same thing when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> tried to
change the ending of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jagged Edge</ENAMEX> . Both incidents burnished his image. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> made headlines by challenging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superagent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX>, then
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> had threatened to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>'
career if he switched to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>; Eszterhas leaked this to the press,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">humiliating Ovitz</ENAMEX>. He twice brought attention to himself by storming off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">set of Basic Instinct</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burn Hollywood Burn</ENAMEX> had its press-getting
Eszterhas stunt, too. He dumped his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and edited the film himself.

            Eszterhas
still presents himself as a radical tough. He has long hair and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motorcycle</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> beard--the sort of hair that looks bad enough at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 33</TIMEX> and
positively absurd at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX>. He has been known to bring a wooden stick into
meetings, then smash it on the table when he's angry. He has turned his private
life into fodder for his myth. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> took up with a
producer named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McDonald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Baka</ENAMEX> took refuge with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> promptly left his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and their
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baka</ENAMEX>. Then, according to press reports, he signed a contract with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> to tell all about the sordid affair. No piece ever ran.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>' posturing worked: He became the
celebrity he'd always hoped to be--brash, appealing, larger than life.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moviegoers</ENAMEX> knew his name and his legendary audacity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Producers</ENAMEX> fell hard for
the schtick, making him the most expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. He got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>
million for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Basic Instinct</ENAMEX> , then <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outline</ENAMEX> (!) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jade</ENAMEX> , then <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Night Stand</ENAMEX> . And
thanks to his bullheadedness, he exerts more control over production than
almost any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors alter</ENAMEX> his scripts at their peril.

            There is
a mysterious disconnect between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>' self-image and his work. Eszterhas
is a self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> but not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX>. He honestly believes himself <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s
bravest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>, and he has written passionately about the need for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> to stand up for artistic integrity. He also honestly believes in
his scripts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most endearing qualities of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">B-movie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Corman</ENAMEX> is their self-consciousness, their recognition that they're making
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crass</ENAMEX>, but fun, junk. That's absent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>: He's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Wood</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> is "delusional in the sense that he believes that everything he
touches is serious," says film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Thomson</ENAMEX>. In the
publicity leading up to the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showgirls , Eszterhas</ENAMEX> gave
interview after interview about the importance of the movie, of its deep moral
message, its serious purpose. He even called it--this T & A sleazefest
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> stripper--"a deeply religious experience."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> is reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Hefner</ENAMEX>:
They share the same exaggerated sense of importance, the same pontificating
humorlessness about their ridiculous jobs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hefner</ENAMEX> published pictures of naked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and believed himself a radical. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> writes movies about naked women
and believes himself an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. (No surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> issue
publishes a long interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>' career did not
have to be this way. He's capable of much more than he usually gives. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>,
he wrote The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music Box</ENAMEX> , a movie about an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who
defends her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant father</ENAMEX> when he is accused of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war crimes.
It is a beautiful, sad little movie about betrayal. It was glowingly reviewed.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and the movie drew most of the publicity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX> didn't.

            This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eszterhas</ENAMEX>' tragedy
and the dark side of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>. When he writes sensationalist schlock, he
gets the attention he craves. When he writes moving, interesting drama, he
doesn't. So schlock it will be.

         
      
   
