
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford Coppola</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every couple of years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford Coppola</ENAMEX>'s devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>--and such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still exist--do something
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heartbreaking</ENAMEX>: They see his new film. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX> has brought the latest Coppola
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">punishment, The Rainmaker</ENAMEX> . Or rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>'s The
movie.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are greeting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s film--the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> tale of an idealistic young lawyer
slingshotting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goliath</ENAMEX>--with a desperate generosity. Casting about for
something nice to say, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> have hit upon the conclusion that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.G.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rainmaker</ENAMEX> is better than the "typical" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movie (by
which they mean it has fewer automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, fewer car chases, and more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character actors</ENAMEX> than regular fare does). One well-meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> called it the
best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grisham</ENAMEX> movie since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Firm</ENAMEX> . This is sad: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford Coppola</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Godfather , The Godfather Part II</ENAMEX> , The
Conversation , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rumble Fish , and Apocalypse Now</ENAMEX> and the winner
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>, is being praised for making the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> movie.

            What's
even sadder: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainmaker</ENAMEX> is actually much better than most of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s recent work. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 15 years</TIMEX>, he's become the most hackish of
the studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>. His last dozen films have ranged from bombastic dreck
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bram Stoker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Godfather</ENAMEX> Part III , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cotton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> ) to infantile dreck ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Captain Eo</ENAMEX> ) to biographical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dreck</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tucker: The Man and His Dream</ENAMEX> ) to pretentious dreck ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One From</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heart , New York Stories</ENAMEX> ). He has also been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> for an
astonishing volume of bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> and television, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> ; the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wind</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Dwarf</ENAMEX> , a sci-fi movie
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>.

            Despite this record of unadulterated mediocrity, a fog of
optimism continues to envelop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>. Rainmaker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are saying
the same thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> that they said when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Godfather</ENAMEX> Part III opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> opened in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>: He's ready to make his comeback. This movie, it is promised, will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s last as a studio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lackey</ENAMEX>. Soon he will return with his own project,
independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s morons, and make the great movie that They
have stopped him from making since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> is cryptic about
what this project will be, but there are vague rumors about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megalopolis</ENAMEX> ,
a long-planned film comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Rome</ENAMEX> and modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. Other rumors
have him filming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kerouac</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On the Road</ENAMEX> .) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX> are sure to
be disappointed--they misdiagnose the cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Coppola's illness</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
continue to believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coppola</ENAMEX> because he is the romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archetype</ENAMEX> of the
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. He has embedded himself in the mythology of the film industry
like no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orson Welles or D.W. Griffith</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> made his name as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> who would risk everything--his fortune, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, even his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sanity</ENAMEX>--for his art. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s and the '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> bucked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> by
opening his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Zoetrope</ENAMEX>. It was a doomed enterprise but a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noble</ENAMEX> one: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coppola</ENAMEX> did free himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">protégés</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s thrall. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX>, he cemented his reputation as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Apocalypse Now</ENAMEX> . He gave himself a nervous breakdown, gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheen</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX>, and spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 million</NUMEX> of his own money to complete the
picture. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">His Apocalypse Now</ENAMEX> lunacy is brilliantly chronicled in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">documentary Hearts of Darkness</ENAMEX> .) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coppola</ENAMEX> drove
himself into bankruptcy again for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One From the Heart</ENAMEX> , his beloved
musical romance. He made a black-and-white movie ... for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rumble</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> has made more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> than any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> other directors
combined, and he has pioneered technology (notably video editing) that other
filmmakers have come to rely on. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> is expansive, generous, a
brilliant talker, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>. He is, in short, the very model of what a movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> should be.

            
This vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> as romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> makes
it very easy to rationalize his failures as poor accountancy. "His career can
be summed up as the case of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who needed a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebert</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> spent much of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> in bankruptcy, driven there by the
failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One From the Heart</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s collapse. So of course he
became a hired gun: He needed to pay his debts. According to the mythology,
Coppola was given third-rate scripts and managed to transform them into
second-rate entertainment like The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cotton Club</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardens of Stone</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peggy Sue Got Married</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>, who had been notorious for
delivering his own movies late and over budget, earned a reputation as a
reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. He stuck to his budgets, and almost all his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> movies,
even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reprehensible</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> , earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">money</NUMEX>.)

            Coppola
too buys into the notion that he would have kept making great movies if only
he'd been debt free. He's obsessed with the notion of artistic purity. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainmaker</ENAMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> tribute to the idea of not selling out. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> on
the graphic to see the movie's emotional climax, when the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer hero</ENAMEX>
confronts the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> villain about selling out.) In recent interviews,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> has upbraided himself for his own .

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coppola</ENAMEX> may be misjudging the reason why he's made so
many bad movies. He thinks that selling out--making movies for financial rather
than artistic reasons--has put a crimp in his style. But he has always been a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sellout</ENAMEX>. Or, to put it more kindly, the quality of his movies has never
depended on whether the movies were sellouts or not. Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s
"personal" movies are magnificent ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Conversation and</ENAMEX>, arguably,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apocalypse Now</ENAMEX> ). But others are dreadful ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One From the Heart</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> ). Some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s sellout movies are dreadful ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cotton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> ...). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s two greatest movies, the
Godfather s, were studio-funded, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>-managed projects. The
Godfather , in fact, was the quintessential sellout: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX> picked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> to direct the movie because he would work for cheap. Why would he work
for cheap? Because he had just bankrupted himself making a disastrous
independent movie called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rain People</ENAMEX> .

            Coppola
has become a studio hack for much more banal reasons. He got older, mellower,
more respectable. He has his estates, his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">winery</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>, his
merchandise. It's impossible to imagine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s Coppola driving himself or his
actors the way he did during the filming of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Apocalypse Now</ENAMEX> . He also
seems to lack the inspiration for a grand project. His last truly personal
movies were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> , back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One From the Heart</ENAMEX> , back in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. Neither was good.

            
Recently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> want me so badly
to do something truly astounding. To show them something they haven't seen
before. I would like to do that, and I really believe I can do it."

            This may be the heart of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s dilemma. He views his life as a story of unfulfilled promise, the
tale of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> constrained by commerce. It isn't. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s life is the
story of fulfilled promise. He made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the greatest, if not the two
greatest, movies in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. These were triumphs enough for any
career. It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s tragedy that he believes his best work is always ahead
of him, yet keeps on making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainmaker s.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
