
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Moyers</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Moyers</ENAMEX> broadcast his
latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> documentary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Close to Home: Moyers on Addiction</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five and a half sobering hours</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and drug addiction. It was an
oddly appropriate subject, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>' shows themselves are a kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">addictive drug</ENAMEX>. After watching a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX> documentary, you are likely to be--for
no rational reason--in a warmhearted, benevolent, slightly euphoric mood: I
feel better for having watched this . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX> is a glass of chardonnay before
dinner, a small toke on a marijuana joint.

            It's easy
enough to mock <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s secular televangelist. He is, after all, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who gave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mythmeister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Campbell</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s movement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guru Robert Bly</ENAMEX>, and the oppression <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya Angelou</ENAMEX> (now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, would you
please take them back?). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX> is capable of turning almost any subject
into liberal squish: In his hands, the book of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genesis</ENAMEX> is a story of family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dysfunction</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Genesis: A Living Conversation</ENAMEX> ), and drug addiction is a
disease for which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> bear no responsibility.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX> is terminally earnest, and more cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
(that is, all of us) tire of his lectures on our frivolity. An ordained <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, he adores sermonizing about his seriousness of purpose. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for
some examples.) His TV manner can be unbearably ingratiating. He does not
address his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> as much as hypnotize it. His gestures are too soothing
(click to view my favorite). His <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> drawl and folksy eloquence are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overpowering</ENAMEX>--like drinking a gallon of sweet, warm <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX>.

            Moyers
also gets hit for making money off public television. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundations</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> give him <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to produce documentaries. He brilliantly markets
for-profit spinoffs: His companion books for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis</ENAMEX>, poetry, and
mind-body medicine series have all been best sellers. It's hard to see what's
so offensive about this commercialization: Why shouldn't Moyers make a fortune
off his books and videotapes? Just because he's on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> doesn't mean he should
be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>' smug piety does not diminish his very
real achievement: He has spent his life trying to bring moral seriousness to
television. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyers</ENAMEX> quit as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon B. Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, he could
have made a fortune anywhere. (Compare him with fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidante</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valenti</ENAMEX>, who has been buck-raking and power-playing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>.) But Moyers
believed he would best serve the public as a TV educator, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in what he
calls the "biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>."

            To that end, he spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
documenting political, artistic, and spiritual subjects that other TV news
dismisses in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. He tackles big issues--the world's great religions, evil,
poetry--and often explains them eloquently. He has done more than anyone on
television to popularize little-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>. Yes, that includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>,
but for every interview with someone like him, there is one with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mortimer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> who used Moyers' show to try to explain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle</ENAMEX>.

            
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have complained that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX> is pernicious because he is
faux high culture. Moyers offers the simulacrum of knowledge. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> watch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adler explain Aristotle</ENAMEX>, they are being diverted from real thought. They are
watching television rather than actually reading philosophy. This seems to me
an ungracious snipe: The time spent watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adler</ENAMEX> probably would have been
spent mooing over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> , not studying <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Aristotle</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>' political documentaries, too, address difficult
issues clearly, if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-sidedly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> cite his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> TV essay as a
model for great television. Documentaries on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, the rise of religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fundamentalism</ENAMEX>, and the minimum wage are much admired, too. And for all his
tendencies to liberal hackdom, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyers</ENAMEX> did make <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Vanishing Family: The</ENAMEX>
Crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black America</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. It linked black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> decline to bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> welfare policy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> acknowledged the issue.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>, incidentally, is one of the culture's best Zeitgeist
indicators. Click to read more.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> public-spirited ambitions do often fail. Many of his broadcasts during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> reflexively reinforced liberal nostrums. Some of his
recent spiritual documentaries have degenerated into New Age banalities. But at
least he keeps trying. And whether or not a documentary succeeds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyers</ENAMEX> always
serves as a tonic to television's mad rush. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>' documentaries are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">languorous</ENAMEX>, even soporific. But his long, unhurried interviews crack his
subjects wide open: They talk to the camera as they would with an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.
Their frankness is a tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>' genuine warmth and empathy. (Lesson:
The thoughtful chin-grab works.)

            
Which brings us to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>' one real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shortcoming</ENAMEX>. He rejects confrontation. He opens <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up by agreeing with
them. Moyers was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to the most political and confrontational of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>, but he is the world champion of consensus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron saint</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Tannen</ENAMEX>. Moyers gathers the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>. His shows are more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">700 Club</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> . His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> almost always share <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>'
belief about the topic at hand. If you watched the addiction series, for
example, you heard little about other popular views of addiction, e.g., that
into victimization.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>'
kind of journalism seems designed to place this thought in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>'s mind:
No right-thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could ever disagree with all these nice, smart
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>.

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knowledge</ENAMEX> is a violent, bright, hot thing, but
you would never know that watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Jarvik</ENAMEX>, author of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behind the Screen</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moyers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> say that television has enough strife elsewhere (very little of it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illuminating</ENAMEX>) and that it's important that the airwaves offer a civil forum
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers'</ENAMEX>. There is lots of truth to that view. But I can't help wishing
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX> would sometimes apply his keen mind to confronting those who
disagree with him. Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moyers with 60 Minutes</ENAMEX> , whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rough-and-tumble</ENAMEX>, ambush journalism is the antithesis of his. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prods</ENAMEX>, provokes, and fights with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. After a great <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>
segment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> shake their heads in anger and disbelief. After a great Moyers
show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> nod in agreement. Which is better journalism?

            
               If you missed the
discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>' self-righteousness, click . If you missed the discussion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>' gift for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> , click .
            

         
      
   
