
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Willes</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> are always dying,
and someone is always killing them. Radio was supposed to bury them. So was
television. So was their aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>. So was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . So was the
Internet.

            The
latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>: the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bean</ENAMEX> counter. He breaches the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> Wall
between business and editorial, cares more about the stock price than about the
front-page lead, favors stories that focus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> want to read, and talks
constantly about "product." To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> tell it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
Willes, who just named himself publisher of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , is of
that ilk. The greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of the West is now being run by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose
newspaper experience totals <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> (much of it spent closing papers) and who
passed the bulk of his career as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Mills</ENAMEX>, a
breakfast-cereal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> (or rather, a breakfast-cereal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, for
chrissakes! ).

            Virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has married some
editorial and business functions, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX> would go further. Rather than
limiting business-editorial contact to the top of the masthead, he proposes to
have each section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> (sports, business, etc.) operate as a
more or less autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>. Each will have its own "minipublisher" who will
set profitability goals and consult with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> on general content (though
not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX> insists, on specific stories). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are aghast. The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> calls it "a revolution in the newspaper
business."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> is
also pushing "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>" stories and civic journalism, the kind of pandering to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that infuriates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. He suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> introduce
new sections aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> and female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> gripe
that such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> would only ghettoize minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelby Coffey</ENAMEX>, the
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX>, quit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> amid speculation that he
couldn't stomach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX>' changes.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper business</ENAMEX> has always been
romantic, and few papers have been more romantic than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . For
most of its life, it was a right-wing rag that rooted unapologetically for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>. Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis Chandler</ENAMEX>, the
surfing, antique-car-collecting scion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (which owns most
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror</ENAMEX>), took over as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chandler</ENAMEX>
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> transformed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> into one of the best papers in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. They hired talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> by the score, ran the longest stories in
the industry, and won <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer after Pulitzer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> was profligate,
editorially bold, and profitable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis Chandler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> --like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sulzbergers' New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grahams' Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and
all great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>--was as much grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> as business.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> retired, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>, the stock went
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">south</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>'s more conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> demanded higher profits. The
era of newspaper romance slipped away in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> (as it did everywhere
else). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> seems to embody the capitalist rationalism that has replaced it.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX>, he first made a name for himself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX> as a
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>, touting "rational expectations" theory long before it
became fashionable. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 35</TIMEX>, he became the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Bank</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, he jumped to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Mills</ENAMEX>,
where he eventually served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief operating officer</ENAMEX>, and vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Mills</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> note, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> where marketing, rather
than content, is king.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> picked him to run their
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.4-billion-</NUMEX>but-still-sickly media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. (In addition to its flagship
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartford Courant</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ; several
magazines; and medical and legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>.) Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> had made
himself one of the most detested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in journalism. In a now infamous
interview, he compared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal</ENAMEX>. Then he shuttered the venerable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Evening Sun</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Newsday</ENAMEX> , the much admired,
much unread, much unprofitable downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> . He also fired
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">175</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, known as the
"velvet coffin" because of its high pay and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cushy</ENAMEX> working conditions, had not
laid off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. Predictably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX> was nicknamed "Cereal
Killer" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cap'n Crunch</ENAMEX>."

            Wall
Street loved what the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom loathed</ENAMEX>. Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX>'s costs plummeted. Profits
soared. The stock has tripled from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18</NUMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX> arrived to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $60</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--the best performance of any big media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> say
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror</ENAMEX> is now one of the healthiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in the industry. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> family has profited from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s rising dividends and stock
price.

            
Times-philes do have some reason to worry about
Willes as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>. The idea of having ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX> and "minipublishers" help
plan editorial sections is terrifying to anyone who's ever met an ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>. "Heroic" and civic journalism do often degenerate into idiotic
rah-rah cheerleading. A push for shorter stories--also said to be in the
works--may well vanquish the elegant, comprehensive (OK, long-winded) pieces
for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is famous. ("We'll just have to be famous for something
else," snaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX>.)

            But there
is a more fruitful way to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX>: He is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> high-profile
newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> who actually believes in newspapers. Newspaper
profits may be at record highs, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> is gloomy.
Circulation has barely risen since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, and it's been falling for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> increasingly feel themselves
irrelevant--marginalized by TV news and the Internet, ignored by a younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of nonreaders.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimist</ENAMEX>. He's a proselytizer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>.
According to those who know him, he has learned why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are a public
trust since his unfortunate cereal interview. (He has forsworn cereal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analogies</ENAMEX>.) Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are shrinking content; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX> wants to add sections
and features. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> fear controversy; he proposes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> "crusades."
His ideas may be terrible--some of them certainly are terrible--but at
least they are new.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX>' boldest goal: to
raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> circulation from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 million to 1.5 million</NUMEX>. No one thinks
he can do it. Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Morton</ENAMEX> says it would be "a miracle" if he
pulled it off. But everyone wants him to try, because only new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will
save the industry in the long run. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> recently halved the price of the
Times to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 cents</NUMEX> to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonsubscribers</ENAMEX>. He's launched a huge ad
campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, more than any
newspaper in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--and about the same number the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lost.

            To add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, or even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> that number, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> will need to steal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> from
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> area, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Daily News</ENAMEX> . This raises an appetizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> is up for sale. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> is rumored to be
interested in buying it and turning it into a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> version of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Post</ENAMEX> . A circulation-hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willes</ENAMEX> vs. the rapacious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>: That's
just the kind of fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> newspaper industry needs.

         
      
   
