
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">New</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Cronkite</ENAMEX>

            The rampant civility of the
presidential and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>presidential debates is enough to make me wanna give
somebody a mouthful of bloody <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiclets</ENAMEX>. That somebody is debate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX>.

            I know my anger is
misplaced. That the debates sputtered rather than sizzled wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX>'s
fault. He may have pitched softballs, but that's what the ground rules of the
occasion required. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> can't be blamed for the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> satisfied themselves by slapping singles when they could have swung for
the fences.

            Still, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irritation</ENAMEX> is not entirely misplaced. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaigns, having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessedly</ENAMEX> dumped the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> of preening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> as
sole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> for a reason. He has become our national icon of broadcasting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">probity</ENAMEX>, and they knew that he would bring the sort of solemnity to the
occasion that would minimize the risk of things getting interesting.

            There's a kind of dignity in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX>'s plodding reluctance
to opine, in his hangdog humility, in his desire to serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> rather
than interrogator. There's also a reward. From his role as the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX>
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> presidential and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>presidential debates, it is suddenly clear
that we finally have a successor to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Cronkite</ENAMEX> in the semiofficial role of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s first TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 62</TIMEX>) obliquely acknowledged this
milestone when he won the debate assignment. "I see my selection as a tribute
to our <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> way of doing things," he said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cronkite</ENAMEX>
retired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two decades ago</TIMEX>, but the chair has remained empty until now.
Who's the alternative? Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>, and has that randy gaze that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> hide their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX>
looks too boyish, and has a speech impediment; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> is famously nuts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>'s got the gravitas and a great magisterial voice, but there's
still something too cheesy about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> mise-en-scène . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Koppel</ENAMEX> is
too in-your-face. The retirement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert MacNeil</ENAMEX> (another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gave Lehrer</ENAMEX> full ownership of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS NewsHour</ENAMEX>, and his debate-moderator
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gig</ENAMEX>--which made him the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> who can lay down the rules to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>--sealed the deal.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX>'s apotheosis has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> in the
making. It began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>, when he abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> newspapering for a
job at the local public-television <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. He moved on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and, during the
Watergate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 1973</TIMEX>, partnered with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacNeil</ENAMEX> to parlay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>' weakness (a
lack of resources to dig for stories) into strength. Presaging the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">télévision vérité</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robin</ENAMEX> covered the hearings
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gavel</ENAMEX>-to-gavel from an Olympian distance, mostly letting the story and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> speak for themselves. An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy</ENAMEX> followed, as did <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">their evening</TIMEX> show
that now goes by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> .

            More talk
show than news program, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> likewise lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and things
mostly speak for themselves. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each week</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, and voluble wonks descend upon the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NewsHour</ENAMEX> 's suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> for mild chat with the anchors
about genocide and tax policy and abortion and air-traffic safety and other
topics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> isn't always as flat as he was required to be in the
debates, but there is the same vacant and impassive style, and there are (for
my taste), too many of the same easily answered--or evaded--questions.
Off-camera, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> is a jovial skeptic. Yet, even though he knows that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> who appear on his show are accomplished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars</ENAMEX>,
he offers little in the way of interruption or contradiction. Like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX>-led debates, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> is a low-scoring game of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singles</ENAMEX>,
passed balls, and sacrifice flies.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> claim to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour stimulating</ENAMEX>,
but I suspect that what they really find it is soothing. Friction and strife
are the post and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> of genuine journalism, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX>'s product is comfort:
first, for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, whom he shields from the passion and fury of the news.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-documentaries</ENAMEX> don't shy away from distressing scenes
of war and misery, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> discussions that follow generally still the
racing heart. Comfort also is extended to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>--and I do
mean "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>." "He looks at you with those big brown eyes," confides one
talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> who has appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> , "and you know you're going to
be safe."

            As on other talk shows,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">NewsHour guests</ENAMEX> are pre-interviewed. (When the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'50s</NUMEX> game shows engaged
in this sort of coaching, it was considered a scandal.) And like other
talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> reserves the right to hammer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> with unexpected
questions. But he rarely does. No wonder, then, that the exchanges between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> seem so articulate and poised; that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> are eager to return to
the show; that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> was a guest at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s pretentious "metaphor
salon" dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> is
unabashed about this socializing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> and power, and it has turned him
into one of them. (He runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> as if it were a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> office
and he, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of the show.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> is not corrupt.
When his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> appear on his show, they get treated no better than some war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> with whom he is not acquainted. Or rather, the war criminal gets
treated no worse than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Cockburn</ENAMEX> once imagined this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacNeil/Lehrer</ENAMEX> segue: "And now, for another view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> ..."

            
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cockburn</ENAMEX> cracked wise in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, the news
business--especially the TV news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>--has grown more aggressive and
competitive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicates</ENAMEX> have expanded news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> coverage,
political talk shows have multiplied like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> shows have grown
more slick, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three 24-hour</TIMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> now clog cable television.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Admirably</ENAMEX> (to many) resisting this commercial tide, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> seems
even more civil and staid. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roper Poll</ENAMEX> concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX>
is perceived by the public as "the most credible" newscast in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
Maybe so. But credibility apparently isn't everything. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 1.2 million</NUMEX> homes
tune in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NewsHour</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each night</TIMEX>, while a combined total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.4 million</NUMEX>
homes watch the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> news on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronkite</ENAMEX> crown, though,
is not awarded on the basis of ratings. "Credibility" is a vital factor, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> does, indeed, have it. It's an odd factor, though: Do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brokaw</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rather</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX>--reading scripts written by others from their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TelePrompTers</ENAMEX>--are making things up? No, it's something more amorphous, like,
"Who do you want to hear it from the next time a plane crashes or a world
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is assassinated<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" Hell, even I might choose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
