
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Presidential Hopeful</ENAMEX>

            After his excruciating
performance in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>
should have had the grace to disappear quietly into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">backwoods</ENAMEX>.
But here we are, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full 900 days</TIMEX> before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexander</ENAMEX>
is running again--airing ads in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, fund raising, pandering, mounting his
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, and doing all the other unappetizing things a presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> must do.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, who has been
campaigning for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> more or less nonstop since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, is the very model of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Presidential Hopeful</ENAMEX>, or RPH, but he's hardly alone. With no
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> apparent, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">2000</ENAMEX> race promises to be the wildest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> primary
in a generation. There are, by my count, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> considered (at
least by their own estimation) viable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> candidates. is the full list.

            And an
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">astonishing</ENAMEX> number of them are already engaged in all-but-official campaigns,
desperate quests to become an "early favorite." The will-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are
competing fiercely for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>, endorsements. (A caveat: Not
all the potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are pre-campaigning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, for example, have carefully avoided any presidential posturing.)

            So who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX>? What are defining qualities?

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> is not easily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deterred</ENAMEX>. Anyone who would spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of his life pursuing an office
that he has no reasonable hope of winning must be irrepressible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> isn't
bothered by the fact that he's been routed before (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>); that he's the most hated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in
politics (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>); that he's a national joke (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>); that hardly
anyone outside his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has heard of him (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashcroft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Ridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Thompson</ENAMEX>); that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will
confuse him with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">S&L</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Keating</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>--he's never heard of you, either); or that he might not get elected if
he were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next-to-last</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> alive (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>).

            
               The RPH
pretends he isn't actually running. It's tacky to be campaigning for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of 1998</TIMEX>, so--even though everyone knows he's
going to run--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> generally insists he isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. He has devised a
number of lies and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-truths to convey this. "It's not something I'm thinking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about right now</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>). He won't decide until "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>),
"for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasich</ENAMEX>), until "after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> elections" (lots of them).
It's just an "exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>). It's "very premature" to talk
about it (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>). "I'm extremely flattered by the speculation," but a worthier
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> will certainly come along" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>). "My focus is entirely on the
state of ______" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Todd Whitman</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>). Instead of
appearing to be the grasping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX> he is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> exudes the impression that he
won't run unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> plead for his candidacy. Rare is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who doesn't hear that plea.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> says he has a real job, but he
doesn't. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">RPHs</ENAMEX> do actually work for a living: Sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> all hold real jobs. But often the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> has
a simulacrum of a career, the kind of work that is an excuse to spend every
waking minute campaigning. (That means you, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Keyes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>. Would you dare say your job is "professional presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>"?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> claims he is working
for the good of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> or both. What, exactly, does
this "work" consist of? Much of it is giving speeches. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> has made nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 18 months</TIMEX>.)

            The rest
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX>'s work is running his political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> or "grass-roots"
advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> . This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> has a magnificent, patriotic name: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> for
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New American Century</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live Free or Die</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solutions America</ENAMEX>! Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>!
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to play a game: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Match the RPH</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> has
ambitious goals: to advocate the flat tax (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>); to draft "an agenda for a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>); to "build and strengthen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>). In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> real purpose: to raise funds
and promote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> before official campaigning (as well as official fund
raising) begins in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.

            What does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> believe in? Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Principles</ENAMEX>-- . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> is high-minded. He frequently quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>.
He especially enjoys taking a bold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> stand against his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>: This
distinguishes him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesman</ENAMEX> who won't sacrifice principles for expediency.
It also guarantees a bit of favorable press. Ashcroft regularly berates the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for having "cut and run" rather than having tackled tough
moral issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> periodically slaps <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compromising</ENAMEX>: "Get real or get out!" is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> slogan. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> makes a habit of
denouncing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>: for expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, for approving treaties, for not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impeaching Clinton</ENAMEX>, etc. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> often slams fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for not
doing enough to ban abortion.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> who must legislate or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">govern</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kasich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>) is quieter about his principles--probably
because he actually has to live by them. There is no such check on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unemployed RPH</ENAMEX>.

            
               The RPH
has a multipoint tax plan (usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX> points, often <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>). The RPH
generally believes in the flat tax, which should be set at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>--that tax-and-spend liberal--would set it at a whopping <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX>.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> might also believe in eliminating the income tax (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>), slashing the
income tax and raising tariffs (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>), or rejiggering the tax code to save
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$985 billion</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX>, by abolishing taxes on inheritances and on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits, among other measures). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> does not much
elaborate on how he would balance the budget after his cuts.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> has hidden
literary talents. You can't turn around in a bookstore without knocking over a
pile of (unsold) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> books. Click for a list of them and another mix-and-match
game.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of the RPH
book is followed by the book tour, which leads to the next fact about the
RPH:

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> likes to
travel--to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> recently toured to promote
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lessons Learned the Hard Way</ENAMEX> . He found himself signing books in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>--undoubtedly because those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are
famed for their interest in great literature. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ashcroft</ENAMEX>,
Kasich, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> have also recently visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ashcroft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX> have stopped off in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> has
traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times. And the pressing business of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-city tour through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and the West.

            The RPH
will also travel to any place where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have gathered. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadership Conference</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> drew
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPHs</ENAMEX>. A similar meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biloxi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> also attracted eight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hopefuls</ENAMEX>. Even the recent summit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
managed to pull in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ashcroft</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>. If you held a
family reunion, you could probably get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashcroft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Keyes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> to give
stump speeches at the barbecue.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> trolls for endorsements. The RPH
knows he needs support from the opinion-making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to win in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The RPH
has almost certainly appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans & Novak</ENAMEX> . If he's lucky, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> has been championed by a pundit: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cal Thomas</ENAMEX> just wrote a paean to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasich</ENAMEX> won a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">full-throated</ENAMEX> cheer from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> .

            There is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> endorsement the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> seeks above all: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>'s . The RPH longs to
sign the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> as a campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kasich</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> have already met with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>
and kissed his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>.

            
Perhaps the most important--and certainly most
ridiculous--element of the pre-campaign is the early polls . Never has so
much been made of such flimsy numbers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> got a media boost when he
finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in a survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter leaders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Forbes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> tout his top finish in a straw poll of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Political Action</ENAMEX>
Conference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. There have been national news stories based on straw polls
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few hundred</NUMEX> party loyalists in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>.
Recently, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">234</NUMEX>-person phone poll by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> TV station made
headlines.

            There is a discouraging
lesson in the polls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, easily, in every poll
except the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPAC</ENAMEX>'s. He is also one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">RPHs</ENAMEX> who
eschews the pre-campaign. He's running for re-election as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>,
and he doesn't want <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> to worry that he'll skip out on them midway through
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">term</TIMEX> (which, of course, is exactly what he'd like to do). So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
has no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> and no book. He hasn't traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, and he
avoids most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> conferences. Instead he's just governing and campaigning in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.

            This
should frighten the daylights out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX>. Perhaps all the scheming,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">posturing</ENAMEX>, speechifying, and money-grubbing in the world can't help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX>.
Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> really want to reward the doer--not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX>,
not the pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX>.

            
               If you
missed the full list of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Presidential Hopefuls</ENAMEX>, click . You can also
test your RPH knowledge with these quizzes about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPH</ENAMEX> and .
            

         
      
   
