
   
   
      
         
            Government and Volleyball

            
               A mere
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years ago</TIMEX>, beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">volleyball</ENAMEX> was just beginning. Now it is not only a sport
[but] in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>. ... And there's a whole new world of opportunity opening
up that didn't even exist <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years ago</TIMEX>, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX> would
have invented it. And that's what freedom is all about.
            

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, addressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Convention</ENAMEX>.

            Not much
has changed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 40 years</TIMEX> on the small island off the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
where I have vacationed most <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> of my life. A few things have been
lost--the inn burned down (though few outside the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> mourned its
loss), as did the little grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> (much mourned when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> supply runs
low and the harbor lies a foggy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three miles</NUMEX> distant)--but not much has been
added. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX>, the shingled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, and the chapel seem
as immutable, in their slightly shabby Wyethian perfection, as the sea that
sparkles behind them.

            Yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> there was something new: a beach-volleyball
net. It stands firmly moored on the white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> beach that lies <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few yards</NUMEX> to
the west of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s cottage and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than a hundred</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">yards</NUMEX> from my own.
I'll admit that when I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> spotted the net, I failed to grasp its symbolic
importance. I thought it was something of an eyesore. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only later</TIMEX>, with the
benefit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">GOP Convention</ENAMEX> instruction (see above), did
I come to realize that what we had here was no less than the fulsome gift from
a mature <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. Sure, it sags a bit by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX>
standards, but it stands, nevertheless, as a symbol of what the human spirit
can achieve when free from the oppression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Government</ENAMEX>.

            Of course,
the volleyball net didn't just wash in with the tide. The tiny island
government that decides such things voted money to sink the concrete pilings
that support the net's posts and to purchase the needed equipment. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies Improvement Association</ENAMEX> provided personpower for the erection effort.
But these are small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX>, more akin to the voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> that
fall on the positive side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s freedom/slavery divide. Still I wonder:
Even if larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, like, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>'s, don't actually put
up the nets, surely they regulate their placement on beaches and other public
places.

            
Now I don't doubt for a moment that if you put
a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> around a conference table, the chances of them coming up
with sensible rules for beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">volleyball</ENAMEX>, much less the seminal concept, are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zilch</ENAMEX>. More likely they would invent a bunch of rules for keeping the players
from spraining their ankles or getting their toes cut by pieces of glass hidden
in the sand or contracting <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tetanus</ENAMEX> from rusty nails stuck in driftwood.
Actually, you know, there are rules sort of like that. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, who is
something of an amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on beaches, tells me, for example, that pursuant
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Resources Protection</ENAMEX> Act (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coastal Sand Dune Rules</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">355</NUMEX>), the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> sets standards for beach cleaning--though more with
an eye to protecting the beaches than the beach-going public. Some might think
that these rules, whether aimed at pristine dunes or uncut feet, also advance
the cause of beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">volleyball</ENAMEX>.

            It occurs to me further that
the beach itself might not have been able to accommodate this monument to
freedom were it not for the fact that, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> took it upon
herself to consult some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, among them actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, about the
erosion that then threatened it. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, notable among them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen M.</ENAMEX>
Dickson of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maine Department of Conservation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Kenneth Fink</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darling Marine Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walpole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, quickly fingered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">culprit</ENAMEX>: the
concrete <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX>, erected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 75 years ago</TIMEX> by an island benefactor--one Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley of Steamer</ENAMEX> fame.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sidewalk</ENAMEX>, they counseled, caused the sea to erode, rather than build, the
important dune that, with its beach <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and surrounding "berm colonizers,"
protects the beach and the north end of the island. And so the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> went
and the dune swells with each passing year and the beach grass slithers in the
wind. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>-volleyball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> everywhere should surely rejoice at the collective
action that, at the cost of some individual freedom, to be sure (mine, for
example, as, with sand-filled shoes, I struggle to navigate my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grocery</ENAMEX>-laden
cart along the dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> that is now the only access to my cottage), has
preserved another venue for their sport.

            Come to think of it, it's just possible that no sport
benefits more from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> than beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">volleyball</ENAMEX>. To begin with, if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> at every level hadn't intervened, beaches everywhere might have
been incorporated by the wealthy into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatsbyesque estates</ENAMEX>, like those that
denied most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Shore of Long Island</ENAMEX> to hoi polloi. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX>
in the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s beach-volleyball championship (as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s other top-ranked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> from the most
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> women's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>) grew up playing on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s spectacular
public beaches. And while the more aggressive types of beach maintenance
activity have fallen into disfavor among coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">geologists</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>,
those beaches, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>'s, have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">' dollars</NUMEX> spent collectively by local, state, and federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bureaucracies</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Squirrel Island Village Corp.</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Corps of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Engineers</ENAMEX>.

            Nor does government support
for beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">volleyball stop</ENAMEX> at dune's end. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s top-ranking male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> got their higher education thanks to the splendid network of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> that their home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> maintains. While in college, they honed
their skills playing regular volleyball--not a sport that pays its own way on
campus. And though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s top-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> earn six-figure incomes from
their prizes and commercial endorsements, many of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> of tomorrow
may even now be benefiting from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s biggest covert subsidy of sports
and the arts--unemployment insurance (and perhaps the occasional food
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stamp</ENAMEX>).

            So let me draw a slightly
different moral from the saga of beach volleyball as it has evolved in our
times: If, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> says, the price of volleyball is eternal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>, still it may take a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> to raise a volleyball net.

         
      
   
