
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Killer Air Bags</ENAMEX>

            Is nothing sacred? Worse
yet, is nothing safe?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> we learned that
air bags-- air bags , once the Holy Grail of consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, the fond
hope of every worried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>--are dangerous to your health. Not only are they
no sure-fire protection against the hazards of driving, but they may even be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid killers</ENAMEX>! Automakers rushed warnings to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of air-bag-equipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. The
tort <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> has, no doubt, been placed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Alert</ENAMEX>.

            Who is to blame for the
air-bag debacle?

            We are,
of course. We, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, tireless in our pursuit of the costless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">benefit</ENAMEX>, loath to accept the randomly aimed slings and arrows of outrageous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fortune</ENAMEX>, ever ready to shift the blame for our own laziness or carelessness to
someone else--preferably someone with deep pockets. We were easy prey for the
safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crusaders</ENAMEX> who argued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s and '80s</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> could not be expected to buckle their seat belts and shoulder belts,
and that the recalcitrant car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> should be required to install "passive
restraints."

            The economics profession lent strength to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>'
arguments. One widely quoted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> study emanating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Institution</ENAMEX> proclaimed that seat belts--to all appearances, a low-cost and
effective way to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from flying through the windshield--actually
failed the test of cost/benefit analysis. What all appearances neglected to
consider, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX> study did not, was the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2.97 seconds</TIMEX> that it takes,
on average, to fasten a seat belt. (For an instructive sample of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>' arcane divinations, .)

            Adding up
all these <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">precious seconds</TIMEX> and a few other minor costs over the life of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> concluded that the total cost of using seat belts exceeds
the benefits by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $1,193</NUMEX>. By contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> stated, the relatively
expensive and unproven air bags would net annual benefits of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 billion</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.2 billion</NUMEX>. From this, they concluded that mandatory seat-belt laws were
ill-advised.

            
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX> grew tired of being
labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>," as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> puts it. Aware that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> didn't like the automated seat belts that were the only alternative
restraint" standards, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> finally jumped on the air-bag bandwagon. By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the air bag was a staple of the industry, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> before federal law
makes dual air bags mandatory in all new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had long
argued that air bags were only effective if the hated seat belts were also worn
(the bags are already marked "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SR</ENAMEX>," for supplemental restraint, if anyone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bothers</ENAMEX> to look). But somehow, those warnings grew fainter as air-bag
enthusiasm mounted.

            So now we
have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of actual experience with air bags. And what does the record
show? Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 650,000</NUMEX> air bag "deployments" have occurred and, by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> count, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,136</NUMEX> lives have been saved. But at what price? The industry puts
the cost of an air bag installed in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $500</NUMEX>, not including
"engineering spillovers," such as dashboard and steering-wheel redesign. At
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, the total cost (to the consumer--not the car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, who pass
the cost along) of installing even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> air bag in each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 million-plus</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> now so equipped is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $18 billion</NUMEX>, to date, and the cost per life saved
is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to $16 million</NUMEX>.

            Of course, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--no less than consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>--now
hasten to add, the value of a human life is infinite, which makes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 million</NUMEX> a
bargain. But what, then, about the value of the lives that air bags have taken?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">As many as 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just the last year</TIMEX>--are reported to have been
killed by air bags in accidents that otherwise would not have been fatal.
Nineteen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> as well, most of whom were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 feet 2 inches</NUMEX> or shorter (a fact
that hits this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> close to home). Surely these lives were of infinite value
too, which means that, by the peculiar arithmetic of infinity, the costs as
well as the benefits of air bags are beyond measure. (Of course, if we truly
believed the value of human life was limitless, we'd ban motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>--which
account for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40,000</NUMEX> deaths a year--altogether.)

            Quite
apart from their costs, however, there's a real question whether air bags, on
balance, save any lives at all. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Commonwealth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>--yes, here are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> again, but this time making a more
plausible argument--studied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of auto-accident claims filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1989</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. They found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> of air-bag-equipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> initiate a
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">disproportionate</ENAMEX> number of crashes involving fatalities, and that, as a result,
the occupants of such <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are at considerably higher risk than those in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
without air bags. It's not that air bags don't work. It's that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel
that their chances of being injured are reduced, they drive more recklessly.
It's called "offset behavior."

            
Reducing drunken driving by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>, for
that matter, could save more lives in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> than have been saved by air bags
in their near-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> of deployment. But that, of course, would require a
considerable sacrifice from a substantial part of the citizenry. Which brings
us back to where we began: Human nature--or, at least, human nature as it has
evolved in our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> times.

            To be fair, the public does
seem to have wised up a lot. While consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> pump for another
technological fix--"smart" air bags that can adjust their behavior to the
stature of front-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>--more and more of us (perhaps influenced in
part by mandatory seat-belt laws in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>) are squandering those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.97</NUMEX>
precious <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> and buckling up. The industry now plans to strengthen warnings
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should be kept, appropriately harnessed, in the back seat, where
they will be neither helped nor harmed by air bags. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> also hope
to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHTSA</ENAMEX> that slower-inflating air bags would provide almost as much
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX> and far less risk than posed by the current standard--as long as
seat belts are also worn.

            There is a lesson here for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policy-makers</ENAMEX> who hope that the public will be easily led to make modest
sacrifices for the common good (or even for their individual good)--such as
accepting controls on medical usage to limit the runaway costs of medical care.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't like to be constrained, whether physically or in our choices.
And sometimes, we are willing to pay a very high price--measured not just in
dollars, but in the currency of lives--for that freedom.

            

               References:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford Winston</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associates</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>). Blind intersection? Policy and the automobile industry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hoffer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995, October</TIMEX>). Are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> of air-bag-equipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> more
aggressive? A test of the offsetting behavior hypothesis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Law</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXXVIII</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">251-279</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
