
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nerd</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nebbish</ENAMEX>

            You can talk about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalization</ENAMEX>, the sexual revolution, or the civil rights movement. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
the greatest upheavals of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> is the liberation of the nerd. Many have
noted the rise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> and the iconification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>. Few have placed these developments in context. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nerds</ENAMEX>, once defined as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squares</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>, now also lord over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX>).

            Just as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights movement revolutionized male-female relations, so also has
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> created its own turmoil. With the advent of the power nerd, we
can no longer say for certain what makes a nerd a nerd. Or, to put it another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, what now separates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> from the nebbishes? The time has come to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reassess</ENAMEX> and redefine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>.

            Nobody--not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dictionary</ENAMEX> --has concretely pinned down the origin of the word nerd .
One theory traces it to a throwaway passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seuss</ENAMEX>' lesser-known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s book If I Ran the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zoo</ENAMEX> . Another considers it a variation of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1940s</NUMEX> put-down nerts to you , as in "nuts to you." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> derives it
from turd .

            Whatever
its origins, the appellation rose to prominence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Age</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conformity</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> employed it to condemn the most conformist of the
conformists, the squarest of the squares. And the phrase conjured up a specific
image: the greasy, pocket-protected teen in thick, horn-rimmed glasses.

            
Clearly, the unstylish, klutzy bookworm has
existed throughout history. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> is an obvious example of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerd</ENAMEX> who
predated the term.) But nerdiness became well defined only after the birth of
its opposite--coolness--during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the prosperous postwar era</TIMEX>, as the middle class
expanded to include vast new segments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. These new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> adopted bourgeois values, among them a fixation with
fashion--what's cool and what's not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nerdy</ENAMEX> was not.

            But the
popular understanding of nerdiness--that a nerd is an uncool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--doesn't
stand the test of time. In particular, it doesn't survive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, an era the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> deemed was characterized by "nerd chic." By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of</TIMEX>
the go-go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> touted the popularity of nerd
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">couture</ENAMEX>--plaid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, horn rims, and oxford shirts buttoned all the way to the
top. Further, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> the proliferation of '80s teen movies valorizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revenge of the Nerds , Weird Science , and Real Genius</ENAMEX> , to
name a few. Underlying this transformation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nerd</ENAMEX>'s image was a
transformation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nerd</ENAMEX>'s economic status. With their entry into new
high-tech industries, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> suddenly became millionerds.

            Let me posit a more durable definition than the nerd-cool
opposition: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nerdiness</ENAMEX> is connoisseurship gone awry. The essential
characteristic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> is that they lack a normal understanding of style and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> graces. The essential reason they get this way is that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> their mental energies into a particular area--film, computers,
politics--at the expense of learning social conventions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nerds</ENAMEX> may or may not
carry their adolescent obsession into adulthood, but the scars of their
obsession remain palpable. (Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rare</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who becomes a nerd later
in life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, for instance, may have developed an unusual passion for
policy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 20s</TIMEX>, but it never interfered with his social being.)

            The
popular parlance conflates nerd with nebbish . But the overlap
between the two concepts is not large, more on the order of this:

            
While one could build a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nerd Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>,
nebbishes are almost always anonymous. By definition, nebbishes are whiners,
lacking self-confidence, generally inept, and on the losing end of social
transactions--all characteristics that work against their ever achieving fame.
The only famous nebbishes are fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Costanza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bashevis Singer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gimple the Fool</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McFly</ENAMEX> in Back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX> ,
and virtually anyone played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Moranis</ENAMEX>.

            Other attributes: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Nebbishes are necessarily schlumpy, never handsome or physically robust. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The
term is usually applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--often implying effeminacy. But it would not be
inaccurate to describe a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> as a nebbish or as nebbishy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Few nebbishes
are actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>--some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> characters excepted. They
lack the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nerd</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> and obsessivesness. By contrast, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handsome</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>) or self-confident to the point of arrogance (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>).

            At the
heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerd-nebbish</ENAMEX> divide is pity. Nebbishes are too pathetic to warrant
actual disdain. They are too easy a target. On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> evoke
envy. We hate them because they are smarter, or more studious, or more focused
than we are. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nerds</ENAMEX> are genuinely threatening.

            It is no accident that the word nebbish originated
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>, a language without a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that is spoken by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> repeatedly
beaten down by pogroms and thus in a good position to empathize with nebbishes.
So, to pose the obvious question: Is there something inherently <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> about
the nebbish? According to the great <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> linguist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Weinreich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
appropriated the word nebbich from their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slavic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 th century</TIMEX>. Indeed, other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> with similar histories
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjugation</ENAMEX> maintain similar words. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukrainian</ENAMEX>, for instance, the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bidni</ENAMEX> refers to an unfortunate, pitiable soul. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poverino</ENAMEX> . The fact that nebbish made it into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> owes much to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Borscht Belt</ENAMEX> comedians becoming '50s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebbishes</ENAMEX> will never ascend
to the heights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX>. There will be no <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revenge of the Nebbishes</ENAMEX> , no
nebbish liberation. A nebbish could never gain real power. More easily, one can
imagine nebbishes banding together to promote a nebbish agenda, kvetching that
they are systematically discriminated against, demanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebbish Studies</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, and complaining that history textbooks treat them as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>. But
only a schmegegge would ever bet on a nebbish.

            
               (Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX> for lending his erudition.)
            

         
      
   
