
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Harrowing Photo: From Guilt to Grace</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Freund</ENAMEX>

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">932</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 21</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of photography's most
terrible strengths is its power to accuse. The ability of imagery to forgive,
to reconcile, is a good deal more circumscribed--but then, that is true of
expression itself. Guilt will be borne; grace is fleeting.

            Yet, both guilt and grace
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> space on front pages and TV screens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX>; they came together
in the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phan Thi Kim Phuc</ENAMEX>, who, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years</TIMEX> of mute and frozen
accusation, stepped forward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Day</ENAMEX> ceremony in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, to lay to rest that portion of a painful past that she has carried in her
own face.

            Anyone old enough to
remember the imagery of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> would surely have viewed the pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vietnam Veterans Memorial</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Ut</ENAMEX>'s harrowing, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
Prize-winning photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> fleeing a napalm attack on a village
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saigon</ENAMEX>. That <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> photo has lost none of its dark horror over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. It still transforms its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>; it still asks of them
the same fearsome question: What have you to do with this?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9 years old</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>,
had taken shelter with others in a pagoda when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military ordered
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese</ENAMEX> air force to attack her village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trang</ENAMEX> Bang because it
had been infiltrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy forces</ENAMEX>. The pagoda was hit, killing, among
others, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>. Terrified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> streamed onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>,
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer Ut</ENAMEX> snapped them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> is naked, screaming in fear and agony,
in the center of the image.

            In fact, the image tells
little of this story. It is not a picture of a military attack and its
aftermath; it is a picture of terror. We know this is war: The presence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> tells us that. And we know something has just happened, because we see
black smoke obliterating the horizon. But what? Terrified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are running
down a hellish <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> that disappears behind them into a smoky vanishing
point, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> that seems to run through a barren and burning plain.

            What can they be running
toward? Perhaps they see something down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>, behind us. But there is no
anticipation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> to be found in their faces. If it is succor toward
which they run, they will have to run forever.

            Especially disconcerting is
the naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>. It isn't clear to us why she is
naked; perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of an explosion has blown away her clothes. Is she
injured? We can't quite tell. Oddly, she is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in the image looking
back at us. And we are the only ones looking at her. Indeed, the very act of
staring at her nakedness seems to only intensify her humiliation. There is a
dimension to her unending scream that seems to be in reaction to our very act
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>. The effect is deeply disturbing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ut's</ENAMEX> was not the only camera
present; the sequence exists on film as well. Because it is more dreadful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">physically</ENAMEX>, the film is less potent emotionally. (The same is true for another
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>'s most famous images: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Adams</ENAMEX>' photo of the gun-to-temple
execution of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Cong.</ENAMEX>)

            Vicki
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>, in her book The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power of Photography</ENAMEX> , describes the full,
filmed sequence:

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and
the others ... ran toward us rather slowly, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> finishing their run.
They passed the camera, it followed from behind. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s back and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> were
seen to be completely covered with black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patches</ENAMEX> of burned skin, no longer
resembling flesh. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> gave her a drink and poured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> over
her.
            

            That is a level of atrocity
from which most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> must recoil. Furthermore, the filmed sequence closes
out the event, and gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> an opportunity to shrug it off. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ut</ENAMEX>'s photo is
of a crowded highway winding eternally through hell, and it won't let you
go.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> reports that the
picture ran on front pages throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Spock</ENAMEX>, who chose the
photo to speak for him in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> exhibition "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talking Pictures</ENAMEX>," certainly
echoed many of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> when he wrote simply, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t horrified me," and
credited it with confirming his opposition to the war.

            The image was, of course, an
important piece of atrocity propaganda for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX>, who were
themselves responsible for significant suffering both before and after they
attained power. Like all such atrocity material, it undermined the morale of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> responsible for the pain it depicted. But the political manipulation
of imagery doesn't delegitimize its content. The pain here is only too real;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> still suffers from her wounds.

            In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> herself became a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of this image. As she told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX>, her desire to study
medicine was thwarted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who wanted her to remain available for media
interviews that stemmed from the photograph's worldwide fame; she herself had
become a propaganda exhibit. Eventually, she was able to study in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, and
during a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> asked for--and were
granted--asylum.

            "If I could talk face to
face with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> who dropped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> said during her remarkable
appearance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, "I would tell him we cannot change history, but we
should try to do good things for the present. ..."

            A little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, naked and in
pain and with burned arms outstretched, staggers toward us down the middle of a
highway. A quarter-century later, she reaches us. Who would have expected that
when she finally covered that last patch of pocked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, she would offer her
hand in grace?

         
      
   
