
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britain</ENAMEX> lost a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">princess</ENAMEX> and found a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>, the angriest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in the
world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s vitriolic, anti-press, anti-monarchy eulogy was wildly popular
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>--it's been called "one of the most important speeches in
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> history" and reprinted by all the vile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> it denounces.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> has invented a literary genre, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Attack Eulogy</ENAMEX>.) You might think
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s plummy accent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Grant</ENAMEX>-y good looks, and lordly manner--well,
he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lord</ENAMEX>--would make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britons</ENAMEX> nostalgic for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the good old days</TIMEX>.
(Remember when toffs were really toffee?) But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earl</ENAMEX> is a very new, very
modern, and almost American kind of aristocrat. The stiff upper lip has been
replaced by the barbed, blabbing tongue; reticence by confession;
traditionalism by populism.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s
eulogy, which did as much to settle scores as to commemorate his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, did
not surprise anyone who's followed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earl</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. The 33-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> has nursed a grudge against the press since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> interrupted his boisterous adolescence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX> was thrust upon him, and
he didn't like it much.

            In a normal aristocratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> would have been
just another playboy. But he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>' younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, so his
noble pursuits--i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, song--became tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fodder</ENAMEX>. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">escapades</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eton</ENAMEX> roughhousing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> carousing, riotous birthday parties,
speeding tickets--made headlines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleet</ENAMEX> Street dubbed him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Champagne Charlie</ENAMEX>."
His many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>-girlfriends decorated gossip columns, much to his annoyance. (Of
course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> wouldn't have been his girlfriends if it hadn't been for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">earl</ENAMEX>'s high profile.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s
rage at the press has grown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, and with much justification. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> of the World publicized his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anorexia</ENAMEX> (or, to use that excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> phrase, "a slimming disease") and
snapped surreptitious pictures of her at a private treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. When his
best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> committed jewel fraud, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Express</ENAMEX> falsely accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> of abetting the criminal. Another paper falsely accused him of selling
black market tickets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bolshoi Ballet</ENAMEX>. A paparazzo in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>,
where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> has lived since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, sneaked into his home as a domestic worker
and photographed him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> has fought back, repeatedly winning damages from
papers that intruded on or defamed him.

            
But, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>--which demands
more celebrity photos even as it shouts for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>
has a much more ambivalent (read: "hypocritical") relationship with the press
than he pretends to have. He uses the media as much as he is abused by it--a
trait he shared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months</TIMEX> after he married, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>
slept with an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. She was preparing to sell her story to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> pre-empted her. He confessed his adultery to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sympathetic Daily Mail</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, got his soft-pedaled version of the
story published, and escaped serious damage. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, this would have
been called . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is spin control.) On another occasion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> went on a
talk show and discussed his sex fantasies--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> orgies, if you're curious. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">earl</ENAMEX> has even practiced the very journalism he decries. For much of the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, he has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, covering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> and the aristocracy. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> TV assignment--no joke--was to serve
up royal gossip for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> at the wedding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Ferguson</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earl</ENAMEX> takes an equally
modern--and practical--approach to his noble heritage. He's worth more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>, but most of the fortune is tied up in land and antiques. He needs
cash flow to maintain his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13,000-acre</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">estate</ENAMEX>, and he's
been savvy about finding it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, he raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$336,000</NUMEX> by auctioning
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of his lesser titles, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX>. The titles were purely
symbolic--they carry no land and no seat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX>--but the sale
nonetheless horrified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalists</ENAMEX>. He has hocked heirlooms to pay taxes,
rented his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> out for conferences and banquets, proposed turning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>
wooded acres of his estate into a housing development, and leased the grounds
for concerts.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most admired
lines in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earl</ENAMEX>'s eulogy was his promise to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> family
will do all it can to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Princes William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> "are not simply
immersed by duty and tradition, but can sing openly as you planned." He
presents his royal nephews with an awkward choice: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles the earl</ENAMEX>. One is hidebound, stiff, silent in the face of media
criticism. The other is entrepreneurial, telegenic, noisy, and restrained by no
tradition. One is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s past; the other is its present.

         
      
   
