
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Parcells</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX> is a sport of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">myths</ENAMEX>, and there is none more powerful than this one: They don't make 'em like
they used to. Remember when they played both ways? When they didn't complain
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a pulled hamstring? When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lombardi</ENAMEX>, not headset
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX>? Even the sourest old-timer, however, will admit that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> is made like they used to be: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Jets</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Parcells</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Parcells</ENAMEX>
is performing his usual miracles during his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX> went <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1-15</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3-13</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>. So far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX>
has coached them to an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> record and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place in their conference, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>. Unless something goes horribly awry during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1997</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX> will
set a record for the biggest single-season improvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> history.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> is football's turnaround <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chainsaw Al</ENAMEX>"
Dunlap of the gridiron. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, "" took over the hopeless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX>
and led them to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> victories. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1993 and 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX>
transformed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Patriots</ENAMEX> from bottom-feeders to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">AFC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">champions</ENAMEX>. In
the entire history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>, only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Shula</ENAMEX> have coached two
different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>. You can bet that by the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> leaves
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>, he will have coached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> there.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Parcells</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">confuses football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. They can't figure out why he's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>. Some
coaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legends</ENAMEX> are chalkboard whizes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">49ers'</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Walsh</ENAMEX>
designed an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> that took the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> to figure out. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bears</ENAMEX>' terrifying "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> defense" cemented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ditka</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy Ryan</ENAMEX>'s
reputations. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> piggybacked to the top on star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>: Any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">idiot</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Switzer</ENAMEX> is that idiot--could have won a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> is an excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>'s-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>.
(He spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> as an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, much of it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Plains</ENAMEX>, where
they really know football.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of no grand
strategy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> to no great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> have been strong
offensively, others defensively. Some have passed a lot, others have run.
There's no single guiding principle to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. Sportswriters throw up their
hands and conclude with banalities: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> is a "great motivator" or a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>."

            
He is. But not in a touchy-feely way. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Parcells</ENAMEX>
is a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> for a reason that is now unfashionable in professional sports:
He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>. If modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro athletes</ENAMEX> subscribe to a political philosophy, it
is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayn Randism</ENAMEX>: What's in it for me? Free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and celebrity endorsements
have exaggerated the influence of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> played at the
whim of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches coach</ENAMEX> at the whim of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>,
traditionally the most team-oriented of pro sports, has fallen under the thrall
of individualism. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX>, for example, hot-dogging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Irvin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deion Sanders</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, guide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.

            Not so on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. A key fact: During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> coaching at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Point</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Academy</ENAMEX>. He conceives of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> as a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> give their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> vast freedom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> owns his: They submit
their will to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and to him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>", nearly <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">250 pounds</NUMEX>, and
aggressively confident, has the rare ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> takes over bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> because he can mold them in
his image. Winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> won't accept the kind of bullying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> dishes
out. Losing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> have no choice. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>, for
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> demanded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> spend most of their off-season in
training: Those who resisted--and some always did--got cut or traded.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Parcells</ENAMEX>
runs his training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> and practices with a drill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX>'s discipline: He
abuses and needles <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to inspire them. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last season</TIMEX>, for example, he
infuriated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">malingering rookie</ENAMEX> by calling him "she." ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">She</ENAMEX>," wide receiver
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Glenn</ENAMEX>, recovered and went on to break the rookie record for catches in a
season.) After a lackadaisical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> went <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3-12-1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> cut or traded
half the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> was one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> to impose
mandatory drug tests. He forbids his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant coaches</ENAMEX> from talking to , and
discourages his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> from doing so.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> discourages stardom: Everyone's
ego--except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX>'-- is sublimated for the good of the whole. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> . (In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX>' coaching career, he has had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> who can
legitimately be called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebacker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Taylor</ENAMEX>. Usually
he collects role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>.)

            The
result: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> has had the most disciplined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
commit fewer penalties than almost any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s win
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX> committed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>.) They have fewer disciplinary
problems, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> weeds out the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX>. They have fewer injuries,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> so emphasizes conditioning. And, while this sounds like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cliché</ENAMEX>, it's undoubtedly true: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> makes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> believe they can win,
so they do. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX> went <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> in games decided by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than six</TIMEX>
points; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-1.

            Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> who stick with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> adore his tough love.
(It's significant that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatorade Dump</ENAMEX>," where the victorious team dumps a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bucket of Gatorade</ENAMEX> on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, was invented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>.) In a league
where head <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches delegate</ENAMEX> everything to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> makes a policy
of trying to talk to every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. When some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> players
had drug problems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> at a rehab <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, scouting if it was
good enough for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> follow him
loyally from city to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant coaches</ENAMEX> were
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>; at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>, he has enlisted former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to
coach his running backs, kickers, and tight ends.

            Like all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> hates to be controlled himself. He has repeatedly
feuded with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> about running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. He quit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> partly because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> and general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> cramped him. His battle
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kraft</ENAMEX> was .

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> has an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>'s relationship with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>. He likes to say, "There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> emotions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>--euphoria
and death." When he graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, he turned down a chance to
play for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Lions</ENAMEX> so that he could start his coaching career. Since
then, he has never managed to do anything but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>. Once he took a year off to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> real estate: He hated it. After he quit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, he spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcaster</ENAMEX>: It bored him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> vacations little during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">off-season</ENAMEX>: He can't relax, worrying that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> are working harder. His
only outside interests are golf and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Both get ignored during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> season.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> once said he
"couldn't live without <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>." Even so, he keeps hinting that his career is
winding down. He's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>. When he signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 6-year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14.4-million</NUMEX> contract with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>, he said the job would be his last. Let's hope not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ditka</ENAMEX> is on
his way out the door. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Madden</ENAMEX> has long since ascended to the press box.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> are an increasingly sterile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> calls them
"computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>." In an age where computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are winning everywhere else,
it's nice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Parcells</ENAMEX> is still around to pound them on the gridiron.

         
      
   
