
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>

            Given the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaper</ENAMEX> has been picking off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> should probably
dry-clean his tux, polish his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guccis</ENAMEX>, and get ready for his limo ride to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Casino</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>'s weak heart has sent him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
twice in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, and there are rumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 4</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbara</ENAMEX>, are already feuding over who
controls his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have put the
finishing touches on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> tributes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sinatra</ENAMEX>
has always said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dyin</ENAMEX>' is a pain in the ass," but it may not be so bad.
Dying, as living, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> is right where he's always liked to
be: at the center of attention. Unlike fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooners</ENAMEX> (notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> hunk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> has transcended irony and avoided kitsch. Music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and
the record-buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, who don't agree about much, agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> is the
greatest popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history.

            And, as the media report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every few days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> is cool
again. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> Duets album--in which he sings his greatest hits with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther Vandross</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U2</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX> (click to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> and Bono
tackle "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I've Got You Under My Skin"</ENAMEX>)--has sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 million</NUMEX> copies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, far more than any of his earlier recordings. The hit movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swingers</ENAMEX> paid slavish tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> lounge culture. Recent articles
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> and elsewhere have depicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rat Pack</ENAMEX> as
the acme of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cool.

            Sinatraism
has become the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> religion at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Details</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later this fall</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Zehme</ENAMEX> will release
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Way You Wear Your Hat</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost Art of Livin'</ENAMEX> (his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apostrophe</ENAMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">245</NUMEX>-page guide to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankness</ENAMEX>. Zehme instructs on swaggers,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cocktails</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> tips, street fights, and seductions. (All should be frequent.)
This <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> for the sleek, prosperous, cigar-swilling,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">martini-puffing '90s</ENAMEX>, a tonic for political correctness. His misogyny and
promiscuity have been recast as healthy libido, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> ties and thuggery as
macho. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. How could you not admire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who bedded Lana
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ava Gardner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Farrow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Ekberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlene Dietrich</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX>?

            
So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> is cool again. Well, Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> has always been "cool again." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> rose and fell as a teen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">idol</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s</TIMEX>, then returned to stardom in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '50s</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1953</TIMEX> and
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'60s</TIMEX>, he made his best records, scored most of his biggest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billboard</ENAMEX> hits, gave his finest film performances ( The Manchurian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Here to Eternity</ENAMEX> , for which he won an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Award), and exerted the greatest political and cultural influence. (Some
particularly enthusiastic, daft <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> fans credit him with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>
election victory, claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> helped line up the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob behind JFK</ENAMEX>.)

            Since
that peak, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> nostalgia has been a cottage industry of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every few years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> is "rediscovered." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> himself doesn't change;
what changes is the way we choose to perceive him. He's a national Rorschach
test: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> periodically concocts a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> to fit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> .

            Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s rebirth as "cool" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>. He
came back as a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me Generation icon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rat Packer</ENAMEX> reincarnated as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">individualist</ENAMEX>. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '60s</TIMEX> albums, dismissed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> attempts to ape rock
when they debuted, were now applauded for their courageous, free-spirit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">experimentalism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> harked back to his original popularity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s</TIMEX>,
noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> had helped to end the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Band</ENAMEX> era and usher in the age of
the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. His signature song, after all, was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Way</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to
hear him sing it.)

            When punk
broke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> was reborn again--this time as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Proto-Punk</ENAMEX>,
popular music's first great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> had been one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> to
start his own record label (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reprise</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>): This was recognized in the late
'70s as proof of his artistic integrity and a kick in the smug face of
corporate music. His brawling and boozing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX> presaged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">punks</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brawling</ENAMEX> and boozing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob</ENAMEX> ties supposedly
demonstrated his flouting of authority. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sex Pistols' Sid Vicious</ENAMEX> recorded
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Way</ENAMEX>," a bizarre combination of homage and scorn.

            
His next incarnation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganite</ENAMEX>. Through the
'80s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> palled around with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>, and his usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of . The punk
became <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ol' Blue Eyes</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganites</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> symbolized all that was once
right about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> (and would be again after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> of supply-side
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>): classy music, machismo, bonhomie, and good times. (The right's
embrace of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> inspired the oddest chapter in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> cycle: a
counterclaim by the left. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and others tried to redeem
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, advertising his early support of civil rights, his
assistance to black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> before such help became fashionable, his
opposition to McCarthyism, and his failed attempt to break the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacklist</ENAMEX>.)

            There's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>
phenomenon that keeps repeating itself: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>, rumors of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob</ENAMEX> ties were family entertainment. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX>'s dishy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">His Way</ENAMEX> , confirmed most of the nasty gossip about his love
life. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later this month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behind the Legend</ENAMEX> , a new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">warts</ENAMEX>-and-all
(and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">warts</ENAMEX>) biography, will hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Author J. Randy Taraborrelli</ENAMEX>
has been somewhat cagey, but early reports suggest that the book will be full
of salacious details about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX>, other
extracurricular activities, and an aborted <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob</ENAMEX> hit on him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giancana</ENAMEX> allegedly canceled the hit after hearing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> album.

         
      
   
