
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bronfman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bronfman</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bronfmans</ENAMEX>, senior
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>, are always great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, and never more than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bronfman Sr.</ENAMEX>--in his role of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Aged Wisdom</ENAMEX>--has just published
Good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Spirits</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Making of a Businessman</ENAMEX> , a memoir brimming with
self-congratulatory tales of his business acumen and generosity. (When he's not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patting</ENAMEX> himself on the back, he has no trouble finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do it for him.
Thanks to his relentless and ongoing pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> have dubbed him, only half-jokingly, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfman Jr.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youthful Folly</ENAMEX>), meanwhile, has been busy running <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfman-</ENAMEX>managed liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX>--into the ground. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years ago</TIMEX>, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liquidated Seagram</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX> stake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> to buy the entertainment giant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> has been a horrific month for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of
its top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> were sacked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. It has released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">flop</TIMEX> after flop
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jackal , Primary Colors</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury Rising</ENAMEX> ), and there is
no relief on the horizon: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> doesn't have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> blockbuster to
compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> keeps promising
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> will turn fabulous profits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>, but no one is
buying. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is overflowing with rumors that someone--anyone--is planning
to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX> and run it properly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX> stock, dragged
down by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>, is stagnating through the biggest bull market in history.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> stock, on the other hand, has more than doubled in value since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> sold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram's DuPont</ENAMEX> interest: This has cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX>.)

            Usually <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few billion dollars</NUMEX> in the bank inoculates you
against bad press, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> has been designated the movie industry's
official idiot--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who's squandering his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>') fortune on romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tinseltown</ENAMEX> fantasies. There is a feeling
that any real media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Diller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>--could eat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> for lunch and still have plenty
of room for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX>.

            A certain
aura of creeping decay does surround the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfmans</ENAMEX>, and it is tempting to view
them as a study in dynastic decline. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Bronfman</ENAMEX>, the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, was an utterly implacable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atilla of</ENAMEX>
liquor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distilleries</ENAMEX> and seedy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '20s</TIMEX>, then cashed in on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Prohibition. He supplied <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bootleggers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer Lansky</ENAMEX> was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX> was lifted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> was one of the most powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distillers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 30 years</TIMEX>, he bullied employees
and terrorized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX> an international liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">powerhouse</ENAMEX>.

            
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-generation <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfman</ENAMEX> was
entrepreneurial and ruthless. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> was managerial and
generous. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX> expanded overseas and extended itself into
real estate and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>. Sound financial practices and organized marketing
campaigns replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s seat-of-the-pants management. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> had concentrated
power in himself; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX> learned to delegate it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX>
also made the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfmans</ENAMEX> the most celebrated name in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropy</ENAMEX>. Since
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '70s</TIMEX>, he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> have been distributing their fortune
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> causes, endowing professorships, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, and scholarships in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. (I challenge you to find an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who
studied in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and received no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfman</ENAMEX> aid.) He also appointed himself the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to the world. He paid off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Jewish Congress</ENAMEX>' debt,
took over its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidency</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, and used it as his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> for action. His
wealth and fame were an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX>. He pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>. He and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WJC</ENAMEX> exposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Waldheim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> past in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'80s</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX> harassed and condemned the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> so
effectively that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waldheim</ENAMEX> tried to sue him. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX>
has been hunting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> who profited from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> evil and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> sorrow.
He recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX> to hold hearings on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> misdeeds, persuaded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to investigate, and eventually forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> to pony
up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 billion</NUMEX> to compensate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.

            If there is a defining quality of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, it
appears to be self-indulgence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> skipped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> for showbiz, using his
family money to open doors. The doors should not have opened: He produced a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of bad movies and wrote even worse songs. He also eloped with an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>. In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-20s</TIMEX>, after a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flop</ENAMEX>, he returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX> as heir
apparent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> soldiered along there during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. He was a competent
liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>, but his love of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> never wavered.

            Then his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> handed him the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. According to Good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Spirits</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> felt
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> was a "boring investment." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Though DuPont</ENAMEX> supplied most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX>'s
profits, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX> had a minority, not a controlling, stake in the chemical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> wanted to be in movies--an information business, not a raw
materials one. First, he bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, amassing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of its stock
in an aborted takeover. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> he closed the romantic but costly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>
deal.

            
But the saga of dynastic decline is not quite
so simple. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is not quite the icon he seems, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is not quite
the flake. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> is mocked for his playboy instincts, but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX>
who has been married <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX>, but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX> who is bullying and grandiose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soft-spoken</ENAMEX> and self-effacing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX> deplores the assimilation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as a
"silent <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>," but he barely observes the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> religion, married three
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and named his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> after himself, a major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> no-no. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> is
pilloried for dragging a liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> into the film industry, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Sr.</ENAMEX>
did it first. He tried to take over a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s</TIMEX> and even
ran <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX> briefly.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>,
obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX>'s infatuation with movies, have missed his real
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX>'s failing is not that he's too romantic about the
movies but that he's too rational about them. To wit: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this month</TIMEX>, he
outraged the industry by proposing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> charge higher prices for more
expensive movies. Why, he asked, should you pay the same amount to see a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> movie as you would to see a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> one? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> and movie types
hooted with derision--that's "like charging for a piece of art based on how
much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bronze</ENAMEX> or paint was used," sneered one.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> wants to treat movies like any other product: If
a movie costs more to produce, you should charge more for it. From a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>, movies are unreliable: No one can predict if a film will make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> or lose it. Studio share prices are erratic because there are no
guaranteed earnings: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> that makes a killing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> may get killed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> accept this instability as the cost of doing
business.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfman</ENAMEX> doesn't, at least
not yet. Most of his moves at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>--such as his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>
"re-engineering" project--seem directed toward making movies behave like, well,
liquor. He wants to find the secret rational formula that will connect movie
costs to movie revenues. It's an impossible task. The formula doesn't exist.
Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> will always be more fickle than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey drinkers</ENAMEX>, and movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> will always be less reliable than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey blenders</ENAMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Jr.</ENAMEX> will
fail in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, but when he does, it won't be the failure of a romantic. It
will be the failure of someone much less interesting: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
