
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX>

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX> were a top
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>--and a fair bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> probably wishes she were--she
would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> speaks, he roils financial markets.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> speaks, she roils--well, everything else. Consider the trial she is
now enduring in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cattlemen</ENAMEX> claim that, upon learning the
dangers of mad-cow <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> uttered a single on-air sentence--"It has
just stopped me cold from eating another <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burger</ENAMEX>!"--that punctured <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
irrational exuberance for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>. Beef prices reeled, and cattlemen lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> claim that the beef swoon was the product of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">droughts</ENAMEX> and high feed prices.)

            Perhaps
book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> should foot her legal bills in the beef trial: Each time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>
selects a new novel for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> blesses her name. A
word from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>, and a novel sells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> copies rather than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 16</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> picked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. The novel
shot to No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> best-seller list, just as several
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX> selections before it had. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> previous picks remain on the
paperback-best-seller list. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> went fitness crazy, books by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX>
and her personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> became nationwide hits. Marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> now
routinely refer to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Effect</ENAMEX>."

            The effect is felt not only by blessed merchandise but also
by the star herself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> has owned the No. 1 talk show in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for
more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>. Her movie debut in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Color Purple</ENAMEX> netted her an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> nomination. She's the highest-paid entertainer in the world, worth well
over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400 million</NUMEX>. And she's thinner than you.

            But of
course, she is a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>-talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, and it's conventional wisdom that
daytime talk shows are deplorable. The shows parade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> in front of the
viewing public. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ricki Lake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> have hiked their ratings by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">showcasing</ENAMEX> increasingly repulsive molesters, abusers, adulterers, and
pederasts, all of them eager to tell the world about their loathsomeness. Talk
shows are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zenith of America</ENAMEX>'s nauseating confessional culture.

            
Among those righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> who don't watch the
shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> is lumped with the garbage. But she doesn't belong. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> stopped booking freak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. It was a huge ratings risk, but her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> stuck with her. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX> has resorted to hawking Too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot</ENAMEX> for TV
videotapes featuring awkward nudity and grim violence-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> , sans
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">freaks</ENAMEX>, continues to win handily in the ratings.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> and, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, this is the problem. She is
indeed the leading practitioner of confessional television. When she lost
weight, she rolled a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative wagon</ENAMEX> of pig fat onstage. She routinely
breaks down in tears, and she never hesitates to let us know when things go
wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stedman</ENAMEX>, her longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beau</ENAMEX>.

            So what redeems <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>? How does her confessional television
differ from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Donahue</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX>'s? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> is the confessor, that's how.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donahues</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springers</ENAMEX> of the world remain aloof, above and separate from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> confess, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> oppress, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> laughs its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> off. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> for the miserable, benighted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. It's the zoo theory of television: Let's make fun of these stupid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>
doesn't condescend to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. She couldn't possibly: When her show featured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of sexual abuse, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> revealed that she'd been abused, too. When she
talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>, she admitted to having tried the drug herself.
Imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donahue</ENAMEX> revealing his drug habit or his scarred emotions ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> there? We're talking about my junkie days"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> is one of the very
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> who owes her fame not to her superhuman qualities (beauty,
athletic ability, etc.) but to her human frailties. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> has said, "One of my
greatest assets is knowing I'm no different from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>." For female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> is also one of the very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>
who hasn't forgotten where she came from. She identifies with underdogs because
she was the underest-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> of them all. She came from less than nowhere: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>,
she was born illegitimate, poor, female, and black in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jim Crow Mississippi</ENAMEX>.
Several male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family members</ENAMEX> sexually abused her. Overcoming these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> has
lent her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> cred with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. They make her success always
astonishing and rarely begrudged.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> lends her fame and
fortune to the right causes. She <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors girls</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX> projects and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endows</ENAMEX> scholarships to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morehouse College</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX>. Some
black female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne Warwick</ENAMEX>) shill for phone-psychic scams that exploit
poor black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>? She started a book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. (Her taste, incidentally, has
been impeccable: No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gray</ENAMEX>; lots of interesting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underpublicized</ENAMEX> novels. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Kazin</ENAMEX> jowled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> represents the
"carpet bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> mind," but even a stuffed shirt like Kazin
can't complain when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 million</NUMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> are urged to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX> and
do.)

            Despite the ban on cameras
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> trial is starting to resemble an episode on her
show. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, a witness collapsed in tears while apologizing to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranchers</ENAMEX>. My hunch is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> will win over even the cattlemen, eventually.
During the trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> is recording her show in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX>, a town supposedly
devastated by her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>-bashing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Locals</ENAMEX> have been lining up for tickets.

         
      
   
