
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flytrap Tonight: That Was an Apology</ENAMEX>?

            I just watched the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s speech at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonah Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. It is here that Lucianne
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> first met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> and here that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Isikoff</ENAMEX>
refused to listen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> tapes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, in short, is the
safe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of the vast right-wing conspiracy. I figure there's no better place
to watch the climax of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> than the place where it began.

            Jonah,
who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> but not an ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul mate</ENAMEX>, has stocked the apartment
with conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX>, and they are in high glee. This is a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of
vindication for them, not a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of magnanimity. Jonah answers the phone
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloating Central</ENAMEX>," and during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> pregame show, every appearance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> is greeted with hoots of laughter. This is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of
average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who are supposed to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apologize, forgive him,
and--to use the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s phrase--"move on with their lives." It does not
surprise me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech wasn't enough for them: Nothing he could say
would have been enough for them. But it does surprise me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech
wasn't enough for me. I arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonah's</ENAMEX> in a forgiving mood: Let's get this
over with. I left a bit puzzled.

            As theater, the Map Room talk was a minor masterpiece.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> looked fresh despite his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">horrible afternoon</TIMEX>. He wore a fine blue power
suit. He wisely kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> out of the picture: Any awkwardness between them
would have been disastrous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Map Room</ENAMEX> was the right choice: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>
would have been presumptuous and seamy (Where's that private study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>?).

            But as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apology</ENAMEX>, this was a feeble effort. Nobody expected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> to make a baldfaced
confession: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to know if their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is a lech.
I am a lech. " But I think almost everyone expected him to at least admit
it. I certainly did. It may have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mea culpa</ENAMEX> , but there wasn't much
culpa to show for it. He sounded angry, not sorry. He conceded an
"inappropriate" relationship. He allowed that he has "misled" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. He "took complete responsibility." But all those are champion weasel
expressions. What does it mean to "take complete responsibility"? Do you
actually have to do anything painful when you take it? What is an
"inappropriate" relationship? Is it sexual? What's the difference between
misleading and lying? (My favorite <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moment of the evening</TIMEX> came when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> pundits
tried to parse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comments about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> deposition. They gave
up, baffled. His words defy comprehension. He believes language is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> of
confusion.)

            
Instead of turning belly up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> followed
the golden rule of spin: When you're explaining, you're losing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
who has always felt more comfortable attacking than defending, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artfully</ENAMEX> turned
his apology into a broadside against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>. (He did this despite endless
pregame predictions that he would leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> alone. By the way, was anyone who
has ever expressed an opinion about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> not on television <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>?
At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point I counted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> separate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, most of them on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>
Live .)

            Out of
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four minutes</TIMEX> for which he spoke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about one minute</TIMEX> explaining
himself and the rest complaining about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, the intrusion upon his private
life, and the distraction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> from serious matters. The speech was
less about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sins than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stella culpa</ENAMEX> , as it were.

            This raises the curious paradox about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Map Room</ENAMEX> speech.
As argument, it was unassailable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is absolutely correct that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
investigations have "gone on too long, cost too much, and hurt too many
innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." He is absolutely correct that his personal life has been
invaded in ways that no one's should. He is absolutely correct that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">horribly</ENAMEX> distracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, and the public from critical
issues of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. (These points are not only true, they are also poll-tested.)
But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> was not <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> to make such arguments. He should have left the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> bashing to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX> was doing a superb job of it.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> for
abject apology, for contrition, for explanation. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> to eat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crow</ENAMEX>. It's a bit much for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> after he finished testifying, to
start impugning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s credibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, after all, is one who lied to us.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is the one who screwed (or whatever) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 22-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intern</ENAMEX> and tried
to cover it up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is the one who has delayed and stonewalled us for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.

            For the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few weeks</TIMEX> at regular intervals, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have been telling
us that we are a forgiving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I'm sure they're right. But can you forgive
someone who hasn't really asked for forgiveness?

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flytrap Today": The complete chronicles</ENAMEX>.

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
