
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">secretary-general</ENAMEX> is traditionally a refuge for knaves, lickspittles, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">villains</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Waldheim</ENAMEX>'s case, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> at once). So <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are
entitled to surprise at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s deft diplomacy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warmongers</ENAMEX> had warned
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> would give away the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> to appease <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. But the
soft-spoken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> gave away nothing and got much. His persistent,
polite diplomacy revived weapons inspections (which have eliminated far more
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> than the war did); calmed nerves throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world; and
saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> from an ill-conceived, unpopular bombing
plan--all without an apparently meaningful concession to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            More important, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>
accomplished all this in a way that brought glory to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>: He
announced--emphatically--that the negotiations would have been fruitless
without the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military threat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> gains credit for diplomatic
restraint; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> gains credit for keeping the peace; the will of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> is enforced; and the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> weapons
continues. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> reneges on the agreement--which is likely--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> has lost nothing but time: There will be far more support for bombing if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein flouts Annan</ENAMEX> than there was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> was simply flouting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> is the perfect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> for an age of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">triumphalism</ENAMEX>. It used to be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War stymied the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> does. It is dominant in
politics, economics, culture. To the rest of the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy is
"We're Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>-ism"--an insufferable combination of gloating and bullying.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has its own ill feelings toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> of meddlesome, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">nags</ENAMEX>
plotting for world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. (In some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' eyes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>'
principal accomplishment is collecting loose change during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNICEF</ENAMEX>'s
trick-or-treat fund drives.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> got his biggest round of applause during
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> presidential campaign when he mocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros</ENAMEX>
Boutros-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ghali</ENAMEX>'s name. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, threatened to stop all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding for the United Nations</ENAMEX>, and many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> have proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> withdrawal.

            Since he
took over as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> has begun to do the
improbable: restore <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s faith in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>' faith in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> has shelved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> ambitions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is building an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> we can live with, one that
is smaller, better run, and more deferential to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            On paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> isn't a promising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to reunite the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. He is too attached to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>,
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> to rise from inside its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>. (This does not
exactly recommend him to anyone outside that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>.) He has spent
his life as an "international civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX>," a phrase that conjures an image
of someone wasting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of U.S. dollars</NUMEX> pushing paper around the Third
World (which is basically what he did).

            Born to a
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ghana</ENAMEX>--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a hereditary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> attended
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macalester College</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Foundation</ENAMEX> grant. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ghana's</ENAMEX> promising democracy collapsed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>, like many
bright young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Africans</ENAMEX>, decided to remain overseas. He went to work for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, rising gradually through the ranks at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Commission on Refugees</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secretariat</ENAMEX>. Eventually
he supervised peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">languorous U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> earned a reputation as someone who actually
Got Things Done. Thanks to his straightforward manner and overwhelming decency,
he was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> to survive
with his reputation unharmed. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> decided to dump
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1996</TIMEX>, everyone touted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> as the compromise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to replace him. (Everyone, that is, except the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. They wanted a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Francophone Africa</ENAMEX>.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is a true internationalist: He speaks
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, and several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> languages fluently. He has lived in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geneva</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Accra</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, among other places. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish</ENAMEX> (the niece of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raoul Wallenberg</ENAMEX>, in fact). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is an
internationalist with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> inflection. He was educated here, he loves
living here--and, according to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, he'll probably retire here.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">secretary-general</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, someone who needs to be independent enough to take
the initiative but tractable enough to heed his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> (that is, the
member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is well suited to this dual role. For example: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
have been demanding management reform for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is the technocrat
who may do it--after all, he has a management degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s recent
reform package cuts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> jobs from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>-person <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secretariat</ENAMEX>, slashes
administrative costs by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX>, and streamlines the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>' absurd
bureaucracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is pushing merit-based promotion and management training,
ancient ideas that are new to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> hasn't
cut enough; others say he has cut too much. In other words, he's doing it just
right. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> kept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> in
uniform. Now, post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, and post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>, there are
barely <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is the world's most gentlemanly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. Where
Boutros-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ghali</ENAMEX> was highhanded and arrogant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is gentle, soft-spoken, calm.
Boutros-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ghali</ENAMEX> spoke English poorly, rarely visited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and
regularly berated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misbehavior</ENAMEX>. He was vicious without being tough. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Annan</ENAMEX>
is tough without being vicious. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would never have let
Boutros-Ghali negotiate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>. He was too reckless, too erratic, too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-American</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> has formed a strong friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>. She and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> could trust him to win peace without
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appeasement</ENAMEX>.

            For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thrive</ENAMEX>, it's not enough that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> trust it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
must also trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. That is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s next test. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
reputation is at an ebb in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Plaza</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> owes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> peacekeeping dues. These arrears are crippling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>, which gets a quarter of its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.6-billion</NUMEX> budget from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has already curtailed essential activities, and may be
forced to shut down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't pay.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> has been trying to pry
the cash out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> since he took office. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last fall</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> all but
OK'd a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1-billion</NUMEX> payout. Then a few conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> killed the funding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> by attaching an unacceptable anti-abortion amendment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> visits
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to push again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> is on his side. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is on his
side. And--perhaps the best indication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s appeal--even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> is
on his side. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two years ago</TIMEX> threatened to end all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> funding,
was charmed when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> called on him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>, too, favors settling the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> debt. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> can get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> to fall in line, he is doing something right.

         
      
   
