
   
   
      
         
            The (Not Yet) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Around-the-World Balloonists</ENAMEX>

            Of all the sorry moments in
the around-the-world balloon "race"--and God knows there have been --the
sorriest occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Hilton</ENAMEX> balloon burst a
helium <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">70 minutes</TIMEX> after takeoff, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Rutan</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-pilot</ENAMEX> were
forced to bail out at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">11,000 feet</NUMEX>. They parachuted directly into a cactus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">patch</ENAMEX>. Rutan, you may remember, is one of the true adventurers of the age: In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, he piloted the Voyager airplane on its astonishing nonstop,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">around-the-world</TIMEX> journey. Now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years later</TIMEX>, the aviation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> is picking
cactus spines out of his face, the latest casualty of the world's most
pointless competition. What is the great balloon race? The irrepressible
pursuing the irrelevant.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> sped around the world by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX> has squandered plenty of
his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's Cup</ENAMEX> yachts. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ballooning is the pastime of
the gentleman adventurer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter</ENAMEX> is around-the-world balloon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>--it's when
the jet stream runs consistently west to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX>--so the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few weeks</TIMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">witnessed</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX> will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, an orgy of circumnavigation
attempts. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutan</ENAMEX>'s crash, commodities <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Fossett</ENAMEX>
gave up his effort when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> ran out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days</TIMEX>
before that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Uliassi</ENAMEX> aborted his flight after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> blew
a hole during takeoff. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX> eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX> (whose last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> took off without him) and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertrand</ENAMEX>
Piccard are each expected to launch their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX> airships.
Uliassi, too, wants to relaunch his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonists</ENAMEX> have captured the public imagination, and
not without reason. The nonstop, around-the-world balloon flight is the only
remaining aviation milestone. The expeditions make great television: They
unfold slowly over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>, and the visuals of sun-kissed balloons are
fabulous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonists</ENAMEX> seem genuinely heroic: They endure cramped quarters
and subzero temperatures, and they face real danger. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belarus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> shot
down a racing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX>, killing its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> are all thought to be hostile to balloon flyovers. And there is something
charmingly antiquated about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>. (No ballooning story is complete
without reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phileas Fogg</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Around the World in Eighty Days</ENAMEX> . So
here it is.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX>, hearkening back to the aviation prizes of the
'20s, has ponied up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to circumnavigate by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonist</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> of his choice).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Balloonists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are calling the race the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Great Adventure</ENAMEX>."
But that phrase does violence to the notion of adventure. Once upon a time,
adventuring was a purposeful activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magellan</ENAMEX> circled the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> in order to
open it to trade, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> went west to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Flying
adventurers, too, recorded genuine, necessary accomplishments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lindbergh</ENAMEX>'s crossing wasn't just a stunt: It made real the idea of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transatlantic</ENAMEX> air travel. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' around-the-world flights made real the idea
of global air travel. Even Voyager had a scientific aim: It vindicated
the notion of ultralight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and proved the value of ultralight
materials.

            
The around-the-world balloon race, by contrast,
is a nonsensical exercise. We have climbed as high as we can and sunk as deep
as we can. We've gone as far north as possible and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far</NUMEX> south. We've broken
the sound barrier on land and in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, circled the globe by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and by air.
Now it has come to this. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> race is the hot-dog-eating contest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">aviation.</ENAMEX> No one has ever bothered to break the ballooning record because
there's no reason to do it. Balloons are a uniquely terrible mode of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>: They are impossible to steer, slow, and dangerous. They are
also hideously expensive. The journey has no real-world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>. Passenger
balloons can contribute nothing to transportation or science. Will a successful
circumnavigation usher in an era of commercial balloon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>?

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insignificance</ENAMEX> is a shame, because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s adventurers are as brave as their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonists</ENAMEX> are adrenalin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX>, but brainy ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> behind <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin</ENAMEX>, is as bold with his life as with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. He
has crossed both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> by speedboat and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX>.
Along the way he's crashed in (and been rescued from) the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canadian Arctic</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fossett</ENAMEX> (who's worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $25 million to $50 million</NUMEX>) is equally
insouciant: He has driven in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Mans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-Hour</TIMEX> Race, raced sled <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> in the
Iditarod, completed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ironman</ENAMEX> triathlon, run an ultramarathon, and set the
ballooning distance and endurance records. Rutan was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter jock</ENAMEX> and
test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piccard</ENAMEX> is a champion hang-glider and professional balloon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">racer</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piccard</ENAMEX>'s family history is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Exhibit No. 1</ENAMEX> in the decline of the great
adventure. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auguste Piccard</ENAMEX> invented the submersible bathyscaph
and was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to balloon into the stratosphere. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques</ENAMEX>
Piccard, set the underwater depth record in another submersible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques</ENAMEX> also
invented the tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX>. The third-generation <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piccard</ENAMEX>, no less a
daredevil, is reduced to competitive ballooning.)

            Balloon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piccard</ENAMEX>, or Rutan decent odds
to complete the circumnavigation, eventually: All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> have pressurized
gondolas that allow them to travel fast through the high jet stream. All have
deep pockets. There are doubts about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fossett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uliassi</ENAMEX>, who fly in
unpressurized gondolas: Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloons</ENAMEX> must travel slowly, at lower altitudes,
and they are more exposed to the cold. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fossett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uliassi</ENAMEX> are also flying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solo</ENAMEX>, making them vulnerable to fatigue on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two-week</TIMEX> trip.

            In any case, let's hope that
someone finishes the race soon, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonists</ENAMEX> can move on to
something worthwhile--such as, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars Prize</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> wants a manned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">outpost</ENAMEX>. Instead of giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400 billion</NUMEX> to build one, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> has
suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> offer a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20-billion</NUMEX> reward for the private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> that does it first. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX> has mulled over the idea of going into
space. Why not the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Red Planet</ENAMEX>? (Its color, after all, matches his omnipresent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virgin</ENAMEX> logo.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars Prize</ENAMEX>--that's an adventure worthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX>'s courage.
And that's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> could actually use.

         
      
   
