
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>

            My favorite story about
acting happened <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> before the filming of a crucial scene in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marathon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX> had to appear physically exhausted, so
half <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> before the shoot, he jogged rapidly <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three, four</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times around
the reservoir, then staggered up to his co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Olivier</ENAMEX>, and gasped
that he was ready. Baffled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olivier</ENAMEX>'s nonchalance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>, still breathing
hard, asked him how he prepared for a scene. "Prepare<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olivier</ENAMEX> replied,
carefully setting down his cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> and languidly rising from his chair. "I
don't prepare. I pretend."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason I love the story
is that it so symmetrically counters the usual assumptions about the difference
between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> acting--the spill-your-guts <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and the
technically polished <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> search for "emotional truth" and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English</ENAMEX> displays of mere skill. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>, for all his straining after
naturalistic verisimilitude, remained dependent on acting-class exercises,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olivier</ENAMEX>, for all his years of training, had so deeply integrated
technique into his being that, like a classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX>, he could stop thinking
about it the moment he began performing. In short, it's the difference between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>--between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Close</ENAMEX> proficiently performing her character's
attributes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ("Look at me, I'm acting!") and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlon Brando</ENAMEX> intuitively
discovering his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s essence ("Look at me, I'm alive!") and conveying
all his ambiguities and contradictions simultaneously.

            These
thoughts were occasioned by what I regard as without question the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enthralling</ENAMEX> performances of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>--and I hasten to temper such a
superlative with a dose of irony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX>' performance in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Shawn</ENAMEX>'s
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Designated Mourner</ENAMEX> (the filmed version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> production of
the play) has been universally praised but, by the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> roll around
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next March</TIMEX>, will surely be overlooked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet McTeer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> performance in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibsen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Doll's House</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, has been both widely honored
and roundly reviled--she won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX> for best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>, but among
the reviews were several sputtering fulminations.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Designated Mourner</ENAMEX> ,
is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate student</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> literature who, in his own description,
"went downhill from there." His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>, are members
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX> in an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the near future, and the
story--told by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> seated at a table in direct address to the
camera--involves the gradual destruction of their lives by an oppressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regime</ENAMEX>, and the moral disintegration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>, the eponymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX>. A man
characterized by envy and cynicism, superficial wit and subterranean rage,
ceaseless introspection and emotional detachment, insufferable smugness and
barely concealed self-loathing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> is a bundle of apparent
contradictions.

            In describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>'
interpretation, the problem of technique immediately arises, because to give
examples of specific line readings suggests that he's merely made a sequence of
acting choices, when what makes his performance so engrossing is his ability to
embody all these aspects of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> at once. Now cynicism comes to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fore</ENAMEX>, now rage, now a brief interlude of tenderness, but their opposites also
are always present--for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> is embodying the character, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s
characteristics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watch Nichols</ENAMEX> in his most typical gesture. He ducks his chin
onto his chest, bobs his head back and forth, gulps as if stifling a burp, then
suddenly lifts his head and expresses a thought that not only seems to have
just occurred to him, but which also seems to have struggled with conflicting
emotions before emerging. A technique, certainly, but one so expressive of
character that it never occurs to us that he's reciting a text. At times he
speaks in short, halting phrases, pausing between the most unlikely words, and
then he'll rush through a series of phrases so quickly that he'll nearly run
out of breath and almost gasp out the last words--rhythm as characterization,
his cadences revealing the contours of his troubled spirit as concisely as his
words.

            It's
tempting to go on for paragraphs. How can one overlook the abruptly truncated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laugh</ENAMEX>, for instance, that conveys a perplexed intellect? Or the voice suddenly
shifting from silky to raspy when derision erupts from his muddled emotions?
But each moment remains significant only as it traces the trajectory of his
spiritual deterioration. Finally, when he learns that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> has been murdered,
he can barely breathe, his anguish seems nearly unendurable, but it's only a
momentary spasm, he regains his soulless equanimity, and as he quietly intones
his last lines--"The greatest pleasure in life [is] the sweet, ever-changing
caress of an early <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> breeze"--we realize we've witnessed the exquisitely
ironic fusion of elegy and despair, the inseparable linking of a brilliant text
and a superb performance.

            
Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> would like to play the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legendary Nora</ENAMEX> but, for much of the first act, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet McTeer</ENAMEX> seems to want to
play the most irritating. She's an unusually sexy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>, but in an annoyingly
kittenish way: flighty and fluttery, as the role calls for, but with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whimpering</ENAMEX> and giggling nervousness. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>, we begin to think, isn't so
much a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> as a collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">manic mannerisms</ENAMEX>. But we gradually realize that
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>, in fact, is playing the role that's expected of her--merely "playing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tricks</ENAMEX>," as she says in the last act--and that there's another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> beneath the
childlike silliness that will astonish even her. There is so much she's not
allowed to experience, much less express--her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> intelligence, her creative
energy, her increasing unhappiness--so much that can emerge only in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distortion</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McTeer</ENAMEX>'s
bold choice to play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> as far more fraught than usual at the beginning of the
play--with a hyperanimation that, in her increasing frustration, becomes
nervous exhaustion and eventually a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hysterical dementia</ENAMEX>--allows her to
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>'s transformation at the end at once more plausible and more powerful.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have suggested that her performance--like most performances of the
role--turns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different and irreconcilable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, the domestic
doll and the feminist icon. But, on the contrary, she subtly provides the
psychological continuity between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> aspects of her character.

            In the opening scenes, for instance, even as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McTeer</ENAMEX> enacts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>'s dependence on her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, she shows the cunning that is the only outlet
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s acute and sensitive mind--submission as manipulation. This
is no ninny--this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> forbidden to use her intelligence. And even as she
proclaims her happiness, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McTeer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> reaches compulsively for her macaroons
with a hint of voracity that hints at her dissatisfaction.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>'s jittery, skittery
behavior is charming in a way. It's certainly the kind of self-abasing
flirtatiousness her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> finds seductive. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McTeer</ENAMEX>'s decision to play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>'s
marriage as erotically electric makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>'s decision to leave all the more
difficult, and all the more shattering.) But when her web of lies begins to
unravel and he calls her "pretty bird," she rolls her eyes in a gesture at once
accepting of his flattery, aware of her deceit, and resentful of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condescension</ENAMEX>. She knows nothing of this consciously but, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of such
gestures, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McTeer</ENAMEX> reveals the unconscious conflation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>'s conflicts--the
way her wildly unfocused energy is the consequence of her inner turmoil, of
both social oppression and emotional repression. Over and over, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McTeer</ENAMEX> portrays
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> with a capacity for feeling she herself refuses to recognize and a
capacity for insight frustrated by her familial role. When she hears herself
saying that being with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is "like being with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">papa</ENAMEX>," she pauses for a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, then flashes her eyes with something close to a recognition of primal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sin</ENAMEX>, utters a sound somewhere between a hysterical giggle and a shriek of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">horror</ENAMEX>, and rushes across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> as if in flight from her own words.

            By the
final confrontation with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McTeer</ENAMEX> has so skillfully foreshadowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>'s transformation that, though it seems bewilderingly abrupt to her, it
seems emotionally inevitable to us. Gone are her neurotic mannerisms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> now
sits in an ominous stillness. "I'm saved," her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says after the arrival
of the forgiving letter. "What about me?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> responds, with a touch of
meekness but at last with a sense of her separable self. Out of her stillness
she suddenly shrieks, not as an appeal but as a demand, "I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>!"
Most astonishingly--for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in my experience of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noras</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McTeer</ENAMEX> even manages to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>'s single most famous line ring true.
When her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> would sacrifice his integrity for another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> has to reply, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have"--an impossible
line for the character, a line in which it is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> speaking but Ibsen
himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McTeer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX>? She lowers her voice a full octave and intones the
words in a constrained fury--the voice not of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> but of wronged women
forever.

            
The trouble with this kind of detailed analysis
is it implies that any competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craftsman</ENAMEX> could carefully study the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">performer</ENAMEX>'s techniques and replicate them--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>'s "preparation." We can only
be grateful that they can't, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McTeer</ENAMEX> become rather than enact
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olivier</ENAMEX>'s "pretending." Perhaps all we can say of great
acting is that it involves assimilation rather than accumulation, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">performer</ENAMEX> isn't so much a surrogate as a vessel. There's paradox in artifice.
The supreme tragedies leave us not devastated but exhilarated, and the sublime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, the moment their performances begin, stop acting.

         
      
   
