
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meet John Doe</ENAMEX>

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of rebellion
gathered momentum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Zaire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> felt
obliged to offer a thumb-sucking retrospective on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s embattled and
dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu Sese Seko</ENAMEX>, who had held power for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. All the commentaries at some point brought up the subject of the
departing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s full name. Born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Désiré Mobutu</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>, he changed his
name, after consolidating his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>, to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu Sese Seko Kuku Ngbendu</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wa za Banga</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Lingala</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>, according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
press reports, the name means "the all-powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> who, because of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endurance</ENAMEX> and inflexible will to win, will go from conquest to conquest leaving
fire in his wake." An alternative translation, according to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> group of
reports, is "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cock</ENAMEX> whose prowess leaves no hen untouched."

            In an age
when national power inheres less and less frequently--or, at any rate, less and
less legitimately--in the hands of an all-powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, the adoption of
a symbolic personal name by way of an aggrandizing personal epithet has sadly
fallen out of favor. Among world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> of this
form of personal rule include <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez al-Assad</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assad</ENAMEX>" means "lion" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkmenistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turkmenbashi</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turkmens</ENAMEX>," the form of
address favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saparmurat Niyazov</ENAMEX>, the landlocked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>'s
opéra - bouffe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX> who has commissioned a stunted replica of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eiffel Tower</ENAMEX>, with a revolving statue of himself on top, for the center of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital city</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ashkhabad</ENAMEX>.

            Most of the world's remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monarchs</ENAMEX> possess a number of
colorful inherited titles (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Defender of the Faith</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX>, "Custodian
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> Holy Mosques" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>), but these are functional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">designations</ENAMEX> and little more than quaint vestigial appendages, like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>'s
arms. There is certainly no contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> with an adopted name as coldly
presumptuous as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin"</ENAMEX> (meaning "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>," an epithet adopted when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josef</ENAMEX>
Dzhugashvili was still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX> away from power), much less one
comparable with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard the Lionhearted</ENAMEX>" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vlad the Impaler</ENAMEX>." The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place
where adopted names retain an organic vitality is in occupations where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> can still claim some prestige based on a perception of personal
exploits or exotic capabilities, such as organized crime (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Grim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaper</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scarpa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gas Pipe</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casso</ENAMEX>) and pornographic entertainment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lipps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Scream</ENAMEX>--to name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the more serene).

            As
decision making has devolved from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autocrat</ENAMEX> to the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, it is
the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>--the anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everyman</ENAMEX>, an embodiment of rights and
responsibilities shared by all--whose name is increasingly invoked. There are a
number of generic possibilities. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> cartoon showed one
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> talking to another in an office near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>, and bore a
caption that read, "So what you're saying is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Sixpack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Blow</ENAMEX> are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>?" Yes--and he may also be "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Q. Public</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zilch</ENAMEX>," the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Common Man</ENAMEX>," and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unknown Citizen</ENAMEX>" invoked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.H. Auden</ENAMEX> in
his poem of that name. (The epitaph on the monument to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizen</ENAMEX> reads, in
part: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Press</ENAMEX> are convinced that he bought a paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>/ And that his
reactions to advertisements were normal in every way./ Policies taken out in
his name prove that he was fully insured,/ And his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>-card shows he was
once in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> but left cured.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>, and the others are probably also
related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose names are found on the credit cards and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s
licenses displayed in advertisements, and I assume they all know the mysterious
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Marts</ENAMEX>" whose name appears on dunning letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX>, above a
signature that looks like it was drawn on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etch-a-Sketch</ENAMEX>.

            
The most venerable among the common names in
the English-speaking world for an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male citizen</ENAMEX>, or indefinitely for
any male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doe"</ENAMEX>; and for his female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Roe</ENAMEX>."
Both names (along with the no-longer-common "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>-a-'nokes" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>-a-'stiles") derive from legal custom dating back almost to medieval
times, in cases where suit needed, for arcane reasons, to be filed against a
legally fictitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. They served precisely the same function that the
names "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaius</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titius</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seius</ENAMEX>" did in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Roe</ENAMEX>,
and a handful of similar variants are used <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to shield the identity of an
actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whose identity is known (as in the famous abortion case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">vs. Wade</ENAMEX> ), or to indicate (as in a so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doe</ENAMEX> summons") an actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whose identity is not yet known. Law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> investigating
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> who, within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
of the crime, was given the designation "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">John Doe No. 2</ENAMEX>," eventually tracking
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> down and also establishing his innocence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>, who was designated "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">John Doe No. 1</ENAMEX>," argued that the bombing was
actually the work of a broader conspiracy. The chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, stated, "We certainly will contend that there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">John Doe 2</ENAMEX>, and maybe
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3, 4</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>." Such a plurality of Does is typically cause to invoke the variant
forms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> will hand down a decision regarding a pair
of cases, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, involving the legality of
assisted suicide. The individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> case were listed
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">appeals-court</ENAMEX> opinion as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Roe</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doe; James Poe</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
Glucksberg, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX>" ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glucksberg</ENAMEX>," of course, is not some ambitious new departure
in the field of generic fictitious names, and there will not soon be a movie
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet Harold Glucksberg</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glucksberg</ENAMEX> is just the real name of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> involved in the case.)

            New words
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everywoman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everyman</ENAMEX> are proliferating, albeit with a qualitative
difference. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Roe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doe</ENAMEX> at least give a nod to status based
on the fact of mere personhood, the new terminology seems to confer status on
the basis of some salient generic attribute--consider "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupant</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
household," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>," "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>." This has come about owing to the continuing
merger of demographic science and marketing, and the tendency is probably not
reversible.

            All the more reason, perhaps, to insist on a little more
bravura individuality on the part of our world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. One could stop well
short of anything as elaborate as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haile Selassie</ENAMEX>'s old
tag line ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conquering Lion</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tribe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judah</ENAMEX>") or the array
of distinctions paraded by the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Waugh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mischief</ENAMEX> (a proclamation begins, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bachelor of the Arts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University</ENAMEX> ...") and yet still provide an
evocative garnish. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility might be to allow sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> (for example) to add the name of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or
other historic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> to their official names. One can easily see, though,
how in some hands this could lead to pandering--the nominal analogue of
ticket-balancing ("I, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Roosevelt Kennedy Patton Rosa Parks</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Milk Sitting Bull Clinton</ENAMEX>, do solemnly swear ..."). A more promising
direction is simply to require <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to absorb their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
code names into their proper names.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>, perhaps
owing to the quotidian proximity that the role affords, has demonstrated a
proven knack for understated aptness in its selections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald "Rawhide</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan "Scorecard" Quayle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward "Sunburn" Kennedy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deacon</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob "Patriot" Dole</ENAMEX>. Should an unelected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> be entrusted with such
power? That is a question for the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>. For myself, I'd be
willing to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger "Headache" Clinton</ENAMEX> at least give it a
try.

         
      
   
