
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plain Speaking</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, shortly before
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> began, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> issued a governmentwide memorandum the first
directive of which takes effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as soon as summer</TIMEX> comes to a close. By the
beginning of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, if not before, federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> are supposed to have
put into place the first elements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plain Language</ENAMEX>
Initiative, which aims to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> "more responsive, accessible, and
understandable in its communications with the public." Those elements include
the use of something called <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Plain Language</ENAMEX> in all documents other than official
regulations--for instance, in all letters, forms, notices, and instruction
booklets. The official regulations themselves--that is to say, the entire
contents of the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> --must come into compliance by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 1999</TIMEX>.

            What is
Plain <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language</ENAMEX>? Ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> might well give different answers,
but according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, Plain <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language</ENAMEX> uses short sentences; common,
everyday words "except for necessary technical terms"; and "you" and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pronouns</ENAMEX> instead of hands-offish nouns such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>" or "lessee." Plain
Language also uses the active voice--although a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> press release
accompanying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s memorandum notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plain Language</ENAMEX>
Initiative, which now forms a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reinventing Government</ENAMEX>"
program, "was developed [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oops</ENAMEX>!] by an interagency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of plain language
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>." This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the press release goes on, "was formed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>."
Implementation of the new regulations, it warns, "must be begun by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>." For its part, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plain Language Action Network</ENAMEX>, a government task force
charged with promoting the regulations, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> on its Web site, "We are guided
by a small steering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>." Ah, well: There is nothing intrinsically wrong
with the passive voice, and the active voice sometimes sounds stilted. Besides,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> didn't build their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in a day.

            What impact the full force and majesty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
government can actually have on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language remains far from clear. To
be sure, some official language programs have enjoyed success. In the late
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Middle Ages</TIMEX>, for example, the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> set out
to turn the dialect spoken at the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> into a national language. With
the advent of a standardized court vernacular, a cadre of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scribes</ENAMEX> trained to
use it, a kingdomwide reliance on the legal and other documents the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scribes</ENAMEX>
produced, and the military might to back up such reliance--under these
circumstances, the spread of the king's <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and the king's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rapid</ENAMEX>. (The language <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Pinker</ENAMEX>, asked once to define the
difference between a dialect and a language, replied, "A language is a dialect
with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>.") Today, of course, government pronouncements constitute a small
and probably shrinking proportion of all verbiage that is in some sense
"national." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Think Different</ENAMEX>" advertising campaign may have a
more lasting impact on the language than any tweaking of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1040</TIMEX> form.

            Still,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> persist in stepping into language debates--and outside groups
persist in putting pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to do so. I won't bother mentioning
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plain English Campaign</ENAMEX>, led by
a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chrissie Maher</ENAMEX>, has sought since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> to make English
laws and regulations more straightforward. The campaign has spread throughout
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth of Nations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Crusade for Plain English Reaches Ghana</ENAMEX>,"
announced a recent cover story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>) and has opened a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>, a doomed utopian named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted W. Kulp</ENAMEX> has
tirelessly promoted his version of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Plain Language</ENAMEX>, to which he gives the name
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kanadan</ENAMEX>." (Consider this sentence from the "introduksion" to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kulp</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diksionari uv Kanadan</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dhis</ENAMEX> diksionari iz aranjaized alfabetikli,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">akording tu dhe ingglis alfabet</ENAMEX>.") <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, the culture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> agreed to simplify the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> language--among
other things, by reducing the rules governing the use of commas from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine</TIMEX>, reducing the number of spelling rules from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">212 to 112</TIMEX>, and performing
Teutonic enhancement on certain foreign loanwords. This <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> version of the
Plain <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language Initiative</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kampf</ENAMEX> auf gut <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deutsch</ENAMEX> , as it might be
called--went into effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 1</TIMEX> but has been challenged in court and will be
challenged again in a referendum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.

            
As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plain Language</ENAMEX>
Initiative, its stated ambitions are in truth astonishing. The initial mandates
apply only to newly drafted documents and regulations--that is, to materials
promulgated on or after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 1998</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 1999</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
memorandum also commits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to cleaning up the backlog. It declares
that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2002</TIMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> "letters, forms, notices, and
instructions" drafted prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 1998</TIMEX>, must be retroactively
rendered into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Plain Language</ENAMEX>. Existing regulations also call for ex post facto
attention. Should the cleanup include all back issues of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Register</ENAMEX> ? All presidential executive orders? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s pardon of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>?
The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilmot Proviso</ENAMEX> ? The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missouri</ENAMEX> 
               Compromise ?
Our problems may have begun even earlier: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, prospective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teachers</ENAMEX> recently complained that one reason so many of them fared poorly on a
teaching proficiency test was that they were unfairly expected to comprehend a
passage from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Federalist</ENAMEX> 
               Papers --in many ways, the essential
gloss on our entire constitutional system. Needless to say, the
Federalist essays do not meet the simple strictures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plain</ENAMEX>
Language Initiative.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enforced</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Plain Language Initiative</ENAMEX> would create a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year 2002 Problem of</ENAMEX>
surpassing magnitude--a revisionist enterprise unprecedented in our history. As
it happens, though, the initiative comes with no enforcement provisions beyond
interagency suasion and popular indignation. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> seem to possess
a tolerance and perhaps even a relish for gobbledygook. In corporate staff
meetings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> everywhere pursue a
game called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Buzzword Bingo</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> score by quietly taking note
whenever a jargon term ("proactive," "incent," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"interface"</ENAMEX>) is wielded by their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>. We would all feel oddly impoverished, I think, in a world where the
occasional malpractice case was never passed off as a "negative patient-care
outcome" or where the occasional plane crash was never described as a "failure
to maintain ground clearance."

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area of modern life where I wish <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plain Language</ENAMEX>
would make more of a mark is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Scripps-Howard National Spelling Bee</ENAMEX>. Over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the words dispensed to the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> seem to have become more
and more obscure--to the point where the contest lies largely beyond the reach
of amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> and is accessible only to a specialized class of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orthographiliac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autodidacts</ENAMEX> who have been training for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> words
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1998</TIMEX> national spelling bee included "prairillon," "daedal," "parrhesia,"
"risorgimento," and "maieutic." Looking back over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX>, one
finds "hebephrenia," "xanthosis," "hirundine," "vivisepulture," "intonaco," and
"bathyseism" all occurring in the crucial home stretch. "They don't use real
words much anymore," lamented the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>, after
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> misspelled "fodient" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">in Round 6</ENAMEX>. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fodient</ENAMEX>" means "fitted for, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pertaining</ENAMEX> to, digging.")

            Traditionally, the national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spelling bee</ENAMEX> is the venue where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> triumphantly demonstrate
mastery of their new language. Too often, now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> demonstrate mastery
of words that don't sound like English at all. Surely we can do a little better
(the dictionary is, after all, a fodient-friendly volume). I don't harbor
enormous hope for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reinventing Government</ENAMEX>. But a few new guidelines for the
spelling bee seem well within our power.

         
      
   
