
   
   
      
         
            They Don't Know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester</ENAMEX> published <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait of a</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> , a book so gushing in its
praise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>, so slack-jawed in awe, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
distributed copies as souvenirs. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and debunkers can
share a collective smirk at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester</ENAMEX>'s naiveté, confident that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> books (by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy Library</ENAMEX>'s rough count) have taught us all a thing or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>; that our understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> literature itself, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX>, complex, ever expanding. The latest additions, however, rattle that
confidence. Traditionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> books have ranged from apologist to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revisionist</ENAMEX>. The current vogue is reductivist: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>, we are now told, was a
fairly simple fellow. Recent releases portray him as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> or hedonist, romantic
or reprobate--but never as all these things at once.

            First,
regrettably and inescapably, there is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>'s The 
               Dark Side
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>-haters. The significance of the
investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s book lies neither in its revelations (which are few)
nor its hype (which is considerable, and has stirred up waves of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attackers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>, including 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>). Rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dark Side</ENAMEX> 's significance lies in the countermyth
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> constructs to displace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX>--an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Camelot</ENAMEX> in which every
public virtue conceals a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> is not shrewd, he is
"fanatical"; he is not coolheaded, he is impulsive; he is not suave, he is
sleazy. Hersh reconciles any contradictions in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> by
eradicating them. At the swimming pool, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> grabs a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s backside; in the
situation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, he flirts with nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">holocaust</ENAMEX>. Reckless at play, reckless at
work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> is just a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a nice smile that made travesties appear to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triumphs</ENAMEX>.

            For every bitter revisionist, however, there is an equally
ardent admirer. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gunilla von Post</ENAMEX>'s slight memoir of a
brief affair during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> again has a winning grin, both
"incandescent" and "offhand." (It fades only when he thinks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>.) But in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX> sees darkness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Post</ENAMEX>, a stunning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish</ENAMEX>
aristocrat, perceives only light. "This wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who simply needed a woman
to satisfy his cravings and would then go on to something else," she explains
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> embarks upon another transatlantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">booty</ENAMEX> call. A philanderer,
perhaps, but hardly a cad. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Von Post</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> even "[makes] love with a surprising
innocence." He swoons, he sighs, he weeps. He looks toward the heavens and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proclaims</ENAMEX>, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gunilla</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> !"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Hellmann, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of English at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State University</ENAMEX>, has little interest
in the debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellmann</ENAMEX>'s focus is instead on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> "image" and its importance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s historical reputation. In
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Obsession</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellmann</ENAMEX> conducts a close reading of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>'s
personal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>: the adventures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivanhoe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Young</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> ; the steely, masculine prose of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX>. In reading
these books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hellmann</ENAMEX> claims, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was shrewdly incorporating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archetypes</ENAMEX>--the lonely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, the sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX>--that would later compose his
public persona. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellmann</ENAMEX> sees no distinction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s image and his
actual achievement; for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellmann</ENAMEX>, the image is the achievement. This is
a helpful insight: All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> engage in what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> calls "creative
self-making." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hellmann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> is too self-aware to be believable. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>'s mind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> at the notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Sorensen</ENAMEX> discussing
"self-presentation" or, more ominously, "liminal marginality." This isn't
politics. This is what lit crits talk about when they talk about politics.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Individually</ENAMEX>, none of these books tells us much
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> that we didn't already know. None, not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX>'s best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seller</ENAMEX>, will greatly alter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s reputation. Considered together, though,
they underscore a truth about JFK: that he can't be reduced to a type. Suave
and sleazy, cool and reckless--these contradictions raise
important and troubling questions about his presidency. How could a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dissolute</ENAMEX> in his private life display such discipline in his public role? If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was so quickly bored by others--his anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dark Side</ENAMEX>
is not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to recall his relentless tapping of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX>, of fingers, of
teeth--how did he endure interminable briefings on border disputes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>? If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> accepts (as one must, increasingly) the portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> as
almost absurdly careless, how does one explain his mastery of the televised
press conference? This was a controversial innovation during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, when
a "live" gaffe might spark an international incident. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> conquered the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, and not just with his winsome smile and quick wit; his preparation
was unmatched by any but the most thorough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>.

            These paradoxes are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">puzzling</ENAMEX>, which explains the temptation to ignore or deny them. It is hard to
believe that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, particularly a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, could embody such
contradictory traits without self-destructing. Perhaps given more than a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thousand days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> would have self-destructed. But his record in office
demonstrates growth, not decay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Bildungsroman</ENAMEX> --his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coming-of-age</ENAMEX>, from fumbling the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pigs invasion</ENAMEX> to resolving the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>
missile crisis--is a tired tale, but newly validated by The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
Tapes , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest May</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Zelikow</ENAMEX>'s edition of the transcripts of those
crucial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">ExComm</ENAMEX> meetings of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1962</TIMEX>. Whatever goings-on are going on in the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet Room</ENAMEX>
performance underscores his ability to "compartmentalize his life," as Hersh
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nicely</ENAMEX> puts it in his first chapter (before denying it in the rest of his
book). The most interesting recent portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Reeves</ENAMEX>' masterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profile of Power</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nigel Hamilton</ENAMEX>'s flawed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">JFK</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reckless Youth</ENAMEX> --confront the dualities in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. If they do not
explain them, at least they acknowledge them, which is more than this current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> of books can boast.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, it is not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> who know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> best. It is his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX> myth crumbled long
ago under the strain of molls, mob money, election fraud, and foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adventurism</ENAMEX>, and it is precisely this sordid mix--sex, glamour, power--that
accounts for much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s enduring appeal. For some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> remains
the anointed apostle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Frontier</ENAMEX>. But it's not because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> passed a
nuclear test-ban treaty or founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, according to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> poll, consider him our greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. For
most of us, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> is a lovable rogue. His broad smile, neither purely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">romantic</ENAMEX> nor wholly cynical, tells the story: This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who breaks the
rules and is attractive, wealthy, and smart enough to get away with it. In his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">audacity</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> is utterly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, and simply irresistible.

         
      
   
