
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veil of Tears</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX>,
visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and monuments and taking note of what everybody was wearing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, but it has put an end to theocratic rule. Its
government and public education system are secular, and both emphasize equality
of the sexes. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> got the vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. I was curious to see how traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> customs interact with
modern fashion in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX> has been meeting West for so many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">millennia</ENAMEX>. I'd already had some exposure to the mixture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>), very far in spirit from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>.
Istanbul, for example, is much closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Odessa</ENAMEX> than it is to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> is
notorious for veiling its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, but such veiling was once universal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engravings</ENAMEX> show draped, enveloping clothes for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are not very
different from ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> women's clothes or early medieval
clothes and that are, in fact, similar to early forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasant women</ENAMEX>'s
clothing all over eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were then simply following standard
ancient-world custom, which required that the head be veiled when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was
outdoors and that the body never be exposed except in private. All around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>, modesty was considered the primary female virtue, its public
expression necessary for an ordered human society. Female physical beauty was
viewed as an incendiary and corrupting influence that could lead to
lawlessness, social disorder, and anarchy. Only after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> fashion hit its
stride in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16 th century</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> flaunting sculptured curls,
rouged cheeks, and exposed chests in public, did the veiled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> begin to
look so alien, so alluring, and eventually so infuriating to Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensibilities</ENAMEX>.

            In the era
following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>, Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s beauty was made to function both as
a creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and as a commodity in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> expanding through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commerce</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conquest</ENAMEX>. Nude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> representing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth and Virtue</ENAMEX> began to appear on public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monuments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titian</ENAMEX> painted great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> young and old, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX>, goddesses, and
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>, all equally delicious to look at. The virtuous but
lively <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> were encouraged to show some ankle
and make advantageous marriages. Fashion-prints were published and studied.
Well-placed married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> in low cut dresses ran salons, manipulating social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and influencing literature and politics. Female beauty helped to
modernize the world.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> would have none of this. Female influence
was potent and important, but it functioned covertly. Female beauty was valued,
but it was nobody's business. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wear a long
straight dress with high neck and long sleeves, and a folded head cloth that
wholly hides the forehead and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>, the ears, neck, and bust.

            The look
of such traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> dress commands instant respect from a modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beholder</ENAMEX>. It has the authority of unself-conscious ancient custom, and the
costume forms a fine visual contrast to the vagaries of fashion in modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. The style is harmonious, dignified, and not impractical. I saw gear
much like it on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hindu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nepal</ENAMEX>, who would wrap and tuck some of the veil
around the midsection, carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, and other sundries in its
overlapping folds. The spirit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>, however, is utterly alien to
Western assumptions.

            To present-day eyes, expressions of extreme female modesty
seem subversive, a stumbling block to the sane ordering of human affairs.
Keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the dark, wrapping them up in public like so many identical
packages, is felt to corrode the social fabric, not strengthen it; to stunt,
not nourish a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s modern political life. It feels that way in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX>,
too. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> there display the range of hairstyles and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cosmetics</ENAMEX> and
physical exposure found in any big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. But many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wear a new version
of pointedly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> costume. Below the neck, they wear modern clothes and
shoes. But on their heads, they wear a modern silk scarf, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci</ENAMEX> look-alike or
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herm√</ENAMEX>®s knockoff folded close around the face to hide <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a third</NUMEX> of it, along
with the ears, the whole neck, and every scrap of hair. This quasimodern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> "veil" makes a self-conscious religious point in a secular society.

            The effect
is very disturbing. This head scarf recently caused a furor in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> schools
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, when an old law prohibiting its use was suddenly enforced. A
similar prohibition was attempted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> religious tolerance, as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> does, and as part of their religion,
young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim Parisiennes</ENAMEX> were demanding the right to wear this same
hybrid scarf in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yarmulke</ENAMEX> or even
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sufi</ENAMEX> turban, have a hard time understanding why these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would find
this harmless religious practice improper. But they do.

            
Looking at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of examples of it in
Istanbul, I came to see the problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> wearing short skirts and smart shoes
who fold a modish scarf on their heads in the ancient veil-like manner are
trying to have it both ways. Unlike the yarmulke, which is strictly symbolic,
the folded scarf is functional. Like the original veil, it serves to create the
conditions of female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">modesty</ENAMEX>.

            No wonder
many hate it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, especially for schoolgirls, who are meant to mix with
others on an equal footing in all respects; and in determinedly modernized
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who wish to wear the scarf in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> say it represents
Muslim female empowerment, and they consider themselves oppressed if it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">forbidden</ENAMEX>. They may claim this, but their very appearance in these scarves
cancels that interpretation. Those who object to them seem closer to the mark
in fearing that the scarves signal a rising fundamentalist opposition to the
secular principles on which modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> was founded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who believe
the scarves mean freedom may in fact be blinded by them. They may not realize
their complicity in a movement that seems likely ultimately to take such
freedom away.

            Every time I saw an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Istanbul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> with a silk scarf
pinching her head and reducing her face, I would think, heavens, take it off,
let me show you how to wear it becomingly with your nice suit--and then I would
remember that, above the shoulders, unattractiveness is the whole point. It was
startling to me how unnoticeable the attractions below the neck became without
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> to avow them. A tightly wrapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, with encapsulated eyes,
nose, and mouth, doubtless suited the publicly shrouded female of antiquity,
whose intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">flowered</ENAMEX> wholly unseen. It seems suitable in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>,
for example, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can't vote, since it squashes public expression along
with hair. But in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX>, the scarf completely depersonalizes the
shapely legs and curving torso displayed in contemporary clothes below it. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> looks brainless, an antique statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX> with no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            It is really too bad that
such inhibiting headgear, a complex <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> tradition, has lately acquired the
status of a strict religious law, which it never was. The modest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> veil is
in fact betraying its ancient and honorable reluctance to take on the
aggressive flavor of fanaticism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodox Judaism</ENAMEX>, likewise devoted to the
suppression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s hair, has long since solved the problem another way,
with fashionable wigs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> has refrained from such an expedient. Meanwhile
the ancient chaste <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> veil and dress persist in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where they have
never been challenged, and they cohabit, more or less, with modern fashion if
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> don't try to blend.

            In any case, I was interested
to notice that no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Herm√</ENAMEX>®s-like silk scarves casually grazed secular female
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clavicles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX>. The sexy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> with terrific hair would dashingly toss a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">yards</NUMEX> of plain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> around their necks; no sign of bright printed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">silk</ENAMEX>. Shiny stacks of beautiful scarves are sold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Bazaar</ENAMEX>, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> girls to wrench into veils and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> to flaunt in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
