
   
   
      
         
            Big-Bang Theology

            Did God cause the big bang?
That is what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> new books about science and religion--whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
range from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>-administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> to an
elementary-particle-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>--are saying. The fact that
the universe abruptly exploded into existence out of apparent nothingness some
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 billion years ago</TIMEX>, they submit, means it must have had a supernatural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creator</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of months ago</TIMEX> the same claim was enthusiastically aired at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> conference sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics and Public Policy Center</ENAMEX> under
the rubric "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beyond the Death of God</ENAMEX>," with eminent thinkers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Charen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX> in attendance. And the idea received a
sympathetic hearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley</ENAMEX>'s show Firing Line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> .
            

            The idea
that only God could have caused the big bang is scarcely new. In fact, the big
bang is probably the only idea in the history of science that was ever resisted
because of its pro-God import.

            For much of the modern era, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> followed Nicolaus
Copernicus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Galileo Galilei</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Newton</ENAMEX> in believing the cosmos to be
eternal and unchanging. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX> applied his theory of
relativity to space-time as a whole, his equations implied that the universe
could not be static; it must be either expanding or contracting. This struck
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> as grotesque, so he added to his theory a fiddle factor called the
"cosmological constant" that eliminated the implication and held the universe
still.

            It was an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ordained priest</ENAMEX> who took relativity to its logical conclusion. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>, Georges
Lemaître of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Louvain</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> worked out an expanding model
of the universe. Reasoning backward, he proposed that at some definite point in
the past it must have originated from a primeval atom of infinitely
concentrated energy. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemaître's</ENAMEX> model was confirmed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronomer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Hubble</ENAMEX>, who had observed that the galaxies everywhere
around us were receding. Both theory and empirical evidence pointed to the same
verdict: The universe had an abrupt beginning in time.

            
Churchmen rejoiced. Proof of the biblical
account of creation had dropped into their laps. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope Pius XII</ENAMEX>, opening a
conference at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vatican</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>, declared that this scientific theory of
cosmic origins bore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> "to that primordial <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Fiat lux</ENAMEX> ' uttered at
the moment when, along with matter, there burst forth from nothing a sea of
light and radiation. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hence</ENAMEX>, creation took place in time, therefore there is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>, therefore God exists!"

            Marxists, meanwhile, gnashed
their teeth. Quite aside from its religious aura, the new theory contradicted
their belief in the infinity and eternity of matter--one of the axioms of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>'s dialectical materialism--and was accordingly dismissed as "idealistic."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bohm</ENAMEX> rebuked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> of the theory as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> who effectively turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX> to science, and discard scientific
facts to reach conclusions that are convenient to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX>."
Atheists of a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> stripe were also recalcitrant. "Some younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> were so upset by these theological trends that they resolved simply
to block their cosmological source," commented the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronomer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX>
Heckmann, a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> of cosmic expansion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of the
profession, Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Eddington</ENAMEX>, wrote, "The notion of a beginning is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repugnant</ENAMEX> to me ... I simply do not believe that the present order of things
started off with a bang. ... The expanding Universe is preposterous ...
incredible ... it leaves me cold ."

            Even some
believing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> were troubled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cosmologist</ENAMEX> Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Hoyle</ENAMEX> simply felt
that an explosion was an undignified way for the world to begin, rather like "a
party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> jumping out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>." In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> interview in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, Hoyle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sardonically</ENAMEX> referred to the hypothesized origin as "the big bang." The term
stuck.

            Einstein overcame his metaphysical scruples about the big
bang not long before his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>, referring to his earlier attempt to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dodge</ENAMEX> it by an ad hoc theoretical device as "the greatest blunder of my
career." As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoyle</ENAMEX> and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX>, they were finally won over
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Labs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> accidentally detected a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pervasive</ENAMEX> microwave hiss that turned out to be the echo of the big bang (at
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they thought it was caused by pigeon droppings on their antenna). If you
turn on your television and tune it between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10 percent</NUMEX> of that
black-and-white-speckled static you see is caused by photons left over from the
cosmogonic event. What greater proof of the reality of the big bang--you can
watch it on television!

            Since the
'60s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have been busy working out, and feuding over, the details of
the big-bang cosmology. But God is not in the details--his existence is
deducible from the mere fact that there is a world at all. So goes the
cosmological argument , one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> traditional arguments toward a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Being</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read the ontological argument and the
teleological argument .)

            
The reasoning starts off like this:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
Everything that begins to exist has a cause of its existence.
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The universe began to
exist.
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Therefore the universe
has a cause of its existence. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to learn more about the surprising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> origins of this argument and what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludwig Wittgenstein</ENAMEX> had to say about
it.)

            There are
many options for attacking the logic of this cosmological argument, and
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of theism have tried them all.

            If everything needs a cause for its existence, then so does
God. (More frequently heard in the form "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">But Mummy</ENAMEX>, who made <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God?</ENAMEX>") This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objection</ENAMEX> fails because it gets <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Premise 1</ENAMEX> wrong. The premise does not say that
everything needs a cause but that everything that begins to exist
does. God never began to exist--he is eternal. So he does not need a cause for
his existence.

            
               Maybe
the universe had a natural cause. But the big bang could not have been
caused by prior physical processes. That is because it began with pointlike
singularity , which, according to relativity theory, is not a "thing" but
a boundary or an edge in time. Since no causal lines can be extended through
it, the cause of the big bang must transcend the physical world.

            
Well, then, perhaps it had no cause at all. It
is hard to think of a principle more amply confirmed by our experience than
that things do not just pop into existence uncaused. No one can really pull a
rabbit out of a hat. Ex nihilo nihil fit. Yet something of the sort does
seem to happen in the quantum world, where, owing to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heisenberg</ENAMEX>'s uncertainty
principle, tiny "virtual particles" spontaneously appear and disappear all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. An entire universe could do the same, claim some cosmologists. Calling
themselves "nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX>," they have produced models showing how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cosmos</ENAMEX> could have burst into being all by itself out of a patch of "false
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vacuum</ENAMEX>," or a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3-D</NUMEX> geometry of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> volume, or--in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexander</ENAMEX>
Vilenkin of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufts University</ENAMEX>--literally nothing at all (this took Vilenkin four
pages of math). So the universe is summoned out of the void by the laws of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physics</ENAMEX>. But this can't be right. The laws of physics are just a set of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">equations</ENAMEX>, a mathematical pattern. They cannot cause the world to exist. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hawking</ENAMEX> has written, "A scientific theory ... exists only in our minds
and does not have any other reality (whatever that might mean)."

            
               Just because the universe
is temporally finite does not mean it had a beginning. Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawking</ENAMEX>,
this is his famous "no boundary" proposal. "So long as the universe had a
beginning, we could suppose it had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawking</ENAMEX> wrote in A Brief
History of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . "But if the universe is completely self-contained, having
no boundary or edge, it would have neither beginning or end: it would simply
be. What place, then, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>?" In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawking</ENAMEX>'s quantum cosmology, the
pointlike singularity of the big bang is replaced by a smooth hemisphere in
which space and time are commingled. "Time zero" becomes an arbitrary point,
not a true beginning; it is no more a boundary than the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Pole</ENAMEX> is.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawking</ENAMEX>'s
proposal is extremely popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laymen</ENAMEX> who are hostile to the cosmological
argument, judging from the mail I get. Apparently they enjoy being baffled by
"imaginary time," a theoretical fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hawking</ENAMEX> uses to redescribe the big bang
so that there is no beginning. In real time there still is a beginning.
Sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hawking</ENAMEX> says that imaginary time is "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>" than real time, which
is a logical contradiction; sometimes he suggests it might be more real than
real time, which is an absurdity.

            OK, so the universe had a beginning, and hence a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Cause, which is, moreover, transcendent. How does it follow that this cause is
God, or even God-like? Now there is an acute question. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philosopher Thomas Nagel</ENAMEX>
has suggested that something humanly inconceivable lies behind the big bang.
What, if anything, can really be inferred about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Cause</ENAMEX>? Well, suppose
that it were something mechanical. An ideal machine produces its effect either
always or never; it does not just suddenly start to operate at some moment,
unless someone gives it a kick. If a mechanical cause produced the universe at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time T</ENAMEX>, there is no reason it should not have done so at time T <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">minus 1</NUMEX>. The
argument can be repeated to T minus infinity: A mechanical cause would have
either produced the universe from eternity or not at all. But the universe was
created at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one moment</TIMEX> out of an infinity of other indistinguishable moments.
This implies that the moment was freely chosen, and hence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> had
a will, and to that extent a personal nature. And power.

            Yet the big-bang cosmology
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unwelcome consequence for theists. It seems to suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creator</ENAMEX>
was a bungler. A singularity is inherently lawless. Anything at all can come
out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. It is exceedingly unlikely that a big-bang singularity should give
rise to a universe whose conditions are precisely suitable for life, let alone
the best of all possible worlds. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Smith</ENAMEX> has
pointed out, "If God created the universe with the aim of making it animate, it
is illogical that he would have created as its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> state something whose
natural evolution would lead with high probability only to inanimate
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> ." The only way God could have ensured the appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> in
his own image was by repeatedly intervening and making adjustments to steer the
evolution of the world away from lifeless disaster. But "a competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creator</ENAMEX>
does not create things he immediately or subsequently needs to set aright,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observes Smith</ENAMEX>. (Remember, we are talking about the universe's physical
infrastructure, not sinners with free will.)

            So did God cause the big
bang? Overcome by metaphysical lassitude, I finally reach over to my bookshelf
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Devil's Bible</ENAMEX> . Turning to Genesis I read: "In the beginning
there was nothing. And God said, 'Let there be light!' And there was still
nothing, but now you could see it."

         
      
   
