
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alphabet Soup</ENAMEX>

            As regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantine Studies</ENAMEX> ; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Biblical Literature</ENAMEX> are by now well
aware, a dispute has long simmered about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in ancient times read
to themselves silently, as we moderns do, or mostly read aloud. The unequivocal
references in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to silent reading are few, and the context often
suggests that the practice is unusual. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Augustine</ENAMEX> describes with amazement
how the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, could follow the written text with his
eyes even as "his voice and tongue stayed still."

            The majority view <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is
that reading aloud was the rule in antiquity--a view that has now received
powerful new support from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Saenger</ENAMEX>, a medievalist and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newberry Library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. Saenger observes in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Space Between Words</ENAMEX>: The
Origins of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silent Reading</ENAMEX> that most ancient texts virtually demanded to be
read aloud, because the words were written in what is known as scriptura
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">continua</ENAMEX> --that is, they were all run together,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forcingthereadertosoundeverythingout</ENAMEX>. Then, in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventh centuries</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-speaking monks, for whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> of literature and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scripture</ENAMEX> was a
foreign language, began inserting spaces, just to help tell all those
unfamiliar words apart. Irish manuscript traditions went on to influence the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> world, and the separation of words became a universal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convention</ENAMEX>--thereby making silent reading practical. Silent reading--now so
vast and entrenched that we take it for granted--seems to have come about more
or less by happy accident.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Specialists</ENAMEX> will no doubt be arguing over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saenger</ENAMEX>'s thesis for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to
come--don't let your subscription to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byzantine Studies</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lapse</ENAMEX>. But I was drawn to the argument of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Space Between Words</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
reasons: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, it treats words as physical objects produced by physical means
and designed to be understood by physical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, it reminds us of
the breathtaking role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">serendipity</ENAMEX> can play in matters of language.

            The physicality of words is something we tend to lose sight
of--literally--although the consequences of physicality are inescapable and
often startling. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years ago</TIMEX> I shouldered the rewarding (and not very
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exacting</ENAMEX>) task of editing some articles by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Lewis</ENAMEX>, distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in our conversations the subject drifted, and I
found myself asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>--thinking he was bound to know--about the kind of
ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> writing that was written from left to right on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> line, then
from right to left on the next, then from left to right again, and so on.
"You're thinking of boustrophedon ," he replied at once. "The term comes
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> words that describe the way an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>-drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plough</ENAMEX> turns in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>."

            I pursued
the matter a little further, asking how such a writing system came to be.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' answer emerged after a pleasant subterranean rumbling that I took to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laughter</ENAMEX> (though his answer was entirely serious). "It probably arose," he
said, "from the practice of writing long inscriptions on cliff faces." Imagine,
he went on, lowering a chap with his chisel from the top of a monument and
moving him along as he does his work. What do you do when he finishes the first
line? Do you haul him all the way back to where he started? Or do you just drop
him down <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few feet</NUMEX> to the next line and then let him continue his work in the
opposite direction? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">subterranean</ENAMEX> rumbling resumed for a moment, making it
clear the answer should be obvious.

            In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">memoir Running in the Family the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ondaatje</ENAMEX> wrote evocatively about the alphabet he
learned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sri Lanka</ENAMEX> as a boy, making note of the aesthetic consequences of yet
another technological imperative:

            I still believe the most
beautiful alphabet was created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinhalese</ENAMEX>. The insect of ink curves into
a shape that is almost sickle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spoon</ENAMEX>, eyelid. The letters are washed blunt
glass which betray no jaggedness. Sanskrit was governed by verticals, but its
sharp grid features were not possible in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ceylon</ENAMEX>. Here the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ola</ENAMEX> leaves which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wrote on were too brittle. A straight line would cut apart the leaf and
so a curling alphabet was derived from its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>.

            There has
been no lack of commentary about the consequences that the latest version of
Ola <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX>--computers and electronic text--will have on the future of reading,
writing, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word</ENAMEX>, and I have no wish to revisit all the speculative Big
Questions here; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sven Birkerts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Joyce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Johnson</ENAMEX>, and the rest of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> can agonize or exult over these without any outside help. Many issues
will simply remain up in the air for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come, no matter what anyone
says.

            Still, computers and electronic text have already wrought
changes in the way the world's words are constructed. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
have long been accustomed to elaborating upon the way their basic names are
written in kanji <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--personalizing names with a flourish of extra
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> or with added or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">subtracted strokes</ENAMEX>. Those flourishes now must come
to an end for official purposes, in the interest of computer standardization.
Likewise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish Language Academies</ENAMEX> has voted to eliminate
"ch" (as in chorizo ) and "ll" (as in llama ) as distinct letters
in what had been a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>-letter <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> alphabet. (An extra <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> letter "n,"
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the tilde, remains in place for now.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, for their part,
have begun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to phase out their distinctive letter for a double "s,"
the letter that looks somewhat like an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> capital "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">B.</ENAMEX>"

            The forces
that are bringing a little more order to orthography are doing the same to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">semantics</ENAMEX>. Because an electronically linked worldwide medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> needs a
common language, new terminology has been adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation of Associations of Anatomists</ENAMEX> to describe human body parts. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s apple is henceforward to be known as the laryngeal
prominence . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Achilles</ENAMEX> tendon now becomes the calcaneal
tendon . The space between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s breasts is now to be known as the
intermammary sulcus .

            
It is beyond me to chart the future byways of
the digital revolution, but I'll venture <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> counterintuitive prediction:
Electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> will usher in a resurgence in the quality and value in
handwriting. Signs of a renaissance of the handwritten word are here and there
discernible. Most obviously, there is the proliferation of specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> for
fountain pens and handmade paper. But it can also be seen, hauntingly, in the
almost sacral reception given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s handwritten letter revealing
his affliction with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX>. "Script's primary power," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>, in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> reflection on the letter, "is to convey
the cursive flow of human thought, from brain to hand to pen to ink to
eye--every waver, every loop, every <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">character trembling</ENAMEX> with expression."

            As handwriting becomes ever
less a daily utilitarian workhorse it may well become ever more a cherished
means of interpersonal transmission--for the sorts of messages that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sets
aside to preserve (or pulls out to reread from one's intermammary sulcus). Some
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Saenger</ENAMEX>, perhaps in a book to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When Hands Left the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyboard</ENAMEX> , will, I hope, be able to tell the story of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more happy
accident.

         
      
   
