
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luck</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>

            Typically, setting off bombs
in crowded places doesn't make you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, although it might well
win you a supporting role as a villain. But the rules are different for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>, which has been bombing civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Britain</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>. While the movies routinely turn other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> into gun fodder
for the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>, IRA crusaders almost always play the
role of the tragic, troubled, and ultimately noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Guy</ENAMEX>.

            Take some
recent cinematic excursions into the Troubles. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>'s The Jackal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">featured Richard Gere</ENAMEX> as a former IRA sharpshooter--not bomber--let out of
prison to stop a mercenary terrorist, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gere</ENAMEX> is a
virtuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> throughout, so much so that at the film's end, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
blithely grant him his freedom. Similarly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Devil's Own</ENAMEX>
gave us <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> confronting corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> and dying a romantic death for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> he loved. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Collins</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>)
sympathetically portrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918-1921</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> war
for independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>--a war won in part by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>' strategy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombings</ENAMEX> and late-night assassinations.

            The latest of the free-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> films, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sheridan</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boxer</ENAMEX> , features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Day-Lewis</ENAMEX> as a former IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> weary of violence
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. This film is more sophisticated than the others, and
it explicitly condemns violence in a way most IRA films don't. But it, too,
draws careful distinctions between "bad" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, represented by a rogue IRA
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who tries to murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day-Lewis</ENAMEX>, and "good" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, represented by the
IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, which tries to protect him.

            We are talking about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, of course, which means that violence--particularly political
violence--must be repudiated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. So nearly every IRA film concludes
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s death (as both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Collins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Devil</ENAMEX>'s
Own do). Most also pay lip service to the idea that murder is not the
solution to political problems, generally by making the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> a regretful killer
who wishes he could just put down the gun. Yet all these films are suffused
with a sense of the basic justice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> nationalist cause and, more than
that, of the purity of the motives that drive the IRA. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> are portrayed as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ascetic</ENAMEX> and hard-nosed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> you can respect even if you don't agree with them.
In another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheridan-Day-Lewis</ENAMEX> collaboration, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Name of the Father</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day-Lewis</ENAMEX> plays a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> framed for an IRA bombing, the one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> who stands for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> and justice is an IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. In
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gere</ENAMEX>'s "passion" and "fire," in explicit
contrast to the chill cynicism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>, whose only cause is money.

            Even when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> do seem indiscriminately violent or crazy, it turns out the
IRA isn't to blame. In <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Patriot Games</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>), militants try to kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Blown Away</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), a lunatic IRA man
sets off bombs all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>; and in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Boxer</ENAMEX> , the rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> kills
an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, beats <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and bombs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX>. Yet in every case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> are
not true IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loose cannons</ENAMEX> who have broken away from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>. The IRA doesn't favor random terrorist activity; splinter groups
do.

            
This is a distortion, of course. Since at least
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, the IRA has supported plenty of random terrorist activity in its quest to
reunify <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> with independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX> was split off from the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX>, as part of the
peace agreement that ended the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> war for independence (an agreement
negotiated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Collins</ENAMEX>). For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly five decades</TIMEX> after that, the IRA
existed only as a shadowy fringe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. But the turmoil of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, during
which a movement for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> civil rights led to sectarian violence, brought
the IRA back into the limelight. When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paratroopers</ENAMEX> gunned down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> peace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marchers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Derry</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, the IRA inaugurated a new campaign of violence.

            Since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> wants to remain a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, and since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> itself has shown little interest in reunification,
the IRA's prospects for success through political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> have always been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX>. Instead, it has pursued a strategy designed to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> too costly for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to endure.
Bombing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brighton</ENAMEX>, mortaring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heathrow Airport</ENAMEX>, and setting
off bombs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> docks were actions meant to remind the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> of what
was happening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, the IRA has shown a greater interest
in solutions short of reunification. It obeyed a cease-fire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between August 1994</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1996</TIMEX> and agreed to another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has
never repudiated the use of terrorism or the targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>.

            So why does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> give the IRA this special treatment?
First, there's the appeal, to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>--or, at least, of our
idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irishness</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> imagine the striving, suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irishwomen</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hard-drinking</ENAMEX>, hard-fighting, working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irishmen</ENAMEX> to be the sort of people
who founded, and now form the backbone of, our own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> look and
sound enough like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--that is, like white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--to make visceral
identification a snap. Aside from race, after all, it's hard to imagine why IRA
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> make more sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> aren't living in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in the desert, either. Instead,
they're hiding in familiar-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and running down familiar-looking
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. And they're speaking a dialect of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> that's distinctly similar--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">precursor</ENAMEX>, in fact--to ours.

            The films
also build upon the long history of popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
independence. As far back as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-19 th century</TIMEX>, the Fenian
movement for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> independence was funded mainly through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
contributions. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> provided crucial financial support for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918-1921</TIMEX> war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> that created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free State</ENAMEX>. (In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> steals his best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> goes
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to raise money.) Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have been probably even
more fervent in their support for the IRA than have the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> themselves.

            
The IRA's tactics also happen to be well suited
to the conventions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>. Because its campaigns tend to involve
the planning and execution of individual acts rather than all-out warfare, IRA
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> look and act more like professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> than like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>. For plot construction, this is a big plus--something <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
has recognized in pro-IRA films dating back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ford</ENAMEX>'s The Informer
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Reed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Odd Man Out</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>). The scenes of planning
terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Odd Man Out , The Devil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Own</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Crying Game</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>) are almost identical to the scenes in
gangster films like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Killing</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Asphalt Jungle</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>), where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hoodlums</ENAMEX> carefully put together their capers. Moviegoers love
the intricacies of a crime, all the more when it's for a good cause.

            Finally, the simplistic view
of politics that animates the IRA fits neatly with the conventional narrative
structures that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adores</ENAMEX>. Real politics is messy and morally ambiguous
and doesn't make for a compelling thriller. But the black-and-white world of
the true believer does, especially when it's festooned with the trappings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> romanticism. The IRA, you might say, already lives in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movie,
with its noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, amoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, and glorious deaths. It's no surprise
that moviemakers figured that out.

         
      
   
