
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jazz Democracy</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'60s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX>
met a teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> who said to him, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man</ENAMEX>, why don't you practice?" If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drummer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Williams</ENAMEX>, hadn't been such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wunderkind</ENAMEX> (or
"motherfucker," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' preferred term), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, who was an amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX>, might
have taught him another kind of lesson. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> listened--and followed
his advice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> tells this story in his autobiography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX> , and it
speaks volumes about his rapport with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mid-'60s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">quintet</ENAMEX>. It's a commonplace that jazz is the musical expression of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy. The unfortunate truth is that jazz more often resembles the
daytime talk show: Everyone gets his or her say before the floor passes to the
next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soloist</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> quintet was the rare exception, a luminous example of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">participatory</ENAMEX> democracy in jazz.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
has just released the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis quintet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> work in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-CD box set, and it's
remarkable how well the music has aged. Here is group improvisation at its most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glorious</ENAMEX>, a conversation <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> respectful of each other's
voices, listening and responding to one another as equals in interplay as dense
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartók</ENAMEX> string quartet, yet still somehow managing to swing. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of small quibbles with the way the box set was put together.)

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> formed this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, he had racked up an enviable
series of accomplishments. He had performed alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Parker</ENAMEX>, led a
marvelous quintet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coltrane</ENAMEX>, and collaborated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Evans</ENAMEX> on such
jazz orchestral arrangements as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sketches of Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porgy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bess</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> sextet recording, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kind of Blue</ENAMEX> , became, with its
haikulike lyricism, synonymous with cool and provided a soundtrack for nearly
every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> with intellectual pretensions. More than any other jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> captivated the paparazzi , which faithfully reported on
his goings-on, his taste for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> suits, and his richly cultivated contempt
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> who didn't get it.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>
was in a creative slump in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '60s</TIMEX>. He couldn't keep a band together,
and he was being outpaced by younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil Taylor</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">saxophonist Ornette Coleman</ENAMEX>, who wanted to liberate jazz from harmonic
conventions. Unlike his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sideman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coltrane</ENAMEX>, who aligned himself with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">avant-garde</ENAMEX> and ultimately became its prophet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> sought a middle ground
between improvisatory freedom and adherence to form.

            
He found it with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> who formed
his quintet in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Shorter</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor saxophone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbie Hancock</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">piano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carter</ENAMEX> on bass, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> on drums, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> had a dream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">quintet</ENAMEX>'s music is as much a display of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> as it is of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>'.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, who had played on landmark sessions with reedmen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Dolphy</ENAMEX> and
Jacky <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McLean</ENAMEX>, accented the backbeat in the drums and played just a little above
everyone else, creating a polyrhythmic, vaguely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">template</ENAMEX> for his band
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>. Shorter, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumnus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Blakey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz Messengers</ENAMEX>, complemented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>
with his elegantly fractured, bagatellelike style of phrasing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX>, a
favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Note</ENAMEX>'s stable, was the most versatile of keyboardists.
He could play in a hushed, romantic style, then plunge, at a moment's notice,
into fiery, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>-flavored syncopation. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> supplied the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with a
harmonic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, becoming, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' words, its "checkpoint <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quintet</ENAMEX> released <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> recordings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1965 and 1968</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.S.P.</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>). ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Water Babies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round</ENAMEX> , which were also
recorded in this period, were released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'70s</TIMEX>.) It is stirring,
complex music, as exploratory as any of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incredibly</ENAMEX>, hardly anyone
recognized this until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">quintet</ENAMEX>'s work was adopted as a
model by young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wynton Marsalis</ENAMEX>. The reason is simple. In the
revolutionary age of free jazz, with its joyful defiance of form and radical
embrace of pure sound, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> quintet seemed just a bit too polished.
Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' well-known militancy, he didn't care to set his music to civil
rights poetry or to compose preacherly anthems in the manner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coltrane</ENAMEX>.

            That said, the music bears the unmistakable imprint of the
'60s. The hierarchy separating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and the led, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>,
was dissolving in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' music, as it was everywhere else. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>' apprentices
kept their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> on his toes--challenging him to take risks and to experiment
with more open forms. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> all but scrapped the traditional boundary between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foreground</ENAMEX> (improvising soloists) and background (rhythm section). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quintet</ENAMEX>'s music was built from the bottom up, assertively declaring jazz's
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> lineage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> is the busiest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>, dusting every corner
with percussion confetti. On the gorgeous title track of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nefertiti</ENAMEX> , for
instance, he is the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soloist</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> and Shorter repeat the pensive theme
hypnotically, without soloing, making this tune arguably one of the first
statements of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> minimalism. Inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> adopted a more
percussive style of improvising, throwing aggressive, staccato <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">darts</ENAMEX> at the
rhythm section. There's an edginess, a tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s melancholy, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' sound.
Gone is the balladeer of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX>.

            The
material was also new. Everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was composing, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shorter</ENAMEX>,
whose strangely floating, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moorish</ENAMEX>-inflected melodies are among the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mesmerizing</ENAMEX> in jazz. Shorter's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX> are like caramel cages: They sound
so fragile you're amazed they hold together. But, in fact, they're quite
pliable, lending themselves to dramatic shifts in tempo and voicing. Listen,
for example, to the haunting "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masqualero</ENAMEX>" from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sorcerer</ENAMEX> , a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">22</NUMEX> measure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">composition in which Hancock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> adapt the song's shape to the soloists,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis and Shorter</ENAMEX>. It's form as a living, organic process.

            
Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> grew tired of
acoustic jazz, and his final sessions with the quintet are restless,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transitional</ENAMEX> works that point the way ahead. After the release of
Nefertiti , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> began experimenting with the electric instruments that
would consume the remainder of his career--to the horror of many in the jazz
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>. He invited guitarists <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Benson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Beck</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>,
and he had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hancock</ENAMEX> perform on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fender Rhodes</ENAMEX> electric piano (and even on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">celesta</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>' writing assumed a pared down pop sensibility on tunes like
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuff</ENAMEX>," from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> . It's a cocky funk tune that wouldn't be
worth its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17 minutes</TIMEX> if the soloists weren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Shorter</ENAMEX>.

            Were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>' electric instruments and simpler forms an opportunistic concession to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>? It's true that some of his later work sounded like the desperate effort of
an aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> to sell records to rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">quintet</ENAMEX>'s foray into
electric jazz was a natural extension of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> experimentation, and of
his voracious search for new colors and textures. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> was losing interest
in the tricky harmonies of bop, he was acquiring a more painterly, and no less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">modernist</ENAMEX>, approach to sound. Listen, for instance, to the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">33 minute</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round</ENAMEX>," in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> plays celesta and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> is joined by guitarist
Beck, and imagine it being played on FM radio. Sure, it drags a bit without the
volatile repartee of the earlier albums. On the other hand, this druggy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">undulating</ENAMEX> succession of ostinatos is as "difficult," as dissonant and woolly,
as anything the quintet recorded, suggesting both the psychedelia of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crimson</ENAMEX> and the minimalism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Reich</ENAMEX>.

            What's more, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s final album, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filles de</ENAMEX>
Kilimanjaro , on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> perform on electric instruments,
produced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' indisputable masterpieces, the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">majestic 14 minute</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tout</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Suite</ENAMEX>." It's a spacey sort of blues, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> and Shorter playing
furiously against the ethereal, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rothko</ENAMEX>-like shadings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hancock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fender Rhodes</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s electric bass and the anxious pulse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' ride cymbal. At
once lush and frightening, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tout de Suite</ENAMEX>" literally vibrates with intimations
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' future explorations beyond jazz. The subtitle to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filles de</ENAMEX>
Kilimanjaro was telling: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Directions in Music</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX>." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> ventured into the lugubrious, brooding <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">funk of Bitches Brew</ENAMEX> . The
quintet was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' last remarkable tango with jazz.

         
      
   
