
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firmness Factor</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearings on
campaign-finance irregularities, conducted since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmental Affairs Committee</ENAMEX>, have eased finally into insentience. As with so
many political efforts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s most lasting achievement is likely to
be linguistic. Much as the one tangible consequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>'s famous
"malaise" speech, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, was that it taught <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> word (which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> in his speech in fact never uttered; the word was
picked up from pre-speech "spinning" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caddell</ENAMEX>), so too a consequence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> hearings has been to
give wide currency to the term soft money , in the sense of "money that
can be collected for use in political campaigns but which enjoys an existence
outside the rules, the oversight, and the control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election</ENAMEX>
Commission." Specifically, soft money can be contributed in unlimited
amounts so long as it is ostensibly spent on vague "party-building activities"
rather than on behalf of, or at the direction of, particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
point in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late October</TIMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> hearings neared their end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, sought to emphasize that it was not only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who relied heavily on soft money. "The soft-money <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> was eaten by
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> said. "This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> permits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. Heck, we not
only permit it, we thrive on it." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week later</TIMEX>, as if to underscore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>'s
point, or at least to carry the culinary metaphor a little further along, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> headlined a story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> fund-raising dinner
with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menu at G.O.P. Feast</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soft Money for Appetizer and Dessert</ENAMEX>."

            There is no deep mystery about the proximate origins of the
term "soft money." In its current sense, it came into use almost as soon as the
present contours of campaign law were established, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>.

            Beginning
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17 th century</TIMEX>, hard money and soft money came to
refer to metallic money and paper money, respectively. Because hard money was
tied intrinsically to the value of precious metals, the term was soon applied
more generally to currencies of enduring and robust value, currencies that were
under tight control and backed with ample amounts of metal. Hard
currencies aren't pegged to metals any longer, but in casual political and
macroeconomic parlance, soft-money 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are those who take an
optimistic and permissive attitude toward control of the money supply, and
hard-money 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are those who take a grouchy and restrictive
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            
It is the "control" rather than the "value"
aspect of the modern hard money-soft money dichotomy that makes the terminology
applicable to campaign contributions. The immediate linguistic conduit through
which it arrived was probably the language of Wall Street, in which soft
money may refer to payments made in the form of noncash goods and services.
(In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> story described an operative for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale</ENAMEX>'s nascent presidential campaign overseeing a vast pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale</ENAMEX> mailing,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that wouldn't count toward the campaign's spending limits because it was
"educational" material technically being sent out by a labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. "Ah, the
sound of soft money," the operative said.) In business terms, hard money
may refer not just to real money--i.e., hard cash --but also to real
money obtained on hard terms.

            All this
is straightforward enough. But let's not lose sight of a larger phenomenon. It
is said that the human tongue naturally distinguishes among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> types of
tastes: sweet, sour, salty, and bitter. Similarly, the human mind is always
ready to divide the world roughly into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> conceptual categories. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell Holmes</ENAMEX> thought that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could be classified according to whether
they were psychologically "internal" or "external." The late <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isaiah Berlin</ENAMEX>, in
a famous assessment, classified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> according to whether they were hedgehogs
(those who know one big thing) or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">foxes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know many little things).
As I have noted elsewhere, other "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-kinds-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" categories
might include <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs vs. cats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savers</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tossers</ENAMEX>, deciduous vs. evergreen,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard</ENAMEX> vs. automatic. Somehow, though, the qualities soft and
hard never made it onto this original list--a significant omission,
given the prominence they are coming to enjoy in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> of
language.

            The softness and hardness at issue here are
not, of course, the words having literally to do with the physical properties
of the same name, but rather the higher, metaphorical qualities associated with
the words: that is, hard in the sense of "stern," "uncompromising,"
"grim," "tough," "realistic," "verifiable," or "physically palpable"; and
soft in the sense of "moderate," "subjective," "subject to emotion,"
"simple," "idealistic," "weak," or "physically immaterial." In religious terms,
hard can often be thought of as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvinist</ENAMEX>, soft as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unitarian</ENAMEX>.
Taking these attributes together, we thus have hard-liners and
soft-liners , hard-core pornography and soft-core
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pornography</ENAMEX> , hard sell and soft sell , hard numbers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">soft</ENAMEX> numbers , hard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> , hard
liquor and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soft drinks</ENAMEX> , hard sciences and soft
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sciences</ENAMEX> , hardhearted and softhearted , hard rock and
soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> .

            Keep an
eye out or an ear cocked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> for the hard-soft distinction, and you
probably will encounter examples within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just a few minutes</TIMEX> (not counting the
ubiquitous hardwares and softwares , hardballs and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">softballs</ENAMEX> ). On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC World Service</ENAMEX>'s main <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> news program a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days ago</TIMEX>, a news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, in a story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> influx into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, spoke
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> as having a soft immigration policy, meaning that illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> are given expulsion orders but not actually subjected to any further
action. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Misty Isles</ENAMEX>, the mythical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Aleta</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valiant</ENAMEX> , once made a practice of slaughtering shipwreck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> the
moment they washed up on beaches. This would be a hard immigration
policy.) Labor disputes in professional sports have centered on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>,
and therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, would be subject to a hard salary cap or a
soft salary cap , "hard" and "soft" in this instance meaning,
essentially, "enforceable" and "unenforceable." The hard-soft distinction crops
up in the jargon of globe-twirlers. Hard power , as foreign-policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> use the term, is power that comes out of the barrel of a gun--pure
military might. Soft power is power that comes in the form of economic
influence or (most softly of all) moral standing.

            
Hard and soft figure in the context of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preferments</ENAMEX> extended to racial and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. According to a recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> in the journal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Interest</ENAMEX> , soft affirmative action
emphasizes efforts to improve educational and job-training opportunities to
improve minority representation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> and the workplace. Hard
affirmative action emphasizes explicit quotas for jobs, promotions, and
college admissions. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>, soft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> are those who simply
seek ever more cultural and political autonomy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Francophone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>,
whereas hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX> demand outright sovereignty. Political theory
distinguishes between a hard state (a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with a relentlessly
efficient, perhaps authoritarian, central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and a high regard for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> market dynamics) and a soft <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> (which features messy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pluralism</ENAMEX> and aggravating domestic politics in an environment of at least
intermittent concern for the general welfare).

            Such hard-soft terminology
is, one could argue, ideally suited to a postideological age in which other
kinds of distinctions--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> vs. conservative, right vs. wrong, nature vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nurture</ENAMEX>--seem increasingly tiresome or obsolete. For the most part, hard
and soft carry no troubling value judgments. They merely express an
attitude--a stance, a pattern of behavior or of thought--and their meaning in
almost any context is intuitively clear. The hard truth, I would argue, is that
this way of seeing the world is itself distressingly soft.

         
      
   
