
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s Willing Executioners

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, while browsing at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those sadly disappearing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>, I ran into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the sadly disappearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> of left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gadflies</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> said he was working on a book about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Jonah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s Willing Executioners: Ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX> . Goldhagen, he declared, was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraud</ENAMEX> crying out to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unmasked</ENAMEX>.

            This
wasn't surprising. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> made a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> angry with that book.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for a quick refresher on why.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>, a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, bills himself a "forensic" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>. He's fashioned a career out of
demystifying what he deems pseudoscholarly arguments. It also made a kind of
poetic sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> would become obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>. Like him,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> and a strident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> affairs. He just comes at them from the opposing side.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s reputation rests on his refutation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1984 From Time Immemorial</ENAMEX> , a book purporting to prove
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian Arabs</ENAMEX> had no claims on the land that is now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, having been
drawn to it only by reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were making the desert bloom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX>'
book was lavishly praised by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, novelists, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX> had manipulated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX>
demographic records to make her case, the book's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> attacked him as an
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> having published articles that
bolstered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s case, his version was the conventional wisdom.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> told me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> was just another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX>. That struck me as
dubious. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s book wasn't a hoax. It was a troubling
interpretation. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> insisted that, whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> said, the
book had been a megapublishing event, and for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> simple reason: It was useful
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist Jews</ENAMEX> who believe that all non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are potential <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, therefore, are justified in using whatever means are necessary to
defend themselves.

            
Calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">propagandist</ENAMEX> seemed
an act of provocation, to say the least, and so it was taken. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> published an article with the lurid title "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Jonah Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Crazy</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thesis</ENAMEX>" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British New Left Review</ENAMEX> . Shortly afterward, it
was excerpted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsmagazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Der Spiegel</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panorama</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> promptly denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>, a radical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Metropolitan
Books, an imprint of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holt</ENAMEX>, decided to publish a revised version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s essay, along with a no less hotly contested attack on Goldhagen
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German-born</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Bettina Birn</ENAMEX> that was first published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cambridge Historical Journal</ENAMEX> .

            Several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> before the publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birn</ENAMEX>'s book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Nation</ENAMEX> on
Trial: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Goldhagen Thesis and Historical Truth</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>
pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX> to cancel it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Wieseltier</ENAMEX>, the literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , got on the phone with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Naumann</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holt</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, to express his outrage.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Foxman</ENAMEX> wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara</ENAMEX>
Bershtel, calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s views "beyond the pale."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> took even worse flak. Goldhagen
accused her of having defamed him in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Journal</ENAMEX> article,
then assembled a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to demand a retraction and an
apology. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Jewish Congress</ENAMEX> is trying to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birn</ENAMEX> removed
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> (where she helps build cases against
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>) on the grounds that, by publishing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>, she
has demonstrated insensitivity unbecoming a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX>.

            The
prepublication attack almost worked. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">István Deák</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> who agreed to write a preface, backed out. He did
provide a blurb, as did <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> other distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Holocaust experts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Hilberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Browning</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intellectual Pierre Vidal-Naquet</ENAMEX>, and the eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobsbawm</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read what some of them say and here to read why they say it.) Now that the book is out, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> irony is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> should consider himself lucky to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>
as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversary</ENAMEX>. Not that it isn't a good dissection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradictions</ENAMEX> and distortions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> handily refutes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s claim
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> anti-Semitism is all that's required to explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read how he does this.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Checking Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s assertions
against his citations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> demonstrates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>'s use of
secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> is untrustworthy. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for another
telling example.) And yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> turns out to be a kind of doppelgänger of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen's</ENAMEX>, equally biased and inflammatory.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First, Finkelstein</ENAMEX> makes much of the point that
the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> "did not cast their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>." Technically
true--but a plurality of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> did. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> votes in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1933</TIMEX> election as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43.9 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> acknowledges the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was a brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>, but he glosses over its disturbingly
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> echoes conventional historical thinking when he says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nazism</ENAMEX>'s main
appeal lay in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s promises to restore order in post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weimar Germany</ENAMEX>, end
unemployment, and make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> an international power. But anti-Semitism
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">permeated Nazi</ENAMEX> ideology, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> is deaf to its nuances. He writes,
"Not the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> but Marxism and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Democracy</ENAMEX> served as the prime scapegoats
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> propaganda" during their rise to power. Also technically true. But the
Nazis perceived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Democracy</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and Marxism as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
creed; when they rallied against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bolshevik</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> did not
need to be told that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> were, if not actual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, then "spiritual
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>." If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> were to apply his logic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Atwater</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Horton</ENAMEX>
strategy, he'd have to write, "Not race but crime served as the prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scapegoat</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> campaign."

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> deduces from some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>' disgust at
the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> lives and property during <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>-sponsored pogroms such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly condemned the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
anti-Semitic atrocities." If they did, they gave new meaning to the term
"silent majority." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, he writes, displayed "the callousness toward
human life typically attending war. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardened</ENAMEX> and bitter, in search of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scapegoat</ENAMEX>, they occasionally lashed out at the weak." The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> adverb casually
banalizes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> brutality; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> diminishes its extent; together, they
come dangerously close to apologia.

            The most
controversial part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s book, though, is the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, in which
he sets out to explain why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> book was such a big deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>
observes that after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1967 Arab-Israeli War</ENAMEX>, there was a boom in the kind of
Holocaust literature that portrayed the catastrophe as the natural culmination
of millennial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>-hatred. Where some <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilberg</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Broszat</ENAMEX>, depicted it as a "complex and contingent event," other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Davidowicz</ENAMEX>, found it more "politically expedient" to focus on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>, especially as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> came under increasing censure. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s explanation of why this logic is
"expedient.") According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s claim that all forms of
anti-Semitism "tend toward a genocidal 'solution' " is expedient in this way,
and therefore popular--though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> adds no more than a
veneer of social science sophistication to this reductionist point of view.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> is not breaking new ground here.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amos Elon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Segev</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Omer Bartov</ENAMEX> have made similar points about ideological
subtext of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> writing. But they also take pains not to dismiss the
trauma the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> visited and continues to visit upon <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. By contrast,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> adopts an ugly conspiratorial tone when he attributes the book's
popularity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to its Zionist message. This is nonsense. The
book owed its commercial success to its soothingly simplistic thesis--and to
astute marketing. At times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s tone even veers toward the jocular,
as when he makes fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elie Wiesel</ENAMEX>'s racist remarks about ungrateful black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. One is reminded of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gershom Scholem</ENAMEX>'s remark to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Arendt</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time of Eichmann</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> : "This is not the way to approach the
scene of that tragedy."

            It's too bad that the noise
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> has drowned out his co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birn</ENAMEX>. She knows the archives
better than anyone, and she has come up with more quietly damning observations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birn</ENAMEX>'s experience as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> gives her a radically different take on the
legal testimony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> bases much of his book on, for the most part
confessions of death <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad members</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> seems to have difficulty
comprehending that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> claim to have been motivated by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
propaganda, it need not be sincere," she writes. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see how these statements could instead form part of a
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birn</ENAMEX> also shows how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s insistence on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> complicity
leads him to soft-pedal the anti-Semitism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX>,
referring obliquely to the "pressures operating on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ukrainians</ENAMEX> that did not
exist for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>." This is flat-out <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">revisionism</ENAMEX>; you
could easily imagine some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> nationalist writing it.

            But the
weightiest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birn</ENAMEX>'s accusations is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> glosses over atrocities in
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> weren't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> recounts the tale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> who
saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> man beaten to death because his name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>; he does not
report the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>'s account, on the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of testimony, of the
"sexually sadistic murder of a young [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Jewish</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> by one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>."
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, this may be one of the most compelling condemnations of Goldhagen
yet: that his focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> leaves him indifferent to the fate of
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, from that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> POW's who were starved
and worked to death in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. Without minimizing the significance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birn</ENAMEX> provides an eloquent rejoinder to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s
blood-thinking. Her essay radiates a dignified humanism that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> lack.

            

               Endnotes
            

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> have traditionally offered a
variety of reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> followed orders to exterminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. These
include anti-Semitism, the culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, the pressures of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">totalitarian</ENAMEX> rule, the hysteria of wartime mobilization, and the effects of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> propaganda. Goldhagen, by contrast, offers a single-bullet explanation. He
posits a society of ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> bred, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">attack dogs</ENAMEX>, to despise <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>,
and unleashed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> that shared their bloodlust. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s uniquely
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> history had, in his view, made most of them "assenting mass
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">executioners</ENAMEX> ... [who] considered the slaughter to be just." The book had its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>, but the reviews were mostly scathing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s Willing
Executioners was dismissed as fundamentally ahistorical in
Commentary , of all places, and as a "bizarre inversion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> view
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as an insidious, inherently evil <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>" in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> .Back

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: This was an unfair characterization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s
views on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accords. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX>, who regards the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accords as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Versailles</ENAMEX>, he is opposed to them. That doesn't make him a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supporter</ENAMEX>. Back

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara Bershtel</ENAMEX>,
who was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naumann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at the time and heard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wieseltier</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>
phone, he said: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, you don't know who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> is. He's poison, he's
a disgusting self-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, he's something you find under a rock." Wieseltier
told me he wasn't trying to silence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>: "The idea that anyone is
trying to suppress the lonely prophet in the wilderness called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comical</ENAMEX>. Virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> has attacked [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s] book, including, I
might add, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> in the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> is just
playing this game of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">épater les juifs</ENAMEX> ." Back

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deák</ENAMEX>, who was so impressed by an early draft
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> sent him that he wrote him praising his efforts, now says, "I
didn't read the article very carefully. I made the mistake of giving my consent
too early, and then had second thoughts." Back

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>: "All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s controversial book should take note
of these much-needed studies, which, in line with serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convincingly</ENAMEX> and authoritatively dismantle its arguments."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
Hobsbawm, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Age of Extremes: A History of the World</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914-1991</TIMEX>

            "In this important volume
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birn</ENAMEX> demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s study of the Judeocide
is monocausal, teleological, and severely blinkered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> carefully sets
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forth Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s distortion and disregard of the secondary literature; Birn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterfully</ENAMEX> lays bare his gravely flawed use and interpretation of archival
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> also raise hard questions about the political reasons for
the inordinate promotion and reception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s book. No serious student
of history can afford to ignore these well-reasoned and withering reflections
on the perils of pseudo-scholarship."

            -- Arno
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayer</ENAMEX>, author of Why Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heavens Not Darken?: The Final Solution in</ENAMEX>
History

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> and Birn
provide a devastating critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s simplistic and misleading
interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. Their contribution to the debate is, in my
view, indispensable."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian</ENAMEX>
Kershaw, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>

            "Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willing Executioners</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Bettina Birn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> stand out for the seriousness and thoroughness with which they have
undertaken their task. Even if I do not embrace every aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s
conclusions concerning the politicization of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historiography</ENAMEX>, I am
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grateful</ENAMEX> for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' courageous, conscientious, and labor-intensive
efforts."

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Browning</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ordinary Men: Reserve Police Battalion</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> and the Final Solution in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Is Daniel Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s Willing Executioners the definitive work on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judeocide</ENAMEX>?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of this volume express serious doubt, which I share. To reduce a
phenomenon of this scale and complexity to the anti-Semitism which permeated
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> society as it also permeated other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> is to be simplistic and to
show contempt for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. This book rights the balance."

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Vidal-Naquet</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jews: History</ENAMEX>, Memory, and the
Present

            "Highly recommended to the
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s controversial book, especially those who were
mesmerized by its hypotheses. Fortunately, in an open society all scholarship
is subject to public scrutiny, and the advance of historical knowledge cannot
do without rigorous criticism of the kind provided in this important and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courageous</ENAMEX> collection."

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volker R. Berghahn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.P. Birkelund</ENAMEX> distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
history, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown University</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birn's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essays</ENAMEX> constitute a sharp rebuttal provoked by the public's and the press's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX> affair with a book that casually dismisses excellent work done by others;
that contains many contradictions; and that upholds dangerous myths regarding
the existence of 'national characteristics.' "

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">István Deák</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyond Nationalism</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political</ENAMEX>
History of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Habsburg Officer Corps</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848-1918Back</TIMEX>

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Browning</ENAMEX> told me: "What's important
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s critique is that he has traced the inconsistencies and
contradictions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>, and no one else has taken the time to do that.
It's not my style of writing. But I don't think he's gone beyond the bounds of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polemic</ENAMEX> in replying to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>'s polemic." In interviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>
sounded grateful that someone had stood up so boldly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldhagen</ENAMEX>, who, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willing Executioners</ENAMEX> , had dismissed the work of virtually every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> who came before him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the blurb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have quite understandable
grudges: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> has, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, been railing against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX>'s emphasis on
peer pressure in explaining why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> participated in genocide; in a
New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> review, he accused another endorser, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arno Mayer</ENAMEX>, of
being a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revisionist</ENAMEX>. In any event, these blurbs often appear to be
more the expressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-wishers</ENAMEX> than of close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobsbawm</ENAMEX> is not
alone in saying he didn't read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX>'s essay "line-by-line." Back

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finkelstein</ENAMEX> notes that anti-Semitism in other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> was often worse; there was, in pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hitler Germany</ENAMEX>, "no equivalent of
the riots that attended the Dreyfus <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affair</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> or the pogroms in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>."
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Weimar</ENAMEX> period, moreover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nationalist Socialists</ENAMEX> found they couldn't
get much mileage out of raw appeals to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Jewish</ENAMEX> prejudice, and often toned
down their anti-Semitism around election time. Back

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>: Footnoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pulzer</ENAMEX>'s sober study
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldhagen</ENAMEX> asserts that only the "core of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">socialist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>" opposed anti-Semitism. In
fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pulzer</ENAMEX> says no such thing. He found little evidence of anti-Semitism
among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Social Democrats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Back

            Note <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>: "Thus interpreted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> extermination both
justifies the necessity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and accounts for all hostility directed at
it: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is the only safeguard against the next outbreak of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">homicidal</ENAMEX> anti-Semitism and, conversely, homicidal anti-Semitism is behind
every attack on, or even defensive maneuver against, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. 'The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>' is in effect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zionist</ENAMEX> account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> holocaust."
Back

            Note <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>: Among other things, they warn against the danger
of removing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> from history and turning it into a sort of secular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>, the central symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> identity. They also deplore the
invocation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> as a justification for policies that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
would deplore if they were implemented in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Back

            Note <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>: Goldhagen asserts the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> police battalions
knew of the planned destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> before entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>,
rather than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> after, as most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> believe. He bases this claim
on the "conclusive" statement of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former storm troopers. In fact, their
statements about extermination orders from above evolved over time, Birn
explains, as part of a "defense focused on superior orders as an
excuse."Back

         
      
   
