
   
   
      
         
            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sands</ENAMEX> Through the Hourglass

            "At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>," a
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> observed recently about campaign
reform, "we remain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX>, less so of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> than of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>'
professions of nonpartisanship." "At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
Times noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> voted once again to
keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> at arm's length, "it is a greater loss to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> than it will ever
be for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>." "At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>," a sportswriter for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal Sentinel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presciently</ENAMEX> pointed out in advance of professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> championship game, "what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC</ENAMEX> primarily has going for it in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> is the law of averages."

            What is
this "day" that everyone is referring to? It is not so much a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of time as a
unit of consummation, and it highlights, in a way, our larger confusion about
what chronological time is and what measuring it is good for.

            The planet's most accurate time is kept by an atomic clock
accurate that every so often the time must be adjusted by adding a "leap
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>" to account for the gradual, if modest, slowing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s rotation.
(This last happened on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 1997</TIMEX>. It will need to happen again sometime
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.) The idea that time's passage has an objective dimension connected
with diurnal rhythms is, of course, increasingly quaint, and may eventually
become obsolete. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Asimov</ENAMEX>, in his futuristic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> Trilogy
novels, imagined a thickly settled universe where the familiar "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-hour day</TIMEX>" is
an accepted convention, presumably based on the rotation of humanity's planet
of origin--but where no one remembers any longer what the original planet
was.

            In
language, too, time seems to have got out of hand. Temporal language often
depicts the passage of time not merely as fast, relentless, and irrevocable but
also, more and more, as conceptually slippery. The term our times and
its portentous relative our time (as in "one of the most important
movies/books/recordings of our time ") are rhetorically vast but
temporally indeterminate, even as they become trivialized by overuse. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> not long ago called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Cisneros</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX> now under indictment, "the most skilled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> of our times.") Decent interval , another modern standby, is
an interval whose length no mechanical or atomic clock can measure; the only
instrumentation that works is emotional. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paschal Zachary</ENAMEX> observed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, or at least <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, was awash in defining moments (you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX> beating, the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>). At this point in time , a
legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, seems to be unequivocally specific, but of course the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subtext</ENAMEX> is that time is fluid, that circumstances change, and that truth could
be different a little later on.

            
By comparison, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> ,
with the sense of "when all is said and done" or "eventually" or "in the
fullness of time," has a shapeliness and finality about it. It has been waxing
in popularity since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>. The term's proximate origin remains
obscure--some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> have suggested an association with the world of sport or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>, where activities are indeed governed by an actual daily cycle and
where a metaphoric sense could easily have arisen out of the literal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC World Service</ENAMEX> can attest, the usage has become widespread
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> spoken throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Commonwealth</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">politician</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>: "At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will
decide whether or not this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>,
also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>: "At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>, the ethnic consideration will rule
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Zorn</ENAMEX> has theorized that the
utility of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of the day</TIMEX> has been augmented by the various
unresolved episodes lumped under the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater</ENAMEX>," which call for an
economical way of expressing the thought "when things finally get straightened
out ..."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert W.</ENAMEX>
Burchfield, the longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX> , treats
the phrase with magisterial derision in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Fowler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usage</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>)--he dismisses it as "one of the ignoble clichés introduced
into the language in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20c</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> recorded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>)." And yet the phrase,
though lately putting in overtime, is not so young. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lexicographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Sheidlower</ENAMEX> has found a reference to it in a passage from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varieties of Religious Experience</ENAMEX> , in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William James</ENAMEX> quotes words
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voltaire</ENAMEX>, for which he gives the date <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1773</TIMEX>: "All comes out at the end of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, and all comes out still more even when all the days are over." That
quotation itself calls attention to apocalyptic antecedents in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, where
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the days</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last days</TIMEX> , meaning "the end of the
world," is often much on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s minds. Thus, from the prophet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>: "And in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX> it shall be, God declares, that I will pour out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spirit</ENAMEX> on all
flesh" (Acts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:17</TIMEX>). And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> says to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prophet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>, "You shall rest,
and shall stand in your allotted place at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the days</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:13</TIMEX>).

            Any cant word or phrase becomes tiresome, which perhaps
accounts in part for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burchfield</ENAMEX>'s impatience with at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> .
(The word parse , rapidly deployed in press conferences and commentary
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used an eyebrow-raising tense to describe his
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, went from inert silage to spent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">husk</ENAMEX> in a
matter of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.) At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> has its good and bad points.
Among the bad: It imposes an implicit template of struggle and confrontation
where none may exist. It also implies the inevitability of resolution. The good
points include its realism: Even as it invokes the traditional language of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, it does not in fact insist on squeezing events into a rigid chronological
mold. (In contrast, consider the false concept of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> , which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX> in Breaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> castigated for having become "the basic
unit of political time," a status ruthlessly enforced by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> schedule of
political talk shows.) Also, the whiff of eschatology that the phrase exudes is
not inappropriate to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>'s approach.

            Are its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> numbered?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>, who once addressed the phrase in passing, seemed to think it a
nonce expression, enjoying an ephemeral vogue. That was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>. Those
inhabiting <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>'s linguistic core may find the phrase cloying, but its
popularity in finance and sport, and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> spoken by non-native
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, suggests that its colonizing power remains robust. My guess is that
it will achieve, at the very least, a kind of status that is going to be
conferred on more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> locutions as time goes on: the status of a
native idiomatic expression whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> is in fact an international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its best days</TIMEX> lie ahead.

         
      
   
