
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuitical</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmudic</ENAMEX>

            An exchange occurred not
long ago in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Superior</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Municipal Courts</ENAMEX>. As a lawyer
attempted to excuse his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s behavior with a convoluted explanation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ford</ENAMEX> interrupted acidly with the comment, "That's just ... that's just
too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuitical</ENAMEX> for words." The colloquy continued as follows:

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pardon me?</ENAMEX>"
            

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's too Jesuitical</ENAMEX> . You probably didn't go to a
Jesuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX>: "Certainly didn't. I am of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> faith."
            

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>: "Then it's too Talmudic for words."
            

            One can almost hear the appreciative chuckles from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> at this bit of repartee--the overreactive,
tension-dispelling response that very mild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witticisms</ENAMEX> tend to produce in solemn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">venues</ENAMEX>. And yet someone should have risen to say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Objection</ENAMEX>!" It is common to
regard "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jesuitical</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talmudic</ENAMEX>" as synonymous, but this does an injustice to
both words.

            
"Talmudic" originally signified nothing more than "of or pertaining to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX> ), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Talmud</ENAMEX> being the postbiblical
Rabbinic code of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> laws and interpretations that is the source of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodox Judaism</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuitical</ENAMEX>" originally signified "of or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pertaining</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuits</ENAMEX>; belonging to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Jesus; Jesuit</ENAMEX>"
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> , again), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jesuits</ENAMEX> being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> clerical order
founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignatius Loyola</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1534</TIMEX> as an intellectual bulwark against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX>. Whatever else may be said about them, both "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talmudic</ENAMEX>" and
"Jesuitical" carry connotations of great learning and meticulous attention to
argument. Where they diverge is in motivation.

            Very early, owing in part to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English Protestant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">propagandists</ENAMEX>, the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jesuitical</ENAMEX>" came to characterize a form of argument
designed less to seek the truth than to make a case, a form of argument that
was aggressive and clever but perhaps not always sincere--indeed, one that was
at times cunningly equivocal or downright deceitful. Aside from pure
anti-Jesuit animus, this nuance probably arose from the work of some
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologians</ENAMEX> who imperfectly employed a method known as
"casuistry" in resolving questions of moral theology--an approach that gave the
broadest possible leeway to individual behavior. This form of justification,
which became known as "laxism," may explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> were the
confessors of choice among <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> aristocracy.

            To characterize a lie as
an "economy of truth" would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuitical</ENAMEX> formulation. To say that one had
smoked marijuana but did not inhale would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuitical</ENAMEX> distinction. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> received his undergraduate degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, a Jesuit
school.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> argues that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jesuitical</ENAMEX>" has by now developed a sense
devoid of any overtones of prevarication: "subtle, intricate, moralistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reasoning</ENAMEX>, informed by a rigorous logic" is his definition. I am not as
sanguine as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX>, and believe that using the word will always carry some
slight risk: It may be wielded as a slur and received as a compliment, or vice
versa.

            "Talmudic" carries none of
this baggage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX>, with its commentaries on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> and its
commentaries on the commentaries (the process goes on and on) cannot be faulted
for using guile to arrive at a congenial "truth." But the word has its own
negative connotations. Talmudic scholarship is famous for the tortuous and
painstaking manner in which truth is pursued and established--if it can be
established at all. It is assumed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmudic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> that the language of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmud</ENAMEX> is precise, and that each word is therefore of surpassing significance.
As a result, even infinitesimal details are treated with the utmost
seriousness. Also, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmudic</ENAMEX> scholarship is sometimes aimed at practical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX> (for instance, civil and criminal law, dietary laws, the status of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>), it also considers issues that have no practical application at all, and
sometimes delves into matters that may seem utterly fanciful.

            In his
book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Essential Talmud</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adin Steinsaltz</ENAMEX> recounts a
famous absurdist parody: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> asked his disciple why the letter peh (p

         
      
   
