
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Diagnosis: Totally Sane</ENAMEX>

            There was a time, back in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX>, when psychiatry appeared to loom over vulnerable minds with a kind of
menacing grandeur. White coats seemed scarcely less ominous than white hoods,
and fervid anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Szasz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Foucault inflamed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> of
freedom against the depredations of nosology. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, though, news of a
freshly minted mental disorder--or, better yet, a new edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychiatric Association</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental</ENAMEX>
Disorders containing many such novelties--tends to be an occasion for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">merriment</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> , now in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its fourth</TIMEX> edition, is the reference book
which details all the mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> currently acknowledged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX>. As
such, it provides comic material for a certain contemporary genre of psychiatry
criticism that finds it laughable (rather than sinister) that psychiatry
appears to be expanding its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> from real craziness to everyday
life--coining diseases like "premenstrual dysphoric disorder" (PMS), and
"caffeine-induced sleep disorder." Countless articles in this vein have been
published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>--the recent controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
piece on the absurdity of the diagnosis "road rage," for instance ("You're Not
Bad. You're Sick. It's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">in the Book</ENAMEX>."), or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.J. Davis</ENAMEX>' sweeping, stumbling
caricature in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last February</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Encyclopedia of Insanity</ENAMEX>--A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Psychiatric Handbook Lists a Madness for Everyone</ENAMEX>.").

            Herb
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutchins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Kirk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> of social work and social welfare
respectively, have, in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> joint effort, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making Us Crazy</ENAMEX> (their
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was called The 
               Selling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> ), combined the paranoid and
the snooty modes of critique to produce a book about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> that's more
reproving than suspicious, and more earnest than parodic. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> are
typical of any number of articles attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> , and can be summed
up in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the most common contra-psychiatric fallacies bandied about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
To wit:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> If you ever do something that's listed in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> as a symptom, it means <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> think you're
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cuckoo</ENAMEX>.
               
            

            This is the most common
criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> . Once upon a time, the argument goes, crazy people
were crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: They were the ones barking like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and thinking
they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Napoleon</ENAMEX>. The rest of us, meanwhile, suffered only from ordinary
problems of living. "There is a growing tendency in our society to medicalize
problems that are not medical, to find psychopathology where there is only
pathos," complain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kutchins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX>. "The psychiatric bible has been making us
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crazy</ENAMEX>--when we are just human."

            The
problem with this reasoning is that the concept "crazy" is entirely foreign to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Insanity</ENAMEX> is a legal and literary notion now, not a psychiatric
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> tend to differ from ordinary problems
less in quality than in quantity and context. Checking to see if your oven is
off is not a sign of mental disorder; feeling compelled to check it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> times
every time you leave your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> probably is. Which is not to say that
someone who checks their oven <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> times is crazy , whatever that
means--but rather that if he should apply to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> for help, he would
find that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> would produce a name for his behavior, would assure
him that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> engage in it also, and might offer him <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to help him
stop.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> changes its mind about what
it's going to call mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every few years</TIMEX>, so obviously we can't
trust it as a guide to what mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> really are.
               
            

            It is certainly the ambition
of the biologically oriented majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> to produce a manual of
mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> which, as the saying goes, "carves nature at its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX>"--one
which lists diseases that are each traceable to a unique, identifiable
malfunction in the brain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> as it now stands, however, has no
pretensions to being such a manual. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> is neutral as regards
etiology, which is to say that its disorders are grouped according to
observable symptoms rather than presumed cause. If you look up a disorder in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> , you will find that it's defined by a list of problems (such as
impaired motor activity, or feeling numb and empty), a certain number of which
qualify a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as having the disease.

            To
maintain, then, as do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kutchins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX>, that "having an operational procedure
for determining whether a phenomenon belongs in a class, such as the checklist
of symptoms in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> , does not substantiate what that construct or class
is," is to completely misunderstand how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> works. Arguing that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Antisocial Personality Disorder</ENAMEX>" is not really what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> says it is,
is like arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madame Bovary</ENAMEX> didn't really do all those things Flaubert
said she did. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antisocial Personality Disorder</ENAMEX> is its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>
description. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutchins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> like to refer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> as "psychiatry's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bible</ENAMEX>," implying that it inspires reverence and is in need of suspicious
interpretation, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> is better described as psychiatry's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX>. It is periodically revised in response to arguments about usage and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">usefulness</ENAMEX>, but new disorders do not represent claims to fresh biological
knowledge. Which is to say that yes, a particular mental disorder is whatever
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> says it is.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 Unbeknownst</ENAMEX> to the credulous public, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> is not truly a scientific document but the product of crude politicking
and cynical compromises.
               
            

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, after a series of
heated and embarrassingly public quarrels on the topic, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX> decided to
resolve the question of whether or not homosexuality should be called a mental
disorder by means of a ballot mailed out to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. The majority of those
responding felt that homosexuality was not a mental disorder, and the
APA accordingly removed it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> 's next published edition. This
incident was unusual, and yet not so very different from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APA</ENAMEX>'s standard
modus operandi. Each edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> is the product of arguments,
negotiations, and compromises. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutchins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> cite a particularly amusing
example of such disputes: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Spitzer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> ,
was sitting down with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that included his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, in the process of
composing a criteria-set for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masochistic Personality Disorder</ENAMEX>--a disease that
was suggested for, but never made it into, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">III</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> (a revised
edition). In response to one of the proposed symptoms, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spitzer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protested</ENAMEX>, "I do that sometimes," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spitzer</ENAMEX> responded, "OK, take it out."

            To
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutchins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX>, this kind of ad hoc list-making is not science but politics.
But it's not clear that any science is so pure that it's exempt from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> decisions about what's to be considered valid research. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutchins</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> isn't a true account of mental illness because
it's informed by particular social values. But of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>
is informed by social values. Medicine is informed by social values. To
declare something a disease (rather than simply a part of life) is to declare
it unacceptable and in need of treatment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. When is a person too
unhappy? When does eccentricity become psychosis, or political suspicion
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>? How much pain is pathological? Under what circumstances should a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s death be described as "natural" and attributed to old age, rather than
described as "premature" and the result of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> questions,
all.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> insults the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of traumas
and societal injustice by calling their problems "mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX>," thus
implying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are wacko and have brought their problems on
themselves.
               
            

            It's always entertaining to
go back and read about the racist inanities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX> past. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuel</ENAMEX>
Cartwright, for instance, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1851</TIMEX> coined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ingenious new diagnoses to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> to slaves: drapetomania , or running away (recommended treatment:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whipping</ENAMEX>), and dysaesthesia aethiopis , whose symptoms were sloth and a
tendency to break things (recommended treatment: whipping). Yes, there can be
no doubt that psychiatry has been--and continues to be--used for very dubious
purposes, and that diagnosis is always inflected by the politics of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX>.

            To assume, though, as do
Kutchins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX>, and many other left-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, that psychiatry is an
inherently sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, and that diagnosis--labeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--is mean,
is to ignore many of the ways psychiatry is used. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Posttraumatic</ENAMEX> Stress
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disorder</ENAMEX>, for instance. This diagnosis, which describes the delayed
aftereffects of extremely unpleasant experiences, made it into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> as a result of lobbying by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who wanted their
continued suffering symbolically and financially recognized. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTSD</ENAMEX> has since
been applied to all sorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> of excessive numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twinkies</ENAMEX>. It has become one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX> 's most popular disorders, in part because it is so very useful to
its diagnosees: It makes them eligible for insurance-reimbursed therapy, for
instance, and it can bolster an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> defense.

            
Paradoxically, though, while it's often used as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> pleas, PTSD
implies not that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are crazy, but rather that they aren't .
Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTSD</ENAMEX> became a recognized disorder, after all, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> veteran
suffering from hallucinatory flashbacks and wild mood swings looked, to the
benighted layperson at least, nuts. But now his behavior seems ordinary, even
to be expected. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutchins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> appear to believe that attaching diagnoses to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> must necessarily be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of evil conservatism, but
pathologizing misfortune is a technique more often employed by the left than
the right--by those, that is to say, who want to mitigate responsibility by
drawing attention to its causes, rather than those who want to assign
blame.

            As long as psychiatry is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of forced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institutionalization</ENAMEX> (and it still is, though less so than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>), it
seems clear that the diagnoses that license dragging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> can
hardly be subject to enough old-fashioned suspicious scrutiny. But with regard
to the vast majority of psychiatric encounters, which involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> showing up
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and asking for help, railing against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in white coats is
mostly beside the point. Labels can be reassuring. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> can be our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
Subtler tools are necessary.

         
      
   
