
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cult of Che</ENAMEX>

            So they have finally given
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX> a proper burial--the interment took place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17</TIMEX>--in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> soil,
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where he achieved his greatest revolutionary victory. You might
suppose that, in these after-days of communism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>'s legendary glamour will
soon enough find its way to a similar interment, though perhaps not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>
itself, where glamour, like everything else, remains under state control.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> was
not, after all, the best of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX>. He was, in his dashing manner, the
worst--an extreme dogmatist, instinctively authoritarian, allergic to any
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> or libertarian impulses, quick to order executions, and quicker
still to lead his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> to their deaths in doomed guerrilla wars. Love
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> was his first instinct, and when he evolved a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, more
critical instinct, it was only because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> turned out to be less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rigidly Marxist-Leninist</ENAMEX> and less suicidal than himself.

            Of the innumerable commentaries on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> that have been
published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alma Guillermoprieto</ENAMEX> offered the clearest, in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> . "He was a fanatic," she wrote, "consumed by restlessness
and a frightening abstract hatred, who in the end recognized only one moral
value as supreme: the willingness to be slaughtered for a cause." But I am
struck most by a commentary that appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Etcétera</ENAMEX> , under the byline <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilberto Guevara Niebla</ENAMEX>--no relation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>
himself, yet a figure of great importance in the revolutionary history of the
1960s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilberto Guevara Niebla</ENAMEX> was arguably the single most important student
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> student uprising of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>--the uprising that was finally
put down in a massacre by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1968</TIMEX>.

            He wrote,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> offered his life to the cause of the disinherited, but he did it by
offering a political method that, in the long run, had disastrous effects on
whoever tried to uphold it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guerrilla</ENAMEX> war imposed a militarist logic and closed
the space for democracy. What <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> lived since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> launched his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slogans</ENAMEX> was a bloodbath and a wave of destruction and terror. ... The myth of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> has been a wall impeding the observation of those fatal historical
results." Who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>? A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who "wanted to change the world through the
means--always sordid--of killing other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>."

            
Couldn't be clearer. Yet, among the kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who once upon a time had admired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> and his cause--a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
especially in the generation that was young in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>--the more typical
commentaries have balanced on a "but," as on a fulcrum. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> was wrong; but he
was good. His ideas were hopeless; but he remains the embodiment of an ideal.
Let me quote the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Nouvel Observateur</ENAMEX> , which devoted an
issue to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>: "That his politico-military theory ... failed
matters little. What remains, on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andes</ENAMEX>, is the example of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of his continent, who knew how to die for his generous ideas in
an unequal struggle." Or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , which
concluded, "What is left is simply the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> who could not part with his
dream, and who earned a place in history precisely because he refused to yield
to it."

            Or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etcétera</ENAMEX> 's special <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> issue, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX> is only the other name of
what is most just and dignified in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>." And so forth, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> after another, which would be hard to believe, except that right
now the world is awash in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che T-shirts</ENAMEX>, mugs, barroom décor, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Che</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> (in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>), posters, and utterly pointless editions (let us hope) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>'s
military writings. And the mania is not just a matter of mass culture.

             

            Among the books about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> that have just now come out, one
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorge G. Castañeda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Compañero: The Life and Death</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX> ,
offers an exceptionally lucid analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>'s life and doings, based on a
tremendous amount of research both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-government files.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castañeda</ENAMEX> knows more about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> guerrilla movements than anybody,
outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.) Yet in a few paragraphs at the front and
close of his book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castañeda</ENAMEX>, this most intelligent and admirable
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, extols "the fervent idealism and generational arrogance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>"
around the world, and then anoints <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> as "the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who most closely
embodied its deeper meaning." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Régis Debray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrade</ENAMEX>, wrote a memoir last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> in which he warned against exactly that delusion--"the anti-authoritarian
revolt of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'68</NUMEX> taking this hardcore partisan of authoritarianism for its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emblem</ENAMEX>." But then, I can understand that particular confusion. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> I wrote a piece of my own about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> and,
though I knew better, I ended up adding a superfluous nod to the innate
"nobility" of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose fanaticism and lack of human sympathy brought
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about</NUMEX> so much suffering and death.

            Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know better
say such things? It is not because of the doctrines of communism. It is because
of the doctrines of glory, which are much more primitive. What is glory? This:
an absolute commitment to your own principle, whatever it may be--the kind of
commitment that expresses itself in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> way, by a willingness to kill
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on its behalf, and to be killed in turn. A commitment, finally, to
defeat. For victory is always partial and compromised, but defeat and death are
total and grand. Victory is secular; defeat is sacred.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> who,
like any ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, had never killed anyone; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> who had
survived his guerrilla adventures, and was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>,
administering some grim <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> or, alternatively, writing
books at home in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>, surrounded by his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> like that would cause no stir at all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> around the world
would not be straining their brains to draw ever finer distinctions between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s calamitous influence and some undefinable greatness.

            
There is a precedent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>. It was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX>, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s craze that
went on for generations--the craze that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stendhal</ENAMEX> described in his character
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julien Sorel</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black and Victor Hugo</ENAMEX> in his character
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marius</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Misérables</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX>, intelligent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> knew perfectly well that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX> had embodied the worst
aspects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Revolution</ENAMEX>, had betrayed the revolution's democratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideals</ENAMEX>, and had spread death and fire from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. Yet those same
clear-thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> found ways of separating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>'s horrors from his
glamour. They would say: He was wrong, but he was great. It was a question of
glory--of his having risen in the world, and having killed his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, and
having failed spectacularly, and not having flinched. It was the appeal of
death--doled out, and accepted. And so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX> was, finally, a
cult of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1821</TIMEX>
Napoleon was murdered--he was poisoned--while in the hands of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, far
away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> was murdered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>. It took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 years</TIMEX> to bring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon's</ENAMEX> remains back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reburial</ENAMEX> took place on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15, 1840</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who should have known better found
the ceremony moving. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Hugo</ENAMEX>, who stood among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, dutifully
recorded, in a poem on the occasion, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX> had been wrong--that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX> had tried to conquer with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> instead of with the mind. Yet a
few lines later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo</ENAMEX> wrote, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonapartist</ENAMEX> blood pounding:

            May the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> forever
keep you in their memory,      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> as beautiful as glory,      <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tomb</ENAMEX>!

            So in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> tropics, too, there has just now been a day
as beautiful as glory, cold as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>. And because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of glory feeds on
defeat and not on victory, we can be sure that, like the passion for Napoleon
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last century</TIMEX>, the passion for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> will disappear no time soon. Not in
this generation, not in the next.

         
      
   
