
   
   
      
         
            Missing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Links</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time-Life</ENAMEX> bought the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zapruder</ENAMEX> film rights <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s murder, a company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">footage</ENAMEX> was so horrific that the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22 second</TIMEX> film would be locked away forever.
As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>, however, you could pick up a digitally enhanced, more
horrific than ever version for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> bucks at the corner video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
surrendered its rights in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">year Geraldo Rivera</ENAMEX> first broadcast the
film on television.)

            Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> already know the imagery--after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX> presented it in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panavision</ENAMEX>--and probably regard it as a valuable "clock" of the assassination,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that created problems for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warren Commission</ENAMEX>. Among other things, the
film led to a "magic bullet" thesis to account for a lot of wounds from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
rapid shots and, later, to the "neurospasm" and "jet effect" theories to
account for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> snap" reaction to the final shot. Assassinologists have
argued for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zapruder</ENAMEX> film alone confounded any lone gunman
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thesis</ENAMEX>.

            Many still think so, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> a late-stage hard
core of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Z</ENAMEX>-film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> has developed a different view. Watching dupes year
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, measuring prints with calipers, subjecting the movie to "vector
analysis" and performing their own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stopwatch</ENAMEX> experiments, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
(including several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>) have discovered the film is not merely evidence
of conspiracy but is also a part of the plot. That is, it's a fake--or, as one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemptuous critic</ENAMEX> describes it, "a cartoon."

            How did
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zapruder</ENAMEX> film become, in one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s phrase, "itself an instrument of
conspiracy"? The film is known to have been copied at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Photographic Interpretative Center</ENAMEX>, though nobody knows when. In one
conspiracist scenario, it was rushed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPIC</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> where Zapruder
had left it. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five feverish hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> edited and optically
manipulated the film to mask what had really happened. Faked prints were rushed
back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> just in time to be given to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zapruder</ENAMEX>. When other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dealey Plaza</ENAMEX>
home movies surfaced, they too were "collected" and altered to match. The
result is "the hoax of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>."

            
But it hasn't fooled everyone. In their haste,
the purported <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hoaxers</ENAMEX> left behind evidence of tampering. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Groden, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspiracist</ENAMEX> specializing in image trickery, argued in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> that frames were missing. (The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groden</ENAMEX> testified in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> civil trial that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruno Magli</ENAMEX> photos were fake.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groden</ENAMEX> thought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
frames were gone, but the stakes on "missing frames" have since risen: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One pair</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> now theorizes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as many frames were exposed as we see
today, that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the "original" film has been removed.

            How can anyone tell? Among
the many clues offered in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assassination Science</ENAMEX> , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> anthology that
devotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> pages to proof that the film is a fraud: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> make supposedly
implausible moves between frames, the "blink" pattern on the presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limo</ENAMEX>'s front lights is said to be uneven, the awful results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> shot
can't possibly have lasted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> frame (the horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frame 313</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
Lifton, famous for his theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was surgically altered before the
autopsy, has written elsewhere that portions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> shot sequence look
suspiciously dark to him and that some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s "movements" may be special
effects.

            But other
Z-film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> argue the film is almost entirely special effects: that the
grassy background one sees is surely a repeated matte shot, because nobody in
it moves; that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> shot sequence features an optical zoom to eliminate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foreground</ENAMEX> figures and make it easier to manipulate; that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> shot itself
is an optically collapsed version of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more widely separated hits. Oddly,
there is even a claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s shocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> snap, among the biggest
challenges to the lone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> thesis, didn't happen and is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> special
effect.

            So what did the real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zapruder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> reveal? To these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, it contained incontrovertible proof of conspiracy (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> shots,
say), but just what that proof was depends on which conspiracy each believes
in. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> believe the lost footage showed an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> actually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shooting JFK</ENAMEX>. No, not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Dog Man</ENAMEX>, who looms indistinctly over the grassy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knoll</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dealey Plaza</ENAMEX> imagery and who may or may not be seen on the
Z-film at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Frame 413</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> have in mind is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, who purportedly braked, drew his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>, and
delivered the coup de grâce in the middle of the motorcade.

            Perhaps the original Zapruder
film still exists. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> may have a copy, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
claims he picked it up for them; or maybe there's a copy at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, where one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> says she watched it. But the real question about the film--in this
context, the inevitable question--was raised by longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspiracist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Livingstone</ENAMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Killing Kennedy</ENAMEX> .

            "Is it possible," asks
Livingstone, "that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zapruder</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingstone</ENAMEX>'s theory is that "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masterminds</ENAMEX>" behind the murder wanted a film they could alter. Otherwise, he
writes, the whole sequence of events is just "too convenient."

            Thus, on close scrutiny, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zapruder</ENAMEX> film's ultimate revelation is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Zapruder</ENAMEX> was himself a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conspirator</ENAMEX>. At least it gives the film a surprise ending.

         
      
   
