
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brother From Another Planet</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, the jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX>
known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> recorded a remarkable album, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz in Silhouette</ENAMEX> . Borne
aloft by splendid dancing melodies and often-startling syncopation, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz in</ENAMEX>
Silhouette soared in the manner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke Ellington</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingeniously</ENAMEX> conceived <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX>, where a boppish swing might break into a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>
cha-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cha</NUMEX>-cha; or a trumpet's eerie whisper, into a thunderous row of piano
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clusters</ENAMEX>. The best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vinyl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz in Silhouette</ENAMEX> is also the most
obscure. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a clip from the album.)

            That's
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>'s reputation was established not by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz in Silhouette</ENAMEX>
but by albums like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heliocentric Worlds of Sun Ra</ENAMEX> , whose
garrulous improvisations and expressionist timbres--devoid of a tonal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>,
with much less of a tune to hang on to--made it an exemplary statement of free
jazz. From a strictly aesthetic perspective, neither of the two volumes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heliocentric Worlds</ENAMEX> holds up well against free-jazz albums from the same
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil Taylor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coltrane</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don Cherry</ENAMEX>. The saxophones cry
balefully, the drums rumble ominously, the marimba echoes warmly--yet the
combined effect is more curious than moving. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a clip from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Heliocentric</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Worlds</ENAMEX> .)

            But then, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Szwed</ENAMEX> makes clear in his new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Space Is the Place: The Lives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of Sun Ra</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>
never aspired to conventional lyricism; he wished to re-create the roars and
the silences of the cosmos. And, in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Heliocentric Worlds</ENAMEX> , he forged an
original style intended to do just that. Rejecting chords--the traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> of improvisation--as an impediment to creativity, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> favored the
more supple backdrop provided by a hypnotically sustained drone, or "space
key." This freed his sidemen to pursue the music in their heads--a fairly
turbulent journey, as it turned out. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the music sounds pretty far
out, clanging with esoteric percussion, electronic distortion, and novel
instrumental voicings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heliocentric Worlds</ENAMEX> was also an expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ra</ENAMEX>'s persona, a persona so extraordinary it ended up casting a permanent shadow
over his art. The cover illustration of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> volume linked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> to a
visionary heritage of space explorers including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da Vinci</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Copernicus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Galileo</ENAMEX>,
Pythagoras, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tycho Brahe</ENAMEX>. The songs were interstellar tone poems, bearing
titles like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosmic Chaos" and "Outer Nothingness</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>'s
fascination with outer space was no publicity stunt. Born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Blount</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX> (he took the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> sun god in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genuinely</ENAMEX> and fervently believed that he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX>. He denied
that he had been born and, therefore, that he would die--a claim he maintained
right until he died, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 79</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. A short, rotund black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, dour of
expression, he appeared in garish flowing robes, a shining turban, and space
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">goggles</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly four decades</TIMEX>, this cosmic jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX> performed, lived,
and traveled across the world with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afro</ENAMEX>-futurist troubadours
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arkestra</ENAMEX>" (a cross between "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ark</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX>"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>'s men
believed in the myth of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s origins and, like him, waited to be
rescued from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> by alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spaceships</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Blakey</ENAMEX>, Arkestra
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">saxophonist John Gilmore</ENAMEX> often boasted about his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">band</ENAMEX>'s concerts were filled with dance, light shows, midgets, fire breathing,
and space chants.

            
Unlike most jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> was not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of the black bourgeoisie. Poor and fatherless, he grew up in 1920s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>, one of the most segregated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. As an adolescent,
he was afflicted by cryptorchidism, an especially ferocious hernia. Terrified
that "others might find out and that he might be treated as a freak," he became
a recluse, burying himself in music. When not practicing piano, he was delving
into mystical treatises at the black-run <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masonic Lodge</ENAMEX>. Declaring himself a
conscientious objector to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, he directed a poignant appeal to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Service Board</ENAMEX>: "I don't see how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or anyone else could
expect me to agree to being judged by the standards of a normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>'s
struggle with disability is the real revelation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Szwed</ENAMEX>'s book. (Oddly enough,
he neglects to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>'s apparent homosexuality, to which jazz
aficionados refer as if it were common knowledge.) Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Szwed</ENAMEX> does
not explore it enough. Might it help explain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>'s attraction to theosophy,
his repudiation of physical reality as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>," his conviction that our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> are mere <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, his obsession with secret layers of meaning? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>
hinted at such connections to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor saxophonist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Griffin</ENAMEX>: "I must be
from someplace else because I'm a total misfit." Many of us have entertained
such a thought about ourselves. The difference is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> actually came to
believe it. There's a tale here as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX> as, and in some ways akin to, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applewhite's</ENAMEX>.

            Like many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'50s outcasts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> came into his own in the
'60s. He was honored as an elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX>, housed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Seale</ENAMEX>, hired as a guest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, embraced by
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippies</ENAMEX>. His appeal to different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> isn't hard to fathom. To
flower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkestra</ENAMEX> was a commune; to black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX>, a black
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commune</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s ensemble structure seemed to prefigure the black music
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cooperatives</ENAMEX> then being set up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, as well
as such emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> funk bands as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sly</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Stone</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, the
eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">funk pioneer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clinton</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>: "This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was definitely
out to lunch--the same place I eat at." It was a compliment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> saw
himself as a charismatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who would deliver his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> through
patriarchal discipline. The anarchism of his music was deceptive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>'s
dream was to rule something like an intergalactic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>. Music, he
believed, provided a "model for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." That model combined futurism,
Egyptology, and black uplift. In the post-Sputnik age, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> argued, it was
incumbent upon black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> to master electronic instruments, notably the
Moog synthesizer. As he put it, "Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are behind on these things, and
they've got to catch up." (If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> were around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, he would almost surely
be an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot</ENAMEX>--as is, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ornette Coleman</ENAMEX>, whose performance
piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tone Dialing</ENAMEX> , owes much to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>.)

            
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> were to achieve transcendence
through self-abnegation. In living with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra, Arkestra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> renounced
drink, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and sex. Until the moment of "emigration to space," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>'s word
was the law. He could wake up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> if he desired,
for rehearsal, or for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">windy</ENAMEX> lecture on ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. Those who crossed him
risked corporal punishment. "We're less than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupils</ENAMEX>," explained one
Arkestra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>. "We're nobodies with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilmore</ENAMEX>, a brilliant tenor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saxophonist</ENAMEX> who influenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coltrane</ENAMEX> and played with both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blakey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>, gave up what was bound to be a distinguished solo career to play with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four decades</TIMEX>. He never led his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            How was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Ra able to</ENAMEX>
command this kind of sacrifice? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Szwed</ENAMEX> stresses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>'s affiliations with
a powerful current of black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> prophecy. From <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>' dreams of being
transported magically back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Song</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> ,
the idea of a miraculous exodus has loomed large in black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> narratives.
It's understandable why this fantasy of flight would take root in black
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, which, at numerous moments in its history, has been given reason to
fear that conditions in the diaspora can never be improved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spaceships</ENAMEX>
did not come, as it were, out of nowhere. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Szwed</ENAMEX> overlooks a crucial
distinction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> and his forebears. He and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> weren't
operating at the level of metaphor. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX>, which claims
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elijah Muhammad</ENAMEX> is currently circling <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">space shuttle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> made his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> of liberation in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> the ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> of a rigorous theology,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, and enterprise. There is a word for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that obey a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">charismatic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, uphold fantastic founding myths, and assemble a body of
secretive lore, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Szwed</ENAMEX> can't bring himself to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkestra</ENAMEX> a cult. It's
too bad he's squeamish. As a jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Ra</ENAMEX> never fulfilled the bright
promise of his early recordings like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz in Silhouette</ENAMEX> . But by founding
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>, he earned a lasting place in the larger culture, which otherwise might
have eluded him.

         
      
   
