
   
   
      
         
            Trash Talking

            Recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
of the world's most populous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were compelled to relinquish their hold
on power: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> amid mounting violence, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sani Abacha</ENAMEX> fell afoul of a fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> key element,
apparently, in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s constitutional system of checks and balances. Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abacha</ENAMEX>, of course, were despicable tyrants, with records of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">venality</ENAMEX> and bloody oppression. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J. Habibie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdulsalam Abubakar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>--did not quite concede as much in the first
public statements they made, but they did use language that seemed to indicate
an awareness of the value of human rights and democratic procedures. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Habibie</ENAMEX>
committed himself to running "a clean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, free from corruption,
collusion, and nepotism." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abubakar</ENAMEX> declared himself "fully committed" to a
"social-political transition program" leading to an elected civilian
government. Afterward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> quoted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> radio described the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> as "making all the right noises ."

            
               Making
all the right noises : The phrase has proliferated over a period of little
more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>--perhaps in part because it itself makes all the right
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noises</ENAMEX>. It signals that the noisemaker under discussion may be no more than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX>-tongued hypocrite, even as it suggests that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, having seen it
all, could not possibly be taken in by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">noisemaker</ENAMEX>'s blandishments. It also
leaves open the unlikely possibility that the actions will indeed live up to
the noises.

            Making all the right noises, carrying the connotation just
described, seems to have surfaced mainly in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in the late
1970s and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1980s</TIMEX>. It surely evolved from earlier use in more literal,
straightforward contexts (for instance, to describe the sound of an automobile
engine or a musical performance) and ultimately from the long-established and
nonjudgmental phrase to make noises (that is, to express oneself about
something), a construction that happily accommodates all manner of adjectival
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prefixes</ENAMEX>. All the right noises , with its stance of jaded cynicism,
quickly spread from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> organs (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> ,
the Financial 
               Times ) into most parts of the far-flung Anglophone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circulatory</ENAMEX> system. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is applied in a wide range of circumstances,
especially when the noises being talked of invite a presumption of hollowness,
sanctimony, or hypocrisy.

            Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, analyzing the economic situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Jong Pil</ENAMEX>, in line to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Dae Jung</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, may
make all the right noises about economic reform, but his own ties to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chaebol</ENAMEX> [industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX>] may be too tight to break." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, writing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> must do
something. And a making-all-the-right-noises kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX> message
is not enough." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Herald</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assigning</ENAMEX> blame for the failure of
campaign finance reform: "In his presidency so far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has made all the
right noises , but has done nothing while playing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same old</TIMEX> games to
raise vast sums."

            Given some
of the tendencies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scripture</ENAMEX> translation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent decades</TIMEX>, it would hardly
be surprising to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:33-35</TIMEX>--the passage in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> promises to
remain a loyal disciple scant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> before turning disloyal--rewritten and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embellished</ENAMEX> to render the response from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> as follows: "Truly you make
all the right noises . But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this night</TIMEX> you will deny me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times."

            
Among the reasons why an expression such as
making all the right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">noises</ENAMEX> achieves wide usage quickly is this simple
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>: The phenomenon of empty talk is so prevalent that new ways of describing
it--especially ones that possess a modest elegance and formality--are always
welcome. As it happens, many wonderful terms for empty or hypocritical talk are
by now quaint and archaic ( humbuggery , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pharisaism</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tartuffery</ENAMEX> ), and some of the most common terms are simply vulgar
( <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">bullshit</NUMEX> ).

            Lip
service, as in the phrase to pay lip service --from the act of raising
one's voice publicly in prayer or song while inwardly harboring contrary
convictions--is probably the most widespread and durable formulation. (Thus,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> currently vying for the nomination to run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> recently accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonse D'Amato</ENAMEX>, of
"paying lip service to gay issues.") Similarly, lip salve is
insincere flattery, though it may be enjoyed by the recipient nonetheless as a
form of ear candy . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lip</ENAMEX> , with its satisfying mouthfeel (to
use the jargon of the food-service industry) and its still-obvious link to an
elemental root (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> leb , with the connotation ""), has
formed numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">slang</ENAMEX> combinations whose meanings touch all the compass points
of verbal intention. To shoot from the lip is to speak rashly. To zip
your lip is to shut up. To invite someone to read your lips is to
emphasize your sincerity. To lip-sync is to move one's lips in
synchronization with a prerecorded sound--and, metaphorically, to mouth someone
else's sentiments.

            Like paying lip service , making all the right
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noises</ENAMEX> possesses just enough color to be memorable and yet not so much
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> as to cloy. It may be in for a long run. In contrast, one has to wonder
about the longevity of its main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> in the linguistic marketplace right now:
talking the talk, but not walking the walk --a vivid expression from
black <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> that seems lately to have become a mandatory part of the
repertoire of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>,
motivational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, newscasters, and sportswriters. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who talks
the talk and walks the walk is one who acts naturally and stylishly, whose
words and behavior are of a piece; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who talks the talk without
walking the walk , therefore, is one who is dissembling, ineffectual, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insincere</ENAMEX>. The incorporation of walk the walk and talk the talk into
white<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-bread</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, often by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> colloquialism is a pose,
may not bode well. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> need only remember how the appropriation of the verbs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dig</ENAMEX> , rap , and groove by grown-ups during the late 1960s
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1970s</TIMEX> proved to be a kiss of death.

            The extent to which the
expression has found favor was brought home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Flynn</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Paul</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> to ordain a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>-bound candidate for the priesthood. There, in a chapel at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College</ENAMEX> on the slopes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Janiculum Hill</ENAMEX>, during a service
otherwise conducted entirely in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynn</ENAMEX> delivered a sermon that included
this injunction to the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>: "When you teach, be sure you receive the word
into your heart before the word forms on your lips. Walk the walk and talk
the talk. Don't preach one thing and turn around and do something
else."

            One can
assume that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>, in response, made all the right noises.

         
      
   
