
   
   
      
         
            Too Much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Thing</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> wouldn't have expected
to see or hear the word in the coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s tragic death--the
event was too sad, the word too impolite--but it might have claimed a
legitimate place in the coverage of the coverage, or at least in the
commentaries about the coverage of the coverage. As far as I can tell, however,
the word overhype was nowhere to be found. It was like an embarrassing
relative sent off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> whose presence lingered nonetheless.

            In a
culture in which the words "of our time" have become synonymous with "of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year or so</TIMEX>," overhype --a noun and verb meaning an excessive amount
of hype , a term which itself connotes an excessive amount of
orchestrated publicity--has evolved to describe one of the distinctive
characteristics of our time. It is, of course, ubiquitous in the world of sport
("even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irabu</ENAMEX> never displayed his overhyped <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">99-mph</NUMEX> fastball"), of fashion
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>, the overhyped <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>"), of trade ("overhyped and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overmarketed</ENAMEX> product"), and of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> in general ("a brief and, she says,
overhyped liaison with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX>"), but it has filtered down to
unimaginable levels, much as a grande caffè latte can now be had in the
coal fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>. Not long ago a newspaper column (in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orleans Times-Picayune</ENAMEX> ) about fishing rods contained the following
sentence: "Nothing has been overhyped more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> than the value of
ball bearings in reel construction."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overhype</ENAMEX> is a thought-provoking term, the provocation
occurring unintentionally, and in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is etymological. My
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Slate columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX> asked me recently: "Isn't it slightly
absurd to apply the prefix over to something whose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> root means
under ?" As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> knows, the hype in overhype probably
comes from hypodermic , as in needle, the components of that term
deriving from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> words meaning "under the skin." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hypodermic</ENAMEX> led to
the slang term hypo , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of needles with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use gave
rise to hype in the sense of "artificial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stimulant</ENAMEX>," which is the direct
ancestor of hype as employed in advertising and the communications
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>. Given the roller-coaster ride of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> that overhyping both
promotes and describes, the stripped-down "over-under" meaning of the word may
be weirdly appropriate. (Note: An alternative etymology of hype would
derive the word from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> hyper , meaning "over," so that to
overhype something is to "over-over" it--more straightforwardly logical
but not nearly as evocative, in my view.)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">provocation</ENAMEX> is conceptual: How does one match up this term and its variants
( hype , underhype ) with a corresponding reality? Overhype
implies there is some normal level of "hypeness," like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> temperature or
blood pressure, which in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> maintains a certain
constancy, but which can rise or fall to dangerous levels. But hype
itself means "intentional excess to create attention" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX>'s New World
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dictionary of Media and Communications</ENAMEX> ), implying that the normal level is
by definition excessive. Underhype , to pursue this line of thought,
could thus refer to a level that is subnormal but nonetheless sufficient to
sustain life.

            
Apossibly fruitful tangent would be to explore
the relationship between hypeness and other terms that calibrate degrees
of public recognition. For example, I received a postcard some while ago
announcing an exhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who are said to be "underknown," implying
that knownness , like hypeness , has a normative dimension. I
imagine that only after attaining the level of being fully known can one
then reach for the low rung of underhyped .

            The concepts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overrated</ENAMEX> and underrated inevitably intersect with this
discussion, because to be described as either of these things one must display
a degree both of knownness and of hypeness. In the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> character learns that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Murphy</ENAMEX> have invented something they call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of the Overrated</ENAMEX>,
and have filled it with, among others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jung</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>:

            Keaton: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX> ... we
can't forget <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX>, can we? How about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>: These people
are all terrific--everyone that you mentioned ...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>: You had a great <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
...Keaton: No, I didn't have it--it was yours ... it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heinrich Böll</ENAMEX>.
...<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy: Oh God</ENAMEX>, we didn't want to leave out old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heinrich</ENAMEX>. ...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overrated</ENAMEX>?! Gee, what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>--you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> wouldn't want to leave out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>--I mean as long as you're trashing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ...Keaton: Oh, well, how about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Van Gogh</ENAMEX>? Or Ingmar Bergman?

            The permutations of ratedness are complex. It is, of
course, easy to think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> who are both overrated and overhyped. A far
more noble category consists of those who are underrated and underhyped. The
most difficult category to conceive, though it does exist, is that of figures
who are underrated and also overhyped. (With some trepidation I float the name
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>.)

            Now that hypeness has
broadened into a full spectrum from underhyped to overhyped , the
concept may be ready for scientific quantification. There is precedent for this
not only in the hard sciences, where one would expect it, but also in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social sciences</ENAMEX> and humanities. Thus, much as we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of heat, called
the calorie , and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of light, called the lumen , social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have devised a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of pain, called the dukkha , from the Pali
word for "suffering." Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> employ a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of beauty, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">helen</ENAMEX> ,
derived from words addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Troy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlowe</ENAMEX> play Dr.
Faustus : "Is this the face that launched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, and burned the
topless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ilium?</ENAMEX>" A millihelen , then, is the amount of beauty
that would launch a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>.

            The basic
unit of hype would have to be the warhol , and obviously it would be
equivalent to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes</TIMEX> of fame. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warhols</ENAMEX> could be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kilowarhol</ENAMEX> or, perhaps, a jewell , after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Jewell</ENAMEX>, the man
who generated news reports for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> despite having failed to participate in
the bombing at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic Games</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>. A milliwarhol , or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about nine-tenths</NUMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of fame, might appropriately be named after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tyke</ENAMEX> whose rescue became a brief focus of attention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> after he fell
through the hole of an outhouse. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nine-tenths</ENAMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, unfortunately, was
how long his name remained in my memory.)

            
Amatter that bears watching: how closely the
language and dynamics of hype come to resemble those of arms control.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overhype</ENAMEX> is, in its way, a strategically brilliant term. It suggests
that anyone who finds overhype unreasonable speaks with a voice of
moderation--"C'mon, enough is enough"--while at the same time setting the
ceiling at a level far higher than what any ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would find
acceptable or sufficient.

         
      
   
