
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enemy</ENAMEX> Within

            The setting is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>--as interpreted in the movie Contact --and presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> have convened to discuss an extraterrestrial communication in the form
of an engineering diagram. The plans, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Arroway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>),
are for "some kind of machine."

            "A machine? That does what,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>?" asks a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>.

            "Some kind of a transport,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arroway</ENAMEX> replies.

            "It could
be anything," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters National Security Adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kitz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Woods</ENAMEX>),
who is dubious of extraterrestrial motivations. "It could be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse</ENAMEX>. We
build it, and out pours the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vegan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>."

            That isn't, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> have in mind, but
the term <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse</ENAMEX> --the durable ancestor of the expressions <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
column and mole , and of the modifier stealth --has certainly
been enjoying a prominent vitality <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, as befits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> that values
frontal hostility far less than it does insidious subterfuge. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan Horse</ENAMEX>," proclaimed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Crown Colony</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> was returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The familiar story of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse</ENAMEX> appears in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aeneid</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, with armed men
hidden inside, is presented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> to the besieged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Troy</ENAMEX>,
and brought within its walls. It immediately achieves an afterlife as metaphor
(in addition to yielding the admonition "beware of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> bearing gifts"). "The
central question," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> correspondent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas D. Kristof</ENAMEX> in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> dispatch, "is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> amounts to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">colossal Trojan horse</ENAMEX>: a
prize so glorious that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> cannot leave it outside the gates but
which, once inside, will destroy those in power" with its irrepressible example
of roiling capitalism and affluence, and its concentrated economic power.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trojan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> has found further application in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX> in the realm of
plastic surgery. The phrase refers to a bodily overhaul so extensive as to
render obsolete all superficial indications of age or identity. "I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trojan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> of such procedures, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>, a self-described
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mensa</ENAMEX>, explained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX> to a newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, "because what you
see is not what you get. I may look young and bimboesque, but I am nothing of
the sort." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this summer</TIMEX> the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amado Carrillo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuentes</ENAMEX> apparently died on the operating table while undergoing cosmetic
surgery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse amplitude</ENAMEX>; law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> needed to perform
forensic testing to confirm that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decedent</ENAMEX> was, in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carrillo</ENAMEX>. Also in
the medical arena are the various kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse invaders</ENAMEX> that trick
their way into acceptance by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s cells, and then cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>; and the
various kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse countermeasures</ENAMEX>, including gene therapy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>.

            
The most prevalent use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is its cyberuse, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades old</TIMEX>, where it refers to hard-to-detect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instructions</ENAMEX> secretly embedded in computer software, making possible various
kinds of unauthorized or unintended outcomes ranging from theft to breach of
security to self-destruction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horses</ENAMEX>, long of concern to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">money managers</ENAMEX>,
database <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, and weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, afflicted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> in the course of an episode concluded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade</ENAMEX>
Commission <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse</ENAMEX>, which acquired the variant name
Moldovan <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> , quietly made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> place a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long-distance</TIMEX> phone call to
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Moldova</ENAMEX> whenever they gained access to a certain pornographic site on the
Internet. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> were unaware not only that they were placing such a call,
but also that exiting from the site did not terminate the call. The Moldovan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse scam</ENAMEX> was inevitably short-lived. A sudden spike in the aggregate volume
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moldova</ENAMEX> telephone traffic, followed by the delivery of outlandish phone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, soon suggested the existence of a problem.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way
to turn almost anything into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">conceptual Trojan horse</ENAMEX> is to attach the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> to it as a modifier. The relatively recent term stealth
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> meanings. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> refers simply to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who seems
not to show up on the political radar screen--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> used the term this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> in speaking of his opponent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. The other, now more
common, meaning harbors an element of deviousness: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in state
and local elections in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 and 1994</TIMEX>, for example, were <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan stalking horses</ENAMEX>
for fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who emphasized popular,
secular conservative issues in their campaigns but failed to disclose that
their candidacies had been covertly planned and energized by the religious
right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stealth</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">usages</ENAMEX> obviously builds on the precedent of the
B-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Stealth Bomber</ENAMEX>, the strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> built by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northop Corp.</ENAMEX> that can
penetrate enemy air defenses undetected. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, in turn, eventually gave
rise to the Stealth condom, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> was sued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northop</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> for
trademark infringement. The Stealth condoms were red, white, and blue--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trojan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> of another color, one might say--and were sold in a deltoid package
reminiscent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stealth Bomber</ENAMEX>'s design, bearing the motto "They'll Never
See You Coming." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northop</ENAMEX> alleged that the condom's name was "likely to cause
confusion, or to cause mistake, or to deceive," a concern that might have been
more understandable if each condom came with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion-dollar</NUMEX> price tag.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> decided to drop the matter.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ATrojan</ENAMEX> horse in espionage is a mole , a foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who has burrowed deep into a society or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The connotation is of
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> provenance and was given broad currency in large part through the
novels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Le Carré</ENAMEX>, whose longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>, the spy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
Smiley, has pursued moles within <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intelligence. Those within a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> who sympathize with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>'s aims, and may render assistance when
the time is ripe, constitute a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> column , a term that goes back to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Civil War</ENAMEX> and the remark of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel general</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emilio Mola</ENAMEX>, to the
effect that his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> columns of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> would be supplemented by a civilian
quinta columna , a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> column of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX>, in their attack on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loyalist</ENAMEX>-held <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX> published a play with the title
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Column</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>. Numerical terminology (think third
wave , <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dimension</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estate</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sixth</ENAMEX> 
               sense ) is an open invitation to extension. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> used the term <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> column in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX> to refer to
rumor-mongerers, hoarders, and others who unwittingly hampered the war effort;
the term <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> column was applied later to those whose carelessness
led to industrial accidents. If every new refinement since then in the quiet
sapping of our national morale has earned a numerical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>column," then by now, I
estimate, we must be up somewhere close to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">78 th</ENAMEX> column" (applied,
maybe, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of the weekly network TV movies about bloody domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mayhem</ENAMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">79 th</ENAMEX> column" (airplane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who bring carry-on
luggage that they know won't fit into the overhead storage bins) or possibly
even higher.

            And my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> sense tells me
that it won't stop there.

         
      
   
