
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody Blues</ENAMEX>

            The decline of the big band
was belabored and cartoonish; it kept coming back long after it seemed to have
drawn its last breath. <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> is what really did it in, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and
rubber shortages prevented large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> from going on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. But once the
big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> no longer played dance music, it morphed into some strange, decadent
forms--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Kenton</ENAMEX>'s small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">municipalities</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> trombones, for instance, or
intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ensembles</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd Raeburn</ENAMEX>'s that magnified bebop's hustled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhythms</ENAMEX> and tricky harmonies.

            One
tradition that survived in altered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">form</ENAMEX> was that of the mood arranger, who went
from scoring music for big bands to orchestrating tone poems for individual
jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. That role was honed to perfection by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Evans</ENAMEX> in his
collaborations with trumpet-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1957 and 1968</TIMEX>--an
often-misunderstood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of work chronicled in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-CD box set called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Evans</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Complete Columbia Recordings</ENAMEX> , released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deluxe</ENAMEX>, semiclassical, and exotic, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hydroponic creature</ENAMEX> of the recording
studio, this music can't be understood simply as jazz. It's a lot more
complicated than that.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Evans</ENAMEX> got his start in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1930s</TIMEX> arranging for a
band in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, which later made theme and incidental music for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
Hope's radio show. He could have gone the way of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Mancini</ENAMEX>, a dance-band
jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> who realized that there would always be more money in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>.
But instead, he walked the tightrope between commercial and art music. His
keenest influence was another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Thornhill</ENAMEX>, who hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> to do
extra arrangements for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. The music from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX> was slow and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">haunting</ENAMEX>, moving like someone trying not to sweat on a boiling day. It had no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vibrato</ENAMEX> and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> horn, which would be combined with clarinets or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tubas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">odd</TIMEX>, hothouse-flower voicings.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>, on
the other hand, had been through small<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-group</ENAMEX> bebop in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s</TIMEX>, and found it
too intense and inward; as he noted in his autobiography, he was struggling to
find a way to make bop sound "sweet." When he convened a nonet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Mulligan</ENAMEX>'s help in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, and recorded the music which would later be
released as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Birth of the Cool</ENAMEX> , he was blending bebop with a reduced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Thornhill</ENAMEX>'s instrumentation. This new sound prefigured white,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> cool jazz, but so had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Strayhorn</ENAMEX>'s arrangements for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellington</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '40s</TIMEX>, and so had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester Young</ENAMEX>'s diaphanous tenor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saxophone</ENAMEX> playing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Count Basie</ENAMEX> even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> always insisted that
"cool jazz" was as much (if not more) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> as white music;
likewise, he never had any problem understanding that jazz was a form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T ></ENAMEX>he duality of high art and mass sensibility is at the heart of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Evans</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> records at the core of the
set-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Ahead</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porgy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bess</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sketches</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> --are music of fantasy, of dreaming. The drums, usually so central to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jazz</ENAMEX>, are for the most part rendered useless by the intricately accented horn
charts within the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>-piece ensemble sound. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> gathers around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soloist</ENAMEX>, rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soloist</ENAMEX> trying to ride the waves of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX>, and
every move is keyed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' sighing sensibility. But the most impressive
moments, oddly enough, are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' tremulous theme readings, laid down as mere
suggestions, like soft, wet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>'
arrangements were plotted like wily preparations for a siege. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 12</TIMEX>
measures of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Meaning</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blues</ENAMEX>," from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX> 
               Ahead , the contents of a rising
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counterpoint behind Davis</ENAMEX>' melody keep mutating: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> horn and trumpet give
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to oboe, which slides back into trumpets, and the progression into the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> measure, with nothing but the treble of muted trumpets in unison, feels
like an airplane taking off. (Its power as an organic whole is no accident:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Ahead</ENAMEX> was recorded in bits and pieces, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Meaning of the</ENAMEX>
Blues" was the only full, unspliced ensemble performance on the album.)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bess, You Is My Woman</ENAMEX>
Now," from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Porgy</ENAMEX> , has a brushed drum pattern underneath that keeps
shifting its emphasis from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> beats to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second and fourth</TIMEX>,
constantly renewing a stirring chill. Sketches sets up processional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhythms</ENAMEX> and rich, slow-motion harmonies behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, and then slyly extends
trickles of harp or flute from the rest of the mass. It is music of painstaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, and the box set, with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternate</ENAMEX> takes (including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> different takes
and portions of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springsville</ENAMEX>," from Ahead ) gives you an idea of how
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> managed to protect an inchoate, subconscious quality in his trumpet
playing, session after session.

            The records were received as instant masterpieces, in
breathless appreciations that couldn't begin to take in the complex way that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil</ENAMEX> had at once gone more commercial than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny Goodman</ENAMEX> and yet
created some of the most deeply vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> music around. But they
didn't transform jazz. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' lead, though fragments of
his sound wash up here and there. His <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">timbral</ENAMEX> combinations and unlikely
harmonies surface in the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX> jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butch Morris</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz Koglmann</ENAMEX>, as well as that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Schneider</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> leader
who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> before his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. But since
it's mainly jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> who grasp the significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>,
you hear his music most often being played by repertory bands. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most
famous pieces of music ever to have emerged out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sketches of Spain</ENAMEX>
isn't jazz at all. It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson Airplane</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White Rabbit</ENAMEX>," with its flamenco
rhythm and cavernous studio sound.

            It's
puzzling how midcult, how kitschy, some of this music sounds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. A quick
check into the sounds of its era reveals what the set's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">198</NUMEX> pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX>
notes don't--that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sketches of Spain</ENAMEX> was recorded, was
also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soul</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> by the mood orchestra <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">101 Strings</ENAMEX> hit
the Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>. Living-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exoticism</ENAMEX> was in. Nearly every major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> at the time
had its own <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> "mood" act. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>'s was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Greco</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>'s was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montoya</ENAMEX> (with his "fiery <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gypsy guitars</ENAMEX>"); countless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPs</ENAMEX> promised
genuine bullfight music. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sketches</ENAMEX> , which some have taken as the high
point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' collaboration, was also another chapter in a
mass-market gambit.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T ></ENAMEX>here are several differences between the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">101 Strings album and</ENAMEX>
Sketches of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> . Solos have no place in true mood music; they're too
unsettling and risky. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' calculated rhythmic displacement is
a major jazz metaphor, one that more commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> would never try to
attain. On the other hand, the music on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil</ENAMEX> is more about
sustaining a mood--and less about forward motion--than most of what we'd call
jazz.

            The real point of mood-music
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">albums</ENAMEX>, though, is to let them work on you. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Schaap</ENAMEX>, the reissue producer
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Evans</ENAMEX> , has made a fitting gesture
toward that end: He has provided a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6.5-second</TIMEX> "pause track" on each CD, so that
you can reflect on what you've just heard. He writes that it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
he's added such a track. Music that conjures up a sense of suspended time and a
still, suburban afterglow seems a perfect occasion for its debut.

         
      
   
