
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Requiem for the Mad Scientist</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of</ENAMEX>
Health happened to be hosting a gene-therapy conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gattaca</ENAMEX> launched their ad campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gattaca</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premise</ENAMEX> is the creation, in the not-so-distant future, of a genetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> has been rejiggered at the embryo stage to eliminate dispositions to such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traits</ENAMEX> as premature baldness and attention-deficit disorder while heightening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cheekbones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IQs</ENAMEX>. The newspaper ads for the film featured a mock promotion
for a biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that offered prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> made to
order." At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> conference, gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX> reported that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>
of trying to insert <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> into the cells of the genetically sick, not a single
cure had been reported. Considering the difficulty of such relatively simple
procedures as these, the world of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gattaca</ENAMEX> seems a distant nightmare.
"There's not a chance in hell," said a conference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geneticist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huntington Willard</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Western Reserve University</ENAMEX>, "that you could
recombine all those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and get a desired effect."

            Still,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Collins</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Genome Project</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>, which is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequencing</ENAMEX> and identifying all human genes, was intrigued enough to see
Gattaca twice, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time leading a matinee field trip of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.S. Lewis</ENAMEX> mold, broods about
the ethical reverberations of genetics quite a bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. What he worries
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> most is genetic redlining, where claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adjusters</ENAMEX> use tests, which he has
helped develop for heritable illnesses, to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> their health
insurance. What fascinates and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">horrifies artists</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is the
impression that geneticists have more creative power than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian</ENAMEX>
Willmut, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scotsman</ENAMEX> who cloned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolly</ENAMEX>, would seem to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> whose work has
really come alive.) In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gattaca</ENAMEX> , as well as in lots of other recent films
and books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> have dreamed up complex nightmares of genetic determinism,
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are mere puppets of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> scripts or of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and
profit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> who manipulate them.

            The wellspring of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.G. Wells</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Island</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moreau</ENAMEX> . In this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1896</TIMEX> novel, a vivisectionist attempts to transform
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> until the misshapen <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures revert</ENAMEX> and kill him, the forces
of nature overcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s civilizing artifices. From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Boys From</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josef Mengele</ENAMEX>, alive and well and cloning Hitlers
at a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attenborough</ENAMEX> alive and well and cloning velociraptors), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells</ENAMEX>' basic formula
has become familiar: an island; a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankensteinian</ENAMEX> experiment; a Faustian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>; something gone terribly, terribly wrong.

            But something else has gone
terribly wrong since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.G. Wells</ENAMEX>' time. In the new genetic thriller, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> is no longer mad, because he has no illusions of mastery. Instead,
he's a lone and often belated moralist, eaten up with remorse and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX>,
pushed into unsavory experimentation less by runaway curiosity than by
unscrupulous corporate overlords. Genetic manipulation is a given. The yucky
thing is the profit motive. And the mistreatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lab animals</ENAMEX>.

            In
Gattaca , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Freeman</ENAMEX> (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Hawke</ENAMEX>), a "faith
birth" whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't tamper with his embryonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. Because baby
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX>'s instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome readout</ENAMEX> indicated a weak heart and a life expectancy
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30.2 years</TIMEX>, he finds as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> that nobody will hire him, particularly not
at the space <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, in a sense, is the company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, who helps
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX> realize his dreams of becoming an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> in order to spite the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biotech-state</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s own eugenically planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> "didn't turn out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way they</ENAMEX> promised").

            
Or consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX>'s thriller Chromosome
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> . Molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Marshall</ENAMEX> works at a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
(shades of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moreau</ENAMEX>) fiddling with the DNA of apes to render their organs
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immunologically</ENAMEX> fit for transplanting into rich <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall</ENAMEX>
notices smoke rising from the island on which the organ-harvested <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">apes</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warehoused</ENAMEX>. Arriving to investigate, he finds them standing around a campfire,
chatting. It seems that he has inadvertently re-created the missing link.

            So what
does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX> do? Resign and register his ethical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>? Write up
his results for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> ? Order his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> to buy biotech?
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, his nostalgia for fuzzy critters results in an act of defiance
against his corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>: He throws biotech and science to the wind and helps
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-apes flee into the wilderness.

            The misgivings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> are particularly shrill in
Frameshift , by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sci-fi writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Sawyer</ENAMEX>. It's a purple
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premise</ENAMEX>: The Treblinka death-camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Terrible</ENAMEX> has adopted a new
identity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> as the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actuary</ENAMEX> for a health-insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
When a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> working in the genome project at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stumbles</ENAMEX> onto a series of murders in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivan</ENAMEX> is implicated, he thinks he's
found a neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> plot to eliminate the genetically challenged. But it turns out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan</ENAMEX>'s goals are more banal: His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is bumping off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> whose genetic
profiles indicate big future medical bills.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gattaca</ENAMEX> and elsewhere, genetic enhancement is harnessed to profit,
reflecting capitalism's relentless remaking of the world in search of
efficiency. This can backfire alarmingly, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Kress</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> novel,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beggars</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> . In it, genetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> adhering to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayn Rand</ENAMEX>-like
philosophy called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Yagaism</ENAMEX>" create a race of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't need to sleep.
The genetically altered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are exceedingly bright, ambitious, and nerdy, as
if cloned from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, and grow up believing that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s only value is
what he or she produces. Eventually, this race of supergeeks becomes so
thoroughly eugenicist that it turns on its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moreau</ENAMEX> , it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monsters</ENAMEX> who
force the moral issues. They're sloppy, imperfect products, trying desperately
to live up to an ideal of progress. "Are we not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>?" they plaintively ask.
Their struggle underscores <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moreau's</ENAMEX> spiritual poverty and capacity for
mischief. "To this day I have never troubled about the ethics," he says of his
work. In the new genetic thrillers, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who makes a last-ditch
stand against an irresponsible society--reflecting a role for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of ethical principles that were born at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> trials at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nuremberg</ENAMEX> and endured through the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treblinka</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagasaki</ENAMEX> may
have given <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> pause, but the doubts they occasioned came too late. They
didn't stop the arms race or radiation experiments using human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guinea pigs</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Genome Project</ENAMEX>, in fact, was built using the infrastructure of the
nuclear-weapons program, taking over unused <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livermore</ENAMEX>. But unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Project</ENAMEX>--in fact, like no other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Science</ENAMEX>
project in history--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genome Project</ENAMEX> has equipped itself with a research
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX> to explore the social and ethical ramifications of genetics. Its
findings have armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Collins</ENAMEX> in his crusade against genetic redlining.
And it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Willmut</ENAMEX>, whose work opened the door to human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloning</ENAMEX>, who most
forcefully denounced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospect</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearings held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>.

            Which brings to mind a line
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fay Weldon</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cloning of Joanna May</ENAMEX> . "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> talk a great deal more about God than does the rest of the world,"
she writes. "What is that but an obeisance to the shadow of the God who ran
off, the God they drove off when bold and young and frightened of nothing!" But
if God has taken flight, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gattaca</ENAMEX> and elsewhere, at least a few of his
imitators are trying to save their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
