
   
   
      
         
            Naming Names

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> elections had no
sooner sloughed into despond than I came across the following sentence in an
election-eve wrap-up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> . "There is no
denying," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> wrote, in the finale to an antic "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign Journal</ENAMEX>" series that
saw him parting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> around various presidential entourages with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prosthetic</ENAMEX> assistance of a television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steadycam</ENAMEX> on his shoulder, "that I was
excited by working alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Koppel</ENAMEX>, driven less by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fallovian</ENAMEX> desire to
inform the public than a lust to become rich and famous."

            The word
popped out: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallovian</ENAMEX> . Could I have been witnessing the birth of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eponym</ENAMEX>--as wondrous a sight in its way as our recent glimpse of an
island-in-the-making off the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>? An eponym, of course, is a word
that has been formed from the name of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, place, or thing
( eponumos is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> word meaning "named on"). For some eponymous terms,
the eponymy is obvious, or famous: Caesarean section ; graham
cracker ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Molotov</ENAMEX> cocktail ; boycott ; leotard ;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luddite</ENAMEX> ; silhouette ; volt . Many more eponyms, though
familiar, are not so obviously eponymous. Maudlin , for instance, comes
from the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Magdalene</ENAMEX>, who in painted and sculpted form is typically
shown weeping. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masochism</ENAMEX> comes from the name of the demented
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leopold von Sacher-Masoch</ENAMEX>, who described the
relevant eponymous practices in his writings. (Recently, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> has
been attempting to raise a monument to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masoch</ENAMEX> in his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lviv.</ENAMEX>)

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallovian</ENAMEX> ? In this case, the contextual evidence
suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' coinage fell into the class of eponym known as a
"derivative"--in this case, derived from a name, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , who has championed an approach to
reporting that emphasizes hard analysis of serious issues and eschews the cult
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> as highly paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>, or oddsmakers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>
confirmed that this meaning was precisely the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> intended, and said that, as
far as he knew, his use of it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Republic</ENAMEX> marked this proper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noun</ENAMEX>'s maiden voyage as an adjective. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallows</ENAMEX> himself, affably abashed, was
unaware of previous appearances of the term.

            Eponymous
words have never needed much tending or encouragement. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 35,000</NUMEX>
of them in the ordinary stock of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language, a figure that does not
include the many eponymous words in the specialized languages of science,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX>, and especially <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>. The use of eponyms in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> is steeply
on the decline, but ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eponyms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linguistic experts</ENAMEX> say, are enjoying a
growth spurt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. According to citations in recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and
magazines, to gump through life is to make one's way by means of dumb
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">luck</ENAMEX>. To espouse <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> positions at once is to pull a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> . To adopt
the hairstyle popularized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> is
to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel</ENAMEX> or to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends</ENAMEX> do . A sagan is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of quantity equivalent to "billions and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX>"--the quotation an
unintentionally self-parodic trademark of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronomer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Sagan</ENAMEX>.
Imeldific , made possible by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imelda Marcos</ENAMEX>, refers to ostentatious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grandiosity</ENAMEX> and extravagant bad taste. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manicure</ENAMEX> is torture.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldheimer</ENAMEX>'s 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> is a convenient lapse of memory.

            
To kevork someone is to assist him in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> of suicide--an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eponym</ENAMEX> derived proximately, of course, from the
work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kevorkian</ENAMEX>, but made possible by the prior success of the
rhyming verb to 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bork</ENAMEX> (from the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>, and meaning to
use every means possible to sabotage a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> to high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>). An eponymous
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">verb</ENAMEX> derived from the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>-- to 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> , meaning "to
slash"--shows some signs of acceptance among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> had a
previous life as an eponym, denoting a big car of the kind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> drove in his
commercials for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz</ENAMEX>. "Drive off in a def <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>," went a line in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> rap
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">song by the Sugar Hill Gang</ENAMEX>.)

            The verb
to 
               bobbitt , with its well-known specific connotation under the
household-amputation rubric, has become so widely used as to have now acquired
metaphoric senses. For instance, the verb is used to mean "to deprive of vigor"
in this sentence from a letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Times : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bravo to Tony Snow</ENAMEX> for exposing the bobbi[t]ting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
leadership when confronted with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tirades</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linguistic</ENAMEX> note from
abroad: The practice of bobbitting , according to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia</ENAMEX> correspondent
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX>--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cait</ENAMEX>, as it happens--is relatively frequent in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>. The local name for the practice is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> word that, when translated
into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, means "feeding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX>.")

            The surge in eponyms is no doubt related, in part, to the
efflorescence of metanames in general. Pseudonyms have never been more widely
employed than they are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of invented, incorporeal identities
are in play in all kinds of electronic communication. The married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
takes her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s family name as a surname yet keeps her own family name as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">middle</ENAMEX> name--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Day O'Connor</ENAMEX>--has unwittingly
introduced a new form of patronymic, which takes its place alongside the more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traditional</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>) versions. Even anonymity,
owing to controversy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> over the authorship of the novel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primary Colors</ENAMEX> , has had to endure an uncharacteristically high public
profile in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX>. I don't know what name future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> will bestow
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our present age</TIMEX>, but arguably the age deserves not a name but a nym.

            Why more eponymy now? Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, of course, have set out to make well-known eponymous terms of their
names, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> is doing with his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trump Style</ENAMEX> . The
proliferation of commercial brand names is certainly a major factor: Consider
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> neck , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Twinkie</ENAMEX> defense , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teflon</ENAMEX> presidency .
For reasons that hardly need belaboring, it is easier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than ever before
for any name--personal or commercial--to become widely known quickly, even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transiently</ENAMEX>. Memorable eponymous terms require memorable nominal roots and, in
the English-speaking world, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s names are becoming more diverse and
interesting as more cultures are demographically and linguistically annexed.
Also, eponymous terms allow almost anyone to display competence, even
brilliance, at coining useful and appropriate-sounding new words--thereby
encouraging further attempts to do so.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leona Helmsley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Fuhrman</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonse D'Amato</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Alomar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>. These and scores of other names cry out for eponyplasty. I look forward
to your suggestions.

         
      
   
