
   
   
      
         
            Listlessness

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Film Institute</ENAMEX>
says that one purpose in creating its list of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> films
was to stimulate discussion. In that, the list has been a success. It has
engendered not merely discussion but objection, accusation, abuse, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excoriation</ENAMEX>--nearly all at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s expense. It's an awful list by traditional
standards but no less fascinating for its shortcomings, and no less culturally
legitimate, either.

            Take your
pick of things wrong with the list. It fails to recognize acknowledged classic
films (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>) and major filmmakers (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keaton</ENAMEX>) and instead includes many more recent box office successes such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaws</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1975) and Tootsie</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>); that makes it a stupid list. It
was culled from a preselected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> titles and voted on by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX>
"prominent" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>; that makes it an
arbitrarily conducted test of popularity. It is designed to stimulate video
rentals; that makes it a commercial list. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> has argued
that in honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birth of a Nation and Gone With the Wind</ENAMEX> , it is
a racist list. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guess Who's Coming to Dinner</ENAMEX>? the list's only
anti-racist entry--and a mediocre <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at that--squeaked in at No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX>.)

            For the sake of argument, let's stipulate that the way the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX> went about filling up its list resulted in an approach to movie "greatness"
that is at best controversial and at worst dumbfounding. But controversy is
likely to follow in the wake of any "best" list. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s effort is a freeze
frame of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> movie taste in a moment of sweeping cultural transition.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s
list of all-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greats</ENAMEX> downplays the influence of credentialed taste-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>,
cinema scholarship, and educated judgment. It nods to expertise by anointing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Kane</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>) the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX>, then largely abandons
expertise. It thereby marks another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> in the decline of cultural
"gatekeeping"--the control over what is deemed worthy (as opposed to merely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">popular</ENAMEX>) long exerted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repertory programmers</ENAMEX>, film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historians</ENAMEX>, and so forth.

            
There's no shortage of would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gatekeepers</ENAMEX>,
but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> their influence has been waning. (Compare the influential
movie-ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>/blurbists of the past with the current proliferation of no-name
"quote whores.") They've been done in by the new technology--VCRs, cable,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">satellites</ENAMEX>, computers--that has provided a wide cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> with vastly
more choices than it had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation ago</TIMEX>, and vastly more power as a result.
The VCR revolution of the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, for example, has completely
transformed access to film's past. The old classic rep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> are now mostly
dark; the new rep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> are on cable, or on your VCR stand.

            Enter the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>--a gatekeeper that, true to its times, has yielded to more commercial
concerns. Its choices for the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> movies on its list are
explicitly designed to stimulate video rentals (and TV ratings for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated TNT</ENAMEX> series). These are films that, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s estimation,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are still willing to pay for and sit through. Less commercial
list-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> might have felt the need to pay lip service to, for instance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Flaherty</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nanook of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>), an undeniably "great"
film that is not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX> list. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flaherty</ENAMEX>'s famous portrait of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eskimo</ENAMEX>'s
daily struggle to survive was the first attempt to join documentary filmmaking
to personal vision, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flaherty</ENAMEX>'s case a vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humankind</ENAMEX>'s struggle to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overcome Nature</ENAMEX>. Once one of the world's most popular works, today
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nanook</ENAMEX> is rarely, if ever, seen by a nonspecialist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            And yet, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nanook</ENAMEX> might have made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX> list a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generation ago</TIMEX>, as might such other silents as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde Bruckman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keaton</ENAMEX>'s
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vidor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Crowd</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>), or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX>W.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith</ENAMEX>'s Way Down <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>). Back then, moviegoers in search of
culture were not only closer in time to the silents, they also acknowledged
their stature, and stature mattered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> then more than it does now.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to find out why.)

            The AFI
compilation reflects more than just technological change and the shifting power
to confer "greatness," however. It also suggests a change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> enjoys watching and with whom it wants to identify. This is
especially notable in the genre films on the list, the tales of tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>,
dames, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX>, spacemen, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> traditionally at the heart of popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> movie drama.

            
There are many genre films on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX> list, but
most of them represent their genre in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late</TIMEX> period-- The Godfather
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Odyssey</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild Bunch</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>), and
so on. These are indeed great films: powerful, handsome, strikingly edited. But
in many ways, they seem just the opposite of the movies from which they
developed. There is a startling difference between the gangster romanticism
portrayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlon Brando</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Pacino</ENAMEX> and the gangsterism embodied earlier
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward G. Robinson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cagney</ENAMEX>. You could admire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robinson's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s toughness, their ability to get their way. But in the
end, you knew they were bad: They broke their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>' hearts and paid too high
a price for their criminal success.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bonnie</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>), on the other hand, presents criminality in romantic soft
focus. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Godfather, Part II</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>) are a
daydream of limitless wealth and power available to those (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brando</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacino</ENAMEX>) clever enough to survive it. The old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX> morality
tales were always said (by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gatekeepers</ENAMEX>) to represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> gangster
film in its glory, but these morality tales are completely absent from the AFI
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>.

            The same is true of the cowboy and the tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. There are
traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> and tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on the list, but the former (as in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stagecoach , 1939</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Searchers</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>) is limited mostly to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX>, and the latter (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Maltese Falcon</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humphrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX>; and you get the sense these films were chosen more out of nostalgia for
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> than for their dramatic power. The old western was almost always a
tale of a courageous loner imposing order on lawlessness, as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX> films
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>). High <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noon</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>), which is on the list, is an
interesting variation. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Peckinpah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild Bunch</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>)
features existentially disillusioned outlaws going out in a montage of bloody
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chaos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>) is an outlaw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>) attempts to revise entirely the
concepts of both "order" and "the west."

            Few dames
made the cut. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Stanwyck in Double Indemnity</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>) is a lonely,
worldly wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on the list. The tough <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fugitive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> once haunted are nowhere to be found. The seductive and corrupting
film noir downtowns featured in so many admired cheap second features might as
well all have been demolished, along with the long-gone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bijous and Palaces</ENAMEX>
where these films first played.

            
Perhaps that makes sense. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twentieth century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture was largely a downtown experience. It isn't anymore. It is
increasingly an at-home experience, increasingly private, increasingly
personal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s list, for all its peculiarities, appears to reflect
that.

            
Obviously, being fairly arbitrary, many of the AFI choices may not lend
themselves to sound cultural interpretation. But there is an upheaval in canon
creation going on throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture, and this list brings that
upheaval to the movies. It's worth trying to understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">AFI 100</ENAMEX> for what it
is and isn't. The alternative is sitting in the dark, waiting for a show that's
really over to begin.

            
               If you
missed the link, click to see how the influence of cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gatekeepers</ENAMEX> has
waned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 50 years</TIMEX>.
            

         
      
   
