
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bible English</ENAMEX>

            Identify
the source of the following quotation:

            "For many are called, but
few are chosen."

            a) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> recruiting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advertisementb</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural Addressc</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Clearinghouse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweepstakesd</ENAMEX>) The Gospel according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>

            If you selected a), b), or
c), then you are probably not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chajul</ENAMEX>, in the mountainous Ixil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangle</ENAMEX> region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chajul</ENAMEX> is one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outpost</ENAMEX> in the far-flung network
maintained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summer Institute of Linguistics</ENAMEX>, an evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aim</ENAMEX> is to translate the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> into all the languages in which its words have
yet to be written. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIL</ENAMEX>, which is a sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, based <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wycliffe Bible Translators</ENAMEX>, has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scripture</ENAMEX> translation
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> under way in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 1,200</NUMEX> languages (at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $100 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">annually</ENAMEX>).

            Because
many of those languages have never even possessed alphabets, let alone
dictionaries, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIL</ENAMEX> translators are doing some of the most important
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linguistic</ENAMEX> work in the world. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chajul</ENAMEX>, according to an article in the most
recent issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural History</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, evangelico missionaries
have made deep inroads at the expense of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Catholicism</ENAMEX>, as they have
elsewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>. The language of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chajul</ENAMEX> into which the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> is
newly making an appearance is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> language known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ixil</ENAMEX>.

            What will be the impact of a vernacular <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> on the future
development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Ixil</ENAMEX> language? One can hardly help but think back to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. All told there have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> translations
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> since the first complete <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wycliffe</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1382</TIMEX>. From the point of view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language, the most
important translations were those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Tyndale</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1530</TIMEX>) and of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>
"learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>" who brought forth the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Version</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1611</TIMEX>). In wresting the
Bible from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>, the translators set a high standard
for ordinary spoken and written <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>. The coinages and cadences of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tyndale Bible</ENAMEX>--"eat, drink, and be merry"; "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>'s paradise"; "fight the good
fight"; "suffer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>"; "the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> of the earth"; "in his right mind";
"the powers that be"--and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Version</ENAMEX> have for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three centuries</TIMEX>
served both as psychic libretto and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as percussion</NUMEX> section for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>
everywhere. And, as the printing press gave momentum to these new vernacular
Bibles, so too did the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language itself acquire new cohesion and power.
(An archaeological aside: The entwining of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, printing press, and popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">literacy</ENAMEX> reveals itself in a curious fact from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX>. In
religion-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">soaked</ENAMEX> colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>, pieces of movable type show up frequently
during excavations of early <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>; they don't show up at all at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> of
comparable age in less aggressively pious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.)

            Whether
biblical language will continue to serve the same functions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is
another story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> wrote the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural</ENAMEX> Address knowing full
well that his biblical tropes ("woe unto the world because of
offenses!"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) would be recognized by everyone. I suspect that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> cannot even name all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX>. Recently I
sent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> "to and fro in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, and walking up and
down in it" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Job</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)--that is, I sent my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lessie Arnold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexandra</ENAMEX>
Custis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Livshin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Malcolm</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Romano</ENAMEX> out into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> and byways of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> metropolitan area. Their task: To ask people
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> if certain well-known phrases from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>--not identified as
such, of course--struck them as being in any way familiar; and, if the phrases
were familiar, to ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> to name the provenance. In all, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were consulted about some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> biblical quotations.

            
The most surprising result is the number of
commonplace expressions that seem no longer to be all that common--that did not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">register</ENAMEX> at all or "fell on rocky ground" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>). As you would expect,
everyone who was stopped for questioning had heard the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And God</ENAMEX> said 'Let
there be light' " and knew they were from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>. But a distinct majority of
those surveyed failed even to recognize the expressions "New <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> into old
bottles" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:22</TIMEX>); "The price of wisdom is above rubies" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Job</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:18</TIMEX>); "Put
not your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in princes" (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Psalms 146</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>); "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can the Ethiopian</ENAMEX> change his skin,
or the leopard his spots?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremiah</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13:23</TIMEX>); "What is truth?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:38</TIMEX>); "He
gave up the ghost" (Luke <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23:46</TIMEX>); and "The poor you will always have with you"
(Deuteronomy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15:11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:11</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecclesiastes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:9</ENAMEX>) allowed
that "There is no new thing under the sun," but for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of those surveyed, the
remark itself was such a thing.

            In many cases, although
an expression may have been generally familiar, its origin remained a matter of
mystery or guesswork. Thus the statement "To everything there is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>"
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Ecclesiastes 3</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) was universally known, but at the same time it was almost
universally ascribed to "a song from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>." "The truth shall make you free"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:32</TIMEX>) was likewise known to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, but only one person
identified the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. (The guesses of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> included:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX>," "something from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>?" "Kierkegaard," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerson</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liar</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liar</ENAMEX> --the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">with Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>.") Some other suggested sources of biblical
quotations: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Twist</ENAMEX> for "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> after his own heart" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13:14</TIMEX>);
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Parker</ENAMEX> for "Don't cast your pearls before <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">swine</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>);
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catullus</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink Floyd</ENAMEX> for "The writing on the wall" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel 5</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX>
recruiting advertisement for "Many are called, but few are chosen" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:14</TIMEX>).

            Note: Of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>-area locations surveyed--and these
included commuter<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-rail</ENAMEX> and subway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX>, and suburban
shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Square</ENAMEX> yielded the most embarrassing results. "If God
spare my life," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyndale</ENAMEX> once vowed to an educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, "ere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> I
will cause a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that driveth the plough to know more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripture</ENAMEX> than
thou doest." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyndale</ENAMEX> has probably succeeded beyond his imagining: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, any
Farm <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Belt</ENAMEX> inhabitant picked at random surely knows more of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripture</ENAMEX> than any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">randomly</ENAMEX> picked inhabitant of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> town. On behalf of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Square</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, it must be said that ignorance was masked by a
bravura self-confidence. Asked the about the expression "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suffer fools gladly</ENAMEX>"
(Corinthians <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:19</TIMEX>), the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> surveyed ventured a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> with
disarming speed: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wordsworth</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Hamlet</ENAMEX> ," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Hamlet</ENAMEX> ,"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> ," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wordsworth</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beowulf</ENAMEX> ," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chaucer</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macbeth</ENAMEX> ,"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrick</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerard Manly Hopkins</ENAMEX>." One might have been tempted to chide
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> with the comment that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pride</ENAMEX> goes before a fall" (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Proverbs</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:19</TIMEX>), but doubtless they would just have snapped back brazenly with
"Euripides" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Racine</ENAMEX>."

            In a recent op-ed article in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Novak</ENAMEX> argued that a new
appreciation for, and sensitivity to, religious matters was "stirring
everywhere." This certainly would hold true in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chajul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX>. Exempted from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX>'s observation might be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> professed to
have been unaware of connotations associated with the name they gave to a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s running shoe: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incubus</ENAMEX>." (An incubus is an evil spirit that has
sex with sleeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; the term is a product of medieval theological lore,
not of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.) Whatever the fortunes of religion itself, a dwindling
cultural acquaintance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is surely inevitable. To
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paraphrase Pink Floyd</ENAMEX> (or was it Catullus?), the writing is on the wall.

         
      
   
