
   
   
      
         
            How to Delight With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistics</ENAMEX>

            
Etymology, the study of word origins, often interests <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> otherwise
uninterested in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>. The reason, surely, is that etymology is tethered to
ordinary life in ways that are easy to grasp. Anyone can enjoy knowing how a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> bill came to be called a sawbuck (the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> numeral "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">X</ENAMEX>" that appeared on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX> notes reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the wooden sawbuck used in carpentry), or how
the word "robot" came into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> (it comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> word "robota,"
meaning "drudgery," and was part of the title of a widely popular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX>
play), or how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> root for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">beech tree</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">bhago-</ENAMEX>," gave us the
word "book" (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> used beech staves to carve runes on). We like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etymologies</ENAMEX> because they tell us stories.

            There would be no telling of stories at all, of course,
without grammar. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uninterested in language issues are content to
remain uninterested in grammar. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grammar</ENAMEX>, the genetic blueprint of meaning,
operates at a level of abstraction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouns</ENAMEX> and verbs and other parts of speech
are considered not as familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> but as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of different species.
Their interactions are considered as elements of an ecosystem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grammar</ENAMEX> is hard
to visualize, and it is harder to enjoy.

            Or at
least it was, until a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward R. Tufte</ENAMEX> began to publish his work about
the display of information in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufte</ENAMEX> has produced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> books
that make it possible to see the dynamics of linguistic grammar in a
brilliantly synesthetic way--books that succeed in this task by not having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grammar</ENAMEX> as their ostensible subject at all.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Tufte</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> who teaches
courses in statistics and information design. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> he produced an elegant
book with the unprepossessing title <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Visual Display of Quantitative</ENAMEX>
Information , which both explained and demonstrated certain rules for
presenting numerical data in a graphically arresting manner. This tour de
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>--written, designed, and published by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tufte</ENAMEX> himself--was immediately
recognized as a classic by data wonks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of fine books alike. It has
never been out of print.

            In his
analysis of such improbably compelling genres as railroad schedules and balance
sheets, chemical symbols and weather summaries, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufte</ENAMEX> reprinted numerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">graphic</ENAMEX> displays that epitomized the statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">draughtsman</ENAMEX>'s conceptual art.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Joseph Minard</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX> encapsulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> campaign, for example, a compact space revealed the diminishing size of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> geographical location, the direction of its route, the
passage of time, and the gradual drop in the temperature. It is a map, Tufte
noted, that illustrates "how multivariate complexity can be subtly integrated
into graphical architecture, integrated so gently and unobtrusively that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> are hardly aware that they are looking into a world of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four or five</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dimensions</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufte</ENAMEX> did not explicitly spell out his ultimate intentions
in that first volume of his trilogy, but it has turned out that the whole
series has been produced according to a precise schema--as he now indicates in
the introduction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visual Explanations</ENAMEX> , which was just published by his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, . The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Visual Display of Quantitative Information</ENAMEX> had been
devoted to pictures of numbers, he explains--"how to depict data and enforce
statistical honesty" whether the subject is traffic deaths or the distribution
of galaxies. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> book in the series, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Envisioning Information</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>), was about pictures of nouns--that is, about representational rather
than numerical reality: the depiction of cartographic information, diagrams,
and signage. (What's the best way to show sunspot activity, for example, or the
working of a subway system?) The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visual Explanations</ENAMEX> , is
about pictures of verbs--that is, about displays that illustrate dynamic
processes and can therefore function as explanatory narratives.

            
These explanatory narratives, these pictures of
verbs, can offer remarkable insight when properly conceived. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufte</ENAMEX>'s inclusion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Snow</ENAMEX>'s famous map of the 1854 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cholera</ENAMEX> epidemic in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> is a case in
point: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-by-street tracking of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cholera</ENAMEX> deaths pointed unmistakably
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">culprit</ENAMEX>--the water coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broad Street</ENAMEX> pump. The pump handle
was removed at once, and the epidemic ceased.

            In
contrast, these verb pictures can also smother insight when ill-conceived--as
were the charts prepared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Thiokol</ENAMEX> to illustrate the
behavior in cold weather of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">O-</ENAMEX>rings on the space shuttle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX>. These
charts, which failed to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> not to launch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle</ENAMEX>, were
confusing--dense with invitations to second-guess, even though crucial
information that would have delayed the launch was undeniably "there"
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> itself, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufte</ENAMEX> makes clear, was not the only design
element whose malfunction contributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> tragedy. After
presenting his own version of what the charts should have looked like,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tufte</ENAMEX> writes, "There are right ways and wrong ways to show data; there are
displays that reveal truth and displays that do not."

            What makes a visual display effective? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tufte</ENAMEX> lays out rules
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> such things as density and emphasis, chartjunk and clutter, layering and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hierarchy</ENAMEX>, color and parallelism--all of which have synesthetic grammatical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analogs</ENAMEX> in writing. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hierarchy</ENAMEX>, for instance, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of large
structures out of small ones, be they nautical charts out of soundings or
sentences out of morphemes.) Aware of the parallels between visual grammar and
written grammar, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tufte</ENAMEX> frequently makes direct comparisons that enhance one's
understanding of each. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place he shows how the rhetorical shape of a
passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gibbon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Decline and Fall of the Roman Empire</ENAMEX> , with its
paired images and a ribbing of parallel verbs, finds a visual counterpoint in
works of landscape design and even dance notation. (To get the full picture, so
to speak, you'll have to look at the book yourself.) An entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> is
devoted to the concept of "smallest effective difference," showing how
distinctions that are subtle but clear (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> light colors on a map, say) can be
far more powerful visually than any amount of heavy-handed contrast--as useful
a lesson in writing as it is in graphic design.

            
What one does not expect in a book of this
kind--a book that is technical even as it is beautiful--is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> will
be not just fastidious but also an evocative and wonderfully quirky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufte</ENAMEX> is all of these. In his discussion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> historic work--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Buchon</ENAMEX>'s
comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> rivers in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1825</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlas Geographique</ENAMEX> --Tufte
notes how the depictions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> must curl around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, since there's no room to show them stretched out like the other rivers.
Actually, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tufte</ENAMEX> says is, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he two rivers meander boustrophedonically
around a tight frame." That word boustrophedon describes writing that goes from
left to right on the first line, then right to left on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, then left to
right on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, and so on; it comes from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> word describing the
turning in a field of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX> and plow. Tufte, too, likes his etymologies.

         
      
   
