
   
   
      
         
            Stock-Market Tumult

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, and investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gurus</ENAMEX> have had almost two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> to explain the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27</TIMEX> stock-market dive. There are plenty of theories.
Here is the assortment in descending order of optimism.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Irrelevant Blip</ENAMEX>: The most bullish of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bulls</ENAMEX> tout
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Paradigm</ENAMEX>." Old laws of economics have been eclipsed by recent
breakthroughs in technology and productivity. Now there is no limit to upward
growth, only momentary breaks for the market to catch its breath. The bulls
cite evidence of the economy's continued strength--the low budget deficit (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion</ENAMEX>), steady GDP growth (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5 percent</NUMEX> projected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>), and strong
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-quarter</TIMEX> earnings reports. As of this writing, the Dow Jones industrial
average is still up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 15 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Necessary Correction</ENAMEX>: Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> agree with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> that the dive was a healthy
reaction to overvalued stock prices. Pre-dive, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> stocks tracked by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard & Poor's</ENAMEX> index sold at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 20</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>'s anticipated
earnings. Post-dive stock values, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan caucus</ENAMEX> predicts, will be closer
to traditional multiples of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 to 15</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> also predicts the crashlet will
have a "salutary effect" of reducing consumer confidence, which in turn will
cause the economy to grow at a slower, more sustainable rate with little
inflation.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irrational Traders</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">crash</ENAMEX> reflects the anxieties
of Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, not the economy's weakness. Reams of studies by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> show that emotions, not economic calculations, determine investor
behavior in a volatile market. The cliché is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> move as
a "herd"--once the bears reach a critical mass, the entire market panics.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myopic Managers</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shrewd Small Investors</ENAMEX>: Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> blame the crash on panicky mutual-fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, who unloaded massive
amounts of stock <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27</TIMEX>. Most credit small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, who bought more stock
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> after the crash, with fueling the recovery. The typical
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> has "guts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>," declared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">5 Hyperbolic Media: Journalists</ENAMEX> created bad vibes with
their wave of stories about a) how the market had topped and b) the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> crash. (See the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Oct.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> cover story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crash, Dammit</ENAMEX>.") Television heightened the panic by
interrupting broadcasts to update "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Market Mayhem</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>). Critics especially
point to the widespread publication of remarks by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan Stanley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Briggs</ENAMEX> that the market had gone bearish. Flip side: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> gets credit for
giving a platform to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bulls</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman Sachs</ENAMEX> market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abby Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, "our spiritual guide," whose recommendations "helped the market change
direction" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> ).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Options</ENAMEX>: The downward acceleration produced by
option-linked selling (the current substitute for the "portfolio insurance"
that was a prominent factor in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> crash) is blamed by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 30 percent</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s slide.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>: No serious market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> believes that
there is something about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> that tends to spook financial markets. But the
fact that so many past market mishaps have happened during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> (some
famous, like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929 and 1987</TIMEX> crashes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> familiar only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>) makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> jittery because they're afraid that everybody else is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superstitious</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8 Circuit Breakers</ENAMEX>: What would have been a minor dip in
the market became a major one when automatic trading halts--"circuit
breakers"--were invoked at the depth of the dive. (See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>" on
"Stock-Market Circuit
Breakers.") Instead of calming jittery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mandated breaks
induced more panic, and were portrayed by the electronic press as evidence of a
major crash. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Traders</ENAMEX> unloaded stock for whatever they could get between the
breaks, fearing a shutdown would prevent them from executing sell orders. Under
current rules, the first circuit breaker kicks in when the Dow falls <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX>
points. That yardstick is too conservative, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, because it was
instituted when the Dow stood at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2,300</NUMEX>, compared with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,600</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> may raise the circuit-breaker threshold.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>: The market tumbled in anticipation
of an economy-cooling rise in interest rates at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s upcoming meeting.
Rumors about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s intentions swept Wall Street <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> prior to the drop.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> is also faulted for not 
               reducing interest rates to spur
growth as inflation has slowed: Adjusted for inflation, rates stand at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX>
percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.98 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>. After the dive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> was universally lauded for putting a happy face on the market in
congressional testimony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s performance was likened to his calm
approach in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, which some say halted the market slide.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Obsession With</ENAMEX> Profits: The stock market's
unhealthy fixation on expected earnings led many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to exaggerate
balance sheets through accounting tricks, distorting true stock worth. The
market recognized this and adjusted. Also, disappointing earnings reports from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> and other blue-chip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two weeks</TIMEX> leading up to the crash
caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to question the value of entire portfolios.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX>: Many trace the dive to economic
slumps in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>--which together
buy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> exports. Dependent on a steady stream of foreign
investment to finance their large trade deficits, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> were forced to devalue their currencies, making their exports
cheaper in foreign markets. In the short term, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> will benefit from
cheap imports (as will <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">multinationals</ENAMEX> that use parts made in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>). On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> may have to lower their own
prices to compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> products. Such deflationary pressures, pessimists
note, set off the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>:
Blame goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> for not helping the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> stabilize their currency the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s aid during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1994</TIMEX> peso crisis. In response to criticism,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> guaranteed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3-billion</NUMEX> loan to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S. Recession</ENAMEX>: Some argue the crash
was the announcement of a long-overdue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> recession. An especially ominous
sign is the lower-than-expected earnings of supposedly booming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX>. There are also new reports of increased
bankruptcy filings--up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>--and predictions that growth will
slow to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5 percent</NUMEX>, down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percentage point from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>.
Conditions are said to resemble those in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> prior to the early '90s
recession. This theory for the stock plunge of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> would not, of course,
explain why stocks soared back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
