
   
   
      
         
            Selling Land to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, a 70-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> was murdered after he violated a new edict by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> making the sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-owned land to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> a capital
crime. The issue of land sales has a long history as a subtheme of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> struggle.

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> who conceived of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zionism</ENAMEX> --the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> survival depends on the establishment of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the biblical land of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>--never worked out their ideology's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">logistics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">settlement</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>, then part of the decaying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>, only proceeded piecemeal. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1880s and 1890s</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 25,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
immigrated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. Most integrated into multiethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaffa, Tiberias</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> wave of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>
came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1905 and 1914</TIMEX>, many of whom were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Zionists</ENAMEX> who wanted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to be socialist. Extolling the virtues of manual labor, they
acquired huge tracts of farmland from absentee <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX>.
The "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Palestinian Jew</ENAMEX> ," they said, needed to be physically tougher
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brainy shopkeepers</ENAMEX> who had been trampled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish National Fund</ENAMEX> was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX> for the
purpose of buying up land from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman Empire</ENAMEX>'s defeat
in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine</ENAMEX> and promised (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balfour</ENAMEX>
Declaration) the creation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. In anticipation, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>
began laying the groundwork for a greater sense of national identity. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish National Fund</ENAMEX>'s charter was amended to mandate that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> could
never be resold to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> or opened to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.

            Following
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish National Fund</ENAMEX> guidelines, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> evicted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> living on
the newly acquired plots. The total number displaced was small. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
owned <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 7 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>, but the perceived threat of displacement was
widespread among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>. Starting around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> railed against
Jewish land acquisition. Among the peasantry, rumors spread alleging an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> conspiracy to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. Anxious to avoid
being blamed for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlessness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> began imposing
token restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> land purchase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>. They publicly supported
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> complaints that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were driving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> off the land.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> say evictions destroyed
their way of life, forcing them to move from rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> to crowded cities
in search of work. They also say that the better-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> had
duped illiterate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> into selling property.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Fund</ENAMEX>, created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX> by wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to purchase land for
displaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>, was ineffective. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> responses
turned violent . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>'s mufti, the spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, decreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> were duty bound to murder other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>
who sold land to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>, who outnumbered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-to-1</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolted</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> land acquisition and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> promises of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nationhood</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were killed in riots and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrilla</ENAMEX> attacks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1936 and 1939</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zionists</ENAMEX> argued that the land purchases benefited all the
territory's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> introduced modern agricultural
technology , which increased productivity and helped fill the markets with
food to feed the growing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zionists</ENAMEX> also maintain that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
became a lucrative market for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-manufactured goods.

            Some
historians trace <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlessness</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>'s entry into the
world economy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1880s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban commerce</ENAMEX> drew some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> from their
family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>. Other subsistence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> found themselves competing with
cash-crop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>) whose successes changed the face of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> agriculture. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> purchases were not the primary factor,
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> say.

            
Very little of the land owned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was acquired by purchase. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
sovereignty and ownership were established the way these things usually are: by
war. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> confiscated all land owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, mostly desert
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1948 War</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX> . Property owned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, who either fled war zones or were forced from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> (another long-standing controversy), was also taken over by
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> or confiscated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, however,
stayed put, retained their land, and became <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.

            A new
school of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> is more critical of the dislocations caused by
Jewish land acquisition, and concludes that it was not always fair. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> popular
theory compares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zionism</ENAMEX>'s imperative to acquire land to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> idea of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manifest Destiny</ENAMEX> (that it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' God-given right to rule
from coast to coast). Others argue that it was a mistake for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Fund</ENAMEX> to prohibit <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> from the newly purchased lands.
However, even these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revisionists</ENAMEX> agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> had not intended to evict
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> believed that the murdered
real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> was executed by plainclothes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>'s decision to make the sale of land to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> a
capital crime reflects <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> frustration with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> land use,
specifically the creation of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> neighborhood now under
construction in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>.

            In the past, death
threats have done little to deter sales of land. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> land
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mufti</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> decree failed to prevent sales. But that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decree</ENAMEX> did not have the power of civil law behind it. Nevertheless, the
incentives to sell at the market price are substantial, and if the threats
create new scarcities, higher prices will probably encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> to unload
their land.

         
      
   
